<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong property: landlords enjoy market rebound as students return, with city rents climbing to 15-month high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/property/hong-kong-china/article/3223831/hong-kong-property-landlords-enjoy-market-rebound-students-return-city-rents-climbing-15-month-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/6b59a007-115e-41d9-948b-a92b2a5d3e97_113a4108.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港的房东正在享受经济重新开放和中国内地需求带来的好处私人住房市场的租金连续第四个月攀升至 15 个月以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中原城租数据，5 月份租金环比上涨 1.4% 至 112.78中原地产编制的指数，追踪全市138个屋苑。这是自 2018 年 8 月录得 1.94% 的涨幅以来的最大涨幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最近，学生和[在职]专业人士开始预租单位，促进了租赁交易，”杨明仪说，中原地产研究高级副总监。 “预计旺季会提早到来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;复苏给行业分析师注入了乐观情绪，他们预测随着香港欢迎游客回归以及来自大陆学生的竞争长期推高价格，这种好转趋势将持续- 定期租赁。在最近一次复苏之前，从 2020 年初 Covid-19 爆发到 2023 年 2 月重新开放，租金已下跌 8.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中原地产预计租金将在年底前稳步上涨。随着暑假的临近，中原表示短租市场将进入季节性繁荣期。该公司的指数在第三季度可能会再攀升 2.9% 至 116，这是自 2021 年 10 月以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着政府吸引顶尖人才的措施，海外高收入人才有望回归或者逐渐来香港，”莱坊大中华区研究和咨询总监兼主管 Martin Wong 说。 “我们预计今年整体房屋租金将增长 2% 至 3%。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;建议出台更严格的规定，以淘汰香港公屋的富人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该机构介绍了租金指数作为政府数据的替代品，以反映私人住房市场的趋势。它从其跟踪的全市 138 个主要住宅区的租户签署的新租约中收集数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场反弹影响了像 Frida Guan 这样的大陆学生，她在香港的校园附近租了一个地方九龙红磡理工大学。续租一年后，她将从8月起每月额外支付1500港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我租的公寓靠近大学，很多学生也在这区找房子，这是租金上涨的主要原因，”她说。她从与同行的聊天中了解到，月租金上涨了 1,000 港元至 2,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份的中原城市租金指数显示，港岛地区的涨幅最大，较上年同期上涨 2.19%一个月前。九龙及新界东分别录得1.55%及1.27%的升幅。新界西是唯一逆势而行的地区，租金下滑 0.04%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就户型而言，中原数据显示，随着租金攀升，面积超过 1,076 平方英尺的单位的需求最为强劲2.64%，连续五个月复苏至 5%，为 2021 年 12 月以来的最高水平。中小型公寓的租金较 4 月份上涨 1.26%，重新创下 2022 年 8 月以来的最高水平。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Cheryl Arcibal 的补充报告&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘He is sunshine’: Chinese father changes mind on lecturing son for average school marks when seeing him give classmates sweets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3223560/he-sunshine-chinese-father-changes-mind-lecturing-son-average-school-marks-when-seeing-him-give?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/11/9e16a5f9-6046-47b2-b9c3-cbc771a94950_501208ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位中国父亲奖励他八岁儿子在学校的慷慨对他学习成绩一般的批评在大陆社交媒体上引起了轰动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位来自中国东部山东省的周姓父亲在看到他的绰号晴朗的儿子给予惩罚后，改变了对处罚的看法。据齐鲁晚报报道，本月早些时候，他给同学们发了糖果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周某拍摄的一段视频中，可以看到庆朗拿着一个装满糖果的塑料袋，笑容满面，兴高采烈地把糖果递给同学。同学们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“谁还没有呢？青浪在视频中问他的同学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我”，一位同学回答。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周先生没有提前告诉儿子就到了学校，本来打算批评青浪的普通学校“他只是在试卷上犯了错误，他没有做坏事，”周说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“拥有健康的人生价值观高于一切，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事有在中国社交媒体上引起了很多人的共鸣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人评论说：“他很阳光。人们在他身边一定很开心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一人评论说：“他生活在一个充满爱和关怀的家庭中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年四月，慷慨的中国中部一名五岁男孩留了三年头发卖给癌症儿童捐款上了热搜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3月，中国东南部一名中学生上了新闻感谢六年来帮助一位截瘫同学，包括扶他上厕所，帮他吃饭。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China sends new patrol ship Haixun 03 on South China Sea mission]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223847/china-sends-new-patrol-ship-haixun-03-south-china-sea-mission?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/23a1e758-a669-458f-8a11-77a399614968_136d8121.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国派遣海巡03号巡逻舰前往有争议的西沙群岛&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国官方媒体周一报道，这艘船于周日抵达永兴岛（中文称为永兴岛），并将在周围海域巡逻至 7 月初.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项任务是在南海声索国争先恐后地在该水域活动的行为准则最终确定之前加强他们的声索之际进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;合法的第二个文本阅读-具有约束力的文件有望在今年内完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在中国称为西沙的西沙群岛建立了军事基地和平民定居点，但美国海军也经常通过该海域航行&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海巡号由海南省海事局 (MSA) 运营，其船员的任务是检查航行路线、电信和灯塔设备、信标、浮标和其他航行设施.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家通讯社新华社报道，他们还将检查该地区船舶的无线电响应和自动识别系统，并打击非法船舶作业和海洋污染。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员们还将与相关人员一起对相关岛屿进行调查，”报告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们将评估海上安全工作、紧急救援、避风塘、航行条件，并首先收集广泛的信息- 传递岛屿及其周围的信息，为南海的安全运输打下坚实的基础。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国对几乎整个资源丰富的南海提出主权主张，并在永兴岛上建立了三沙市2012 年管理中国领土主张的岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在 1974 年与南越短暂交战后获得了该岛的控制权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他南海声索国包括菲律宾、马来西亚、文莱和台湾，各自占据一些岛礁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是中国最大的海洋巡逻舰海巡03号于2021年下水并于去年服役的首次此类任务。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这艘长 128.6 米（42 英尺）、宽 16 米的船只设计航速为 20 节，航程约为 10,000 海里。它可以在没有补给的情况下巡逻 60 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据官方媒体报道，该船拥有配备先进综合监控系统的海事数据中心。据其设计师称，它还可以搭载多架直升机。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;南中国海：东盟将在中国紧张局势下举行首次联合军事演习&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;MSA 的巡逻舰队，专注于海上安全，与负责一般执法的准军事组织中国海岸警卫队平行运行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京倾向于使用 MSA 和海岸警卫队等“非军事”单位来对付敌对的声索国，留下人民解放军对付美国海军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，海事局和海岸警卫队的船只完全有能力对抗东南亚邻国的军舰。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ethnic minority pupils in Hong Kong face hurdle in obtaining visa for study tours to mainland China, principals say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3223859/ethnic-minority-pupils-hong-kong-face-hurdle-obtaining-visa-study-tours-mainland-china-principals?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/e98e12cc-fcd4-467b-8ebb-8b37acad2adf_72d0905a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港中学警告，少数族裔学生必须勇往直前才能获得参加强制性游学活动需要签证，呼吁当局简化程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参加中学文凭（DSE）考试的中五学生必须去大陆游学作为明年称为公民身份和社会发展的新核心主题的一部分。每年有1000多名少数民族学生参加考试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一批学校于4月开始了一日游，其他学校则计划在学期结束时的7月参观。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;明爱屯门马登基金中学校长袁国明表示，他们于五月组织了一次前往深圳和广州参观大学的行程。八名非中国学生参加了这次旅行，他们被要求在边境填写表格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然后他们都在手动通道中等待，”他说，并补充说学生们坚持回家许可证可以通过电子渠道快速过关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们等了半个多小时，8名持外国护照的非中国学生过关。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁表示担心在即将到来的 7 月旅行期间，学生和教师将不得不等待长达两个小时才能进入大陆，预计将有 30 名少数民族学生参加，占中五学生的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;校长表示，长时间等待出入境检查会缩短行程，并补充说交通工具已经花了两个多小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“一切都是中文”：香港少数族裔学生碰壁&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;他指出，过境的老师和学生在出发前必须等待所有人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为最后留给实地考察的时间不多了，”Yuen &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主要是少数族裔学生的明爱胡政中中学校长欧海健表示，学生必须准备很多文件才能获得签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “学生需要上交父母的身份证复印件、结婚证复印件，以及他们自己的旅行记录。他们还需要填写一份包含大量信息的表格……不同的国籍对文件有不同的要求，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Au 说他预计一些学生的父母可能会选择不申请签证&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Au 和 Yuen 都敦促当局与边境同行合作，简化移民程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Au 表示，他希望大陆当局能够让少数民族少数民族学生申请回乡证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持少数民族社区的关注组织 Hong Kong Unison 的执行董事 John Tse Wing-ling 表示，如果这些旅行只持续一段时间，就无法实现政府的目标几个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不符合最初的目的，就是让学生了解中国大陆，”谢说。 “他们的学习也将是微不足道的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;研究：少数族裔学生在香港接受特殊教育面临障碍&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中四和中五年级学生引入新的核心科目以取代2021 年的通识教育，此前有人指责该课程使年轻人变得激进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新课程的重点是国家安全、身份认同、合法性和爱国主义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育局早些时候提供了 22 条可能的路线适合大陆游。其中八人为一日游，六人为两天，其余为三日游。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年中五的学生是第一批学习新科目的学生。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;该局发言人表示，已要求大陆当局提供适当帮助，以加快非中国学生的移民程序，并补充说，学校可以要求学生提早集合，以便有足够的时间过关。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s wedding woes see annual unions nearly halved in past decade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3223818/chinas-wedding-woes-see-annual-unions-nearly-halved-past-decade?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/0c39e1c9-c3c9-4539-af51-6254f5cd3672_7c5478b3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的结婚人数已降至自 1970 年代后期以来的最低记录水平，进一步说明该国日益恶化的人口危机，其中包括 60 多年来首次出现的人口下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;结婚登记现已连续九年下降，去年的 683 万新婚夫妇几乎是去年的一半根据民政部的数据，2013 年有 1347 万对新人结婚，创历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国上一次结婚人数如此之少还是四十多年前，当时有 637 万对新人登记结婚1979 年结婚。然而，与 2022 年的 14.1 亿相比，当时中国的人口还不到 10 亿，这意味着现在的结婚率要低得多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在的年轻人追求的是一种生活中国人口协会副会长、天津南开大学人口学教授袁欣说。 “如果组建家庭阻碍了他们自身的发展和幸福，他们会选择不生育，甚至不结婚。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新婚人数逐年下降与该国的人口不断减少，2022 年减少了 85 万人——这是自 1961 年以来死亡人数首次超过出生人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年新生儿人数也在现代历史上首次降至 1000 万以下，这加剧了人们对中国人口增长的担忧人口危机加深并引发了关于如何鼓励生育的新一轮讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生活和结婚成本上升；年轻人数量下降；对儿子根深蒂固的文化偏好；根据独立人口统计学家何亚夫的说法，以及结婚者平均年龄的上升都是导致结婚人数减少的因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，结婚的个人数量而非夫妻数量根据《中国统计年鉴 2022》，首次结婚人数同比下降近 70 万人，降至 1160 万人。这还不到 2013 年首次结婚人数 2390 万人的一半。&lt;/p>; p>;根据《中国人口普查年鉴 2020》，中国人的初婚平均年龄也从 2010 年的 24.89 岁显着增加到 2020 年的 28.67 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断变化的文化和社会规范正在也在这些决定中发挥重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着负担的堆积，年轻的中国人“不能全神贯注地组建家庭”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在中国传统文化中，一个人的生活可能会被考虑没有配偶是不完整的，没有孩子的家庭可能被认为是不完整的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传统上，中国年轻的父母一直在努力和辛勤地资助他们的孩子，但现在年轻人越来越多地把钱用于资助人口统计学家 Yuan 补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，选择生育的家庭也越来越少。中国的头胎生育率——一个妇女一生平均生育的孩子数量——从2019年的0.7下降到2022年的0.5，进一步拉低了二胎和三胎的生育率。在这三年中，生育第一个孩子的女性的平均年龄从 26.4 岁增加到 27.4 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从 1978 年到 2019 年，离婚人数也有所增加，超过 400 万。 2021 年，一项新法律要求夫妻必须等待 30 天才能完成离婚，2022 年离婚人数骤降至 210 万。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong doesn’t need homes on Fanling golf course with big housing projects under way]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223700/hong-kong-doesnt-need-homes-fanling-golf-course-big-housing-projects-under-way?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/11/3e89340a-f5d0-4e55-9d25-5080cc71a56e_95a396e9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;有112年历史的粉岭高尔夫球场建公屋争议爆发上周，规划署提议将 32 公顷指定用地的用途从“住宅”临时更改为“未定”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这在社交媒体和主流媒体上引发了激烈的争论.环保署5月才批出部分发展公屋路线的环境影响报告书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为最近的变化，有人怀疑政府是不是变心了关于使用 172 公顷球场的五分之一建造 12,000 个公共住房单元，以及保护区和娱乐区。不过，发展局表示，用途的改变只是暂时的，当局仍致力于兴建公屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论如何，这件事可以作为一个插曲，重新评估兴建房屋的理由这个至关重要的高尔夫球场，考虑到失去中东的巨大商机和继续在香港举办著名高尔夫锦标赛的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让我们现实一点。提供经济适用房的需求不像以前那么紧迫。此外，即使修订后的发展计划获得通过，仍需要相当长的时间才能动工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了更好地理解这个问题，我们需要回到2017年。由于草根阶层严重买不起房，而且担心公屋的轮候时间长得难以忍受，时任行政长官林郑月娥着手寻找增加土地供应的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;下一步是什么有争议的香港高尔夫球场建屋计划？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其中一项建议是使用部分粉岭高尔夫球场作为公共房屋。这既有赞扬也有反对，利益集团、环保主义者、高尔夫爱好者、商业部门和公众都在权衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，快进到 2023 年。今天，有两个主要的工程中的发展——交椅洲人工岛项目（前称明日大屿愿景）和北都会。它们合起来可为超过 100 万人提供足够的私人和公共住房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港人口的预测下降也需要考虑在内。根据政府数据，在暴力社会动荡和 Covid-19 大流行之后，该市的人口数量已经小幅下降，总人口从 2019 年底的约 750 万下降到 2022 年底的 733 万。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;即便如此，不可否认的是，仍有一些人难以负担得起体面的出租房屋，被迫住在条件恶劣的分隔组屋中。对于其他人来说，拥有自己的房子仍然是一个白日梦，因为房产成本很高。因此，政府在继续推进交椅洲和北都会项目的同时，必须继续探索短期和中期的住房解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超推出轻型公屋计划并正在推出更多的青年旅馆，以减轻房地产市场的压力。此外，我们应重新审视前行政长官梁振英所倡导的发展郊野公园边缘地区的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;积极解决房屋短缺问题，平均公屋轮候时间逐渐减少从上个月的5.5年到5.3年，我们应该借此机会评估在粉岭高尔夫球场使用少量土地兴建公营房屋的成本和收益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人提出关注，例如，关于缺乏公共交通工具。然而，更令人担忧的是，如果该计划继续进行，遗产树木和几种极度濒危物种将无法挽回地消失。这也可能影响香港举办著名高尔夫锦标赛的能力，包括由沙特阿拉伯资助的赛事，李最近努力与沙特阿拉伯建立融洽关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，让我们退后一步，审视所有提供公共住房的其他可用选择。或许到那时我们就可以把粉岭高尔夫球场排除在外了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden root canal forces abrupt postponement of Nato meeting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223858/joe-biden-root-canal-forces-abrupt-postponement-nato-meeting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 06:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/2ac422d3-69d9-442e-860a-7f3c2b7d23e1_480ab03d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔拜登周一接受了牙根管治疗，几乎没有公开警告，迫使推迟所有预定的活动，包括与北约秘书长的会晤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与北约秘书长延斯·斯托尔滕贝格的计划会晤，以及晚间外交招待会，“将重新安排在明天”，白宫豪斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统医生凯文·C·奥康纳 (Kevin C. O&#39;Connor) 在一份声明中说，拜登右下颌的一颗前臼齿接受了根管治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新闻秘书卡琳·让 (Karine Jean)皮埃尔说，该程序“已成功完成。总统身体很好，他今天下午肯定会在官邸工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管白宫淡化了这一事件，但拜登已经 80 岁了，是有史以来最年长的总统。由于他争取在 2024 年赢得第二个任期，因此对他的健康状况进行了严格的审查，到他离任时他的健康状况将达到 86 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯托尔滕贝格会议原定于上周白宫与在拜登为 7 月在立陶宛举行的北约峰会做准备之际，盟国英国和丹麦的首相们纷纷出动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西方联盟积极参与协助乌克兰抵御俄罗斯的入侵，现在所有人都在关注命运乌克兰为解放领土而大肆宣扬的攻势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约要解决的另一个大问题是为斯托尔滕贝格选择继任者，斯托尔滕贝格的任期将于 10 月结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登开玩笑说他得到了 &#39;在仪式上摔倒后被沙袋包裹”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;奥康纳说，拜登的牙齿问题是从周日开始的疼痛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沃尔特里德总统医院的一个团队立即对他进行了检查，该团队被派往怀特House。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团队“能够在白宫牙科手术室进行检查，包括 X 光检查。他们确定牙髓治疗（根管治疗）是最合适的。当时进行了初始根管手术，并计划在不久的将来进行专门的牙髓跟进，”奥康纳写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医生说拜登“对手术的耐受性很好。没有并发症。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，总统说他“感到更加不适”，导致决定完成根管治疗，奥康纳说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为周日的牙科工作没有公开宣布，周一提出了关于是否发生了更严重的事情的问题。让-皮埃尔驳斥了这一说法，称该手术“没什么不寻常的”，“数百万美国人都经历过这种情况”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她强调说，只使用了局部麻醉剂，这意味着不需要援引第 25 条修正案并将总统权力暂时移交给副总统卡马拉哈里斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，牙科干预提醒人们医疗问题如何突然打乱政府的节奏。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登嘲笑年龄的笑话, 攻击新闻媒体的“谎言”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管保证没有发生紧急情况，但根管治疗显然是计划外的，因​​为需要推迟在白宫举行的两次高层会议.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登出席第三场活动——与大学运动员一起庆祝活动——在活动开始前不到一个小时就被取消，取而代之的是哈里斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让-皮埃尔说哈里斯自己发现周一早上，她将代替拜登参加运动员活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，“这并没有什么神秘的”，让-皮埃尔说。 “这是很多人经常经历的事情。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As US-China ties hit new lows, are diplomatic backchannels still effective?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223820/us-china-ties-hit-new-lows-are-diplomatic-backchannels-still-effective?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/19e851e8-1b4c-4436-a611-933128aa9e5a_3f73ee39.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最近几周中美高级官员之间的会谈给中美两国之间的紧张局势带来了希望世界上的两个大国可能正在放松。在关于中美关系的第三篇文章中，施江涛探讨了幕后外交是否仍能像五年前那样帮助两国关系重回正轨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当美国前总统理查德尼克松和他的前任总统1989 年底，国家安全顾问亨利·基辛格 (Henry Kissinger) 应中国政府的邀请访问北京，这对现实主义者的任务是挽救几乎破烂不堪的双边关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所谓的“实况调查”之旅，单独但在两周的时间里，发生在血腥的天安门广场镇压几个月后，但得到了美国总统老布什的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管布什政府的正式政策禁止此类高层访问，北京和华盛顿都对尼克松和基辛格重现 1970 年代初的成功抱有很高的希望，当时他们共同策划了与中国的历史性和解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼克松被认为传达了个人信息布什总统告诉中国最高领导人邓小平，尽管存在“巨大且不可逾越的”分歧，两国仍应“超越当下的尖刻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须从这里开始建设。据《纽约时报》报道，这位前总统在与邓小平会面后告诉记者，如果我们在 72 年能做到，我们现在也能做到。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国代表团与前美国官员、高管会谈&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于中美关系近几个月跌至历史低点，有人呼吁重演这种非正式的外交努力，这对稳定动荡的关系起到了重要作用。但观察人士表示，随着两国之间日益增长的不信任和敌意，近年来通常被称为 Track 1.5 和 Track 2 对话的反向渠道外交已基本无效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果没有针对共同竞争对手的利益战略联盟，今天就无法复制与北京的秘密渠道。然而，一些人希望它仍然有助于设定一个“最不坏”的底线，以避免双边关系彻底破裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼克松和基辛格的访问是“中美之间秘密渠道外交的一个例子”四川大学国际事务教授庞中英说，自从后者 1971 年秘密访华开启了与北京的秘密渠道以来，美国处于最佳状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去五年的大部分时间里他说，几十年来，幕后外交在帮助稳定经常动荡的美中关系方面发挥了“重要且不可或缺”的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然第二轨道对话通常涉及来自学术界和智库的非政府代表, Track 1.5 对话通常涉及以非官方身份行事的政府官员与其他对话者之间的非正式交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据康奈尔大学教授兼亚洲协会政策研究所高级研究员 Jessica Chen Weiss 的说法，非官方对话对北京和华盛顿更好地了解对方的看法很重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它们还创造了空间来探索双方可以合理共存的潜在理解和条款，同时支持传统外交当官方外交重新接触正在寻求获得牵引力和势头时，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，双边关系处于半个世纪以来最严重的螺旋式下降，尤其是在 Covid-19 之后大流行和俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，官方交流已减少到最低限度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多人还对学术和民间交流的冻结感到震惊。最近几个月，越来越多的学者、智库和前政府官员效仿基辛格打破僵局的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“缺乏面对面的接触并不是关键两国之间紧张局势的根源，但它是稳定关系、避免危机以及在双边问题和全球挑战（如气候变化和公共卫生）方面进行合作的障碍，”一对学者——一名中国人和一名美国人——警告说4月《外交》杂志文章。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;幕后外交的回归为美中关系带来希望&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;文章由专家王缉思联合撰写北京大学的美国问题研究专家斯科特·肯尼迪和华盛顿战略与国际研究中心的中国商业和经济专家斯科特·肯尼迪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅和肯尼迪决定分别访问美国和中国，而中国的零 Covid 限制已经到位，可以与学者和政策专家会面并写下他们的经验。肯尼迪去年秋天访问了中国，王毅在 2022 年春季和秋季两次访问了美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在随后发表的题为“打破僵局”的报告中，他们确定了不断恶化的关系和自我强化的恶性循环“a sense of fatalism in both Beijing and Washington about the trajectory of ties”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November, Wang also joined a semi-official Chinese delegation on a rare US tour led by former deputy foreign minister Wang Chao. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of Beijing&#39;s efforts to stabilise ties, the visit was believed to be sanctioned by Chinese President Xi Jinping himself, and participants included former commerce minister Chen Deming and former Chinese ambassador to the US Cui Tiankai.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;They met a slew of Beijing&#39;s “old friends”, including Maurice “Hank” Greenberg, the 98-year-old former chairman and CEO of insurer American International Group, and Kissinger, who turned 100 last month.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;It was not the first time Beijing sought to boost backchannel diplomacy through unofficial conduits, such as Wall Street veterans Greenberg and former Goldman Sachs president John Thornton.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a rare six-week visit to China in 2021, Thornton was given privileged treatment, including a week-long trip to Xinjiang, where Beijing&#39;s suppression of the ethnic minority Uygur population has become a global focal point in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Zhiqun Zhu, an international relations professor at Bucknell University, said it would be virtually impossible for Beijing to find a replacement for Kissinger to conduct effective backchannel diplomacy with Beijing in times of crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the mixed results from the Bush administration&#39;s secret diplomatic efforts, pundits said Nixon and Kissinger were well-positioned to make the trips to China thanks to their influence in both Washington and Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Indeed, Beijing does not have a close ally in Washington now who can help it to access the White House directly. To some, despite his diminishing influence or perhaps overrated role, Kissinger remains an intermediary between the two governments,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted there were “very few people” who could match Kissinger in this role or who would be willing to help Beijing now. “Perhaps Greenberg and [former treasury secretary] Hank Paulson are some of the other candidates, but none enjoys the high esteem and status of Kissinger in China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;After Shangri-La Dialogue fuelled the fire, what&#39;s next for US-China relations?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Zhu Feng, an expert on US affairs at Nanjing University, said it would be wishful thinking to pin hopes on backchannel diplomacy, which would not be as effective as during the Nixon-Kissinger era in the 1970s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The era is gone when Washington needed Beijing to counterbalance Moscow. Although the US and China still share some common interests, Washington views Beijing as its biggest rival. So the strategic imperative behind the push for backchannel diplomacy is no longer there,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite Kissinger&#39;s longevity and his relatively balanced views on China, Zhu doubted the US statesman would still have a big role to play in future US-China ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Backchannel diplomacy is important in principle and it is still necessary to maintain contact and communication at all levels, but given the unanimous consensus on the US policy towards China, I don&#39;t see how much difference those backchannels can make,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun Sun, a senior fellow at Washington&#39;s Stimson Centre, also said it would be impossible to recreate the success Kissinger achieved 50 years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Backchannel diplomacy worked during the Kissinger era primarily because the US and China shared common interests vis-à-vis [the] Soviet Union. Without such strategic alignment of interests, mere backchannel diplomacy could not have achieved the rapprochement,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun said that for Beijing, the biggest issue was not the lack of conversations with Washington, but the bipartisan consensus in the US backing an anti-China policy shift.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Exchanges do help to improve understanding and clarify issues. But currently the issue is not misunderstanding, but a fundamental distrust of each other as their most consequential threat and challenge by both US and China,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To assume that exchanges can change things is to assume this perception by both countries is wrong. And that is a big assumption to make. Beijing doesn&#39;t have as high an interest in resuming dialogues with the US because it does not bring benefits, and US hostile policies continue regardless of the dialogues.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sourabh Gupta, a senior fellow at the Institute for China-America Studies in Washington, said another reason backchannels might not work effectively was the change in China&#39;s attitude.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gupta said “hope was for the most part given up” at the highest echelons of Chinese leadership in the summer of 2019 after the failure of trade war negotiations, in which Xi had “vested a great deal of sincerity and political capital”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said backchannel diplomacy, which served as “the lubricant that helped grease good intentions and interests into tangible outcomes”, could no longer work because the two countries were each other&#39;s rivals today.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While these dialogues have contributed mightily in the past to narrow conceptual gaps between the two sides and build understanding, they have lost their vitality and utility as bilateral relations have nosedived over the past five years,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While unofficial dialogues on climate change and non-technology commercial exchanges might still be useful in exploring common interests and potential for cooperation, Gupta said the role of the Track 1.5/2 mechanisms were largely ineffective for contentious issues concerning defence and technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But according to Gupta, another form of backchannel diplomacy, similar to Nixon and Kissinger&#39;s visits in 1989, could prove increasingly important with the deterioration of bilateral ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To the extent that backchannel diplomacy is conducted by interlocutors who are known by the other side to be very close to senior decision-makers, such engagement will continue to have utility,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citing Cui&#39;s meeting with US deputy secretary of state Wendy Sherman and other officials with the State Department&#39;s new “China House” unit during a trip to Washington in the spring, Gupta said those dialogues could have “real value to both sides”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;At 100, Kissinger still seen as influential &#39;old friend&#39; in China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last June and July, the Centre for China and Globalisation, a government-linked think tank in Beijing, organised a 10-day tour of Washington and New York in a bid to promote the resumption of face-to-face scholarly exchanges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its founder and president, Wang Huiyao, a former Chinese government official, said the in-person exchanges with nearly a dozen US think tanks, including CSIS and the Brookings Institution, were still of some significance in clarifying misperceptions and misconceptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We became the first Chinese think tank delegation to visit the US in over two years, which came at the height of China&#39;s Covid-related controls. It set an example of how non-governmental groups could help break the impasse between the two countries, more or less similar to what Kissinger did in the 1970s,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While he admitted it would be hard to replicate Kissinger&#39;s groundbreaking success, Wang said the value of unofficial exchanges should not be underestimated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report commissioned by the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission last year urged the Pentagon to reestablish Track 1.5 and 2 military dialogues with China to manage the growing risks of mishaps and miscalculations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gupta also agreed that backchannel diplomacy, though it might have lost its shine, would still be useful in preventing the worst-case scenarios.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is recognition at Beijing&#39;s end that China – to serve its own geopolitical and development interests – needs to forge the &#39;least worst&#39; relationship with the US, lest bilateral ties hurtle to the point of total breakdown.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US says it had to declassify information before confirming Chinese spy base in Cuba]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3223857/us-says-it-had-declassify-information-confirming-chinese-spy-base-cuba?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 06:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/13/2c9a659b-67cb-406e-90ff-db2d434e75f5_16bb3862.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Officials in US President Joe Biden&#39;s administration scrambled to downgrade classified information about an alleged Chinese spy base in Cuba in an effort to correct what it called inaccurate reporting on the matter, a senior official said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said information about the base was too sensitive to provide guidance for The Wall Street Journal, which first reported that Beijing and Havana had struck a secret agreement for a facility on the island that could capture electronic transmissions in the southeastern US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A White House official confirmed over the weekend that China has been operating a spy base in Cuba since at least 2019. Beijing&#39;s foreign ministry has denied any knowledge of such a facility and called Washington out for “secretive activities” in Cuba.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Havana also denied The Journal&#39;s report, with Deputy Foreign Minister Carlos Fernández de Cossío calling the newspaper&#39;s information “totally mendacious and unfounded.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reports of cooperation between China and Cuba on surveillance capabilities have sparked inquiries about how long such activities have been going on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The sensitive nature of this information is such that we just simply couldn&#39;t go into more detail, even before the [Wall Street Journal] story appeared to try to better inform that reporting,” Kirby said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After the first stories appeared, we worked very, very hard and as expeditiously as we could with the intelligence community to try to get some context downgraded so that we could provide it over the weekend.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;News of the alleged base in Cuba also comes amid reports that US Secretary of State Antony Blinken plans to visit Beijing next week, resetting a visit that was postponed after a Chinese balloon that Washington says was meant for surveillance flew across the US in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Blinken to visit China, carry out trip postponed after spy balloon incident&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US officials have said that Beijing refused to take calls from the Pentagon about the balloon before Biden ordered it shot down and has been unwilling to engage in high-level military-to-military talks since.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken said on Monday that former president Donald Trump&#39;s administration knew in 2019 of efforts by the Chinese government to upgrade intelligence collection facilities in Cuba and that actions by the Biden administration have slowed them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our experts assess that our diplomatic efforts have slowed down this effort by the PRC,” Blinken said, referring to the People&#39;s Republic of China. “We&#39;ve been executing on that approach quietly, carefully – but, in our judgment, with results – ever since.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Kirby denied that US intelligence about China&#39;s alleged cooperation with Cuba on surveillance would derail Blinken&#39;s plan to visit Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nothing&#39;s changed about the fact that we understand that the bilateral relationship with China is tense right now, and nothing&#39;s changed about the fact that [Biden] wants to keep the lines of communication open with the PRC,” Kirby said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some of the important lines of communication, military-to-military, are not open and we want to get them back open,” he added. “As for whether this recent reporting out of Cuba is going to affect Secretary Blinken in his travel plans, I would not expect so.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine claims new gains in early phase of counteroffensive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3223856/ukraine-claims-new-gains-early-phase-counteroffensive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 04:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/13/f4dab6b9-1db0-4117-bae4-3edd6a21d0e5_e5e57b43.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukraine said on Monday its troops had recaptured seven villages from Russian forces along an approximately 100km (60-mile) front in the southeast since launching its long-anticipated counteroffensive last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The task of ending Moscow&#39;s occupation of southern and eastern Ukraine is daunting, given Russia&#39;s numerical superiority in men, ammunition and air power, and the many months it has had to build deep defensive fortifications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, soldiers were seen in video holding the Ukrainian flag in the village of Storozheve, along the Mokri Yaly river which flows northward out of Russian-held territory. Reuters confirmed the location.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A day earlier Kyiv said its forces heading south had liberated three other nearby villages along the Mokri Yaly: Blahodatne, Neskuchne and Makarivka.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy Defence Minister Hanna Maliar said in a Telegram post late on Monday that Ukrainian forces had also recaptured Levadne and Novodarivka, around 10km (six miles) west of the Mokri Yaly, as well as Lobkove, southeast of the city of Zaporizhzhia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maliar said troops had advanced a total of 6.5km. “The area of the territory taken under control was 90 square km (35 square miles),” she said. Maliar added that the seven settlements were taken over the past week, without giving details of precisely when.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not possible to verify all the battlefield claims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The push is already Ukraine&#39;s most rapid advance for seven months, though still short of a breakthrough, with Russia believed to have a strong line of fortifications further south.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Sure to win&#39;: North Korea&#39;s Kim vows to &#39;hold hands&#39; with Russia&#39;s Putin&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The furthest advance claimed by Kyiv leaves its forces still some 90km (55 miles) from the Azov Sea coast and the prize of cutting Russia&#39;s “land bridge” to Crimea, the peninsula Moscow seized from Ukraine in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Ukrainian defence spokesman said Russia had blown up a dam on the Mokri Yaly to make it harder for Ukrainian forces to thrust farther south. That came less than a week after a huge dam was destroyed on the much larger Dnipro River, causing a humanitarian disaster in a swathe of the south.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kyiv has also launched assaults at other locations along the long front line, probing for Russian weaknesses, though it has given few details so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine is banking on the tens of billions of dollars&#39; worth of weaponry, training and intelligence it has received from the West, combined with its own battlefield resolve, tactical nous and the motivation of driving an invader from its own land, to give it the edge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also knows it may have to show significant progress over the summer to maintain the same level of Western military, financial and political support, and one day have a chance of recovering from the loss and devastation inflicted by Moscow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s armed forces said they had engaged in two dozen heavy battles in the previous 24 hours on the eastern front, near the town of Bakhmut, further south near Avdiivka and Maryinka, and further north near Bilohorivka.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They have not been providing similar detail about fighting on the southern front, where the main counteroffensive is expected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moscow has yet to officially acknowledge any Ukrainian advances. On Monday, Russia&#39;s defence ministry repeated regular assertions of the past week that it had repelled attempted offensives in the Donetsk and Zaporizhzhia regions, and said it had hit Ukrainian army reserve locations with long-range missiles.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine says it recaptured village, Russia insists it is repelling attacks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But prominent Russian military bloggers said Ukrainian forces had in fact taken Blahodatne, Neskuchne and Makarivka, and were pushing on southward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Monday said it was too soon to say exactly where Ukraine&#39;s counteroffensive was going but that Washington was confident Kyiv would continue to have success.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at a press conference in Washington, Blinken said the United States was determined to maximise its support for Ukraine. A “robust” package of political and practical support for Ukraine, Blinken added, could be expected at the coming Nato summit in Vilnius.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some Western military analysts said it was too early to draw conclusions about the counteroffensive, and the skirmishes so far might show Ukraine is still just testing Russian defences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US-based Institute for the Study of War said Ukraine was attempting “an extraordinarily difficult tactical operation – a frontal assault against prepared defensive positions, further complicated by a lack of air superiority”, and that initial assaults should not be overinterpreted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ben Hodges, a former commander of US forces in Europe, said the main attack, when it came, would feature several hundred tanks and infantry fighting vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The offensive has clearly started, but not I think the main attack,” which would involve large, armoured formations, he wrote in an article for the Washington-based Centre for European Policy Analysis.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine&#39;s Zelensky says troops &#39;positive&#39; as counteroffensive under way&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Russia has yet to face this kind of onslaught, but its unconvincing battlefield performance in the 15 months since its full-scale invasion has led to frequent changes of command and public arguments with the private militias summoned to fight alongside the army.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Vladimir Putin marked Russia&#39;s national day with an award ceremony in the Kremlin, but made only glancing mention in his speech of the war he had unleashed, at enormous cost to his own citizens in lost lives, money and international relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, at a difficult time for Russia, [feelings of patriotism and pride] unite our society even more strongly … [and] serve as a reliable support for our heroes taking part in the special military operation,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Eat, Pray, Love writer Elizabeth Gilbert yanks new Russia-set novel after Ukraine outcry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223855/eat-pray-love-writer-elizabeth-gilbert-yanks-new-russia-set-novel-after-ukraine-outcry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 03:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/15f451dc-de5b-4013-b7c9-339c2817ac66_4b898f8c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;作者伊丽莎白·吉尔伯特 (Elizabeth Gilbert) 制作了销量数百万的美食、祈祷和爱情进入由朱莉娅·罗伯茨 (Julia Roberts) 主演的好莱坞大红大紫，周一表示，她正在搁置她的新小说，因为这部小说的背景设定在俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举说明了出版商、名人以及体育和艺术团体所面临的困难因为他们试图处理莫斯科入侵乌克兰的后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉尔伯特上周宣布《雪林》将于明年初出版，但暴风雪般的负面宣传迫使情况发生逆转。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“我收到了乌克兰读者的大量反应和回应，他们表达了愤怒、悲伤、失望和痛苦，因为我会选择立即向世界发行一本书——任何一本书，无论如何她在 Instagram 视频中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不想对已经经历过并且正在继续经历严重和极端伤害的一群人增加任何伤害。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这部小说以 1930 年代的苏联俄罗斯为背景，讲述了一个家庭试图&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管它与现代事件相去甚远，但 Goodreads 网站上的读者几乎一致抨击了主题的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当乌克兰人快死的时候来自俄罗斯恐怖分子的著名作家正在写关于他们的书，并将这些混蛋浪漫化，”留下一星评论的数百人中的一位写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国作家被控谋杀丈夫，讲述悲痛的死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“你写的是俄罗斯，在这个国家在乌克兰犯下种族灭绝和生态灭绝的同时浪漫化这个国家吗？一个完整的耻辱！我对你很失望！”另一位写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约大都会歌剧院去年与俄罗斯明星 Anna Netrebko 保持距离，因为她之前支持总统弗拉基米尔普京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯和白俄罗斯运动员被禁止参加一些在他们的国旗下进行的体育比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吃，祈祷，爱——被拍成电影时没有标点符号的程式化——讲述了一个中年妇女在之后进行的自我发现之旅的故事痛苦的离婚。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>