<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[India’s human-hair trade at risk as ‘rampant smuggling’ to China via Bangladesh, Myanmar cuts into profits]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3226155/indias-human-hair-trade-risk-rampant-smuggling-china-bangladesh-myanmar-cuts-profits?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/404f5515-fb05-46af-88f8-da5fb1bd8176_ad8e93a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;每天五个小时，哈西娜·比比 (Hasina Bibi) 煞费苦心地梳理脱落的人类头发、分类将其切成股，并将长度超过六英寸（15 厘米）的碎片制成“球”，将其余的扔进垃圾箱。每月解开约 25 公斤头发，她可以赚取 7,500 卢比（92 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法想象废弃的人发可以为我提供稳定的收入来源，”35 岁的 Bibi 说道。住在印度西孟加拉邦首府加尔各答西南约 100 公里处的 Habi Chak 村。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东部邦的许多像 Bibi 这样的贫困妇女的收入几乎占印度人发出口的一半。据印度人发及发制品制造商和出口商协会称，该国人发行业价值约 10 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;头发交易商收集毛球（俗称“goli”）。或 chutti——来自 Bibi 等分拣机，然后在小作坊中进行半加工。球中的毛发长度范围为 4 至 40 英寸（10 厘米 - 101 厘米），半加工过程包括清洗、劈开并按尺寸排列它们，然后使用从根部到尖端相同长度和厚度的发丝将它们拉直。 /p>;&lt;p>;这些双拉接发然后被合法出口到其他国家——中国、美国和欧洲国家是印度头发的最大买家——这些国家用它们为当地和国际制造假发和其他发制品过去，中国公司以每公斤约200美元的价格直接从印度企业购买头发，并用其为全球制造假发、接发、睫毛、画笔和假胡须。但他们现在聘请当地代理商，以每公斤 60 至 70 美元的价格从印度贸易商处购买毛球，然后将其从该国走私到邻国孟加拉国——近 400 公斤被运往印度。据边境部队称，仅 2021 年就查获了这些毛球，这意味着印度损失了大量税收。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一旦毛球到达孟加拉国，它们就会被送往当地作坊进行加工，然后最终出现。在中国销售，通常通过缅甸陆运。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;缅甸的人发贸易生意兴隆&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sunil Eamani，印度人发及发制品制造商成员和出口商协会表示，无良的中国贸易商会选择走私头发，以避免缴纳进口价值约 30% 的关税和税金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，人类头发很早就从印度走私到缅甸。与 2012 年一样，但随着过去五年中国进口商利用当地廉价劳动力在孟加拉国设立加工厂，头发现在也被走私到邻国南亚国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eamani 表示，561,000 名印度人失去了头发过去三年，由于西孟加拉邦、新德里、拉贾斯坦邦、特伦甘纳邦、安得拉邦和泰米尔纳德邦的许多小型头发加工作坊被关闭，走私导致了他们的工作岗位被走私。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人发走私已成为一个严重的问题。这让印度边防部队更加头疼，因为他们已经在努力应对抓捕也在与邻国孟加拉国 4,096 公里边境沿线活动的牲畜、黄金和毒品贩运者的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度边境安全官员不愿透露姓名的西孟加拉邦表示，今年迄今已在边境查获 350 公斤人类头发，而去年则扣押了 1,104 公斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管印度是世界上最大的出口国，其次是印度尼西亚埃马尼表示，今年迄今为止，已向中国和美国出口了价值 6.078 亿美元的人发及相关产品，如果能够制止走私贸易，该国每年可以赚取 30 亿美元。利润和税收。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度头发重量轻、有光泽、呈波浪状且有弹性，是全球假发和接发的首选。印度出口的 5% 以上是质量最好的所谓“人头马头发”，从单一来源收集，角质层仍然完好无损。这些头发是从印度南部的寺庙收集的，那里的妇女出于宗教原因剃光头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但印度出口的其他头发是非雷米的剩余头发 - 通常是从美容院的地板上捡来的，然后购买或购买与较贫穷的妇女进行物物交换，以换取现金、器皿或小饰品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;55 岁的加尔各答 Nishibala Ari 仔细收集并梳理自己所有的废发，每根售价 5,000 卢比（61 美元）。公斤给经常上门拜访的女性毛发收集者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，2018 年的价格为每公斤 2,000 卢比，但随着需求的增加，价格也在上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我卖每六个月大约产生 250 克废发。这对我来说是额外收入。”担任家庭佣工的 Ari 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Eamani 表示，当地贸易商通常更愿意与为中国进口商工作的代理商进行交易，后者支付费用现金或通过“哈瓦拉”网络——一种在印度被禁止的非正式资金转移系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他声称这使得当地商人能够将毒品和黄金走私到印度。他表示，与此同时，印度出口商通常只能通过银行转账方式支付重大交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 2021 年的市场研究，到 2026 年，全球假发和人发市场预计将达到 133 亿美元阿里兹顿咨询和情报局的报告称，但猖獗的走私意味着印度预计只能看到这笔财富的一小部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;头发出口商、总部位于金奈的 Allure Hair Products 总监萨蒂什·甘地 (Sathish Gandhi) 表示，腐败的中国贸易商在全球范围内以比印度出口商更具竞争力的价格出售印度头发，因为前者通过逃税省钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;当中国男子因拒绝剪长发而被处决时&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同时，尽管印度出口商一直蒙受损失，孟加拉国的官方假发出口却猛增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该国出口促进局的数据，2022 年 7 月至今年 5 月，孟加拉国出口了价值 1.13 亿美元的假发和人发比去年同期的出口额 9550 万美元有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甘地表示，规模较小的中国进口商最有可能参与头发走私以逃避税收。他说，大多数较大的进口商都是光明正大的，并补充说，如果没有印度的供应，中国的头发贸易将无法生存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但埃马尼声称，中国通过在印度销售印度头发制成的产品，正在从印度窃取利润。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国公司使用先进的机器制造假发和接发，因此他们的[利润]利润约为每公斤300美元，而我们只能获得每公斤200美元的利润，因为由于缺乏技术和技能，我们的最终产品不符合他们的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但印度人发和发制品制造商和出口商协会主席本杰明·切里安 (Benjamin Cherian) 认为，使用最先进的技术并聘请来自欧洲和韩国的假发和接发专家可以推动该行业的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然印度政府去年强制要求所有生人发出口商必须Cherian 说，为了打击走私，在交易前获得许可证，但一些走私记录不佳的商人仍然设法获得了他们所需的文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，他的协会成员呼吁政府指示所有村委会从住户收集毛球，只出售给印度出口商，所得资金用于当地发展和卫生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;今天的头发，明天就会消失：香港的头发假发行业&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说，在此之前，头发走私可能会继续下去，而边境部队则在努力解决自身的局限性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;边境安全部队官员在接受《本周》采访时表示亚洲表示，他们对人口贩运采取零容忍政策，但需要“万无一失”地升级边境围栏，包括闭路电视摄像机，“以确保没有人逃脱”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，回到哈比Chak，Bibi 花几个小时耐心地整理成堆的废发，只赚微薄的钱，却不知道这些头发最终会落到谁的头上，也不知道它们会如何到达那里。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 11:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong must improve competitiveness amid declining global ranking, city leader John Lee says, defending import of low-skilled workers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3226268/hong-kong-must-improve-competitiveness-amid-declining-global-ranking-city-leader-john-lee-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 11:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/6ee6e4aa-c9d4-47fd-a322-82eaf72f3176_7311a06b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港领导人表示，在全球排名下降的情况下，香港必须提高竞争力，同时捍卫有争议的劳工政策，即输入更多低技术工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超周日表示，政府推出的政策“走在正确的轨道上”，有助于香港赢得胜利&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在瑞士国际管理发展研究所上个月发布的《世界竞争力年鉴》年度报告中，香港的排名从第五位下滑两位至第七位。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;香港领导人誓言以实际行动和成果赢得公众信任&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港曾被视为全球最具竞争力的经济体，2018年位居榜首。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说香港必须解决住房、办公室租金和汽油等领域长期存在的高物价问题，同时还要解决劳动力短缺的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有必要填补香港的缺口，因为这会影响到香港的劳动力短缺问题。”当地的竞争力，”他在广播节目中说道。 “我们不仅要有足够的竞争力，还要战胜别人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他解释说，香港的就业人口赤字超过20万，其中一半以上是劳动人口。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局上个月宣布将允许输入劳动力填补 26 个非技术或低技术岗位，包括服务员、文员、仓库管理员和送货员。在与政府的一次会议上，劳工代表举行罢工，抗议该政策推出前缺乏协商。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港李家耀一周年：看看他更具争议性的举动&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;李说，永远会优先考虑本地就业，当局会严格控制批准海外工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，输入劳工的工资不能低于个人收入中位数政府将加强对当地工人的职业培训。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 11:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UN chief calls on world to make troubled Haiti ‘top priority’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3226269/un-chief-calls-world-make-troubled-haiti-top-priority?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 11:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/df25b722-13b7-43f9-8c26-b071addcf035_b39a811c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在访问海地关注暴力和混乱问题时，联合国秘书长周六呼吁国际社会做出强有力的努力，帮助该国陷入困境的警察打击猖獗的犯罪团伙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个月来，安东尼奥·古特雷斯对西半球最贫穷国家的局势敲响了警钟，该国饱受蹂躏。不断升级的暴力、日益恶化的公共卫生状况和政治不稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他前往太子港——这是他作为联合国首脑首次访问海地——以实地阐述自己的观点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须将海地纳入国际政治版图，让海地人民的悲剧成为国际社会的首要任务，”古特雷斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我遇到了海地人，我古特雷斯在会见总理后表示，“现在不是忘记海地的时候”。阿里尔·亨利部长以及其他政治和民间社会领导人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯敦促将于本月晚些时候讨论海地局势的联合国安理会“授权立即部署一支强大的国际安全部队” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10 月，他转达了亨利要求派遣一支非联合国部队来支持不堪重负的国家警察部队的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这一呼吁并未得到重视。一些国家表示愿意参与，但没有一个国家自愿在一个过去多次外国干预陷入困境的国家领导一项行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我呼吁那些有能力提供援助的国家古特雷斯说：“我们需要强大的安全部队，停止犹豫，并准备好遵守安理会的决定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每一天都很重要。如果我们现在不采取行动，不稳定和暴力将对几代海地人产生持久影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，联合国官员对团伙枪击、绑架和强奸对海地人的影响做出了越来越严峻的评估。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“太子港被武装团伙包围，封锁了通往北部和南部省份的主要道路，控制了水、食品和医疗保健的获取，”古特雷斯周六表示。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他“以最强烈的措辞谴责武装团伙广泛使用的性暴力作为灌输恐惧的武器”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;海地暴民烧死可疑团伙成员的可怕场景&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;本周早些时候，联合国儿童基金会执行主任凯瑟琳·拉塞尔在访问太子港后表示，世界“辜负了海地人民”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她讲述了一个可怕的故事：一名 11 岁女孩被五名男子绑架，并被其中三名男子强奸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们交谈时，她已经怀孕八个月，几天后就生下了孩子，”拉塞尔说，回顾武装团伙控制了 60% 以上的首都和大片农村地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几乎一半的人口，即 520 万人，需要人道主义援助，其中包括近 300 万儿童。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2016 年以来没有举行过任何选举，亨利在 2021 年 7 月总统若弗内尔·莫伊兹遇刺前几天被任命为总理，他的合法性面临质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯说，他与亨利和其他人就“需要达成政治协议来结束危机”进行了“坦诚的交流”，但没有提供具体细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他呼吁公民领袖“克服个人利益，海地问题结束后，古特雷斯将前往特立尼达和多巴哥参加加勒比共同体（Caricom）峰会，会上将围绕海地问题进行讨论。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯也将出席峰会。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 11:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[French riots an unwelcome, perilous crisis for Emmanuel Macron]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226266/french-riots-unwelcome-perilous-crisis-emmanuel-macron?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 10:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/eeb832ad-ea54-427a-af77-fbb9848bfd12_140fdb6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国因警察杀害一名青少年而引发的骚乱代表了一种非常不受欢迎和对于总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙来说，这是一场危险的危机，正当他寻求推进他的第二个任期时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在马克龙最终平息了长达半年的针对他备受争议的养老金改革的抗议活动后，暴力事件爆发。今年大部分时间的国内议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，全国各地商店被洗劫、公共汽车被烧毁的景象也有可能损害马克龙的国际地位，而此时他希望在结束俄罗斯对乌克兰的入侵中发挥重要作用。并被视为欧洲第一大权力掮客。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法国骚乱仍在继续，数百名哀悼者聚集在一起为被警察杀害的青少年举行葬礼&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于马克龙来说，骚乱的发展极为尴尬迫使他取消了原定于本周末开始的对德国的国事访问，这也是法国国家元首 23 年来首次进行此类访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推迟对法国来说是双重尴尬。由于经常发生暴力养老金抗议活动，马克龙领导的爱丽舍宫今年早些时候推迟了英国国王查理三世计划进行的国事访问，这将是他作为君主的首次出访。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还削减了本周他缩短了出席布鲁塞尔欧盟峰会的时间，直接赶回巴黎主持危机会议，但没有举行新闻发布会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在以打击反政府黄背心抗议活动为主的第一任期结束后然后是 Covid-19 大流行，这位中间派的第二个任期再次面临着解决问题而不是实施政策的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骚乱“对总统来说是非常坏的消息”，他一直希望一切顺利巴黎政治大学政治研究中心研究员布鲁诺·考特雷斯表示，进入夏季后，内阁将进行改组，以重振政府活力并摆脱养老金危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们很惊讶地看到我们的国家如何面对一个接一个的紧张局势、暴力和危机，”他补充道，并警告说：“任何领导人都不能冒几个月内再次发生这样的大火的风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周爆发骚乱，当时马克龙正在结束对南部城市马赛为期三天的重要访问，他试图在那里推动解决法国最贫困地区城市问题的议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还受到外国媒体的嘲笑，指责他周三在巴黎参加了埃尔顿·约翰的告别演唱会，而几天前一些最严重的骚乱爆发了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着新冠病毒的爆发，黄背心和一位与马克龙关系密切、不愿透露姓名的消息人士表示：“在乌克兰战争中，没有什么能幸免。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙的执政党在 2022 年立法选举中失去了议会的绝对多数席位，他需要在国内小心行事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他敏锐地意识到极右翼领袖马琳·勒庞(Marine Le Pen)的目标是在2027年的选举中入主爱丽舍宫 — — 即使他无法在这些民意调查中站稳脚跟，这也会破坏他的政治遗产 — —并在安全问题上推动政府向右转。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全世界的目光——惊讶地看到在巴黎和里昂等旅游城市外拍摄的近乎世界末日的图像——也在巴黎准备好时投向法国在短短一年多的时间里举办奥运会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在处理骚乱时，马克龙一直急于平衡对警察杀戮的愤怒（他称之为“不可原谅”）和严厉呼吁维持秩序，包括恳求家长们让他们的孩子待在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们将根据他缓解紧张局势的能力来评判他。对他来说，危险在于显得软弱和优柔寡断。”专门研究政治史的历史学家让·加里格斯 (Jean Garrigues) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法国骚乱：青少年被杀如何将愤怒集中在警察策略上&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是迄今为止，马克龙尚未按照右翼的敦促，宣布受影响地区进入紧急状态，这将赋予警察更大的权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《世界报》称，他已试图“阻止恶性循环”通过大幅加强[警察使用的]手段和政治沟通来遏制城市暴力，同时不宣布进入紧急状态”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对2005年爆发的城市骚乱采取强硬立场两名被警察追捕的年轻人的死亡被证明对时任内政部长尼古拉·萨科齐（Nicolas Sarkozy）大有裨益，后者后来登上了总统宝座。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“坚定的政策也可以为埃马纽埃尔·马克龙（Emmanuel Macron）带来回报， ”嘉里格斯说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong retail property segment cashes in as mainland Chinese tourists return to spend on luxury, dining out]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226097/hong-kong-retail-property-segment-cashes-mainland-chinese-tourists-return-spend-luxury-dining-out?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/e4d66e56-d745-4b25-9498-273fc4a766b4_c9dc0424.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港零售地产板块从中国大陆游客回归中获益最多分析师表示，品牌和食品和饮料运营商抢购了商业街和豪华购物中心的商店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的零售额增长了五分之一以上，达到 137 港元。根据官方数据，今年前四个月的入境旅游收入增长了 50 亿（175.6 亿美元），而在此期间，入境旅游同比增长了 451 倍以上，达到 730 万人次。超过四分之三的游客来自中国大陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;游客回归和零售销售的改善已经使第一季度黄金商业街地段和主要购物中心的租金上涨了 3.9%，根据咨询公司第一太平戴维斯 (Savills) 的数据，分别增长了 5%，比 2019 年至 2022 年记录的 2.1% 至 33.2% 的年度跌幅有了巨大改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在所有不同的房地产领域，复苏都在高力香港研究主管凯西·李 (Kathy Lee) 表示：“零售业最快。” “它的表现优于所有其他房地产领域。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自今年早些时候重新开放与中国大陆的边境以来，“游客返回城市正在推动零售市场的增长”，李说。 。 “全年，我们预计高街商铺租金将上涨 8%。上半年增长了3％，因此今年下半年的复苏将有所加快。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;零售部分租金的增长非常显着，因为它与写字楼形成鲜明对比高纬环球 (Cushman and Wakefield) 的数据显示，该细分市场的租金在 2023 年第一季度较去年第四季度下降了 1.1%。此外，今年早些时候住宅市场最初的热情也已经消退，根据政府指数，二手房价格在 5 月份下跌了 0.7%，而在一手市场，开发商在高位徘徊的情况下一直在将价格降至 2018 年的水平。利率和不断增加的库存。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在香港上市的德视佳将在罗素街开设首家诊所&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;内地游客是香港零售业的命脉。据咨询公司奥纬咨询 (Oliver Wyman) 的数据，在 2019 年抗议活动和冠状病毒大流行之前，他们贡献了该市奢侈品零售额的约 70%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们回归后完成了 108 笔租赁交易，据高力国际统计，截至 6 月，铜锣湾、中环、旺角和尖沙咀等核心购物区的交易数量很可能超过 2022 年全年的 147 笔交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;公司的扩张计划也提振了零售房地产领域的乐观前景。例如，在香港上市的中国运动服饰品牌特步国际宣布，计划最晚于明年初在香港为其 2019 年以 2.6 亿美元收购的美国品牌盖世威 (K-Swiss) 开设旗舰店。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;其他企业也迅速采取行动，抢占香港传统购物区的黄金地段。中国证券公司富途控股以每月约 70 万港元的价格在尖沙咀弥敦道 96 号租用了 4,437 平方英尺的零售单位，包括地面和一楼，成为富途在尖沙咀的第一家分行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;法国奢侈品牌Chanel已在铜锣湾国会大厦中心租用18,000平方英尺的空间，月租在250万至400万港元之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在中环，澳大利亚快时尚品牌Cotton On 已从前德己立街迁往皇后大道中。 Swatch 还在中环租用了 8,735 平方英尺的空间，月租为 100 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瑞士画廊 Hauser &amp; Wirth 在中环租用了 10,000 平方英尺的“无障碍”空间&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在尖沙咀，新港中心一间占地75,000平方尺的零售单位，包括地面、一楼及二楼，已以每月约500万港元租给新港中心一间餐饮及娱乐集团。预计现场将开设一家动漫主题餐厅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡休闲时尚品牌Love, Bonito继中环和旺角开设两家店后，即将在新城开设最新店本月沙田的广场。据高力集团称，该公司还在铜锣湾皇室堡购物中心买下了约8,000平方英尺的面积，月租约为32万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在附近的Fashion Walk，受欢迎的美国三明治连锁店Eggslut有吸引了饥饿的购物者排队，而经营咖啡烘焙店 Cupping Room 等餐厅的 Caffeination Group 在利园 3 号开设了一家北欧风格的 Aroma Wine Bistro。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在在 Covid-19 大流行期间，我们能够与房东达成有利的租赁协议。”Caffeination Group 首席执行官 Teddy Pun 说道。 “利园地区是一个优质且价格实惠的葡萄酒餐厅服务不足的市场，特别是考虑到它靠近甲级写字楼和高端购物中心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于该公司“谨慎乐观”， Pun表示正在评估几种扩张前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一季度，Midland IC&amp;I在热门购物区录得10笔主要商铺租赁交易。其中包括日本和本地药店、手表品牌、化妆品店和火锅店等零售商的交易，面积介乎2,600平方英尺至12,000平方英尺，月租介乎55万至150万港元。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;由于疫情影响房地产收入，香港九龙仓预计 2022 年利润大幅下降&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;4 月至 5 月期间，主要零售租赁交易数量增加了一倍多，达到 22 笔——主要由中国人完成米德兰表示，与今年前三个月相比，餐馆的情况有所改善。租出的空间介乎300平方尺至17,000平方尺，月租介乎41,300港元至748,000港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港正走上复苏之路，[甚至在]游客到来之前[返回] ] 到 2019 年大流行前的水平，”世邦魏理仕香港零售咨询和交易服务高级总监 Lawrence Wan 表示。 “我们相信，随着内地游客数量预计将增长，零售市场将继续改善。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年零售物业租金可能会上涨 5% 至 10%，万说仲量联行驻香港零售业务主管 Oliver Tong 表示，尽管已经退出香港的品牌不太可能很快回归，但今年新品牌可能会进入香港.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing stokes opposition to US bases in Japan’s Okinawa as it seeks to ‘win hearts and minds’ amid Taiwan tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3226123/china-stokes-opposition-us-bases-japans-okinawa-it-seeks-win-hearts-and-minds-amid-taiwan-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/e73998cb-8621-4fdf-87ec-d2bfab172ad5_c877a1c9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最近关于该国与日本南部一系列岛屿的密切关系的言论尚未确定分析人士称，这是北京“扰乱民意”的又一次尝试，同时也激起了人们对美国在该地区建立军事基地的反对，以便在台海爆发冲突时加大对日本的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 6月初，中国国家主席习近平在视察国家档案馆时表示，他在担任国家主席期间了解了包括日本冲绳县在内的琉球群岛与中国南方省份福建省之间的“深厚”关系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;琉球在 1879 年被日本吞并之前是一个拥有独特文化和语言的独立王国，在明朝时期以向中国进贡的君主制进行统治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;习近平在琉球问题上的讲话是他上任以来首次就这一问题发表讲话，被广泛解读为试图向东京施压，要求其不要插手与台湾有关的问题，因为北京认为台湾问题是内部事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ryo东京大学国际关系助理教授山口日向表示，习近平的言论表明中国再次试图在冲绳“扰乱舆论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[这]部分显示了中国的心理和认知他说，这不仅会激化日本南部县与东京之间的关系，还会扰乱涉及冲绳岛和驻该岛美军的防御计划。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;习近平发表此番言论之前，中国民族主义小报《环球时报》四月份发表社论，称冲绳县议员向日本政府提交的一项决议“在东京显然被忽视和忽视”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该决议称日本避免在冲绳或其他琉球群岛部署导弹或其他军事手段，以增强其军事实力并试图实现威慑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国将在日本各地部署配备导弹的海军陆战队&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;《环球时报》社论指责日本和美国在冲绳的军事部署威胁和平与稳定，并接着问道：“这是企图永久限制冲绳吗？ 】 战争阴影的噩梦？东京真的关心冲绳人民的焦虑和愤怒吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，冲绳居民一直对美国在冲绳岛存在军事基地表示不满，而冲绳岛居民仅占冲绳人口的 0.6%。日本列岛的领土，但拥有 70% 的美军基地用地以及 5 万名驻军的一半以上。和平活动人士长期以来一直呼吁从冲绳撤走所有美国军事基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了被视为不成比例的负担之外，美国基地的事故和污染也是冲绳 150 万居民持续不满的根源日本国际事务研究所高级研究员乔纳森·伯克希尔·米勒 (Jonathan Berkshire Miller) 表示，中国多年来一直在“玩影响力游戏”，但显然正在以“更具冒险精神的方式”加大在冲绳的宣传力度。米勒表示，“[这是通过]质疑其他国家对与中国有‘历史联系’的土地的主张来实现的。”他补充说，如果台湾紧张局势升级，北京将“向东京施压，使其采取更加和解的语气”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹麦奥胡斯大学全球研究副教授雷蒙德·山本 (Raymond Yamamoto) 表示，习近平的言论应该结合 2013 年共产党喉舌《人民日报》上的一篇文章来理解。 Daily, which cited scholars from the Chinese Academy of Sciences challenging Japan&#39;s sovereignty over the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days after the article&#39;s publication, People&#39;s Liberation Army two-star general Luo Yuan chimed in with the following: “I am not saying all former tributary states belong to China, but we can say with certainty that the Ryukyus do not belong to Japan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The message was “not well received in Tokyo”, Yamamoto said, noting that the article&#39;s “aggressive tone” led to strong reactions in Japan and subsequent attempts by Chinese officials to “distance themselves from the content”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, Beijing had instead tried to “win the hearts and minds” of the Okinawans by constructing a narrative in which China was portrayed as “a country with close ties to the islands”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[China appears to] care about the suffering of the Okinawans that has been ignored by Tokyo,” Yamamoto said, adding that “publicly showing empathy” with the anti-US bases movement “is a smart move”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It fuels the domestic debate in Japan over the heavy US military presence, a key element in preventing a potentially forceful &#39;unification&#39; of Taiwan with the mainland,” Yamamoto said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If successful, the charm offensive attempted by Xi could force Tokyo to make greater concessions towards the concerns of Okinawans, affecting the military capability of the US.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, Okinawa governor Denny Tamaki travelled to Washington to lobby for a reduced US troop presence in the prefecture, while on May 13 2,000 people took part in a march calling for troops to be withdrawn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With tensions in the Taiwan Strait heightening in recent months, military watchers say a Chinese attack on the self-ruled island would likely be countered by a US-led coalition with crucial support from Japan and the American troops based in Okinawa, just an hour&#39;s flight east of Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AA Bastian, a historian based in the US with an interest in foreign policy, pointed out that any new bases and the potential for war would be “re-traumatising” for Okinawans, adding that listening to what they wanted was most important right now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Though outsiders may believe there won&#39;t be war, Okinawans have to live their lives relying on that to be true, which is a larger stake in the game,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tamaki is expected to visit China this month to strengthen trade and people-to-people ties, especially with Fujian province, and promote the anti-US bases movement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tamaki took Xi&#39;s comments as a “willingness to develop future exchanges”, said Kazuyuki Nakazato, director of Okinawa&#39;s representative office in Washington, adding that the prefectural government would continue to build friendly relations with China and others in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Robert Kajiwara, president of The Peace For Okinawa Coalition, said Western and Japanese media had ignored the history of Luchu – the Okinawan term for the Japanese “Ryukyu” – as a peaceful, prosperous and independent country with close ties to China, Korea and Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan to expand Okinawa ground force amid China threat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The coalition is a non-profit led by millennial Luchuans aimed at promoting Luchu&#39;s history, culture, language and independence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi is simply acknowledging the rich history and culture of Luchu, which both the US and Japan have long trampled on,” Kajiwara said. “I see nothing wrong with that at all.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Travis Seifman, a Ryukyu scholar at Ritsumeikan University in Kyoto, said “Luchu” more closely approximated the pronunciation in the indigenous Okinawan language, whereas “Ryukyu” reflected the standard Japanese pronunciation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To my mind, it falls in line with indigenous and identity movements elsewhere in the world, pushing for decolonisation of language and the re-adoption of native peoples&#39; own names for themselves or for their homelands,” Seifman said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Very human and cute’: bathhouse in China offers ‘rent-a-dad’ service to keep boys out of facilities reserved for women]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3225921/very-human-and-cute-bathhouse-china-offers-rent-dad-service-keep-boys-out-facilities-reserved-women?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/3f5275ed-abaa-4eb7-9564-9022b56aa9ae_3f79bd02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A bathhouse in China has rolled out a new “rent-a-dad” service – and if the response on social media is anything to go by, it looks set to become a hit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The service offers assistance to female guests with young sons in an effort to keep boys out of the women-only facilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Red Star News published a report on a promotional poster from the bathhouse in Shenyang, Liaoning province, in northeastern China, that advertised the new service, which had been shared online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is really considerate for both mums with sons and single women, so I took a photo of it,” the person who shared it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the report, the bathhouse explained how the service works: “If a woman brings her son here, we can help change his clothes, give him a bath, and then guide him to a designated area to find the mother. This service is free of charge.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was unclear from the report if the male attendants were screened or received special training, and age limits for the boys were not mentioned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese bathhouses usually have separate areas for male and female guests, as well as a unisex lounge area for guests to enjoy food, drinks, massages, entertainment and other amenities after bathing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new service allows for young boys to be bathed separately, while still ensuring that mothers and sons can share quality time together in the lounge afterwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most people who commented on mainland social media seemed enthusiastic about the idea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is very human and cute,” said one person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This should be promoted nationwide. No need to see any young boys in the women&#39;s bathing area anymore, or even in the restroom, I don&#39;t want to see boys,” wrote another online observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Shenyang truly deserves the title &#39;bathing capital&#39;. They&#39;ve really thought it through. This way, mothers can enjoy their meals and play with their children at the bathing centre. How wonderful!” another person commented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, some raised concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One mother wrote: “It truly provides a more human and convenient option. But, as a mother myself, I would not choose to leave such a young child in the care of others. If any issues arise, the bathhouse might be held responsible.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why is Hong Kong missing out on Taylor Swift and other big stars? Industry blames lack of large concert venues and slow reopening after Covid-19]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3226237/why-hong-kong-missing-out-taylor-swift-and-other-big-stars-industry-blames-lack-large-concert-venues?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/02/b7f7c53e-53df-4ee2-ab61-23350f02c38d_0f015d26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong remains an attractive destination for international artists to hold concerts, but the lack of a large venue may have deterred some big names from coming, industry players have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mega acts such as Taylor Swift, Coldplay and The 1975 skipped the city for world tours which will include places such as Japan, Singapore, Taiwan, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines and Thailand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industry players said the reasons the city missed out also included how late it reopened to the world after the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Veteran producer Patrick Siu Chiu-shun said the stars might have been unable to take Hong Kong into account when planning world tours as the city&#39;s stringent pandemic restrictions remained until the start of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Compared with other Asian regions, Hong Kong was more or less the last to open up to the world,” he said. “It might have been too late to book venues after Hong Kong reopened.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong dropped all restrictions on arrivals last December and fully reopened its border with mainland China in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concert and music festival organiser Joshua Chan Yee-jing said international headliners used to performing before tens of thousands of fans could not do so in Hong Kong, which did not have a space large enough.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It may be unjustifiable for these artists to organise a concert in Hong Kong with only around 10,000 and set ticket prices similar to those for a 50,000-capacity concert,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong fans snap up 14,000 free tickets in minutes for Harbour Chill Carnival&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The industry hoped the new stadium coming up in Kai Tak, with a capacity of 50,000, would attract mega acts. It is expected to be completed this year or next.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;American singer Taylor Swift announced multiple dates for her world tour next year, including Japan and Singapore in February and March. Her decision to stop at only two Asian countries left fans disappointed across the continent, including in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;British band Coldplay will perform in Japan, Taiwan, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines and Thailand from November to February, while British band The 1975&#39;s world tour will take them to Singapore, Malaysia, Indonesia and Taiwan in July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kpop girl group Twice will appear in Singapore, Thailand and the Philippines in September and October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lisa Hui Ping-sum, chair of the Performing Industry Association, said she expected more headline acts to perform in Hong Kong in the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that in the past, the Hong Kong Coliseum in Hung Hom, which could hold an audience of 12,500, held a leading position across Asia as there were no venues as big in other cities. But as it had to be booked a year in advance, it was used mostly by local artists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, places such as Shenzhen, Macau, and Singapore had caught up with even bigger venues and Hong Kong now lacked concert spaces for larger productions, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s main indoor concert venues now include the AsiaWorld-Expo in Chek Lap Kok, which can take up to 14,000, Star Hall in Kowloon Bay which can hold 3,600, and the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre in Wan Chai, which seats 8,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central Harbourfront Event Space provides almost 36,000 square metres (387,500 sq ft) of outdoor space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hui and Siu said Hong Kong remained competitive as artists such as Blackpink, Mayday and Jay Chou had performed in the city since it reopened this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong star Eason Chan cuts ties with mainland concert organiser&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Siu, the chairman of Wellfit Productions Limited, said artists considered factors such as their schedule, the availability of venues and the local market when deciding where to perform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Hong Kong had a geographical edge too, as some artists viewed it as “a stepping stone” into the mainland market, while it was convenient for fans from places such as Taiwan and Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For now, however, the city did not have a lot of venue choices for large concerts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If AsiaWorld-Expo has no available dates, bigger names will not be able to perform in Hong Kong,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Stadium could hold 40,000 spectators, but it was unsuitable for concerts because of its proximity to residential areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Siu said concert organisers liked venues near casinos, which usually took up a certain number of tickets for their clients and also provided attendees amenities such as shopping centres and restaurants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pointing out that Hong Kong&#39;s venues currently lacked such amenities, he hoped that a 350,000 square metre retail complex opening next to the AsiaWorld-Expo next year would help to make a difference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gary Ng Cheuk-yan, a senior economist at Natixis Corporate and Investment Bank, said that unlike Hong Kong, Singapore had put a lot of effort into developing event-based tourism from 10 years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong has no specific strategies in tourism as the government simply aims to attract as many tourists as possible,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong has to further develop event or concert-based tourism as it can give a reason for tourists to come to the city, giving a boost to the aviation and hotel industry, restaurants and other spending.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Ng Kang-chung and Wynna Wong&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China tackling ‘bad faith’ trademark hoarding, squatting rules to protect IP, be more attractive to investment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3226147/china-tackling-bad-faith-trademark-hoarding-squatting-rules-protect-ip-be-more-attractive-investment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/61162510-eda0-472e-b622-8d825df326bd_9efeb8f1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China is out to crack down on “bad faith” practices and stimulate investment with proposed changes to its Trademark Law in a latest bid to improve intellectual property protection and address the concerns of businesses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, the United States said China continues to be the top source of counterfeit products in the world, with Chinese intellectual property theft costing US$225 billion to US$600 billion per year to the US economy alone, according to a congressional estimate in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese officials have proposed to update the law this year to control trademark squatting and hoarding and other hits against big companies, with China more eager than ever to attract investment amid a cooler-than-expected economic recovery after the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing also hopes, analysts said, to protect domestic companies to boost the Chinese economy that has been affected by the China-US trade war and global supply chain decoupling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are on our way from being a large intellectual property country to a strong intellectual property country, but we&#39;re in between big and strong now,” said He Jing, founder of the Gen Law Firm in Beijing, a former US patent lawyer who specialises in intellectual property issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China will link intellectual property to national security.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eyeing international competition, China considers protection of intellectual property – – that covers trademarks, patents and copyrights – “critical for innovation”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Squatting involves registering a well-known trademark before the original brand owner, while hoarding entails filing large numbers of registrations to stop others from using the names and logos.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US says China has failed to crack down on copyright infringement, IP piracy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Internet searches of new but popular foreign brands allows trademark “pirates” to file in China for rights to use their names domestically, said Joe Simone, a partner with Simone Intellectual Property Services in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The original owner must then pay from US$100,000 to US$1 million to obtain the trademark before they can conduct business in China, Simone added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple lost a trademark case in 2016 over use of the name “IPHONE” on handbags sold in China after the vendor had secured the trademark in 2010, three years before Apple registered its smartphone brand in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The practice of squatting is “victimising some real brand owners”, Simone said, given China&#39;s first-to-file system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Proposed changes to China&#39;s Trademark Law would ban repeat applications by a single owner and limit the number of trademarks per applicant. They would also ban the imitation or translation of known existing trademarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Trademark Law has already been revised four times since entering into force in 1983, and it is under its fifth revision this year, in part because of pressure from foreign trade groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The general feeling is that it&#39;s a step in the right direction, as it further clarifies ambiguous concepts about the law and therefore makes it easier to interpret in a case or trial situation,” said Guilherme Campos, a Shenzhen-based international business advisory manager with professional services firm Dezan Shira &amp; Associates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China had more than 4.2 million patents as of 2022, according to data from the National Intellectual Property Administration, with domestic media outlets claiming it is the first country to pass 3 million registrations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two decades ago, foreign governments, multinationals and industry groups regularly asked Chinese officials for tougher punishments for violations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pirated software and DVDs were often openly sold in public, and foreign firms complained of barriers to filing intellectual property lawsuits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has addressed many concerns, analysts said, with guidelines issued in 2019 by the State Council calling for overcoming the high costs of suing, small damages awarded by courts and barriers in providing legal evidence of violations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foreign companies can freely sue in China, but multinationals may be comfortable with “more of a process” in court compared to their Chinese peers, He from Gen Law Firm in Beijing added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US Trade Representative (USTR) called out China in April over “bad faith trademarks”, as well as counterfeiting and online piracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China targets trademarks violations, but unlikely to satisfy US demands&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In its annual Special 301 Report on intellectual property protection and enforcement, the USTR cited amendments last year to three intellectual property rights laws but said “the pace of reforms” had slowed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The USTR embodies the worries of American companies that are afraid to come forward on their own, Simone said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials are focusing on Chinese companies largely for domestic reasons, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China “produces a lot of intellectual property”, said Dexter Roberts, director of China affairs with the University of Montana&#39;s Mansfield Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One recent change is that China patents everything, even stuff you wouldn&#39;t expect,” Roberts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Intellectual property lawsuits are becoming more common, and around 85 per cent are filed by Chinese companies, the HG.org Legal Resources website estimated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said thousands of intellectual property cases surfaced after 2010 and the number is “increasing exponentially”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a landmark case in 2017, a Chinese court ordered three shoemakers to pay more than 10 million yuan in damages to sports shoe designer New Balance for infringing on its signature slanted “N” logo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, though, remains under an international glare because many of its citizens do not see copying as a violation and believe that legally protected material should be shared, said Tan Loke-khoon, a partner with the international law firm Baker &amp; McKenzie in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Intellectual Property Administration did not respond to a request for comment on the latest changes to China&#39;s Trademark Law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in January, it said the proposed Trademark Law changes would “promote the high-quality development of the socialist market economy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The ultimate aim of the changes is to improve the consumer experience by strengthening the legitimacy of registered trademarks and improving the business environment by stamping out anticompetitive trademark practices,” professional services firm Dezan Shira &amp; Associates said in February.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Eye on AI as US-China rivalry enters new frontier with Unesco policymaking]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225957/eye-ai-us-china-rivalry-enters-new-frontier-unesco-policymaking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/01/2df04d2a-b169-46a3-864f-f2237dba4a58_7e59377a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Washington has received the green light to rejoin United Nations heritage, cultural and science body Unesco, a move expected to give rise to yet another front for US-China rivalry – this time over setting the global rules on artificial intelligence (AI).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers said the US will push back on increasing efforts by China to mould Unesco policymaking on emerging technologies, which is deemed important in shaping global regulations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A US proposal to rejoin the body was adopted on Friday, with “a very large majority” of the 193 member states voting in favour, according to a Unesco press release.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With this return, Unesco will be in an even stronger position to carry out its mandate,” director general Audrey Azoulay was quoted as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China was among the 10 members that voted against the motion, alongside Russia, North Korea, Belarus, Iran, Eritrea, Indonesia, Nicaragua, Syria and the Palestinian representatives, while 132 voted in favour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This comes after the Biden administration submitted a formal application to rejoin Unesco on June 8, some five years after then-president Donald Trump ordered an exit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US will fund the equivalent of 22 per cent of the Paris-based body&#39;s regular budget, and also progressively repay estimated arrears of US$619 million, Friday&#39;s press release said. Unesco&#39;s annual operating budget is US$534 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Peace, not division&#39;: China warns against conflict as US regains Unesco seat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;John Bass, the US under secretary of state for management, said in March that absence from Unesco was hurting the US in its rivalry with China, which has invested large sums in UN organisations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[If the US is] really serious about the digital-age competition with China … we can&#39;t afford to be absent any longer”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, which quickly became the top UN donor after the US pulled out, earlier criticised Washington&#39;s bid to return, saying international organisations should not be used as “arenas for geopolitical competition”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Bart Édes, a distinguished fellow at the Asia-Pacific Foundation of Canada, “Washington is reclaiming a seat at the Unesco table as its role in making recommendations on AI is of particular concern to the US.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unesco plays a critical role in leading global dialogues, publishing concept papers and providing technical advice to governments, and is expected to shape the international discourse on AI.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In early June, it published a policy paper setting norms on AI ethics to address global concerns about the lack of regulation standards, especially as OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT takes the world by storm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While UN policy papers are merely advisory, they often carry a lot of weight in shaping global norms and values, and inform policymaking processes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Édes said participating in Unesco and being involved in rule-setting and allocating resources offer China and the US opportunities to promote their values and interests in the international arena.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the US said it would leave in 2017, China quickly increased its contribution and became the largest donor the following year. Also in 2018, it successfully backed Chinese diplomat Xing Qu to serve as Unesco&#39;s deputy director general, the No 2 rank in the organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The changes came as China sought a bigger say on global AI rule-setting. In 2019, it co-hosted with Unesco the International Conference on AI and Education in Beijing, where important figures from more than 120 member states gathered to discuss AI strategies for digital transformation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both Unesco and the Chinese government hailed the Beijing Consensus policy paper as a key achievement of the conference, which was hosted by China&#39;s capital city for three years in a row.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beijing Consensus outlines AI-related recommendations to member states, promoting a “whole-government” to AI regulation and “giving special priority to Africa” in AI financing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Becoming a key political and economic player in Africa has been high on China&#39;s recent global agenda. China has also relied on Unesco&#39;s platform to publish and promote its science agenda, such as “Made in China 2025” – a strategic plan to promote technological self-reliance and push manufacturers to decouple from US tech suppliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Michael Frank, a senior fellow at the Wadhwani Centre for AI and Advanced Technologies under Washington-based think tank Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), said blocking China&#39;s efforts to set AI standards and constrain its AI ability is of strong interest to the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been active in international organisations that set standards for all kinds of emerging technology, from AI to 5G, and the UN is increasingly seen as a platform for Beijing to channel its global ambitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, China&#39;s aims of guiding coalitions like Unesco to serve its interests might face a hurdle if the US was able to steer other major economies away from the UN system, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;AI to be &#39;driving force&#39; of China&#39;s new wave, have impact on production and life&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US can set standards among fellow democracies in blocs such as the Group of 7, the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, the Quad, and the US-EU Trade and Technology Council – alternatives that are not available to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frank said the US recognises that even by being in the room, it will be more effective at blocking China from pushing its AI agenda through the organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Unesco had a comparatively limited role in AI rule-setting, he pointed out. “I doubt Unesco will play a major role in settling the most important international aspects of AI, like intellectual property, weapons development, and existential risk.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, the Chinese government lobbied for its candidate, Wang Binying, to head the UN&#39;s rule-setting World Intellectual Property Organization, which handles a more critical aspect of the issue. But he was eventually defeated by a US-backed candidate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid intensifying US rivalry and a sluggish post-Covid economic recovery, China has vowed to double down on unleashing the power of AI, hoping it will transform industries and boost growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is fundamentally miscalculating its ability to develop world-leading AI on its own,” Frank warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since ChatGPT went viral, many Chinese tech firms have also launched their own chatbots, but they must comply with national censorship rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The request from China&#39;s top internet regulator for AI companies to use algorithms that “uphold core values of socialism” imposed significant technical limitations that would make Chinese AI firms lag behind their foreign peers, Frank said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Efforts to develop a domestically self-sufficient AI ecosystem, and then export AI products and services around the world after determining China-friendly standards, will not work,” he forecast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“AI ecosystems are simply too complex.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Anti-Trump video shared by DeSantis campaign is homophobic, says conservative LGBTQ group]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226264/anti-trump-video-shared-desantis-campaign-homophobic-says-conservative-lgbtq-group?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.02 04:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/02/9494e024-b963-42cf-ac83-646891ba066e_31fe14a6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A prominent group that represents LGBTQ conservatives says a video shared by Ron DeSantis&#39; presidential campaign that slams rival Donald Trump for his past support of gay and transgender people “ventured into homophobic territory.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “DeSantis War Room” Twitter account shared the video on Friday – the last day of June&#39;s LGBTQ Pride Month – that features footage of the former US president at the Republican National Convention in 2016 saying he would “do everything in my power to protect our LGBTQ citizens.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump had been pledging protection from terrorist attacks weeks after the shootings at the Pulse Nightclub, a gay nightclub in Orlando, Florida that was the deadliest mass shooting in US history at that time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video also highlights “LGBTQ for Trump” T-shirts sold by the former president&#39;s campaign and his past comments saying he would be comfortable with Caitlyn Jenner – the former Olympic decathlete who came out as a transgender woman in 2015 – using any bathroom at Trump Tower and OK with transgender women competing one day in the Miss Universe pageant, which Trump owned at the time of those remarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video then suddenly veers in a different direction, accompanied by dark, thumping music and images of DeSantis, the Florida governor who is trailing Trump by wide margins in the polls for the 2024 Republican presidential nomination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It promotes headlines that DeSantis signed “the most extreme slate of anti-trans laws in modern history” and a “draconian anti-trans bathroom bill.” The images are spliced together with footage of muscular, shirtless men and several Hollywood actors, including Brad Pitt, seen wearing a leather mask from the film Troy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To wrap up &#39;Pride Month,&#39; let&#39;s hear from the politician who did more than any other Republican to celebrate it,” the DeSantis campaign tweeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump complains that Fox News is using &#39;horrible&#39; photos of him&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The video drew immediate criticism from prominent LGBTQ Republicans, including the Log Cabin Republicans, which bills itself as the nation&#39;s “largest Republican organisation dedicated to representing LGBT conservatives.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today&#39;s message from the DeSantis campaign War Room is divisive and desperate. Republicans and other common sense conservatives know Ron Desantis has alienated swing-state and younger voters,” the group said in a tweet, adding that DeSantis&#39; “extreme rhetoric goes has just ventured into homophobic territory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group said his “rhetoric will lose hard-fought gains in critical races across the nation. This old playbook has been tried in the past and has failed – repeatedly.” The post said DeSantis&#39; “naive policy positions are dangerous and politically stupid.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jenner accused DeSantis&#39; campaign of using “horribly divisive tactics!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“DeSantis has hit a new low,” Jenner wrote on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Donald Trump sues accuser for defamation over post-trial rape claim&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Representatives of the DeSantis campaign did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video comes as Republicans have been wading into increasingly hostile anti-LGBTQ territory, attacking Pride month celebrations, trying to ban displays of rainbow Pride flags and passing legislation to limit drag shows, along with broad attacks on transgender rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That rhetoric has seeped into the Republican presidential campaign, taking a prominent role that had been absent during recent past competitive primaries, including in 2016, when Trump, a New York reality television star, generally presented himself as a supporter of LGBTQ rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis leaned in on anti-LGBTQ legislation as he prepared to jump into the 2024 White House race. He signed legislation banning classroom instruction about sexual orientation and gender identity in all years, banned gender-affirming care for minors, targeted drag shows, restricted discussion of personal pronouns in schools and forced people to use bathrooms that align with the sex assigned at birth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis also went after US President Joe Biden for prominently displaying the Pride flag at the White House last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump himself pledged in a speech on Friday that if were elected, he would sign executive orders on his first day in office to cut federal money for any school pushing “transgender insanity” and to instruct federal agencies “to cease the promotion of sex or gender transition at any age.” Hospitals and health-care providers offering gender-affirming care for minors should be deemed in violation of federal health and safety standards and lose federal funding, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both Trump and DeSantis have also railed against transgender women taking part in women&#39;s sports and have referred to gender-affirming care for minors as “mutilation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Trump&#39;s rally in Pickens, South Carolina on Saturday, the crowd booed congresswoman Marjorie Taylor Greene for her reference to Pride month: “The rainbow belongs to God,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Rivalry between Trump and DeSantis deepens at campaign events&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While such rhetoric appeals to the party&#39;s conservative base, it risks alienating the more moderate and swing voters who generally decide the outcomes of general elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video, originally posted by the pro-DeSantis “@ProudElephantUS” account, was shared hours after the Supreme Court&#39;s conservative majority ruled that a Christian graphic artist who wants to design wedding websites can refuse to work with same-sex couples.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision marked a major defeat for gay rights, with one of the court&#39;s liberal justices writing in a dissent that the decision&#39;s effect would be to “mark gays and lesbians for second-class status.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 02 Jul 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>