<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump accused of asking staff member to delete footage in bid to obstruct classified documents investigation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229184/donald-trump-faces-new-charges-documents-case-mar-lago-worker-indicted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 06:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/e0af5223-9260-4234-936e-b3c7d0b58426_993b7850.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;唐纳德·特朗普要求一名工作人员删除他佛罗里达州庄园的摄像机镜头根据周四公布的最新起诉书，该起诉书增加了对前总统的新指控，并指定了另一名被告，以阻碍联邦调查他持有机密文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;起诉书包括新的妨碍司法罪名和故意犯罪罪名保留国防信息，加剧了特朗普的法律危险，尽管他正准备在华盛顿因他试图推翻 2020 年总统选举结果的行为而受到额外起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;额外指控凸显了今年的严重程度对特朗普进行的长期调查于上个月首次提出指控，对特朗普及其贴身男仆沃尔特·诺塔 (Walt Nauta) 提出了 38 项起诉书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普发言人驳回了这些新指控，称其“只不过是持续不断的”拜登政府“不顾一切地试图骚扰特朗普总统及其周围的人”并影响 2024 年总统竞选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些机密记录是特朗普在离开后带到海湖庄园的2021 年 1 月向白宫提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;替代起诉书指控特朗普另有一项罪名，即故意保留与前总统在 2021 年 7 月在白宫接受采访时讨论美国攻击另一个国家的军事计划有关的国防信息。新泽西州贝德明斯特，高尔夫俱乐部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次采访是为了他的前幕僚长马克·梅多斯 (Mark Meadows) 撰写的回忆录，他在随后的书中将这个国家命名为伊朗。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;佛罗里达州法官设定唐纳德·特朗普的秘密文件审判将于 2024 年 5 月 20 日开始&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据起诉书，特朗普将这份被标记为绝密且未获准向外国人展示的文件归还给2022 年 1 月 17 日向联邦政府提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这标志着检方对特朗普案件态度的显着转变，指控他保留一份文件，据称这位前总统在离任后知道该文件高度敏感 - 并且不仅仅是因为在被要求时未能将其归还给政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普和诺塔都表示无罪。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s concertgoers splash the cash, but is revenge spending sustainable to rock the economy?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3229131/chinas-concertgoers-splash-cash-revenge-spending-sustainable-rock-economy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/023f367e-5710-48fe-b31c-1ecfdd03c362_b1e0a441.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是关于 2023 年上半年动荡的经济陷阱和逆风的第五篇文章这让中国难以摆脱多年来由新冠病毒引发的锈迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自中国去年 12 月取消与冠状病毒相关的限制并再次允许娱乐场所开业以来，面对面的活动已经被禁止需求量很大，歌迷们疯狂地寻找多余的音乐会门票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就像一种重新发现欣赏的感觉，是一种报复性消费，”应届大学毕业生刘英说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这位 22 岁的年轻人今年已经参加了三场音乐会，门票花费超过 7,000 元人民币（980 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在大流行之前，我认为没有必要，但后来，我意识到参加音乐会和旅行等机会有时可能是一生一次的机会，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[疫情]让我意识到生活就是活在当下并拥抱当下近几个月来，音乐会在中国社交媒体上热度不断，今年上半年，中国举办了超过500场大型演出和音乐节。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国表演艺术协会的数据，他们的门票收入总计达 25 亿元人民币（3.5 亿美元），售出超过 550 万张门票。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;复苏每况愈下》：中国经济数据的 6 个要点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;仅第二季度的三个月就占了门票销量的近 90%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更广泛的范围今年前六个月，包括流行音乐会、舞蹈表演和歌剧在内的营利性演出数量猛增400%，达到19.33万场，门票收入猛增673%，达到168亿元人民币，上座人数增加了增长十倍以上，超过 6200 万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，尽管音乐会市场正在经历显着的繁荣，但它与更广泛的经济复苏相比却显得异常，而经济复苏已逐渐失去动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;鲜明的对比表明各行业的复苏之路并不平坦，并引发人们对是否可以仅依靠消费作为中国经济复苏的主要驱动力的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在为期一周的劳动节假期期间， 5月份，音乐会和音乐节带来了超过12亿元的消费支出（不包括门票销售），包括交通、酒店、餐饮服务等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着疫情影响的缓解，突然出现了“释放压抑了三年的情绪，以及暂时摆脱现状的强烈愿望。”现于香港工作的 28 岁石翔宇说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;石曾参加过今年将举办三场音乐会，下个月还将举办两场音乐会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这几乎就像是一项通过旅行和参加音乐会来验证自由权的实验，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“然而，频繁且高水平的支出可能不可持续。我认为平衡支出能力与需求非常重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国城市计划举办数月的摇滚活动，将经济提振至 11&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;类似的报复性支出也出现在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但与部分消费领域的强劲反弹相比，复苏乏力。耐用消费品（包括汽车和家庭用品）以及中国经济重新开放后的房地产销售低迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年前六个月房地产投资下降 7.9%，而疲软的需求进一步削减房价上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这反过来又压低了建筑、家具、家电等方面的大额预算支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“演唱会是高端消费，针对城市中产阶级恒生银行中国首席经济学家王丹表示，“就业市场异常高的压力也意味着人们愿意花更多钱来放松” 。这是典型的口红经济现象——经济严重下滑时，能够提供情感价值的东西的消费往往会上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但收入增长永久放缓，演唱会消费的炒作因此不再存在。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的复苏受到国内外不利因素的打击，包括房地产市场萎缩、出口需求下降以及私营部门信心疲软削弱消费者信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;第二季度，中国经济同比增长 6.3%，尽管分析师指出，去年的基数较低，当时经济因全国范围内的封锁而陷入停滞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，就业市场的不确定性上升，笼罩着悲观和不安的情绪，也促使居民削减开支。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月份16-24岁年龄段的失业率达到前所未有的21.3%，此前，自 2020 年以来呈上升趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计 7 月和 8 月将进一步上升，因为今年将有创纪录的 1158 万大学毕业生离开校园涌入就业市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;对普遍裁员、减薪和针对 30 岁以下工人的年龄歧视的担忧也被视为阻止了消费者超支。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国中年求职者面临“臭名昭著的 35 岁玻璃天花板”&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;独立智库安邦德研究员何军表示，一两项政策并不能刺激消费，消费者的收入和信心才是拉动消费的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果收入增加，人们自然会花更多的钱；人们如果对未来有信心，就会敢于消费，甚至会借钱来增加支出，因为他们相信自己有能力偿还债务。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“消费的恢复不能通过&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就业困难会显着抑制消费，更多人会选择平躺心态。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平躺运动代表&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“支持和刺激消费的政策将会出台，但对于这些政策找出根本原因至关重要。”何补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，即使政府选择非常规的直升机撒钱，也称为直升机空投，印制和分发大量货币&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们主要会满足基本需求，将资金用于偿还债务，从而减少了消费支出。”何说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一直在通过减税和优惠券来刺激消费，但效果并不明显。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管政府有这样的目标与省政府有联系的智库广东省改革研究会执行会长彭鹏表示，用消费拉动经济很难实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭补充说，消费已经成为经济增长的动力。是中国经济三大支柱中最弱的一个，其中还包括投资和出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当前，中国外贸低迷，房地产投资疲软，低成本消费主导消费支出。”彭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，经济没有复苏，消费就很难全面繁荣。”消费与经济的关系应该是相辅相成的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国暑期旅游热潮为黯淡的经济复苏增添了色彩&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;消费占中国国内生产总值的32.8% 2022 年的增长率将低于 2021 年的 54.5%，而且许多发达国家仍低于 80% 以上。恒生银行的王补充道：“转移支付将是有效的，但这不是中国政府习惯的货币工具。”“现在的经济政策仍然关注经济安全和供应的长期实力链。短期刺激消费或投资不会被优先考虑。”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐天辰表示，未来两到三年，家庭消费对经济的比重将高于投资。经济学人智库的经济学家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这一趋势将主要由投资下降驱动——尤其是在政府和房地产开发商去杠杆化的情况下——而不是中国消费者变得更加富有并变得更愿意消费。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“从技术上讲，政府应该增加支出，以弥补私人需求的缺口，例如通过发放现金转移支付。但现在它的行动能力受到财政压力以及议程中债务解决优先事项的限制，”徐说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这在一定程度上解释了为什么政府促进收入和消费的承诺没有得到兑现。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这种背景下，政策制定者很可能让事情自行发展——提供的支持有限——而消费者将依靠自己的手段。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s Taobao to live stream Tencent’s Honour of Kings in rare partnership of China’s top tech giants]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3229152/alibabas-taobao-live-stream-tencents-honour-kings-rare-partnership-chinas-top-tech-giants?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/fb52b375-f2af-406a-84f7-4e516db71df4_8a22ac0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团控股与腾讯控股罕见联手推广各自旗舰品牌中国两大科技公司之间的合作，在经济放缓的背景下，当地网上吸引眼球的竞赛愈演愈烈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴的电子商务平台淘宝和腾讯广受欢迎的手机游戏《王者荣耀》正在发出邀请-据淘宝网和天猫集团周四发布的新闻稿称，决赛将于 8 月 5 日在直播服务淘宝直播上直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;淘宝网，其母公司拥有《南华早报》 ，称其正在呼吁“各行各业的游戏玩家”开始在该平台上直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举标志着淘宝首次进军电子竞技直播领域，该领域一直由少数视频主导阿里巴巴的中国商务业务占集团总收入的很大一部分，但由于全国零售销售疲软，阿里巴巴的中国商务业务受到了影响。阿里巴巴的财务报表显示，在 3 月份的这个季度，该领域的销售额同比下降了 3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一季度，腾讯（按收入计算是全球最大的视频游戏业务运营商）的国内收入出现了下滑。这家总部位于深圳的公司报告称，游戏销售额增长了 6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国放松了多年来对视频游戏行业的打击，一直在推动电子竞技，以在即将到来的未来增强其软实力。亚运会，电子竞技将首次成为奖牌赛事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《王者荣耀》是亚运会上的七款电子竞技游戏之一，已在淘宝开设官方店铺超过 10 年。四年来，它从未赞助过阿里巴巴平台上的任何视频游戏直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电子竞技已成为“真正具有全球影响力的新兴运动”，并已进入关键的“塑造期”腾讯首席运营官任宇欣本月早些时候表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家科技巨头之间的新合作关系正值淘宝和天猫努力留住用户基础并寻求新的增长点之际。在 3 月份宣布正在进行的重组之后，该子公司将成为总部位于杭州的阿里巴巴仍全资拥有的六个业务部门中唯一的一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月份的一次非正式会议上，阿里巴巴创始人马云为公司的管理层提供了建议。 - 据中国媒体《LatePost》上个月报道，商务高管将重新关注淘宝及其消费者，以求在残酷的竞争中生存下来，并经受住中国经济放缓的考验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，马云表示阿里巴巴无法占据其在中国电子商务的主导地位&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与《王者荣耀》的合作，帮助淘宝加快了内容转型的步伐，直播内容不再局限于网购，还包括直播内容。该公司在声明中表示，电子竞技。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年以来，淘宝直播用户数量同比增长 70%，中小型直播主的增长速度加快，该公司补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Views of China ‘broadly negative’ in India and Brazil, survey finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3229183/views-china-broadly-negative-india-and-brazil-survey-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/57fe9cad-6d57-4a98-be6f-241959fa5be7_4c3b4b53.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度和巴西这两个最大的成员国对中国的负面看法飙升皮尤研究中心周四发布的一项研究显示，金砖国家集团的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查结果显示，巴西和印度对中国的“普遍负面”看法激增了 21 个百分点。南非的增幅预计为 5 个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于华盛顿的智库在 2 月至 4 月期间进行了这项调查，采访了 24 个国家的 30,000 多名受访者，其中包括印度的 2,611 名受访者。巴西有 1,044 人，南非有 1,502 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近一半的巴西受访者（48%）对中国持负面印象，高于皮尤上次对中等收入国家进行民意调查的 2019 年的 27%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同期，印度人对中国持负面看法的比例从2019年的46%飙升至67%。在南非，对中国的负面情绪从 35% 上升到 40%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据统计，过去十年，印度和南非认为中国无视其国家利益的人比例大幅增加皮尤研究中心的劳拉·西尔弗 (Laura Silver) 和该研究的首席研究员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西尔弗认为，对中国人权政策的担忧可能会加剧金砖国家的负面看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度经历了其观点发生了相当大的负面转变，在我们调查的中等收入国家中尤为突出。”西尔弗说道。 “巴西的观点也变得更加消极，但仍然存在一些有利和不利的分歧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;华裔美国人对台湾的看法比中国更有利：皮尤调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;相比之下，南非只出现了轻微的变化。虽然 40% 的受访者对中国表示负面看法，但 49% 的受访者表示，他们仍然对这个亚洲巨人抱有好感。南非受访者对调查中提出的其他问题也持更加积极的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西和印度人似乎对中国对全球和平与稳定的贡献更加持怀疑态度，分别为 62% 和 56%分别表达负面观点。相反，南非人则更为乐观，47% 的人对北京的角色采取了有利的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，67% 的印度人和 57% 的巴西人不信任中国领导人习近平推动世界经济发展的能力。正确的决定，47%的南非人对他充满信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“南非对中国的看法相对积极，并且在许多其他国家的情绪急剧转为负面的时期内变化很小。”西尔弗说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她认为，结果反映出南非人倾向于“更积极地”看待中国的投资、软实力及其全球作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西尔弗还表示，多种因素可能会刺激印度负面看法急剧上升，包括2020年中印边境的冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一方面，在巴西，数据似乎表明，随着国内政治的发展，对中国的看法下降台词：支持巴西现任左翼执政联盟的受访者中有 45% 对中国有好感，而不支持总统卢拉·达席尔瓦的受访者只有 36%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查结果印度金达尔全球大学的卡琳·科斯塔·巴斯克斯表示，这对印度来说并不令人意外，因为 2020 年与中国的边境冲突中的死亡事件“在政治上被用来加剧印度教民族主义并巩固[印度总理纳伦德拉]莫迪领导的党派团体的影响力”以及总部位于北京的智库中国与全球化中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴斯克斯说，在巴西，冠状病毒大流行以及前总统贾尔·博尔索纳罗将其与中国联系起来可能加剧了对该国的负面看法。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;中国想要新的金砖国家成员，但印度、巴西担心“失去影响力”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“贾尔·博尔索纳罗积极推动了‘中国病毒’、‘中国疫苗无效’等叙事的构建”，与特朗普政府的反华情绪一致，并被巴西媒体惯性转载。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴斯克斯表示，这一结果令人怀疑中国以经济为导向巩固与金砖国家合作的能力、安全和人文交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，中国政府一直致力于发展与民间社会的关系，寄希望于人与人之间的联系以增进理解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充道。 &lt;p>;“当人们拒绝此类倡议时，就像在印度发生的那样，对话就会变得更加困难，关系也更容易产生敌意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皮尤研究中心最近的数据说明了一个严峻的现实，尽管巴西智库观察中国的保罗·梅内凯利 (Paulo Menechelli) 表示，北京的文化举措旨在增强全球对中国的了解，但只有四分之一的受访者对中国的电影、电视剧和音乐持积极态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;外国电影制片人就制作电影提出了建议梅内切利表示，中国传达的信息更具吸引力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这与当前人们对亚洲文物（尤其是来自日本和韩国的文物）日益浓厚的兴趣相矛盾。这也与中国驻巴西大使馆在电影节、读书俱乐部、汉语课程推广和中国节日庆祝等领域深化投资形成鲜明对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，北京对文化输出的严格控制可能会影响巴西的文化输出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平不断强调要‘讲好中国故事’，但这些故事是什么？”梅内切利问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的审查制度，特别是围绕政治机构和政党领导层发现的甚至略有争议的话题，直接阻碍了这些产品的出口能力，他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅内切利说，许多人巴西人通过《纸牌屋》等电视剧熟悉美国的政治制度，而他们对中国制度的了解有限且缺乏透明度。这导致了人们的无知和随后的不安，不仅在巴西，而且在全球范围内导致了更多对中国的负面看法。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Western officials make a beeline for Indo-Pacific to counter China’s influence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229182/western-officials-make-beeline-indo-pacific-counter-chinas-influence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 05:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/584e086c-74cd-43a3-90d2-714ffde6ac8d_4cc7d3bd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;针对北京在印太影响力的重大外交反攻正在全面展开，没有比西方领导人同时访问该地区曾经被忽视的岛屿更好的迹象了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周跳岛游的最著名人物包括法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙和美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯。美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀也访问了巴布亚新几内亚，而英国武装部队部长詹姆斯·希佩则在斐济停留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在西方客人中最引人注目的是马克龙，他在访问镍矿时- 富饶的法国海外领土新喀里多尼亚警告说，如果这个战略位置优越的群岛获得独立，“明天就会有中国海军基地”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果独立意味着明天你会决定在这里建立一个中国海军基地，或者依赖另一支海上舰队，祝你好运 - 这不是独立，”他周三在新喀里多尼亚首都努美阿表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他呼吁支持独立的土著卡纳克人接受亲法国的立场2022 年第三次也是最后一次自决公投。卡纳克人抵制了这次投票，有关该领土在法国统治下的地位的谈判仍陷入僵局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要摆脱面对面的紧张局势，这是让新喀里多尼亚在共和国和太平洋地区走上未来道路的唯一途径。”马克龙敦促道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国在新喀里多尼亚设有海军基地，新喀里多尼亚被宣布为法国囚犯殖民地。 1853 年拿破仑三世。2018 年和 2020 年举行的前两次独立投票有利于法国统治。然而，随着卡纳克人口的增长，支持独立的选票随着时间的推移而增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙保护法国殖民帝国遗迹的努力在新喀里多尼亚得到了充分展示，但在访问瓦努阿图期间，他警告提防“新帝国主义”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;汤加的布林肯指责中国的“掠夺性”行为&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;瓦努阿图在 1980 年获得独立之前一直由英国和法国共同统治。此次访问，马克龙也成为首位踏足独立太平洋国家的在任法国总统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印太地区，特别是大洋洲，新帝国主义出现，权力逻辑正在威胁几个国家的主权——最小的国家，往往也是最脆弱的国家，”马克龙周四在维拉港表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然他没有具体说明，但中国仍然深入参与该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悉尼智库洛伊研究所的一份报告显示，北京在该地区的发展融资于 2016 年达到顶峰。但它仍然是太平洋岛国的主要基础设施贷款人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦努阿图在 2017 年至 2021 年间向中国发放了新贷款，据路透社报道，中国进出口银行也是该国最大的债权人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马克龙在维拉港宣传法国的印度太平洋战略时声称，该战略的目的是“通过伙伴关系捍卫该地区所有愿意与我们合作的国家的独立和主权”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，在澳大利亚放弃法国潜艇合同、转而加入奥库斯联盟及其将提供的英国和美国核动力潜艇之后，法国重新启动了印太战略，以夺回其在该地区的利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙的瓦努阿图之行与奥斯汀对法国领导人下一站巴布亚新几内亚的访问重叠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯汀是第一位访问这个拥有 1000 万人口的岛国的五角大楼负责人，他宣布美国将部署一艘海岸警卫队快艇前往巴布亚新几内亚 - 但赶紧补充说，华盛顿并不打算在那里建立永久军事基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴布亚新几内亚是第二次世界大战期间太平洋的一个重要战场，现已成为地缘政治的焦点中国和美国之间的竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在中国立场摇摆不定的情况下，西方列强质疑新西兰的“可靠性”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当奥斯汀忙于与巴布亚新几内亚建立更深层次的防务关系时，布林肯 –美国高级外交官 – 在惠灵顿与新西兰外交部长 Nanaia Mahuta 举行的联合新闻发布会上，不排除扩大 Aukus 的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在回答有关新西兰加入该联盟的问题时，布林肯表示“新西兰和其他合作伙伴在他们认为适当的情况下继续参与的大门是敞开的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的言论是在他访问汤加期间警告南太平洋岛屿几天后发表的布林肯声称，“随着中国在该地区的参与不断增加”，它参与了“一些掠夺性的经济活动，以及在某个地区进行的投资”。这实际上会破坏良好的治理并助长腐败”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯将前往澳大利亚，他和奥斯汀将在那里会见澳大利亚外交部长彭妮·黄(Penny Wong)和国防部长理查德·马尔斯(Richard Marles)。周五和周六举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次聚会是在希皮上周访问斐济之后举行的，他在那里参观了斐济海军基地并讨论了英国在太平洋安全中的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道称，英国确认与斐济军方加强合作，更多英国军舰来到这个太平洋岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管其他领导人的行程仅限于太平洋，但马克龙正在将触角延伸至印度洋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他将于周五前往位于印度洋贸易十字路口的斯里兰卡，与斯里兰卡总统拉尼尔·维克勒马辛哈 (Ranil Wickremesinghe) 举行会谈，这是在任法国总统的第一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社和法新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best &lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s first durian sales just days away after month-long delay due to weather]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229132/chinas-first-durian-sales-just-days-away-after-month-long-delay-due-weather?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/7122ef8e-66b1-48de-8f74-c1f021932a5b_56c41396.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国本土榴莲即将在几天内上市，但据官方媒体报道，在实现大规模商业种植之前，其有限的产量和高昂的价格预计不会挑战东南亚进口商的市场份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在南部热带岛屿海南岛，据新华社周三报道，国产榴莲已经成熟，并准备在市场上首次销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，首批榴莲收获范围涵盖该省 93.3 公顷（230.6 英亩）的开花地块，但报告称，种植者优旗农业集团总共种植了 800 公顷土地，这应该会支持未来几年产量的增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它们的价格为每公斤 120 元（16.80 美元），约合人民币 3 美元。总部位于上海的 MZ Marketing Communications 周二发布的《农产品报告》显示，其成本是绝大多数进口榴莲的成本的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国能否在首次大规模收获时降低本土榴莲价格？丰收？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“国产榴莲的价格短期内不会下降，中国仍将依赖东南亚市场来满足榴莲需求。”海南省农业科学院热带果树研究所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据海关总署的数据，中国作为全球最大的榴莲消费市场，2022 年进口了 82.5 万吨榴莲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;海南省农业科学院研究员冯告诉早报，由于海南天气变化，收获推迟了一个月左右，第一批预计6月份上市。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“本次生产的国产榴莲非常有限。 They are now available only in the orchards, but their production will go up annually in the future,” Feng said, adding that domestic durians focus more on flavour and quality but are unable to compete with Southeast Asian countries in terms of price.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the biggest difficulty for Hainan and the whole of East Asia to grow durian is the constant typhoons,” Feng said at a seed conference in Hainan in early April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fragile trunk of a durian tree makes it difficult to withstand high winds, and a sort of metal “shelf” installed to collect fallen durian can cost 1,000 yuan per tree, according to Feng.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s still a question as to whether this shelf can survive a typhoon,” Feng said, adding that the lack of durian-planting experience among most farmers is also an obstacle to China&#39;s large-scale commercial planting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s domestic durian cultivation is mostly carried out by private companies, which rely heavily on imported durian seedlings, while seed quality is difficult to judge by appearance, and the lack of sufficient land and mother trees is hindering large-scale durian planting in the country, Feng added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China to eat first local durians in June. Is Malaysian, Thai dominance at risk?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Seedling introduction is a time-consuming and labour-intensive work that is mainly undertaken by private enterprises,” he said, adding that the government “needs to provide greater support to these companies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s fresh durian imports in the first three months of this year totalled 91,400 tonnes, and the value of imports was US$507 million – figures that were up 154.29 per cent and 124.62 per cent, respectively, compared with the same period last year, customs data shows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s durian imports are highly dependent on Southeast Asian countries, including Thailand, Vietnam and Malaysia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first quarter of this year, Vietnam exported US$153 million worth of durians – 7.3 times more than a year prior. And China accounted for 87 per cent of that total, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine recaptures Staromaiorske village from Russia, Volodymyr Zelensky says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229181/ukraine-recaptures-staromaiorske-village-russia-volodymyr-zelensky-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 04:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/23445ded-f0b9-4b7a-911b-53ede38f7f61_32536757.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian soldiers have recaptured the southeastern village of Staromaiorske from Russian forces in Donetsk region, a video published by President Volodymyr Zelensky showed on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The 35th brigade and the &#39;Ariy&#39; territorial defence unit have fulfilled their task and liberated the village of Staromaiorske. Glory to Ukraine!” said a soldier in a video that Reuters was unable to immediately geolocate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The village lies to the south of a cluster of small settlements that Ukraine recaptured during a counteroffensive it began early in June against Russian forces who hold parts of southern and eastern Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our defenders are now continuing to clear the settlement,” Ukrainian Deputy Defence Minister Hanna Maliar said, declaring Staromaiorske liberated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oleksandr Kovalenko, a Ukrainian military analyst, said Ukrainian troops now needed to reach another village, Staromlynivka, less than 5km away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It really serves as a stronghold for the Russian occupiers, the peak of the second defensive line in this location,” he said in an interview with the RBC UA media outlet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The process is therefore entirely logical – first, take Staromaiorske, stabilise the flanks, and advance to the second line, where the main striking groups will be engaged to break through,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine: nuclear plant surrounded by landmines, UN watchdog warns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Russian troops are heavily entrenched in the strategically important south where they have prepared a sprawling network of trenches, minefields, anti-tank ditches and lines of “dragon&#39;s teeth” barricades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that Ukrainian attacks in the south had intensified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky has acknowledged progress in the counteroffensive has been slower than desired, but last night touted “very good results” from the front, without providing details.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[No place for ethnic profiling of academics, whether in Hong Kong or US universities]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228907/no-place-ethnic-profiling-academics-whether-hong-kong-or-us-universities?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/27/956ccc87-5434-452a-bea5-8b049201392e_484e6fa6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The so-called mainlandisation of Hong Kong&#39;s universities has become a topic of interest in international academic media. Recently, University World News, in noting that mainland academics in Hong Kong universities outnumbered local faculty this year for the first time, said it raised “fears” over “the international character of universities in Hong Kong, and their culture of open research”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It would be ironic if mainland Chinese scholars and scientists fleeing ethnic profiling in the US arrive here only to find themselves being profiled again in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the number of academic staff in the city born on the mainland has increased over the past five years, it has not affected the international rankings of Hong Kong&#39;s universities. If anything, the rankings have improved, from just three local universities among the world&#39;s top 100 in 2018, according to Times Higher Education, to five this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The simple reason is that academic appointments in Hong Kong are based on performance, and not ethnicity, nationality, gender or religion. Anyone who has served on a search and recruitment committee would confirm it, as I can. This is also backed up by data from an international study of the academic profession in 20 university systems, in which more Hong Kong academics agreed – more than those from other systems – that appointments and resources were made depending on performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The University of Hong Kong – the city&#39;s premier higher education establishment – is ranked year after year as the most international university in the world, which some contend is because non-local academics from the Chinese mainland count as international. In fact, the vast majority of them earned their doctorates overseas. That adds to the kind of diversity that universities in Hong Kong are known for in their staffing profiles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My corridor of nine offices had notable academic staff with overseas degrees who were natives of Canada, Portugal, South Korea, Ukraine, India, Georgia, Hong Kong and the mainland, and there were other faculty colleagues from Finland, Honduras, Britain and the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, the international character of Hong Kong&#39;s universities is intact. While the Covid-19 pandemic and the national security law may have pushed some talent away, the Donald Trump administration in the US was an inflection point that induced paranoia, making American universities haemorrhage Chinese talent, some of whom were pushed to Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the firing of Dr Hu Anming from the University of Tennessee at Knoxville in 2020, the FBI agent who accused Hu of spying admitted under oath that there was no evidence to back up his claims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similarly, the Department of Justice&#39;s assumption that five mainland-born academics had engaged in nefarious activities turned out to be frivolous as all charges against them were dropped in July 2021. Unsurprisingly, back in 2019, the president of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology was already warning against “a toxic atmosphere of unfounded suspicion and fear”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is not to deny that technology theft has occurred in some instances, but it shows how government overreach can damage academic careers and the functioning of universities. Before the atmosphere turned toxic in 2018, more than 10 per cent of US inventions were made by scientists of ethnic Chinese origin, according to research by a senior associate dean at Harvard University. Government actions, in whatever country or jurisdiction, can at times thwart the academic research enterprise from doing innovative teaching and research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Profiling scholars and scientists impairs the intellectual vitality and dedication of the academic research enterprise. University work carries a solemn responsibility to establish and confirm truth by way of the scientific method and, when necessary, to speak truth to power. This means prioritising professionalism over nationalism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a choice for leading research universities in Hong Kong, on the mainland and overseas to either distinguish themselves as instruments of strategic competition within a toxic atmosphere of suspicion and mistrust, or as institutions for international peace and human progress based on an international convergence of mutual academic and professional interests for the global common good.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Profiling based on ethnicity or nationality can create a self-fulfilling prophecy as professors become viewed first as locals, mainlanders or other nationals, rather than as professionals based on their academic and research discoveries, innovations and research accomplishments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The best universities adhere to the highest values of the academy, values that the Hong Kong model of higher education has long fought to maintain. The merit of science-based research findings should not depend on the identity of the scientist. The warping of scientific findings by authoritarian systems during those dreadful parts of the 20th century should warn us not to fall prey to an identity politics of science in the metaverse of the 21st century.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the world faces existential challenges, there is a danger of myths abounding about the sacred nature of any one model of higher education. Cross-border university communities operate best on the basis of respect and understanding. It ensures productive collaboration in an environment of academic freedom to address problems like climate change, pandemics, food insecurity, poverty and inequality, and other, unforeseen, challenges. That leaves no time for ethnic or national profiling in or outside academia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: US intelligence report says China likely to be supplying tech for Russian military]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229179/ukraine-war-us-intelligence-report-says-china-likely-be-supplying-tech-russian-military?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 02:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/f5f92e29-c880-4dca-8eab-6d792619721a_d0380645.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China is helping Russia evade Western sanctions and likely providing Moscow with military and dual-use technology for use in Ukraine, according to an unclassified US intelligence report released on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The assessment by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) was published by the US House of Representatives Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has repeatedly denied sending military equipment to Russia since Moscow&#39;s all-out invasion of Ukraine in February 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The [People&#39;s Republic of China] is providing some dual-use technology that Moscow&#39;s military uses to continue the war in Ukraine, despite an international cordon of sanctions and export controls,” the ODNI report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The customs records show PRC state-owned defence companies shipping navigation equipment, jamming technology, and fighter jet parts to sanctioned Russian government-owned defence companies,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also said China has become “an even more critical partner” of Russia after Moscow invaded Ukraine last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ODNI said China and Russia had increased the share of bilateral trade settled in China&#39;s yuan currency, and both countries&#39; financial institutions are expanding their use of domestic payment systems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has increased it importation of Russia energy exports, including oil and gas rerouted from Europe, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Putin plans to visit China in October, Kremlin says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;ODNI attributed much of the information to media reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It added: “The Intelligence Community lacks sufficient reporting to assess whether Beijing is deliberately inhibiting United States government export control end-use checks, including interviews and investigations, in the PRC.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, French President Emmanuel Macron&#39;s top diplomatic adviser Emmanuel Bonne said China was delivering items that could be used as military equipment to Russia, although not on a massive scale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US officials have previously raised concerns about transfers of “dual-use equipment” from China to Russia.然而，他们一再表示，尚未看到向俄罗斯转移致命援助以供战场使用的证据。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump lawyers meet US special counsel as second indictment looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229177/donald-trump-lawyers-meet-us-special-counsel-second-indictment-looms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 02:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/5137a4cc-c896-4d6c-ac6f-45f75eed44a9_3b77a00d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Donald Trump&#39;s lawyers on Thursday met Justice Department officials investigating the Republican former president&#39;s attempts to overturn his 2020 election defeat, said the ex-US president, who is the target of a special counsel investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump said on his Truth Social platform that the Department of Justice had not told his lawyers when action was likely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My attorneys had a productive meeting with the DOJ this morning, explaining in detail that I did nothing wrong, was advised by many lawyers, and that an Indictment of me would only further destroy our Country,” Trump said. “No indication of notice was given during the meeting.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Special Counsel Jack Smith is investigating actions by Trump, the front-runner for the 2024 Republican presidential nomination, to try to reverse his loss to Democrat Joe Biden in the 2020 election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials have testified that during his final months in office, Trump pressured them with false claims of widespread voter fraud. His supporters attacked the US Capitol in a January 6, 2021, bid to stop Congress from certifying Biden&#39;s win.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump said on July 18 he had received a letter from Smith stating that he was a target of the probe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several US news outlets reported Trump&#39;s lawyers had arrived at a Justice Department building and were meeting officials in Smith&#39;s office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not uncommon for defence lawyers to meet federal prosecutors before an indictment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump says he has been told he&#39;s a target in 2020 election investigation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Trump is already the first former US president to face criminal charges, which he has sought to portray as a politically motivated witch hunt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Any indictment in the election case would represent a second round of federal charges from Smith, who was appointed in November by US Attorney General Merrick Garland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s lawyers previously met officials at the Justice Department, including Smith, before a grand jury in Miami indicted Trump in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump pleaded not guilty in Miami to a 37-count indictment charging him with unlawfully retaining classified government documents after leaving office in 2021 and obstructing justice. Prosecutors accused him of risking some of the most sensitive US national security secrets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first charges brought against Trump came in March when a grand jury convened by Manhattan&#39;s district attorney indicted him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump in April pleaded not guilty to a 34 charges accusing him of falsifying business records concerning a payment to porn star Stormy Daniels to buy her silence before the 2016 election about a sexual encounter she said she had with him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump, 77, leads a crowded field of Republican presidential candidates as he seeks a rematch with Biden, 80, next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Earth in ‘era of global boiling’, UN chief warns, as July set to be hottest month on record]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3229176/earth-era-global-boiling-un-chief-warns-july-set-be-hottest-month-record?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 01:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/9038cf49-de04-41e7-9268-dd798fb02032_46b37067.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;UN chief Antonio Guterres on Thursday pleaded for immediate radical action on climate change, saying that record-shattering July temperatures show Earth has passed from a warming phase into an “era of global boiling”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The secretary general&#39;s remarks came as UN and EU monitors said that July is set to be the hottest month in recorded history and likely “unprecedented” for thousands of years, warning that this was a taste of the world&#39;s climate future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking in New York, Guterres described the intense heat across the Northern Hemisphere as a “cruel summer”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For the entire planet, it is a disaster,” he said, noting that “short of a mini-Ice Age over the next days, July 2023 will shatter records across the board”. “气候变化就在这里。这太可怕了。 And it is just the beginning. The era of global warming has ended; the era of global boiling has arrived.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Searing heat intensified by global warming has baked parts of Europe, Asia and North America this month, combining with wildfires that have scorched across Canada and parts of southern Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the first three weeks of July already registering global average temperatures above any comparative period, the World Meteorological Organisation and Europe&#39;s Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S) said it is “extremely likely” that July 2023 will be the hottest month on records going back to the 1940s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Carlo Buontempo, Director of C3S, said the temperatures in the period had been “remarkable”, with an anomaly so large that scientists are confident the record has been shattered even before the month ends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond these official records, he said proxy data for the climate going back further – like tree rings, or ice cores – suggests the temperatures seen in the period could be “unprecedented in our history in the last few thousand years”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Firefighting plane crashes in Greece, two dead, as blazes rage&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The previous hottest month was July 2019, according to Copernicus, which will publish finalised data in early August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The extreme impacts of climate change have been in line with scientists&#39; “predictions and repeated warnings”, Guterres said, adding that the “only surprise is the speed of the change”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the face of “tragic” consequences, he repeated his call for swift and far-reaching action, taking aim once again at the fossil fuel sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The air is unbreathable. The heat is unbearable. And the level of fossil fuel profits and climate inaction is unacceptable,” said the former Portuguese prime minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Leaders must lead,” he said. “No more hesitancy. No more excuses. No more waiting for others to move first.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ahead of the Climate Ambition Summit he is set to host in September, Guterres called on developed countries to commit to achieving carbon neutrality as close to 2040 as possible, and for emerging economies as close as possible to 2050.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “destruction” unleashed by humanity “must not inspire despair, but action”, he said, warning that to prevent the worst outcomes humanity “must turn a year of burning heat into a year of burning ambition”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>