<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘I thought they didn’t want me’: Chinese girl with cerebral palsy, 6, delights millions online with reaction to securing a primary school place]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224374/i-thought-they-didnt-want-me-chinese-cerebral-palsy-girl-6-delights-millions-online-reaction?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/c440c1b5-0b59-4b5a-8382-43ad787f45a4_28b1a0c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个在线视频捕捉了一个中国脑瘫小女孩发现的瞬间&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外号豆豆的 6 岁张君如在看到妈妈杨峰时，无法抑制自己的喜悦。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但那一刻充满了悲伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我以为他们不想要我，”豆豆在视频中说，既高兴又如释重负这显示她在前往中国西南部重庆市一家治疗中心的路上练习步行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们为什么不要你？豆豆很棒，”杨在视频中迅速回复了她的女儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，杨在她的抖音账户——中国版的 TikTok——上发布了这段视频，她说当她听到这个消息时感到“心碎”豆豆对此消息的回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“像豆豆这样的孩子不能轻易上学的想法在我们的脑海中根深蒂固，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早产的豆豆，两岁时，她还没有学会走路，被诊断出患有脑瘫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;确诊后，她的父母将她从四川农村的老家带到邻近的重庆进行治疗。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预后是毁灭性的。医生告诉他们，豆豆“永远无法站立”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨拒绝放弃女儿。她在重庆的治疗中心附近租了一套公寓，每周带豆豆去那里六天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了帮助支付治疗费，她的父亲张琳在遥远的地方当了一名民工建筑工人。 -跑到河北、陕西等北方省份，而杨则全职照顾女儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨说，豆豆也表现出了决心，每天都坚持去治疗中心，尽管要忍受疼痛的按摩和腿-拉伸治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但辛勤工作得到了回报。经过一年的治疗，豆豆可以自己站起来，五岁时可以自己走路了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年12月，有人看了一段她从治疗中心走路回家的视频在社交媒体平台哔哩哔哩上的浏览量达到 350 万次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频中，豆豆走在女儿身后，每一步都缓慢而稳定。 300米的路程包括好几段楼梯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爸爸，我回来了！而且我一个人走了一路！”回家后，她高兴地对父亲大喊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;脑瘫是指一组影响一个人移动、保持平衡和姿势能力的疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国， 2020 年出版的《脑瘫儿童康复小组标准》的主要撰稿人庞伟表示，每 1,000 名儿童中就有超过两名患有脑瘫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并非每个脑瘫患者都患有智力障碍，但对这种情况的误解仍然存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些学校拒绝接受脑瘫儿童，认为他们没有资源来照顾他们的人身安全。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Scientists say new nanomaterial can harness sunlight to produce hydrogen for green energy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3224504/scientists-say-new-nanomaterial-can-harness-sunlight-produce-hydrogen-green-energy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/13dfda09-ddb3-4a13-8ac1-84c0f34644a0_9e52100a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个国际科学家团队开发了一种新的纳米材料，可以在太阳能电池中从水中提取氢-动力工艺，可以打开绿色高效清洁能源生产的大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员表示，这种材料可以在环境条件下用于淡水和盐水，而无需特定的温度或压力水平.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;氢气被认为是最终的无污染燃料和未来的储能介质。一种传统的制氢方法是在称为电解的过程中使用电将水分解成氧气和氢气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了消除该过程中对电力的需求，英国、加拿大、香港和中国大陆的科学家&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科学家提高钙钛矿太阳能电池效率&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;植物进行光合作用，即利用阳光、水和二氧化碳在植物中产生氧气和能量的过程糖的形式。同样，还有一些光合细菌可以有效地从阳光中转移能量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月 18 日发表在 Nature Catalysis 上的一项研究中，科学家们模仿了细菌的独特结构，即充当光传感器，创造了...该工艺使用光将水转化为氢气，用于燃料电池和甲醇和醛等工业产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团队已在同行评审期刊（包括能源和环境）上发表了他们长达数年的项目的其他发现Science and Nature Communications。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席科学家、香港大学物理化学教授兼主席 David Lee Phillips 表示，该团队的下一步将是构建光催化工具包，将二氧化碳转化为有用的物质&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说能够在环境条件下部署纳米材料是太阳能转换研究的一个突破。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“纳米材料在环境水中足够稳定。这是一个很大的突破，因为很多用于光催化反应的东西在水中不一定是稳定的。在这里，我们使用水作为反应物——有点像大自然的反应，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，如果催化可以在环境温度下进行，则可以更有效、更便宜地完成，因为它不需要大量的能源或复杂的设备来控制温度或压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;浮动氢农场使中国更接近清洁可再生能源&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;郭正孝，联合教授香港大学化学与机械工程系博士与菲利普斯合作领导太阳能氢研究，他说纳米材料系统的另一个优势是它可以生产高纯度产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在工业中，我们希望纯净的东西。我们需要纯氢，而不是氨或碳氢化合物等其他物质，因为杂质会降低燃料电池等设备的性能，”他说，并补充说可以使用膜进一步过滤掉不需要的分子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总之，这技术可以实现真正绿色且具有成本效益的选择性工艺来生产特定产品，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;聚变反应堆正在发生故障——泰国科学家很高兴&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，一组中国科学家成功地将海水转化为氢气和氧气，而无需在漂浮的氢气农场进行脱盐。中国东南部的海上平台利用风能和太阳能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲利普斯说，中国团队的项目是绿色发电的试点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们尝试做的事情提供了使用新系统非常有效地做到这一点的方法，希望它可以进行测试并集成到实际应用中，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，这种新材料可以提高制氢效率，同时使它更坚固，因此太阳能电池板和其他相关设备可以使用更长时间。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As China steps up its economic stimulus, currencies of South Korea, Australia soar]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3224535/china-steps-its-economic-stimulus-currencies-south-korea-australia-soar?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 09:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/19/bb1fb52c-3b15-48ec-a955-b77c2326321e_29241dea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国加大刺激措施以提振经济的举措对人民币，而其代理货币在区域领先排行榜上攀升并有望扩大涨幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于出口关系密切，韩国的韩元和澳元的表现与中国密切相关，它们有望成为全球领先的货币。本季度亚太货币排名。韩元的升值引人注目，因为它是今年前三个月表现最差的货币。不过，中国的刺激措施可能对两种货币的出色表现发挥的作用有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们更加谨慎地认为，中国的刺激措施是澳元的主要积极催化剂，”澳大利亚外汇策略师 John Bromhead 表示与新西兰银行集团有限公司在悉尼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当前的投资和刺激组合旨在促进国内消费，而不是大规模的基础设施建设。总体而言，这种组合的钢铁密集度较低，因此对铁矿石和澳元的利好程度较低。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，韩元和美元找到了其他驱动因素。 Bromhead 将本月意外加息的鹰派澳大利亚储备银行归功于澳大利亚股市上涨的主要催化剂。 “市场已将对澳大利亚央行最终现金利率的预期从 3.85% 上调至 4.5%，这对澳元来说是一个主要的推动因素。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他预计到年底美元将升至 70 美分上周五，韩元本季度上涨近 3%，至 68.85 美分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，英伟达公司的“井喷”预测帮助提振了韩元，因为外国投资者将资金投入科技股亚洲，尤其是韩国和台湾。全球基金本季度净买入了 40 亿美元的韩国股票，尽管上个月有所上涨，但一些分析师仍认为亚洲芯片制造商的股价便宜，因此可能还会有更多资金流入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“韩国股市的好转在围绕 AI 的乐观情绪好转的情况下，流入资金的增加推动了韩元的快速增长，”东方汇理银行香港分行高级新兴市场策略师 Eddie Cheung 表示。 “还有报道称韩国公司将股息汇回国内，这增加了对韩元的支持，”Cheung 说，并补充说他预计该货币在短期内将继续跑赢其他货币。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巴基斯坦使用中文人民币从俄罗斯购买降价石油&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;继今年前三个月下跌 2.8% 之后，本季度韩元上涨 2.3% 至 1,272.35。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人民币然而，该国经济反弹乏力仍令其承压。随着国家货币政策在降息后进一步偏离鹰派美联储，上周美元汇率接近突破 7.2 的关键水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民银行在其一年期中期利率上调在周二将 7 天逆回购利率意外下调类似幅度后，周四将定期贷款便利下调 10 个基点。投资者现在将关注本周国家的一年期和五年期贷款最优惠利率是否也会降低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前，有利于美国的收益率差异扩大可能仍会在一定程度上削弱人民币，但如果中国的支持措施确实获得进一步的牵引力，那么这可能有助于稳定人民币情绪，”新加坡华侨银行外汇策略师 Christopher Wong 表示。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HKMA’s global financial summit, BIS conference to bring hundreds of bankers to Hong Kong in November]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224497/hkmas-global-financial-summit-bis-conference-bring-hundreds-bankers-hong-kong-november?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/559e5ed7-4e3b-443c-aac0-4cf6ea75e05c_40a302e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;近 300 位全球顶级银行和金融高管以及数十位央行行长将齐聚香港香港金融管理局 (HKMA) 于 11 月在香港举行了两次会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港事实上的中央银行将于 11 月 6 日至 8 日在香港举办第二届全球金融领袖投资峰会四季酒店，随后于 11 月 27 日举行了国际清算银行 (BIS) 年度行长会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;适逢金管局成立 30 周年，这两项活动是香港努力展示世界各地的人们都希望这座城市在经历了三年的大流行病破坏后恢复正常。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金管局首席执行官余伟文表示，金管局预计将有 280 名首席执行官以及银行和金融业的高级管理人员参加此次峰会。他补充说，在迄今为止发出的邀请中，将近 60 人已经接受，而且可能会有更多人做出回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还在继续，”岳在接受媒体采访时说。 “积极响应也是因为今年的峰会是为了庆祝金管局成立30周年。由于这些金融公司是我们的合作伙伴，他们的高层都想来参加我们的生日聚会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港金管局于 1993 年 4 月 1 日成立，合并了外汇基金办公室——管理货币储备以捍卫当地货币 - 以及银行监管机构银行业专员办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二届银行家峰会继去年的活动取得圆满成功之后举行。来自世界各地的 200 多名顶级金融家参加了 11 月的会议，当时该市在 1 月全面重新开放边境之前开始放宽对 Covid-19 的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年的峰会上，美国银行业巨头花旗集团宣布在尖沙咀开设首个全球财富管理中心，而瑞士私人银行瑞士宝盛公布其未来在香港的扩张计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“峰会向世界发出了一个强有力的信息，即香港Kong 回来了，”财政司司长陈茂波在去年的峰会后表示，并补充说，许多参加峰会的国际金融家计划升级他们的业务，派遣更多的全球高级管理人员，并增加在香港的本地招聘。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;不过，Yue 表示，金管局没有计划将该活动变成年度特色活动或扩大其规模。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于场地的 [规模] 限制，我们的目标是带来 280顶级金融家今年将出席，这样他们就可以进行密切对话，”他说。 “如果我们把它变成年度峰会，它也可能不会很好地运作，因为高层管理人员可能每年都不会出席。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的峰会将像上一届一样安排。第一天将举行闭门晚宴，随后是第二天的银行和金融问题公开论坛。随着香港金管局与证券及期货事务监察委员会共同举办资产管理论坛，此次活动将落下帷幕。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;John Lee 敦促全球银行“走在前面”，因为香港呼啸而过&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;Yue 拒绝透露已确认参加的银行家的姓名，并表示将在稍后阶段公布与会者名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于会议标志着金管局成立 30 周年，Yue 说他会邀请一些前任央行行长，包括来自英国和日本的人，分享他们对过去三十年银行业演变的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的两位前任任志光和陈德霖Tak-lam – 也将在活动中发言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，11 月 27 日的国际清算银行年度行长会议之后将于次日举行高级别的 HKMA-BIS 会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;香港旅游发展局数据显示，今年1月全面重开边境的香港今年首5个月接待游客约1000万人次。去年，该市在此期间的入境人数仅为 34,982 人，而前一年仅为 27,549 人。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong lawmaker Tommy Cheung in push to get university to pay for private bill he initiated to revamp governing council]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3224526/hong-kong-lawmaker-push-get-university-pay-private-bill-he-initiated-revamp-governing-council?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/cb2049d9-520a-46f1-86d1-521779bda66b_d3c5971c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位也建议香港领导人的立法者正在推动当地大学支付更多费用据《邮报》获悉，他发起的一项旨在削减其管理机构工作人员比例的私人法案的费用超过 70 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自由党立法会议员张宇仁在消息人士周日表示，中国大学理事会最近召开的一次会议立即遭到了一些其他成员的强烈反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在“骇人听闻”的抗议处理之后推动香港大学改革&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据两个不同的消息来源，同时担任政府关键决策执行委员会成员的 Cheung 表示，拟议的管理机构重组是为了大学的利益，因此它应该负责准备私人法案所产生的费用。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;但部分议员在会上争辩说，这是张先生的倡议，议会从来没有讨论过，也没有批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这笔钱是用来支付履行职责所产生的费用和开支。提出修改香港中文大学条例的私人法案的要求和手续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，Cheung 曾表示大部分费用用于“宪报费”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位出席会议并因保密规定不愿透露姓名的理事会成员说：“[Cheung] 希望中文大学结清款项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的印象是他认为他为中文大学做了[账单]。但为什么大学要为一个自行发起大学校董会改组私人议案的立法会买单呢？”批准或同意”获得大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是私人会员的法案。你指示律师起草[大学]条例和章程的修正案。按照常识，你应该承担费用，”该成员说&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港中文大学专责小组在校董会改革中采取中间立场&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据了解，讨论是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据另一位熟悉情况的消息人士透露，据说 Cheung 还声称行政长官李家超的想法是让他提出一项法案来全面改革大学的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung 周日表示他没有评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但三位立法会议员之一的 Bill Tang Ka-piu发起这项法案的人说，他们只希望大学支付宪报费，而不是法律费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，不是张或我们要求大学偿还我们钱。我们的观点是，大学有责任支付这笔款项，”他说。 “这些修正案是专门为大学设计的。大学应该支付费用，这是非常合理的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港中文大学校长将留任至 2026 年&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;唐指出岭南大学和香港的私人账单Kong University of Science and Technology，并指出产生的费用由各机构承担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大学发言人表示不予置评，并补充说理事会会议的讨论是根据保密原则进行的。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;教育局发言人表示，行政长官已根据《基本法》第七十四条同意有关私人条例草案。他补充说，根据《私人法案条例》，政府可能会在特定情况下并应法案发起人的申请免除应缴费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府根据法律要求和适用程序处理此类申请， ”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修改《中文大学条例》的私人法案是由校董会的三位立法会议员发起的，第三位是刘国帆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计最早将于 6 月 28 日提交立法会进行一读和二读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三人正寻求将立法会议员人数从 55 人减少到 34 人，同时大幅增加外部代表的比例，以便他们将以 2:1 的比例控制机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案还寻求提高理事会任命大学校长的门槛，以获得理事会四分之三的选票，并增加香港领导人选择的成员人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的举动被视为建制派集团对有争议的重新任命段崇智教授的回应，段崇智教授将继续担任大学校长至 2026 年。被一些亲北京人士指责在 2019 年社会动荡期间同情抗议学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港大学全球排名下降归咎于缺乏合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据第 74 条根据《基本法》——香港的小宪法——立法者可以向立法会提交法案。但此类法案不能与“公共支出或政治结构或政府运作”相关，并且在提出与政府政策相关的法案之前需要行政长官的书面同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两个私人法案立法会议员刘志鹏教授和陈仲年教授分别提议对《岭南大学条例》和《香港科技大学条例》进行技术更新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘志鹏教授也是协理副主任岭南大学校长拒绝讨论私人账单的总费用，但表示：“大学将承担全部费用，而不是我。作为立法会议员，我的职责是帮助大学向立法会介绍法案。恰好我是大学高层的一员。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Asean’s hopes for easing US-China tensions through defence diplomacy depend on getting its house in order]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224316/aseans-hopes-easing-us-china-tensions-through-defence-diplomacy-depend-getting-its-house-order?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/0f5d32a8-4c08-4abe-adf3-dcfa28cefa20_cd9f48d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“我们希望……展现 [人民解放] 开放自信的新形象陆军]海军，”中国军官雷晓在最近结束的印度尼西亚大型多国海军演习中说。中国人民解放军的新闻媒体 PLA Daily 将南苏拉威西岛附近的科莫多多边海军演习描述为该地区国家“进一步加深相互了解和务实合作”的关键一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;来自印太地区 30 个国家的多达 40 艘军舰参加了在印度尼西亚海域举行的备受瞩目的演习。让今年的演习变得尤为重要的是美国和中国海军的联合参与，凸显了东南亚在地区地缘政治中日益增长的中心地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于军事与军事之间的虚拟崩溃，这一点至关重要- 超级大国之间的军事外交，仅在过去一个月，超级大国的武装部队就在南海和台湾海峡发生了几次险情。美国和中国的国防部长未能在今年的新加坡香格里拉对话会上举行直接会谈，双方在会上相互指责对方导致地区安全架构恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对令人不安的事态发展感到担忧，印度尼西亚是今年东南亚国家联盟（东盟）的轮值主席国，再次成为调解美中关系的中心。东南亚国家也欢迎中国人民解放军海军特遣队的友好访问，以缓和南中国海的海上紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚也在推动东盟的更大团结。因此，它将于今年晚些时候组织地区国家之间的首次海军演习，以确立东盟在印太地区的中心地位。尽管有着良好的意愿和日益增长的战略影响力，但雅加达领导的东盟必须克服深刻的内部分歧，以有效调解美中之间的长期缓和关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东盟国家展示了他们的外交实力，例如何时去年美国众议院议长南希佩洛西访问台湾后，他们在将华盛顿和北京走到一起方面发挥了核心作用。与此同时，新加坡警告两国不要在梦游中陷入冲突，强调针锋相对的制裁和激进言论的意外后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不久之后，11 月 14 日，美国总统乔拜登会见了中国国家主席习近平在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 20 国集团峰会期间。在会谈中，两人誓言要更积极主动地管理战略竞争，并表明他们共同致力于“共同应对跨国挑战”。但东盟调解的缓和很快瓦解，尤其是在今年早些时候发生中国“间谍气球”事件之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现任中国国防部长李尚福在美国的制裁名单上，使直接制裁的努力复杂化外交。更糟糕的是，最近几周双方几乎发生冲突，双方在南中国海上空的飞机近距离通话以及一周后在台湾海峡的军舰之间相互指责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;为了防止热战，印度尼西亚提出了与美国和中国以及东盟国家之间的合作活动——包括联合巡逻和演习——以加强国防外交和缓和地区紧张局势。然而，有效的东盟国防外交面临三大挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，该集团受到功能失调的决策过程的阻碍，该过程强调共识而非有效领导。通过天真​​地坚持在敏感的地缘政治问题上达成一致，它一直未能组织集体应对其后院的重大危机。过去，即使在冷战最激烈的时候，东盟的创始者也会通过小多边合作而不是坚持达成共识来对危机做出果断的反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，东盟国家对威胁的看法和战略也各不相同。一方面，东南亚海洋国家更直接地受到该地区紧张局势升级的影响。一些国家，特别是印度尼西亚和新加坡，也将自己视为塑造区域安全的积极利益攸关方，而菲律宾和马来西亚则是南中国海的积极声索国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数东南亚大陆国家不仅更加孤立海上争端，但也更依赖中国的投资和援助。这在很大程度上解释了为什么柬埔寨在区域海上安全问题上违背了东盟创始成员的意愿，停止​​了与印度尼西亚在南中国海附近提出的联合钻探计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2012 年，柬埔寨甚至试图阻止讨论海上争端这被视为对北京的尊重。其结果是东盟天生无法就地区地缘政治问题达成最佳共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么柬埔寨对中国修建的金边-西哈努克公路有着复杂的感受&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这让我们想到该组织面临的最严峻挑战：其队伍中丑陋的分歧。一方面，菲律宾加强了与西方的防务关系，最近与美国、澳大利亚和日本举行了首次四方安全会议，讨论今年晚些时候在南中国海进行联合巡逻的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;本月，菲律宾还与美国和日本举行了首次海岸警卫队联合演习。因此，有人担心马尼拉可能更像是西方的延伸，而不是负责任的东盟成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，柬埔寨似乎正朝着相反的方向发展，有报道称它可能成为第一个在该地区拥有中国海军基地的国家。作为回应，一些地区思想领袖呼吁将柬埔寨驱逐出东盟，因为它过度依赖北京。简而言之，如果东盟寻求在美国和中国之间进行有效调解，它就必须把自己的房子弄好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Training Hong Kong nurses to give eye injections could ‘reduce patient waiting times, cut workload for doctors’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3224491/training-hong-kong-nurses-give-eye-injections-could-reduce-patient-waiting-times-cut-workload?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/4630785d-fb67-4aeb-bef8-796c215f6e68_7268fa6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;培训香港公立医院的护士进行眼部注射有助于减少等待时间一项正在进行的试点计划背后的医学专家表示，患者和减轻了医生的繁重工作量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，玻璃体内注射通常由医生处理，用于治疗因年龄相关性黄斑变性引起的中心视力模糊。根据目前的安排，患者平均需要等待三个月才能接受注射。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;九龙东医院联网眼科服务主管李开旺教授说，大约 25% 的患者区域的玻璃体内注射一直由护士进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们能够使计划正常化并有更多的护士进行静脉注射，我相信我们可以进一步减少患者的等待时间，”他说，并补充说这样的举措可以帮助医生腾出时间来处理其他病例。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“香港医院管理局需要更多工程师来监督设备工作”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卫生局向立法会提供的数据3 月 15 日发现，香港公立医院在 2020 年 4 月至 2022 年底期间失去了 1,247 名医生，其中只有 15% 退休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该集群的眼科团队，设在观塘基督教联合医院和将军澳医院的医院去年开始培训护士进行注射，这有助于将等待时间缩短至四个星期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医学专家也获管理香港公立医院的医院管理局表扬，并于今年 3 月荣获“2023 年杰出团队”奖项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该先导计划是香港首创，自项目开始以来，护士已经治疗了 240 多名患者，并希望到 2023 年底达到 314 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门的运营经理 Monica Lee 表示，护士必须接受多层次的培训计划才能管理该项目&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须参加 4 小时的理论讲座，参加 3 小时的实验室课程，在那里我们使用 3D 打印的眼睛模型练习玻璃体内注射，并通过笔试we move on to the clinical practice stage,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the clinical practice stage, we have to deliver at least 100 injections to patients under the supervision of a doctor, which usually takes three months to half a year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the ophthalmological team, 98 per cent of patients had expressed satisfaction with their treatment after receiving an intravitreal injection from a nurse trained under the scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Doctors would seek patients&#39; consent before they received the jab from nurses, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong makes over 130 job offers to doctors based in UK as part of hiring bid&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Doctors also explain to patients that there is no difference between doctor-delivered and nurse-delivered shots in terms of safety,” said Ng Lai-kuen, an associate nurse consultant with the department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hospital cluster has five nurses trained to administer intravitreal injections, but health officials there did not say whether they planned to increase that number.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The specialist team also declined to discuss other possible plans to train nurses to handle tasks currently performed by doctors, saying it would focus on finishing a review for the pilot scheme by the end of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hospital Authority figures showed some patients considered to be stable cases waited up to 216 weeks, or more than four years, to receive their first appointment at eye-specialist outpatient clinics.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump criticised by Republican White House hopefuls over handling of classified documents]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224534/trump-criticised-republican-white-house-hopefuls-over-handling-classified-documents?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 07:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/19/5d1cb3a8-5556-4869-8c29-383edf22d9d8_f6b66779.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Fresh off Donald Trump&#39;s 37-count indictment, several top Republicans, including White House hopefuls Mike Pence and Asa Hutchinson, on Sunday criticised the ex-president&#39;s handling of classified information as rivals plot their potential paths to 2024.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The comments, including harsh criticism from former Trump defence secretary Mark Esper, came on the first round of major weekend political talk shows since Trump pleaded not guilty in a Miami courtroom on Tuesday to mishandling some of the US government&#39;s most sensitive secrets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors also allege that Trump schemed to prevent federal investigators from recovering the classified material, which he took with him upon leaving the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The remarks on Sunday stand in sharp contrast to those of many Republicans in Congress who have either defended Trump or declined to criticise him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can&#39;t defend what is alleged,” Pence, Trump&#39;s former vice-president, told NBC&#39;s Sunday talk show Meet the Press, alluding to his ex-boss&#39;s behaviour in the documents affair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hutchinson, the former governor of Arkansas, went further, calling the allegations “serious and disqualifying.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think that he should drop out” of the 2024 race, Hutchinson told ABC&#39;s This Week.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ron DeSantis quiet on Trump indictment as he faces conservatives in Trump country&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Trump, who has claimed the Department of Justice is being weaponised against him, is accused in the indictment of endangering national security by illegally keeping top secret military plans and nuclear weapons information at his Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case is one of multiple legal challenges casting a shadow over his run for another term in the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the allegations are true, that it contained information about our nation&#39;s security … it could be quite harmful to the nation,” Esper told CNN&#39;s State of the Union.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Echoing remarks last week by the special prosecutor who filed the charges, Esper said “no one is above the law,” and called the revelations “disturbing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republican presidential contenders are finding themselves in the tricky position of trying to stake out room between themselves and Trump, the party&#39;s current clear front runner, without alienating his loyal and powerful base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The former president deserves his day in court,” Pence said. “I want to reserve judgment about this until he&#39;s had an opportunity to take his case into the courtroom.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pence also made clear that he and Trump “have parted ways” on other issues as well, including on the national debt.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump-appointed judge Cannon in &#39;tough position&#39; as she oversees his case&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Former New Jersey governor Chris Christie, who threw his hat in the ring last week with a vow to directly take on Trump, on Sunday blasted the former president for “constantly whining and complaining and moaning about how things are unfair.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Christie, a former federal prosecutor, also attacked Trump for berating ex-underlings who cross or disappoint him. “He&#39;s a petulant child when someone disagrees with him,” Christie told CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last Monday, former US ambassador to the United Nations Nikki Haley unleashed a fierce critique of her one-time boss.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If this indictment is true … president Trump was incredibly reckless with our national security,” Haley told Fox News.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong needs more, not less, public engagement in project planning]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224360/hong-kong-needs-more-not-less-public-engagement-project-planning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/c99bf3ed-d317-42b7-824f-7a7e93870e89_867907c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;In today&#39;s improved political environment where open opposition to the government is scarce, most of our lawmakers seem happy with government decisions most of the time. But if we look at how much Secretary for Development Bernadette Linn Hon-ho has been in the limelight lately, we get a sense that not all is fine and dandy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linn has been outspoken on the need to enhance speed and efficiency in administrative procedures related to increasing land supply. When challenged over the government&#39;s ambitious plans to create three artificial islands off Lantau, Linn said time should be spent on discussing how to carry out the project successfully rather than debating whether it should be undertaken.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linn&#39;s stance is understandable. The more time devoted to debating the project, the longer it will take to create the land needed for it. However, impatience is no excuse for a lack of adequate public engagement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government must respond to the public&#39;s concerns about mega-projects as they have a widespread impact. In the case of the Kau Yi Chau artificial islands project, the environment isn&#39;t the sole concern. Its cost and how that factors into other mammoth projects, such as the Northern Metropolis, make the debate over it legitimate and necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How is Hong Kong going to pay for all this? This will affect not only future generations but future administrations. Streamlining procedures must not become an excuse for cutting corners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Barely four months have passed since the Development Bureau said plans to build 12,000 public flats on part of the Hong Kong Golf Club&#39;s Old Course would go ahead, and now the plan looks like it faces more delays. The Environmental Protection Department conditionally approved the government&#39;s plans, but included a requirement that a 0.4-hectare patch of woodland be preserved, which further complicates the government&#39;s intention to build high-density public housing blocks on the site.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This led to the Planning Department suggesting to the Town Planning Board that it temporarily rezone the proposed public housing site from “residential” to “undetermined” to buy time for planners to go back to the drawing board with the project&#39;s entire design – the layout, building height and development density.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government will get the land back from the prestigious private club, but there are constraints on what it can do with it. The Development Bureau has said this will affect the scale and timeline of the intended public housing. The Town Planning Board held public hearings last week, and it was quite the sight to see former secretary for commerce Frederick Ma Si-hang attending one of the hearings and making his case against the government&#39;s plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The board received 6,788 responses from the public last year, with an overwhelming 99.6 per cent against the Fanling housing proposal. Whether one agrees with Ma&#39;s reasoning – that the golf course is more than a sports venue, and losing it as a place where business is conducted by senior executives would hurt the city&#39;s status as an international financial hub – is beside the point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These public hearings are an important part of the policymaking and execution process, giving the public an insight into the variety of views on government proposals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government must make efforts to garner public support of its policies, unless it considers consulting the people of Hong Kong to be an inconvenience or a nuisance. Engaging the public leads to better policy outcomes because the process ensures inclusion by providing opportunities for people to take part and greater transparency so residents can understand why and how decisions were made.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What to know about new Hong Kong public-private scheme to tackle housing crisis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Deliberation allows for effective communication, which is essential to building consensus. To strengthen social harmony and cohesion in Hong Kong, the government must do more, not less, in the way of public engagement. Shutting ordinary people out of ways to channel their grievances, express their views and ask questions of their leaders would lead to the toxic confrontations we have had in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Streamlining procedures cannot take the form of cutting the public out of the discussions. Perhaps we should stop discussing whether the government should invite public participation in and support for its initiatives, and instead talk about how it can do so successfully. Perhaps it is time to set rules of public engagement that make clear the different forms of consultations the government must avail itself of and when.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[LME set to defend itself in 3-day trial in London over nickel chaos from last year’s trading freeze]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224512/lme-set-defend-itself-3-day-trial-london-over-nickel-chaos-last-years-trading-freeze?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 06:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/18/a4814133-b472-4d28-b96c-9fe99b15be43_caf74159.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The London Metal Exchange (LME) is preparing to defend itself in court on Tuesday, more than a year after it was forced to suspend nickel trading following a short squeeze that threatened to destabilise the global market in March 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US hedge fund Elliott Associates and quantitative investing firm Jane Street Global Trading have sued the 146-year-old bourse in London, saying its actions to stem the chaos favoured some clients over others and violated their rights under the European Convention on Human Rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The LME maintains that Elliott&#39;s and Jane Street&#39;s grounds for complaint have no merit and are based on a fundamental misunderstanding of the situation on 8 March 2022 and the decisions taken by the LME,” an LME representative said. “All the actions taken on 8 March were lawful and made in the interest of the market as a whole.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case will be heard before two judges in the UK High Court over three days this week. Elliott is seeking US$456 million in damages, while Jane Street is seeking US$15.3 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can HKEX-owned LME rebuild its reputation a year after nickel chaos?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The trial comes just over 15 months after the nickel market descended into chaos in March of last year as the metal&#39;s price soared more than 270 per cent over a three-day period following Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine, triggering nearly US$16 billion in margin calls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rapid price movement squeezed dozens of short-sellers, including the world&#39;s largest stainless steel producer, Tsingshan Holding Group of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX)-owned bourse suspended trading and cancelled billions of dollars of transactions on March 8, 2022, a move that has sparked a series of legal actions and an enforcement inquiry by British regulators over the LME&#39;s response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since last year&#39;s chaos, the LME has introduced a series of measures to try to avoid similar situations in the future, including daily price limits for contracts that require metals to be physically delivered when a futures contract expires.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last summer, the bourse also began requiring its members to report their over-the-counter (OTC) positions on a weekly basis for these metals, including contracts for aluminium, copper, nickel, tin and zinc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, an independent review by the consulting firm Oliver Wyman found the LME needed to tighten its rules to improve its ability to identify and prevent future market distortions, including adopting LME-specific position limits and revamping its existing accountability level framework to help address risks created by large positions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, the bourse said it would overhaul its margin requirements and introduce a new nickel contract focused on the Asian markets to improve liquidity. It also said it would seek to further enhance its monitoring of liquidity and OTC positions, as well as make daily price limits on physically delivered metals a permanent feature of its markets going forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Large off-exchange positions in nickel have been partially blamed for chaos.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;LME to overhaul margins, introduce new nickel contract in market revamp&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Despite the reforms, average daily trading volumes for nickel continue to lag their February 2022 levels, as the LME struggles to rebuild its reputation, with an average of 37,746 lots of nickel traded every day in May. That compared with 85,639 lots a day in February of last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chamberlain said last month that the exchange is making “incremental” progress in restoring investor confidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think restoring confidence is something that just happens overnight,” Chamberlain told the Post on the sidelines of the LME Asia Metals Seminar in Hong Kong in May. “Every day you have to show you&#39;re doing something to earn that trust, and people have to see the market behaving as it should, which it is, and then eventually, you get there.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Heatwave triggers big storms, power cuts in US Southeast, raises wildfire concerns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224533/heatwave-triggers-big-storms-power-cuts-us-southeast-raises-wildfire-concerns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.19 06:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/19/317fb1dd-d7ca-479e-8fbe-28c0e8d46dad_56c49be1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Forecasters warned people celebrating Father&#39;s Day outdoors to take precautions as triple-digit temperatures prompted heat advisories across much of the southern US, triggered thunderstorms that knocked out power from Oklahoma to Mississippi and whipped up winds that raised wildfire threats in Arizona and New Mexico.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A suspected tornado struck near Scranton, Arkansas early on Sunday, destroying chicken houses and toppling trees on to homes, the National Weather Service said. There were no immediate reports of serious injuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meteorologists said that potentially record-breaking temperatures would continue into midweek over southern Texas and much of the Gulf coast. Storms producing damaging winds, hail and possibly tornadoes could strike the lower Mississippi Valley.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you have outdoor plans this #FathersDay, don&#39;t forget to practice heat safety! Take frequent breaks, stay hydrated, NEVER leave people/pets alone in a car!” the weather service office in Houston said on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Louisiana Governor John Bel Edwards declared a state of emergency for north and central parts of his state after strong winds and severe weather caused widespread power cuts on Saturday. On Sunday, more than 740,000 people were without power in Oklahoma, Texas, Louisiana, Arkansas and Mississippi, according to PowerOutage.us.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 30 people spent Saturday night at a cooling centre in Shreveport, Louisiana. Residents were thankful to have a place to get out of the sweltering heat, said Madison Poche, director of the non-profit Highland Centre, which opened its doors to anyone who needed somewhere to cool off.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We definitely had a few people tear up because folks have been stuck inside some pretty hot spaces and really just need a space to be physically comfortable for a while,” Poche said. She said that damage from the storm appears widespread in Shreveport.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3 separate US shootings leave 4 dead and 34 injured&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Florida, the weather service issued another heat advisory Sunday, this time mainly for the Florida Keys. Forecasters said heat index readings – the combination of high temperatures and oppressive humidity – could reach between 108 degrees Fahrenheit (42 degrees Celsius) and 112 degrees Fahrenheit (45 degrees Celsius) in places such as Key Largo, Marathon and Key West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These conditions will cause increased risk of heat illness for people outdoors or in non-air conditioned spaces,” the weather service said in a bulletin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Southwest, where fire crews are battling multiple wildfires in Arizona and New Mexico, forecasters said triple-digit temperatures and gusty winds would lead to critical fire weather over the next couple of days. Sunday promised to be the hottest day of the year in Arizona, with highs up to 110 degrees Fahrenheit (43.5 degrees Celsius) in Phoenix.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winds were forecast to gust from 30mph to 40mph (48-64 kph) on Sunday east of Flagstaff, Arizona along the Interstate 40 corridor and up to 50mph (80kph) on Monday, creating potentially critical fire weather across much of northeast New Mexico.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A large brush fire that broke out on Friday afternoon south of Tucson, Arizona shut down a state motorway on Saturday. Arizona 83 reopened on Sunday and no homes were in immediate danger, authorities said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prolonged closure took a toll on local businesses during what is usually a busy Father&#39;s Day weekend in an area with recreational lakes and reservoirs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dena Proez said the only business at her Corner Scoop ice cream shop along the motorway in Sonoita was serving a few travellers who stopped to get updates on the fire “and feeding all the firefighters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Much of Nevada was under a high-wind advisory with gusts up to 55mph (88kph) with blowing dust that could hamper visibility on highways, the weather service said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 19 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>