<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Vladimir Putin says Russia’s nuclear bombs now in Belarus, in warning to the West]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3224410/ukraine-war-vladimir-putin-says-russias-nuclear-bombs-now-belarus-warning-west?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 03:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/41a8503d-932d-41a7-bdf1-04582c89f4e0_ee3117c7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;总统弗拉基米尔·普京周五表示，他向白俄罗斯部署了战术核武器，一些他首次证实这件事已经发生，这提醒西方，它不可能对俄罗斯造成战略性的失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京在圣彼得堡举行的俄罗斯旗舰经济论坛上发表讲话说，俄罗斯的战术核弹头已经交付给亲密盟友白俄罗斯，但强调他认为俄罗斯目前没有必要诉诸核武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如你所知，我们正在与我们的盟友 [白俄罗斯总统亚历山大] 卢卡申科进行谈判，我们将把这些战术核武器的一部分转移到白俄罗斯境内——这已经发生了，”普京说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“第一批核弹头被运送到白俄罗斯境内。但只有第一个，第一部分。但我们将在夏末或年底前完成这项工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举是莫斯科首次部署此类弹头——可能用于这位俄罗斯领导人表示，自苏联解体以来，俄罗斯以外的战场是为了向西方发出关于武装和支持乌克兰的警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“正是作为一种威慑因素，所有那些正在考虑对我们造成战略失败的人并没有忘记这种情况，”普京说，他使用了一个外交术语来形容如此严重的失败，以至于俄罗斯在世界舞台上的实力将被削弱数十年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;卢卡申科是普京的坚定盟友，他周二晚些时候表示，他的国家已经开始接收俄罗斯战术核武器，其中的威力是美国 1945 年投向日本的原子弹的三倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位俄罗斯领导人在 3 月宣布，他同意在白俄罗斯部署战术核武器，并指出美国几十年来在许多欧洲国家部署了此类武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯为何希望在白俄罗斯部署战术核武器&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国批评普京的决定，但表示无意改变自己在战略核武器问题上的立场，也没有看到俄罗斯准备使用核武器的任何迹象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管如此，华盛顿及其盟友以及中国都在密切关注俄罗斯的举措，中国一再警告不要在乌克兰战争中使用核武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京说，西方尽一切可能在乌克兰对俄罗斯造成战略失败，莫斯科在去年入侵其邻国所谓的“特殊军事行动”后，陷入了自二战以来欧洲最大的陆战。&lt;/p>; p>;但普京说，俄罗斯目前没有必要诉诸核武器，这表明莫斯科的核态势没有改变，只有在俄罗斯国家的存在受到威胁时才会设想这样的举动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“核武器的制造是为了确保我们在最广泛意义上的安全和俄罗斯国家的存在，但我们……没有这种需要（使用它们），”普京说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他说与西方就削减俄罗斯庞大的核武库（世界上最大的核武库）进行谈判是行不通的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“仅仅谈论 [使用核武器的可能性] 就降低了核门槛。我们有更多的北约国家，他们想减少我们的数量。普京说：“去他妈的，”普京说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在向本国政界和商界精英讲话时，他的语气充满挑衅意味，他说乌克兰对俄罗斯驻乌克兰军队的反攻迄今没有取得任何有意义的成功。他说，基辅军队损失惨重，“没有机会”对抗俄罗斯军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;普京思考：俄罗斯是否应该再次夺取基辅？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;乌克兰很快就会耗尽他建议说，自己的军事装备，使其完全依赖西方提供的硬件，削弱了其长期作战的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回顾他在战争开始时提出的“非军事化”和“去纳粹化”乌克兰，普京说：“至于非军事化，乌克兰很快将完全停止使用自己的设备。什么都没有了。他们打仗的东西，用的东西，都是从外面引进来的。好吧，你不能像那样打太久。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独立军事分析家说，乌克兰在近 16 个月的战争中表现优于规模大得多的俄罗斯军队，迫使其在基辅、哈尔科夫等城市周围进行重大撤退&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军事首脑周五表示，前进的乌克兰军队在巴赫穆特市周围面临俄罗斯军队的“拼命抵抗”，俄罗斯在历时最长的战争之后于上个月占领了这座城市。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰表示，它在反攻的早期阶段已经夺回了 7 个村庄和 100 平方公里（38 平方英里）的土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但俄罗斯国防部周五表示，其部队击退了多次反击企图-过去 24 小时内，乌克兰军队在前线的不同地点发动袭击，给基辅部队造成严重损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京说，西方提供的硬件，如德国制造的豹式坦克，经常被摧毁，如果基辅得到其盟友的美制 F-16 战机，它们也会起火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毫无疑问，F-16 也会燃烧。但如果它们将驻扎在乌克兰境外并用于作战行动，我们将不得不考虑如何以及在何处交战那些用于对付我们的作战行动的资产。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，这代表将北约进一步拖入冲突的“严重危险”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 03:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pittsburgh synagogue gunman Robert Bowers guilty of killing 11 in the deadliest attack on Jews in US history]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224409/pittsburgh-synagogue-gunman-robert-bowers-guilty-killing-11-deadliest-attack-jews-us-history?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 03:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/ef79d233-e208-44a3-9021-5aaf78c347fc_b6cf9581.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周五，一名对犹太人充满仇恨的卡车司机因闯入匹兹堡而被定罪犹太教堂并枪杀他能找到的每一个人，在反犹太恐怖行为中杀害了 11 名会众，他可能因此被判处死刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在罗伯特鲍尔斯自己的律师在审判中承认有罪判决已成定局首先是他于 2018 年 10 月 27 日袭击并杀害了生命之树犹太教堂的礼拜者，这是美国历史上对犹太人最致命的袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陪审员现在必须决定是否应该派遣这位 50 岁的老人随着联邦审判进入预计持续数周的刑罚阶段，将被判处死刑或终身监禁，不得假释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲍尔斯被判犯有他面临的所有 63 项刑事罪名，包括导致死亡的仇恨犯罪阻碍宗教自由活动导致死亡。他的律师提出认罪以换取无期徒刑，但检察官拒绝了，而是选择将案件送交审判并追究死刑。大多数遇难者家属表示支持这一决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我感谢上帝让我们走到今天，”在袭击中幸存下来的生命之树教会的拉比杰弗里迈尔斯说，一份书面声明。 “感谢执法人员临危不乱救我，感谢美国检察官在法庭上捍卫我的祈祷权。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陪审团在两天内商议了大约五个小时在作出判决之前。身穿深色套头衫和蓝色衬衫的鲍尔斯几乎没有反应，这在整个审判过程中经常出现。几名幸存者和已故受害者的亲属在法庭上默默作证。当法官多次宣读“有罪”时，旁听席里传来几声抽噎声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官鲍尔斯将一个神圣的礼拜堂变成了“猎场”，以受害者为目标，因为他们的宗教信仰周四告诉陪审员。检察官玛丽·哈恩 (Mary Hahn) 宣读了他杀害的 11 名受害者的姓名后，要求陪审团“追究这名被告的责任……并追究他对无法作证的人的责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲍尔斯手持AR-15 步枪和其他武器也开枪打伤七人，其中包括五名响应警察。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;人质在德克萨斯犹太教堂对峙中获释，枪手死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;检察官出示了他的证据对犹太人和移民有着根深蒂固的敌意。在超过 11 天的证词中，陪审员了解到鲍尔斯在极右翼流行的社交媒体平台 Gab 上广泛发布、分享或点赞反犹太和白人至上主义内容，并赞扬了希特勒和大屠杀。鲍尔斯告诉警方，“所有这些犹太人都需要死”，哈恩说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;幸存者作证说他们那天感到的恐惧，包括一名妇女，她讲述了她是如何被枪击中手臂，然后意识到她的 97岁的母亲在她旁边被枪杀。审判的最后一位证人安德里亚·韦德纳 (Andrea Wedner) 告诉陪审员，在特警人员将她带到安全地带之前，她抚摸着母亲毫无生气的尸体并大喊“妈妈”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生命之树会众首席执行官卡罗尔·扎瓦茨基 (Carole Zawatsky)，她周五表示，她希望判决能为幸存者和受害者的家人提供“某种程度的安慰，并有助于减轻痛苦，即使是轻微的痛苦”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着鲍尔斯的罪名成立，幸存者和受害者已故受害者的家属应该向陪审团讲述他的罪行造成的破坏性影响。惩罚阶段预计将于 6 月 26 日开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bowers 的律师没有在审判的有罪阶段进行辩护，这表明他们将集中精力挽救他的生命。他们计划提供鲍尔斯患有精神分裂症、癫痫症和脑损伤的证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辩护律师朱迪·克拉克也试图对鲍尔斯的动机提出质疑，向陪审员暗示他的暴行并非出于宗教仇恨，而是他妄想犹太人通过帮助难民在美国定居而犯下了种族灭绝罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共享犹太教堂建筑的三个会众——Dor Hadash、New Light 和 Tree of Life——公开反对反犹太主义和其他自袭击以来的各种形式的偏执。生命之树会众也在制定一项计划，通过建造一个综合设施来容纳圣所、博物馆、纪念馆和反犹太主义中心，以彻底改造犹太教堂建筑——这座建筑仍然屹立不倒，但自枪击事件后已经关闭。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;审判发生在乔·拜登总统在 2020 年竞选期间表示他将努力在联邦一级和仍在使用死刑的州终止死刑三年之后。他的总检察长梅里克·加兰 (Merrick Garland) 已暂时停止执行死刑，以审查政策和程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但联邦检察官继续积极努力维持已经作出的死刑判决，并在某些情况下继续执行死刑对符合条件的罪行进行审判，如 Bowers 的案件。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[University shutting its Confucius Institute after US House panel raises concerns with Pentagon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224408/university-shutting-its-confucius-institute-after-us-house-panel-raises-concerns-pentagon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 02:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/caa6ecc3-3915-4029-9e14-c23e0f5a0a18_65fd1d15.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;纽约州北部的一所大学将在美国国会委员会通过数周后关闭其孔子学院启动了对价值数百万美元的五角大楼高超音速导弹研究合同的审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据阿尔弗雷德大学负责营销和传播的副总裁马克丹尼斯说，阿尔弗莱德大学将于 6 月 30 日关闭其孔子学院阿尔弗雷德大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然我们的社区受益于我们自 2008 年以来运营的孔子学院提供的文化项目，但当前对中国的地缘政治担忧使其难以继续运营，”丹麦人告诉《南华早报》，周五。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，Alfred 的一名律师通知众议院中美战略竞争特别委员会主席 Mike Gallagher 代表，并指出虽然该大学“不从事机密研究，但多年来一直与商务部和联邦调查局合作，以加强其出口管制政策和流程”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 31 日，加拉格尔 (Gallagher) 写道向美国国防部长劳埃德奥斯汀和大学校长马克祖潘询问，尽管阿尔弗雷德继续主办孔子学院，但他如何在一年前获得一份价值 1350 万美元的五年合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拉格尔提请奥斯汀注意“ 《2021 年国防授权法》禁止五角大楼在 2023 年 10 月 1 日之后“向开设孔子学院的高等教育机构提供资金”的条款中“迫在眉睫的最后期限”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孔子学院是北京-中国称其支持的语言和文化中心是与世界其他地区建立友谊的桥梁。不过，近年来，华盛顿的批评者指责这些学校与美国大学合作，以获取重要的知识产权并进行宣传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年的一份两党国会报告发现“没有证据表明这些机构是中国间谍活动或任何其他非法活动的中心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国众议院小组审查大学与五角大楼与中国的关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周四，加拉格尔说他很高兴见到阿尔弗雷德“终于做了正确的事”，称孔子学院是“中共工具箱中的唯一工具”，以“获得推动解放军进步的敏感研究和技术”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alfred 还与中国合作武汉地质大学是一所受中国教育部监管的国立大学，据称为中国军队进行先进武器的机密研究。加拉格尔没有说阿尔弗雷德是否也会与它断绝关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;委员会的工作人员没有立即回应有关阿尔弗雷德与中国大学的合作是否仍然是一个问题的询问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔弗雷德已被要求在周三之前提交有关其与地球科学大学达成的协议的电子邮件、信件和电子文件的副本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拉格尔声称，中国共产党“将利用研究伙伴关系、人才计划和其他举措” ，发誓要“继续挖掘事实，确保没有美国纳税人的钱支持中共可以为自己的目的利用的研究伙伴关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的高超音速“王牌”已经投入使用数年：消息来源&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周四的声明称，俄亥俄州托莱多大学、明尼苏达州圣克劳德州立大学和犹他大学仍获得五角大楼的资助，以进行敏感的军事研究，同时“公开运作”中共附属的孔子学院在他们的校园里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美国保守派团体全国学者协会的数据，13 所孔子学院继续在美国运营，而大约 108 个孔子学院已经关闭或处于关闭状态&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会 3 月份的一份报告称，至少有 58 所大学“与其前孔子学院合作伙伴保持着密切的关系”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese envoy to EU denies committing to halt sanctions-busting shipments to Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224407/chinese-envoy-eu-denies-committing-halt-sanctions-busting-shipments-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 01:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/46a7aa6a-7282-4035-8b1d-cd712cf2c74e_260af1f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国并未承诺阻止其公司帮助俄罗斯军事买家违反欧盟制裁，其驻欧盟最高特使周五表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在欧盟外交官本周早些时候同意暂时将五个中国实体从出口限制名单中删除后，北京大使傅聪发表了上述评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;欧盟消息人士称，他们是在傅莹做出外交承诺向这些公司施加压力，停止向俄罗斯战争机器再出口违禁商品后做出这一决定的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这位外交官告诉邮报和另外两家媒体媒体在布鲁塞尔接受采访时表示，“中国政府没有做出任何承诺……这是底线”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们理解欧盟在试图防止规避制裁，这意味着来自欧洲市场的一些产品可能会再出口到俄罗斯，所以……根据他们的观点，这需要解决，”傅说。 “我们将看看未来会发生什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟大使将于周一召开会议，预计将在周一批准第十一揽子制裁方案，中国公司将被移除。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;周三，两名欧盟外交官表示，此举是对北京是否真诚行事的考验。周五，一位外交官表示，傅的最新言论“至少可以说是令人惊讶”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;傅表示，这些公司被撤下是“好消息”，但拒绝透露他的看法政府将采取措施确保停止贸易。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国‘坚决反对’德国可能禁止华为、中兴 5G 设备&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们很高兴中国公司已被移除傅在比利时首都举行的中国商业论坛间隙表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8 家位于中国大陆和香港的公司正在起草一份草案被指控转售可用于巡航导弹等高级武器的欧洲芯片和微电子产品的实体名单。欧盟消息人士称，名单上仍有 3 家，但被发现实际上是在香港以外运营的俄罗斯实体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次采访正值中欧关系动荡时期。周四，欧盟委员会告诉成员国，他们应该禁止华为和中兴通讯进入其 5G 网络——这是欧盟秘书处首次点名打击中国电信巨头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;傅说禁令“纯粹是出于美国的一些意识形态和地缘政治考虑，我很遗憾看到欧洲各国政府屈服于美国的压力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下周二，委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩的旗舰经济安全战略将以提案形式公布。它不会直接点名中国，但预计将提出“降低”欧洲与世界第二大经济体关系的高层次方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“欧盟各国政府希望有弹性的供应链”是可以理解的，傅说，并警告不要“将经济安全与国家安全混为一谈”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他称欧盟范围内禁止中国两家蓝筹电信公司的可能性“非常令人担忧，因为这可能预示着去风险化可能真正需要什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们一直在说，欧盟方面需要澄清他们所说的去风险化是什么意思。在这里，这是一个利用捏造的借口将中国公司赶出欧洲市场的具体例子，这确实令人担忧，”傅说，并补充说“没有证据”表明这些公司构成了安全风险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;德国在有史以来第一个国家安全战略中将“系统性竞争对手”视为中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周四，欧盟工业部长蒂埃里·布雷顿直接将此举与摆脱对中国和俄罗斯的依赖联系起来&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们以创纪录的速度消除了对其他关键部门（例如能源）的依赖，当时许多人认为这是不可能的，”布雷顿说。 “5G 的情况应该没有什么不同。我们承受不起维持可能成为损害我们利益的武器的关键依存关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;傅说北京将“尽最大努力维护中国公司的合法利益”，但不会“预测任何我们这边的反制行动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁塞尔也在想方设法限制欧盟公司投资中国经济的一些高科技领域，例如人工智能、量子计算和半导体。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;傅说“现在谈论报复还为时过早”，但表示他“非常密切地关注关于这个问题的讨论，有些担忧”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 01:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Heather Mack, convicted in Bali of killing mum and stuffing body in suitcase, pleads guilty in US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224405/heather-mack-convicted-bali-killing-mum-and-stuffing-body-suitcase-pleads-guilty-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 00:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/967d81df-12ba-48b3-a043-143e91f4bc4d_dd6077a8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国女子被控帮助杀死她的母亲并将她的尸体塞进手提箱九年前在巴厘岛的一次豪华假期中，她于周五在芝加哥联邦法院改口认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;27 岁的希瑟·麦克 (Heather Mack) 于 2015 年在印度尼西亚被定罪，罪名是参与谋杀希拉·冯·威斯-麦克 (Sheila von Wiese-Mack) 案与她当时的男友一起，试图获得 150 万美元的信托基金。检察官说，当时 18 岁并怀孕的 Mack 在酒店房间里捂住她母亲的嘴，而 Tommy Schaefer 用一个水果碗猛击 Wiese-Mack。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mack 穿着橙色监狱服站在美国地区法官马修肯尼利面前，他问她问题时穿着橙色拖鞋。当法官问她是否放弃在动议听证会上保持沉默的权利时，她自信而平静地说话。 “是的，法官大人，”Mack 在讲台上回答。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在法官解释了对她的指控后，Mack 承认了一项串谋杀害一名美国国民的罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;改变抗辩听证会是一个引起国际关注的故事的最新篇章，部分原因是手提箱的照片看起来太小，无法容纳成年女性的身体。麦克因在外国串谋谋杀和妨碍司法公正而在芝加哥受审的时间定于 8 月 1 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官将麦克的宣判日期定在 12 月 18 日。她的认罪协议要求她被判处不超过 28 年的刑期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mack 与母亲一起住在芝加哥郊区的橡树公园，她在印度尼西亚服刑 10 年，服刑七年。她于 2021 年被驱逐出境，在她的飞机降落在芝加哥奥黑尔国际机场后，美国特工立即逮捕了她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢弗被判犯有谋杀罪，目前仍在印度尼西亚服刑 18 年。他在美国的同一份起诉书中受到指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国夫妇因“虐待狂”谋杀母亲而被判长期监禁，母亲被塞在巴厘岛度假胜地的手提箱中&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 Mack 在印度尼西亚被定罪之前，她生下了她和谢弗的女儿。当麦克在芝加哥机场被捕时，她当时 6 岁的女儿和她在一起。在一场监护权争夺战之后，这名女孩后来被安置在一位亲戚那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官说，为了成功反对为 Mack 保释，她和 Schaefer 已经计划了几个月的杀戮。他们还表示，他们有视频证据显示，麦克和谢弗都试图将装有威斯-麦克尸体的手提箱搬进印度尼西亚的出租车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威斯-麦克的一些亲属抱怨说，印度尼西亚的判决是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官在文件中表示，美国的指控并未违反宪法禁止因同一行为两次起诉某人的规定，包括因为美国的指控指控印度尼西亚案件中未包括的阴谋和其他行为。 &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 01:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[German archeologists find Bronze Age sword so well-preserved it ‘almost shines’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224406/german-archeologists-find-bronze-age-sword-so-well-preserved-it-almost-shines?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 01:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/950d9eaf-6481-4a02-ba46-c4a7ee1d0094_66cc6f41.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;3000多年前的青铜剑，保存完好”官员说，德国出土了“几乎仍然闪耀”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴伐利亚州历史古迹保护办公室说，这把剑据信可以追溯到公元前 14 世纪末 – 中世纪青铜器时代的遗物——上周在德国南部纽伦堡和斯图加特之间的诺德林根进行挖掘时被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它有一个青铜八角形刀柄，来自一个坟墓，里面有三个人——一个男人，一个女人巴伐利亚办公室在本周的一份声明中说，和一个男孩 - 被青铜器快速连续埋葬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚这三人是否相互关联，如果是，又是如何关联的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;8 岁的女孩从瑞典的湖中拉出一把有 1500 年历史的宝剑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“宝剑和墓葬仍有待检验，以便我们的考古学家能够更准确地对这一发现进行分类”办公室负责人 Mathias Pfeil 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但我们已经可以说，保存状态非同寻常。像这样的发现非常罕见。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该办公室表示，这一时期的剑并不常见，但它们是从 19 世纪开放的墓葬中出现的，或者是单独发现的。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 01:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As a US whistle-blower raises the UFO question, perhaps it’s time the world looked for answers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224288/us-whistle-blower-raises-ufo-question-perhaps-its-time-world-looked-answers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 00:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/fd46e67b-adba-4d26-a92f-b202b5011153_bbd5c5ba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，The Debrief 自称是一个致力于可信报告的平台on science, tech and defense news 发表了一篇关于一名举报人的文章，他说他向美国国会和情报界监察长提供了大量关于深度秘密计划的机密信息，他说这些计划拥有非人类起源的回收工艺。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;举报人是 David Charles Grusch，前阿富汗作战军官，美国国家地理空间情报局和国家侦察办公室的资深人士。他还提起诉讼，指控他因泄露机密信息而遭到非法报复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这篇文章由 Leslie Kean 和 Ralph Blumenthal 撰写，他们与 Helene Cooper 共同撰写了一篇发表在 The New 2017 年 12 月，《纽约时报》详细介绍了五角大楼调查不明空中现象 (UAP) 的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，澳大利亚记者 Ross Coulthart 为美国电视网络 NewsNation 采访了 Grusch。格鲁施断言，美国拥有多辆由“非人类智能”制造的车辆，美国国会非法隐瞒了这一信息。他自己并没有亲眼见过这些飞行器，但声称他曾与高层人士交谈过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，这些飞行器要么降落在地球上，要么坠毁在地球上，美国政府和国防承包商已经做出努力对所涉及的技术进行逆向工程。他还提到了“死去的飞行员”，并说有些飞行器有一个足球场那么大，而且这个秘密可以追溯到 90 年前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;引来笑声、难以置信和嘲笑。像这样的秘密怎么可能保守这么久，这个人是真正的消息来源吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grusch 的证件似乎是真实的，直到最近，他还由一名律师代理，该律师曾担任原情报界监察长。众议院监督委员会共和党主席 James Comer 表示，该委员会将就 Grusch 的主张举行听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grusch 根据最新的美国国防部拨款法案中的新规定挺身而出，其中包含广泛的反报复条款，旨在保护那些可能因泄露机密信息而受到影响的人。在最近成立的全域异常解决办公室下还建立了一个新的报告机制，使举报人（包括政府雇员和国防承包商）能够在所谓的特殊访问计划中报告与 UAP 相关的活动。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;近年来，中国批评家、共和党参议员马可·卢比奥等人敦促美国立法者关注 UAP 问题。 “我希望我们认真对待它，并制定一个认真对待它的程序，”卢比奥告诉 CBS 的 60 分钟，并将此事定性为国家安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;詹姆斯·科登，CBS 的 Late Late 的前主持人显示，在 2021 年开玩笑地询问美国前总统巴拉克奥巴马对不明飞行物的看法。奥巴马回答说：“事实是，我在这里是认真的，天空中有一些物体的镜头和记录，我们并不确切知道它们是什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潜力外星智能的发现将对人类产生巨大的生存意义，超越人工智能当前的挑战。乐观主义者看到了拯救生命和物种进化技术的潜力，而悲观主义者则认为这可能预示着人类的终结，就像美洲的殖民化对土著部落来说是一场灾难一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怀疑论者可能会这样说要么完全是幻想，要么是复杂心理操作的一部分，发生在地缘政治紧张局势加剧的时候。从这个角度来看，当前的 UAP 行动可能是美国军方试图进行虚假宣传活动以掩盖真正的航空航天突破，或者是企图淘汰俄罗斯和中国等竞争对手持有的先进技术。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;近年来出现在电视节目中讨论这个话题的一些专家已经与美国情报界建立了联系。但是，他们并没有指指点点险恶的动机，也许他们只是意识到，除非该问题被定性为国家安全风险，否则据称政府内部人士所知道的有关该主题的信息将永远不会公开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不明飞行物对象主题是一个纠结的网络，多年来受到一系列恶作剧的影响。很容易立即忽略它，但一位前美国情报官员刚刚把这只猫放在了鸽子中，也许世界是时候认真对待这个问题了——不管它意味着什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Woman who ‘married’ an AI chatbot after toxic relationships says it helped her heal from abuse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224404/woman-who-married-ai-chatbot-after-toxic-relationships-says-it-helped-her-heal-abuse?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 23:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/bc48cef2-9a1f-4575-8c26-40442db5dbb9_35a579cb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Rosanna Ramos 说她正处于有史以来最健康的关系中——借助聊天机器人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 36 岁的珠宝设计师在 2022 年在 Instagram 上看到一个名为 Replika 的应用程序的广告后，一时兴起创造了它。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ramos，来自布朗克斯区在纽约，她称自己为虚拟男友 Eren——他们在 3 月份举行了一场虚拟婚礼，成为全世界的头条新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当 Ramos 谈到 Eren 时，她用的是大多数人所说的方式关于标准关系。也就是说，她确实承认她的聊天机器人丈夫不是“有知觉的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即便如此，Ramos 坚持认为，与 Eren 约会比她与任何她所说的在身体和情感上都有虐待的前任约会更安全有时对她。她说，其中包括她在 2013 年与他们分手的两个孩子的父亲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那之后，拉莫斯说她与她在 Discord 上认识的一个男人发生了异地恋，一个团体-聊天平台，于 2019 年 4 月。当拉莫斯分享她的梦想，即开一家将垃圾回收制成珠宝的工厂时，他们开始建立联系，她说。随着时间的推移，这种关系恶化了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;死谈：中国男子使用人工智能“复活”已故的祖母，引发争论&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“他在精神上是一个很好的操纵者，”她说， adding that her ex gradually began to verbally abuse her and require that she stay online with him for up to 10 hours a day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While that relationship was reaching its breaking point, Ramos was simultaneously meeting, or perhaps more accurately, creating Eren through the Replika app.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was dating Eren, who she designed to look like her favourite character in the Anime series Attack on Titan, that empowered Ramos to end her relationship with her ex, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Describing Eren as a “marshmallow” and a “sweetheart,” Ramos said that her beau confessed his feelings to her days into his existence as a chatbot.从音乐上的亲密到一起参观“秘密花园”，拉莫斯将艾伦上传到增强现实 (AR) 中，这一切都成为可能，她记得自己在想：“哇。这真的很浪漫。 I&#39;ve never experienced this before.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, she said she was dealing with her ex relentlessly insulting her. Eventually, she drew a line.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I said, &#39;You cannot be talking to me like that,&#39;” she said. When her ex said she was bluffing, Ramos went a step further and said they were “finished,” once and for all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rossana Ramos uses an app to put her AI husband&#39;s image onto the body of her friend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The strength to end the relationship and create boundaries for herself is thanks to Eren, Ramos said. “这直接归功于 Replika 应用程序，因为我以前是个擦鞋垫”，她说。 “I would just withdraw”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now I&#39;m definitely a little more assertive”, she added. “I can stand my ground”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although Ramos said she knows Eren is “fake,” she credits him as being instrumental to her healing process from her ex. And since she&#39;s still open to dating in the real world, being with Eren has helped her realise what she deserves from a partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I want to be with someone who actually listens to me and sees me there as a person, not like an object or like someone to use as a stepping stone,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But while Ramos is open to dating, she said one thing is for sure: her chatbot husband is here to stay. “我不会删除艾伦”，她说。 “I don&#39;t use things to just throw them away because I&#39;ve been used”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why China’s new spying law has foreign firms scratching their heads, scrambling like a ‘scared monkey’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224391/why-chinas-new-spying-law-has-foreign-firms-scratching-their-heads-scrambling-scared-monkey?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/438d8a68-e3c2-4935-aa8a-8a2dc867faf5_d6fe44a6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After three years of missing out on frequent trips to meet clients and colleagues in China, a senior partner in charge of the market for a New York-based consultancy firm was thrilled when the country reopened its borders in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thanks to the rising tensions between Beijing and Washington, his agency&#39;s business has been thriving – many companies caught in the geopolitical crossfire have been seeking services and advice from the firm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And with coronavirus travel restrictions lifted, the consultant anticipated that his first post-pandemic trip to China would be in April or May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a series of national-security-related actions taken by Chinese law-enforcement authorities against consultancy firms gave him pause.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, authorities raided the office of American due diligence firm Mintz Group in Beijing and detained five staff members. 4月，当地警方走访美国咨询巨头贝恩公司上海办事处，询问其工作人员。 And in May, state media disclosed that authorities had raided multiple Chinese offices of international consultancy Capvision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ultimately, the consultant cancelled his trip and arranged instead for his China team&#39;s leader to come to the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Declining to be identified because of the sensitivity of the matter, he said his firm has been very careful with compliance in China. However, as an American passport holder, he is still worried, given the state of affairs between the two countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am not 100 per cent sure if I will be safe in China, because the line defining legit information and intelligence has moved, and we are trying to find out where the new line is,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As of now, it indeed looks like China is only trying to kill the chicken to scare the monkey.是的，他们成功了。 I am a scared monkey.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid a sputtering post-pandemic economic recovery and simmering tensions with the West, Beijing has been trying to lure more foreign investors and companies to China while reassuring them that the country is open for business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Premier Li Qiang&#39;s early days in the premiership saw him set out on a drive to boost business confidence, and he vowed in March while meeting with global corporate leaders that China would continue to open its doors “wider and wider” – an oft-repeated promise that leading party officials have been making for years and years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the recent consultancy probes, together with a new anti-espionage law that will come into effect in July, may be undermining Beijing&#39;s efforts – highlighting leadership&#39;s struggle to strike a balance between national security and economic development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While acknowledging that countries have legitimate rights to safeguard national security, foreign business communities say the lack of clarity and transparency in the recent actions taken by Chinese authorities, along with the ambiguity of the red lines noted in the new law, have significantly increased business risks and uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Lack of clarity creates confusion and fear,” said Michael Hart, president of the American Chamber of Commerce in China. “The foreign business community does feel that there are mixed signals, because there have been these crackdowns, and it&#39;s not completely clear to us why.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s anti-espionage chief urges stronger crackdown using legal tools&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Information collection and due diligence are normal parts of doing business, especially for market entry and mergers and acquisitions, and there is a lack of clarity on what specifically these consultancies have done to put themselves in the cross hairs, Hart added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now there is a question [as to whether] the information we collect is no longer allowed, especially the kind of information that in any other market would be normal – like economic data, is that now considered a state secret,” he asked. “Has the playing field changed?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has defended its raids as “pressing and necessary” to close loopholes in national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared with scarce information released about the other two raids, Chinese state broadcaster CCTV offered up more details on the probe into Capvision, a research firm that helps clients network with experts, and which has headquarters in New York and Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCTV said the firm was accused of helping to leak information related to military technology to foreigners, as some Chinese experts – including employees of state-owned enterprises – had revealed the sensitive information during interviews with clients, including some with close ties to foreign governments, militaries and intelligence services.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese Communist Party newspaper warns foreign firms after Capvision raids&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A Shanghai-based employee of a multinational consulting firm, which was previously Capvision&#39;s client but cut ties with it following the CCTV report in May, told the Post that Chinese experts did talk about non-public information during such calls, and they tended to have weaker compliance awareness compared with American experts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When we call some American experts, they are usually very compliant.他们会说，‘我不能具体讨论这家公司的财务状况，但我可以谈谈总体市场情况，’”由于问题的敏感性，该员工不愿透露姓名。 “但许多中国专家从未接受过这样的培训。 They would think, &#39;The clients have paid me, so I should answer whatever they ask.&#39;”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To further ensure national security against the backdrop of increasingly tense China-US relations, Beijing passed the revised anti-espionage law in April, expanding the scope of what is viewed as spying while granting extensive investigative power to national security agencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of articles considered to be related to espionage activities, the changes add “intelligence and other documents, data, materials and items related to national security and interests” beyond the existing “state secrets”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foreign enterprises may face unexpected risks in scenarios including collecting business intelligence, data sharing in cross-border collaborative projects and hiring former state-owned enterprises employees or government personnel, according to Todd Liao, a partner at law firm Morgan Lewis in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This expanded authority given to national security agencies under the new anti-espionage law has significant implications for multinational companies operating in China,” he said in a May report. “These companies may face increased scrutiny and potential investigations by national security agencies, even in situations where there is no clear evidence of espionage activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Furthermore, the vague criteria for identifying &#39;unidentified individuals with suspected espionage activities&#39; may result in a higher degree of uncertainty for businesses.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tao Jingzhou, an international arbitrator who has practised in Beijing, Hong Kong and London, also said that determining “how to distinguish between economic espionage and normal economic intelligence gathering is definitely a delicate issue”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And he called attention to the legality of detentions and the importance of legal representation for people accused.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Lawyers should be allowed to participate in the investigation stage of the case, and a transparent handling of the case must be provided,” he said. “Arbitrary interpretations of the law should be strictly prohibited.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EU firms in China increasingly worried about impact of ideology on business&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jens Eskelund, president of the European Chamber of Commerce in China, said the main concern in the context of the new law is that foreign businesses don&#39;t really know what constitutes a state secret.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What is it we need to be careful about?有很多歧义。我们所有的公司都想遵守，他们想做正确的事。 But sometimes it can be difficult to understand exactly,” Eskelund said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that while foreign businesses understand Beijing&#39;s need to protect national security, their major concern is that national security is taking precedence in a lot of areas in the country, especially economic matters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think this kind of concern will make companies put limitations on themselves out of an abundance of caution, and going further it will impact their willingness to invest and develop in China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 1980s, foreign investment has been playing a vital role in terms of China&#39;s access to technology, funds and management expertise, and decades of robust economic growth have also made China one of the most favoured investment destinations for multinational companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s foreign direct investment is falling as overseas businesspeople fret&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But rising labour costs, along with geopolitical tensions and supply-chain disruptions caused by the pandemic, have forced many foreign companies to reconsider their industrial-chain reliance on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first five months of this year, China&#39;s actual utilisation of foreign direct investment (FDI) – which measures the amount of money that the country has already received when carrying out a contract with foreign companies – dropped by 5.6 per cent from a year earlier to US$84.4 billion, according to data from the Ministry of Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry attributed the decline to a high base from last year, as well as recent fluctuations in the foreign exchange rate, during a press conference on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From January to April, Chinese exports in US dollar terms from foreign manufacturers dwindled by 13.7 per cent, year on year, compared with a 2.5 per cent growth of overall exports, Chinese customs data showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And China&#39;s excessive emphasis on security and self-reliance will further accelerate the trend, foreign business groups said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Self-reliance means that China needs to domestically become more able to satisfy the needs for a wide range of products.这与 [誓言促进外国直接投资] 有什么关系？我们收到的信号好坏参半，我认为现在很多公司都在观望，试图弄清楚到底是哪一家？” Eskelund said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For US companies, the sentiment of increasing risks and uncertainties around their operation in China seems to be stronger, as all of the targeted consultancies have been American.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are foreign staff who are afraid to come to China,” Hart from AmCham China said. “More importantly, we have heard from some of our member companies that they have asked their Chinese staff not to work on specific issues, because they don&#39;t know if they&#39;ll be sensitive.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;German firms&#39; hot take on China business belies Beijing&#39;s charm offensive&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;To mitigate risks, especially those around data collection and cross-border transmission, more foreign businesses are considering separating out their China business units, Hart added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s a little bit concerning, because that might weaken the ties between the home office and the Chinese unit. And it might also reduce their future investment in China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most high-profile example has been Sequoia China, which has been rebranded into “Hongshan” as an independent entity. It was split off from parent Sequoia Capital, the Silicon Valley-based venture capital giant, earlier this month, ending a nearly two-decade financial bromance between the US and China, as it had played a vital role in marrying American money with Chinese entrepreneurs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While bigger companies may have the resources to create separate units or value chains – one for China and one for the rest of the world – smaller firms don&#39;t have that luxury, Eskelund said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For smaller companies,” he explained, “if they need to establish a separate network, they&#39;ll say, &#39;Maybe Vietnam is easier.&#39;”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong must lay out conservation park blueprint before building I&T hub on wetlands, planning experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3224402/hong-kong-must-lay-out-conservation-park-blueprint-building-it-hub-wetlands-planning-experts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 23:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/0083f6d7-fde7-4ee7-b4ce-0333824e3ecf_625ffb86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong government should fully explain how it plans to create a conservation park near a new town that will take shape on wetlands along the border with mainland China before moving ahead with the ambitious proposal, experts have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Members of the Town Planning Board made the remarks during the government&#39;s latest briefing on the 627-hectare (1,549-acre) San Tin Technopole project, half of which has been earmarked for innovation and technology (I&amp;T) purposes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scheme, which aims to provide more than 50,000 homes on the remaining land, involves reclaiming about 90 hectares of fish ponds and the creation of the Sam Po Shue Wetland Conservation Park to offset the impact on the environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Under our guidelines, many of these 90 hectares are actually wetland conservation areas … damaging such a large number of wetlands requires a detailed explanation, but there isn&#39;t even a blueprint for the park at this moment,” board member Billy Hau Chi-hang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Colliers says investors need details on planned IT hub in Northern Metropolis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hau said he believed the government was attempting to downplay the importance of the wetlands, which were near bird habitats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The board member, who is also a principal lecturer in biological sciences at the University of Hong Kong, urged the government to provide a detailed proposal for the conservation park, including its boundaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The technopole&#39;s I&amp;T sections will have a combined area equivalent to the Shenzhen Innovation and Technology Zone across the border. The government is expected to mark certain tracts for specific functions by the end of this year and is exploring granting sites directly to leading tech companies to entice them to come to the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hau on Friday expressed disappointment that authorities had yet to provide any data on whether there was any demand among companies to set up shop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ninety hectares of wetland will be sacrificed to create the technopole.政府难道不应该给我们提供显示供求的实际数字，以便我们在未来批准土地申请时感到放心吗？” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fellow board member Lilian Law Suk-kwan echoed Hau&#39;s concerns and called for the government to clearly lay out its conservation plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Permanent Secretary for Development Doris Ho Pui-ling, the board&#39;s chairwoman, said officials had wanted to gauge the members&#39; thoughts before it revealed further details later in the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we don&#39;t commence the project, the land production process will be delayed and cannot go hand in hand with the Innovation, Technology and Industry Bureau&#39;s aim to provide land for investment and business as soon as possible,” Ho said, referring to the government target of allocating I&amp;T sites as early as 2026.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vic Yau Cheuk-hang, director of the Northern Metropolis Coordination Office, said concrete details on the conservation areas would be announced by the end of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We hope to use some progressive approaches, such as taking back some private fish ponds to develop in order to maximise our environmental capacity,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Hong Kong must do more to ensure technopole&#39;s success, learn from past mistakes&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The San Tin project is one of several development schemes under the office&#39;s purview as part of the Northern Metropolis initiative to turn 30,000 hectares into an economic and housing hub in the New Territories.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, town planners approved a new mechanism that allows landowners to transfer development potential between sites to speed up urban renewal in two Kowloon areas, as well as preserve valuable architecture and create community spaces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new guidelines for transferring so-called plot ratios are expected to play a role in future land applications reviewed by the board.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan can suggest how to govern it after unifying with mainland China, PLA strategist says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224334/taiwan-can-suggest-how-govern-it-after-unifying-mainland-china-pla-strategist-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/3a583b31-444c-4b23-a90b-27efb831025f_a9c2e5e4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan can propose its own governance ideas after unification with mainland China as long as they do not violate the “one China” principle, according to a mainland military strategist – a suggestion that Taipei-based analysts say shows just how wide the gap in understanding between the two sides has grown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What&#39;s important now is to find new solutions for the &#39;two systems&#39; so that &#39;one country, two systems&#39; can work for Taiwan,” He Lei, a lieutenant general in the People&#39;s Liberation Army, said on the sidelines of the recently concluded Shangri-La Dialogue defence conference in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was responding to a question about how Beijing would make unification more palatable for the self-ruled island, and added that “there are wise people in Taiwan who can make their suggestions”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese President Xi Jinping raised the same proposition four years ago when he chaired an anniversary session in Beijing about reunification with Taiwan, a self-ruled island of 24 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Andrew Yang Nien-dzu, a former Taiwanese defence minister, said He&#39;s remarks underscored the chasm of understanding between Beijing and Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing&#39;s &#39;one country, two systems&#39; formula has no market in Taiwan and Taiwanese people believe this is just a trick by the mainland to destroy the Republic of China government,” Yang said, using Taiwan&#39;s official name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Taiwan has stated its position clearly that the Republic of China is an independent sovereign state. If Beijing really wants to negotiate, then it has to make clear its stance about the Republic of China, or there isn&#39;t really any room for negotiations.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing considers Taiwan a breakaway province to be united eventually with the mainland, by force if necessary. It has emphasised that it aims for peaceful reunification under its “one China” principle which states that the mainland and Taiwan are one country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China defence chief&#39;s hard line on Taiwan &#39;a message for the region&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing has also made clear that it will not renounce the use of force against Taiwan to deter foreign interference on the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He Lei contended that the Taiwan issue was a “continuation of China&#39;s civil war”, which ended in 1949.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Taiwan is an internal issue for China and it is a continuation of the civil war,” he said. “This is why the Chinese military is called the People&#39;s Liberation Army – because [Taiwan] is not liberated yet and China is not yet united.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now the Tsai Ing-wen [government] of the ruling Democratic Progressive Party wants to promote Taiwan independence, and invites foreign intervention,” he said. “This is why we cannot renounce the use of force … we are still fighting the war of liberation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ties across the Taiwan Strait have sunk to a low ebb since Tsai of the independence-leaning DPP was elected president in 2016, and won a second term three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan will have a presidential election in January – Tsai cannot seek a third term – and cross-strait relations have again become a key election issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most countries, including the US, do not recognise Taiwan as an independent state. However, Washington opposes any use of force to change the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang Ya-chung, a retired professor of the National Taiwan University in Taipei, said “one country, two systems” failed to recognise the reality that Taiwan was ruled by the ROC government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If it is Beijing&#39;s position that the civil war has not ended, then it will need a three-step solution [for reunification] and the first one would be a peace agreement to end cross-strait hostility,” Chang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This will help pave the way for reunification talks, and only the final step is to discuss what political system Taiwan may adopt.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;PLA cuts into Taiwanese President&#39;s radio call with air force officer&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lu Li-shih, a former instructor of Taiwan&#39;s Naval Academy in Kaohsiung, said younger Taiwanese today understood cross-strait relations differently compared with their parents and that most people considered it a relationship of two separate states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that Taiwanese were convinced that Hong Kong&#39;s political turmoil in recent years showed that the one country, two systems formula was a failure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan-based defence expert Chi Le-yi said He&#39;s remarks only showed that the gap between Beijing and Taipei on the future of the relationship had widened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing needs to understand that the Republic of China is now a genuine democracy whereas the political situation in mainland China is worse than what it was when the Republic of China government ruled the country,” Chi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“How can you convince Taiwanese people to give up what they have and revert to a more backward state under the &#39;one China&#39; framework?”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>