<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China steps in with vocational school overhaul and 11 ‘key tasks’ to help boost self-sufficiency and tech prowess]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228137/china-steps-vocational-school-overhaul-and-11-key-tasks-help-boost-self-sufficiency-and-tech-prowess?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/18/61392c0e-0016-4c2e-a433-824d047e916f_cda50fef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;教育当局表示，中国支持和发展职业教育的方式需要进行全国性改革由于熟练工程师和蓝领工人的短缺正在阻碍国家的产业升级和经济发展，培训体系尤其是战略性行业的培训体系受到了限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为此，教育主管部门发布了一份清单，其中包含 11 个“关键岗位”任务”供地方当局基本上用作职业培训路线图，并且每年都会仔细监测其进展情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中短期内，地方政府的任务是弥合桥梁教育部周一在网上发布的声明称，职业学校与工业企业和研究机构合作，以更好地适应市场需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“教育部将在先进轨道交通等五个领域设立区域试点项目工信部表示，“装备、航空航天装备、船舶及海洋工程装备、新材料、兵器工业”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国“脱节”的职业体系能否填补蓝领空缺？&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;该通知多次提及 2025 年的多项目标，但该计划似乎更像是一项开放式、渐进式的任务，具有渐进的里程碑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还强调了北京将如何介入，以实现不超过 2025 年的目标。不仅可以培养足够的高技能工人来填补制造业和技术领域的巨大缺口，而且还可以确保他们的学位不会随着国家从“中国制造”向“中国设计”的转变而浪费。经济更加发达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科技进步在应对中国少子化和人口老龄化问题上也发挥着越来越重要的作用，专家表示，劳动力素质的提高在一定程度上可以&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工信部表示，还将指导在先进制造业、高新技术产业等重点行业和领域建立首批产学研结合共同体，包括机械工具和机器人、能源电子、生物医药等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了更好地适应产业转型和革命，教育体系还应加强核心课程、教学设备、师资、数据库、公告称，教育部还将引进更多国外优质教育资源，扩大留学生和培训项目规模，拓宽国际合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其目标是“系统打造一批具有中国特色的国际知名职业教育品牌，包括境外教育项目、海外职业技术学院”，以及“培养一批高素质职业教育师资队伍”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到2025年，中国计划支持300所左右具有鲜明中国特色的职业学校.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;就业岗位少，工资低：中国职业院校毕业生面临现实检验&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;广东省改革研究会执行主席彭鹏，广东省改革研究会是与省政府有联系的智库，指出，随着越来越多的本科层次职业学院的建立，质量也在不断提高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“广东华商学院正在与诺贝尔奖获得者合作建立实验室；尤其是广东华立学院，战略性地将校区选址在开发区附近或开发区内，直接服务当地企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一方面，这些高职院校与市场紧密结合，使得更容易促进产学研合作。另一方面，它们也在国际合作中经历着转型，尽管这种进展不可能一蹴而就。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2016年以来，至少有20个被称为鲁班工坊的中国支持的职业培训中心在中国开设。 19 个国家。通过职业培训，中国为制造业、建筑业、农业和科技等各个领域提供技术专长、知识转移和能力建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对外开放职业教育，吸引外国专家相对容易，但中国职业教育走出去更具挑战性。”一位政府支持的智库的顶尖教育研究员不愿透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国家正在制定一个建设教育强国的规划纲要，各部门正在制定详细的发展规划。” “然而，其中一些计划可能会不经意间落入以口号和陈词滥调的形式追求短期、表面政治成就的陷阱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上述领域和行业所需的人才远远超出他补充道，技术教育体系可以培养什么。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Meta makes ChatGPT rival Llama open source as it guns for OpenAI and Google, but it is not trained on Facebook data]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3228171/meta-makes-chatgpt-rival-llama-open-source-it-guns-openai-and-google-it-not-trained-facebook-data?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 10:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/915b92bf-7fb7-435c-8b76-2bdb56ca9f91_18b9fedb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Facebook 母公司 Meta Platforms 构建了一个可与 ChatGPT 等产品相媲美的人工智能系统和谷歌的巴德，但它采取了不同的方法：免费发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 首席执行官马克·扎克伯格周二表示，该公司正在与微软合作推出下一代 AI 大语言模型，并开发该技术，被称为 Llama 2，免费用于研究和商业用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像科技同行谷歌和微软一样，这家社交媒体公司长期以来拥有一支由计算机科学家组成的大型研究团队，致力于推进人工智能技术。但随着 ChatGPT 的发布引发了人们热衷于从“生成式人工智能”工具中获利，这些工具可以创建新的散文、图像和其他媒体，它的光芒已经黯然失色。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国电子商务巨头京东推出了自己的大型网站语言模型 ChatRhino&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meta 还试图通过比一些大型科技竞争对手更加开放的方式来脱颖而出，让人们可以查看其用于构建人工智能系统的数据和代码。有人认为，这种开放性使外部研究人员更容易帮助识别和减轻人工智能系统通过吸收真实人们的写作和交流方式而产生的偏见和毒性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开源推动创新，因为它使更多的开发人员可以使用新技术进行开发，”扎克伯格在周二的 Facebook 帖子中表示。 “它还提高了安全性，因为当软件开放时，更多的人可以仔细检查它以识别和修复潜在问题。我相信，如果生态系统更加开放，它将带来更多进步，这就是我们开源 Llama 2 的原因。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扎克伯格指出了 Meta 开源其人工智能工作的历史，例如其广泛使用的机器学习框架 PyTorch 的开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，介绍新模型的研究论文反映出的开放性不如 Meta 之前在其工作中所表现出的开放性，即构建需要摄取大量数字化著作的模型，例如书籍、新闻文章和社交媒体提要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它表示最新模型是根据“来自公开来源的新数据组合进行训练的，其中不包括来自 Meta 产品或服务的数据”，但并没有指定使用了什么数据。它确实说 Meta 从已知包含“大量有关私人个人信息”的网站中删除了数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 使用缩写 LLaMA（大型语言模型 Meta AI）来描述第一个版本其型号于二月份公布。现在，它的第二个版本 Llama 2 去掉了大写字母。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扎克伯格表示，人们可以直接下载其新的人工智能模型，也可以通过合作伙伴关系下载，这些模型可以在微软的云平台 Azure 上使用，“同时还有微软的安全性和安全性”。内容工具”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该合作伙伴关系的财务条款并未披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然 Meta 将 Microsoft 描述为“首选”合作伙伴，但 Meta 表示这些模型也将通过以下方式提供：微软主要的云竞争对手 Amazon Web Services，以及人工智能初创公司 Hugging Face 等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微软还是 ChatGPT 制造商 OpenAI 的主要资助者和合作伙伴。 ChatGPT 以及 Microsoft 或 Google 的类似产品都不是开源的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微软和 Meta 还在周二面向企业客户的微软年度活动中透露了新的人工智能合作伙伴关系。微软在另一份声明中表示，两家公司“共同致力于人工智能及其好处的民主化，我们很高兴 Meta 采取开放的方式。” Meta 已经是微软 Azure 云计算平台的客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微软还利用名为 Inspire 的虚拟活动透露，它将向企业收取其旗舰生成式 AI 的每位用户每月 30 美元的费用在这些组织已经为 Microsoft 服务付费的基础上，还提供了 Microsoft 365 Copilot 工具。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China says AI should not become a ‘runaway horse’ as UN Security Council holds first meeting on tech risks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228169/china-says-ai-should-not-become-runaway-horse-un-security-council-holds-first-meeting-tech-risks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/aec3498a-1911-4131-9e6a-dcb4ae14e536_f0d5badd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国安理会周二举行首次人工智能会议，中国表示这项技术不应该成为“脱缰之马”，美国警告不要使用它来审查或镇压人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国外交大臣詹姆斯·克莱弗利 (James Cleverly) 在伦敦担任该机构 7 月份主席期间主持了这次会议，他表示人工智能将“从根本上改变人类生活的方方面面。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们迫切需要塑造变革性技术的全球治理，因为人工智能无国界，”他在表示人工智能可以帮助解决气候变化和促进经济。但他也警告说，这项技术会助长虚假信息，并可能帮助国家和非国家行为者寻求武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯、杰克·克拉克等人向由 15 名成员组成的委员会通报了情况。 -备受瞩目的人工智能初创公司 Anthropic 创始人、中英人工智能伦理与治理研究中心联席主任曾毅教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;世界首届全球人工智能监管峰会会“被冻结”吗？ &#39; 来自亚洲的公司？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯说：“人工智能的军事和非军事应用都可能对全球和平与安全产生非常严重的后果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯支持一些国家的呼吁仿照国际原子能机构、国际民用航空组织或政府间气候变化专门委员会的模式，建立一个新的联合国机构，“支持管理这一非凡技术的集体努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国联合国大使张军将人工智能描述为一把“双刃剑”，并表示北京支持联合国在制定人工智能指导原则方面发挥核心协调作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论是好还是坏、善还是恶取决于人类如何利用它、如何规范它、如何平衡科学发展与安全。”张说，并补充说，应该以人和人工智能为好，来规范发展，“防止这项技术成为脱缰之马”。 .”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国驻联合国副大使杰弗里·德劳伦蒂斯也表示，各国还需要在人工智能和其他新兴技术方面开展合作，以应对威胁破坏和平与安全的人权风险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何成员国都不应使用人工智能来审查、约束、镇压或剥夺人民的权力，”他对理事会说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯质疑负责维护国际和平的理事会是否应该这样做俄罗斯副联合国代表表示：“我们需要的是一场专业、科学、基于专业知识的讨论，这可能需要数年时间，而且这种讨论已经在专门平台上进行。”德米特里·波利安斯基大使。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand-China relations: Wellington’s ‘weakest link’ image in focus as Western allies pursue hawkish line on Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3228136/new-zealand-china-relations-wellingtons-weakest-link-image-focus-western-allies-pursue-hawkish-line?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/18/0ef39c29-c768-4b08-afc9-988044162c69_4185ff6a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，随着惠灵顿的到来，新西兰对中国的和解态度正日益受到威胁新西兰总理克里斯·希普金斯(Chris Hipkins)在上个月访问北京之前，缓和了对侵犯人权、台湾紧张局势和中国大陆问题的批评。拒绝谴责俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京，希普金斯会见了中国国家主席习近平、国务院总理李强，并签署了一系列贸易协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，从美国返回几天后在立陶宛维尔纽斯举行的北约峰会上，希普金斯表示，随着中国变得更加自信，太平洋地区的竞争变得更加激烈，安全性也越来越低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一在奥克兰举行的中国商业峰会上，希普金斯表示，北京试图施加影响力是加剧战略竞争的主要驱动力，特别是在印太地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;惠灵顿维多利亚大学民主项目的地缘政治分析师杰弗里·米勒（Geoffrey Miller）专注于新西兰的外交政策，他表示，该国的平衡方针由于西方伙伴向北京施压，要求其表现得更加加强硬，美国对北京的态度现在受到威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;希普金斯出席本月的北约峰会“显然是一项长期提议，远非一次性举措”。米勒表示，“表现出与乌克兰的团结”，并指出新西兰最近发布了一份评估报告，将未来描述为“严峻”，并指出中国的“自信”外交政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，New新西兰还与澳大利亚、加拿大、日本、英国和美国一起签署了《反对与贸易有关的经济胁迫和非市场政策和做法的联合声明》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;反核新西兰“在玩”吗？米勒说：“[这]显然是针对中国的，尽管它没有提到北京的名字。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼古拉斯·罗斯·史密斯坎特伯雷大学欧洲国家研究中心专注于大国竞争的高级研究员表示，新西兰发现自己处于一个充满挑战的境地，战略对冲变得越来越难以实现。&lt;/p>;&lt; “目前，可靠性似乎是西方的一个大问题，新西兰不仅在北约 AP4 中，而且在五眼联盟中都享有最薄弱的一环的声誉，”史密斯说，他指的是跨大西洋安全联盟的四个国家“亚太伙伴”和五眼国际情报联盟，其中还包括澳大利亚、英国、加拿大和美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约与亚太四国（澳大利亚、日本、新西兰和美国）的关系更加密切。韩国——近几个月来在中国与俄罗斯军事和安全关系不断增强的情况下“加强对话与合作”。北京指责该联盟试图建立一个地区安全集团，以遏制中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;挪威特罗姆瑟大学政治学和国际关系副教授马克·兰泰涅 (Marc Lanteigne) 表示，其中一位专家表示促使希普金斯对太平洋安全感到担忧的因素是上周中国与所罗门群岛签署的警务协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者担心此举将“巩固中国在太平洋岛屿的战略利益，而牺牲新的利益”。兰泰涅说，北京最近宣布即将访问库克群岛。库克群岛是一个与新西兰“自由联合”的自治国家，管理自己的事务，但其人民被视为新西兰公民并享有自由。在那里生活和工作——也加剧了惠灵顿的焦虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新西兰政府面临着一个严峻的可能性，即维持对中国事实上的不结盟政策正在迅速变得不可行，”Lanteigne &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚、新西兰敦促中国就所罗门群岛警察协议“提供透明度”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;所罗门群岛总理上周访问北京期间签署了一系列协议部长玛纳西·索加瓦雷 (Manasseh Sogavare) 表示，其中包括一项允许中国在 2025 年之前在这个太平洋国家维持警察存在的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰奥塔哥大学国际关系教授罗伯特·帕特曼 (Robert Patman) 表示，这种说法是不准确的惠灵顿以“纯粹被动的方式”在中国及其西方盟友之间进行对冲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帕特曼在提到希普金斯 7 月 7 日的外交政策演讲时表示，新西兰已经明确表示，尽管其与中国的关系是该国“最复杂”的，它将坚持与北京进行“诚实和开放的对话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然希普金斯在访问期间采取了外交手段，但他的政府继续与中国保持着密切的交流北京在一些问题上的立场，”帕特曼说。 “新西兰认为，不能将中国和俄罗斯混为一谈，良好的对华政策将包括挫败普京对乌克兰的非法入侵。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上周，中国驻新西兰大使新西兰王小龙警告惠灵顿不要与北约合作，在该地区遏制北京，从而“为魔鬼敞开大门”。北京对北约将其利益更正式地扩大到亚太地区的可能性表示关注，并在维尔纽斯峰会发表联合公报后采取了激烈的态度，该公报表示，中国的野心和强制性政策挑战了北约的“利益、安全和价值观”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“北约正在寻求将亚太纳入其战略利益范围，这对北京来说是一个红灯，”兰泰涅说。他补充说，中国希望让新西兰相信保持较少对抗的立场的好处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥塔哥大学帕特曼指出，新西兰自 2012 年以来一直是北约的热情合作伙伴，他表示惠灵顿“拒绝”，并指出南太平洋国家外交部长 Nanaia Mahuta 驳斥了王对安全联盟的描述。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着太平洋超级大国竞争的升级，新西兰有何计划？&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰有何计划？ h3>;&lt;p>;马胡塔表示，其他国家与北约的关系是他们自己的事，但新西兰和北约有着悠久的合作历史，并对基于国际规则的体系有着共同的坚定承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;然而，坎特伯雷大学的史密斯表示，由于新西兰依赖中国作为出口目的地，因此新西兰可能会听取王的评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和新西兰之间的年贸易额超过美国2021年将达到247亿美元，是2008年两国首次签署自由贸易协定时的四倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年4月，两国升级版自贸协定生效，其中包括新的市场准入商品和服务方面的承诺，以及额外的贸易便利化措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地缘政治分析师米勒表示，与惠灵顿与北京的贸易协议相比，与欧盟的协议“凸显了新西兰仍然需要中国”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后一项协议将新西兰牛肉进口量限制在每年 11,000 吨，该地区拥有 4.5 亿人口。新西兰每年向中国出口超过20万吨牛肉。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 elite Hong Kong schools behind city’s 4 top DSE scorers in university entrance exams]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3228170/3-elite-hong-kong-schools-behind-citys-4-top-scorers-dse-exams?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/3ef51bf4-a8ff-4865-b595-53692f224668_bb60ce60.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年香港高考四位尖子生来自三位传统名校据《华盛顿邮报》报道，周三早上，当学生们返回校园领取成绩时，《华盛顿邮报》获悉，其中两名优秀学生来自中环圣保罗男女中学，其中一名来自蔡区好望学校。洪先生和铜锣湾皇仁书院的另一位学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，该市在中学文凭考试（DSE）考试中取得了 11 名高分，每一位都来自不同的精英学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;今年四门核心科目中，中国语文模块成绩升幅最大，而英国语文成绩跌幅最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DSE考试于4月21日至5月18日举行， 48,762名考生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4名香港学生在DSE考试中获得满分，创历史新低&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两名男生和两名女生在DSE七级评分中获得满分5**香港考试及评核局周二透露，今年所有七门科目的评分均达到了标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中三名学生（两名男孩和一名女孩）在扩展数学模块选修课中获得了 5** 的成绩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;今年的高分考生人数比 2022 年下降了 64%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考试机构秘书长魏向东早些时候表示，这一数字归因于“运气” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然高分学生较少，但获得高分的学生数量与去年相比并不低，”他说，并指出，今年有 107 名学生获得 40 至 42 分，而 2022 年为 102 名.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些学生可能缺乏一点运气，无法成为尖子生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还指出，今年获得5*和5**的考生总数有所增加0.1个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及香港的移民潮是否导致明星学生流失时，魏说：“我们不认为顶尖学生已经离开香港。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港 DSE 考试第二周比第一轮更容易管理：学生&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;学生将通过大学联合课程招生系统 (Jupas) 竞争约 12,000 个一年级资助名额，该系统是一个统一的大学联合招生系统 (Jupas)。申请全日制本科课程的机制，或1.45名合资格学生分配一个名额的比例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外3,000个资助名额将提供给通过非联招途径申请的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;四门核心科目中，考生的中文进步最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共有10.7%的考生取得5级或以上成绩，高于去年的9.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约58.9%的学生取得三级或以上成绩，这是进入公立大学的基本要求，较去年的58.5%略有上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学生完成中学文凭核心科目后松了一口气考试结束&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与去年相比，英语语言成绩在所有核心科目中下降幅度最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有 9.7% 的学生在英语语言方面取得了 5 级成绩，低于 10 分%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高达 51.6% 的学生在该科目中取得了 3 级成绩，这是进入公立大学的基本要求，比去年的 52% 略有下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/ a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I was paying off his loan’: Taiwan woman pays rent for 10 years then discovers boyfriend owns flat after he dumps her]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227688/i-was-paying-his-loan-taiwan-woman-pays-rent-10-years-then-discovers-boyfriend-owns-flat-after-he?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/56795231-a733-4299-ae9b-34a52dd08c3d_52dfd832.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾女子以为自己要和男友分摊10年的房租&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子在大陆社交媒体上发帖称，两人恋爱已有多年。 20年了，在男友坚称比买房更划算后，两人一起租了一套公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子说，她的男友似乎立刻就找到了他们现在的公寓，三房一卫，每月有房租。租金为新台币 28,000 元（900 美元），尽管从未看到租赁协议或任何有关租金金额的文件，但他们均摊了租金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，她只看到了她被引导相信的房主。一次。每当公寓里有什么东西需要修理时，都是由技工来完成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我联系所谓的业主时，他告诉我，因为他拥有多处房产，所以他雇用外部承包商来处理维修事宜。这在租赁行业很常见，所以我没有怀疑什么。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的男朋友也向她保证：“我们的房主非常重视租客的隐私，而且他住得很远，所以除非有必要，他不会来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;租金支付过程现在​​回想起来也很可疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的男朋友会在她付清自己的份额后把钱给“业主”。给他。他还声称，业主的地址离他工作的地方很近，所以他更容易直接与他打交道，并声称他担心如果她遇见他，业主可能会尝试和她约会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在在他们交往的第 12 年，这位女士开始了一份新工作，需要更长的通勤时间，并提议搬到离工作单位更近的地方。然而，她的男朋友立即拒绝了这个想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他一直恳求我，承诺找出长途通勤的解决方案。他甚至提出开车送我上下班，并承担所有家庭责任。”她在帖子中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位女士补充说，20 年后，她认为他们都在期待结婚。她错了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，令她惊讶的是，男人突然结束了他们的关系，指责她懒惰、小气，说他们没有未来，并让她搬出去。&lt;/p>;&lt;与此同时，一封写给男友的房贷还款信可疑地寄到了公寓，终于惊悉男友竟是他们居住了10年的公寓的业主。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“看来有人故意转发这封信。信封上明显有被打开过的痕迹。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每月的抵押贷款金额与她“分享”的租金金额相同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以我只是她还清了抵押贷款，结果却被抛弃了。”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的故事很快引起了网上观察人士的同情，其中许多人还就她如何行使其对该房产的合法权利提出了建议.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以你男朋友只付了首付，然后让你替他还了20年的贷款？如果您通过银行转账支付租金，仍有机会拿回钱。但如果你给了他现金，我很遗憾地告诉你，你可能不得不接受损失。”一位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位人士补充道：“你的男朋友可能犯了诈骗罪。收集证据并咨询律师。先别和你男朋友对质，这可能会引起他的警觉！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tricked into trafficking? Hong Kong drug mules face uphill fight to prove innocence, with most spending years in prison before release]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3228156/tricked-trafficking-hong-kong-drug-mules-face-uphill-fight-prove-innocence-most-spending-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/09b75011-6939-44a3-aef4-1a61a80a67bf_10d4557d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Aminah* 和她的阿姨 Sunarti* 抵达香港国际机场时感到震惊海关人员用电钻将她们的行李箱拆开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关人员在袋子里发现了5公斤冰毒（俗称冰毒），印尼妇女因贩毒被捕&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 2019 年 6 月被捕前几周，居住在龙目岛的 25 岁家庭主妇阿米娜 (Aminah) 与她在香港担任家庭佣工的印度尼西亚朋友卡蒂尼* (Kartini*) 取得了联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;上半年香港机场检获毒品猛增80%&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kartini表示，她结识了一名正在创业的尼泊尔年轻人，需要从印尼进口物资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他愿意为每人提供 1,000 美元，”阿米娜告诉《华盛顿邮报》。 “我阿姨病了，我想用这笔钱让她去香港接受治疗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;55岁的Aminah和Sunarti同意携带两个行李箱从印度尼西亚到香港，但不知道里面有毒品&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿米娜因被捕并被关押在新界戒备最高的监狱大榄女子监狱而感到震惊，但当她发现自己怀上了第一个孩子时，情况发生了转变。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年，她在伊丽莎白女王医院产下一名男孩，并被允许在监狱里陪伴孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2019 年因毒品被捕的年轻人数量下降了 24%香港：警方&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这两名女子在监狱里待了三年等待审判，去年被无罪释放，因为有足够的证据让法官相信她们被骗了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aminah，她的孩子和她的阿姨已经返回龙目岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些妇女是因贩毒或走私而被捕的少数人之一，她们成功地让法院相信她们被欺骗了，从而避免了香港的严厉处罚被判处无期徒刑和 500 万港元（64 万美元）罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港海关的数据显示，自取消 Covid-19 旅行限制以来，更多毒品通过&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年首5个月，机场检获约1,840公斤危险药物，价值8.98亿港元，较去年同期增加1.5倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 据当局称，国际贩毒集团增加了利用快递员向香港走私毒品的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年前六个月，有 30 名入境航空旅客因涉嫌走私近 46 公斤毒品而被捕价值3,900万港元的毒品。 2022年全年，共有20名航空旅客因走私罪被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们年龄在14岁至72岁之间，来自巴西、爱沙尼亚、埃塞俄比亚、马达加斯加、乌干达、蒙古、丹麦和美国。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;青少年毒骡被捕时年仅 15 岁。 Now she&#39;s serving 17 years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Father John Wotherspoon, a prison chaplain and chief executive officer of Voice for Prisoners, an NGO that helps people arrested after being duped into trafficking, said he had seen a wide range of tactics used to trick people into carrying drugs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were men who tricked their girlfriends after being in long-term relationships, travel agents who offered deals that were too good to be true and online scammers who fooled people into believing they were helping others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I would estimate that about 20 per cent of those arrested have been tricked,” said Wotherspoon, 76, a Catholic priest from Australia who has been in Hong Kong for more than 30 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People who have been tricked into becoming drug mules are not criminals or members of drug syndicates, they are innocent victims.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past eight years, Voice for Prisoners helped 16 people accused of smuggling drugs get acquitted. It is now helping four others whose cases are pending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of those the NGO helped were women. Wotherspoon said single mothers or women in desperate situations tended to be targeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For those eventually acquitted, the whole process of gathering evidence to fight the charges took time, which meant sometimes spending years in prison before finally walking free.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The prison chaplain who&#39;s stopped 150 drug mules reaching the city&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;Tricked by &#39;a good friend&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Malaysian personal assistant Siti*, 51, was caught in June 2018 with 2kg of cocaine hidden in a suitcase after she arrived in Hong Kong from Sao Paulo, Brazil.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said she was tricked by a Nigerian man she met in Kuala Lumpur and had known for 11 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He was a good friend, he knew my family and would come to our house,” she told the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man ran a furniture export business in Kuala Lumpur.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had done translation work for him, so when he asked me to attend some meetings for him in Sao Paulo and Hong Kong, I agreed,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When she arrived in Sao Paulo, Siti was told the meeting had been cancelled, but did not suspect anything.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I stayed in Brazil for three days and was on my way to the airport to go to Hong Kong, when he called from Kuala Lumpur and asked me to help him bring a suitcase of clothes back.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Customs officers at Hong Kong airport took apart the suitcase and found the narcotics.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Drug dealers use travel perks and quick cash to lure teens into trafficking&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;By working with her family in Kuala Lumpur, Voice for Prisoners helped collect enough evidence to prove she had been tricked and the jurors at her trial decided unanimously that she was innocent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The single mother of four was acquitted in December 2020, after being remanded for two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now back in Kuala Lumpur, Siti said she was unable to work because she had to care for her sick mother.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Civil servant Parvati*, an Indian national, was living in Kuala Lumpur when someone she thought was a travel agent offered her an attractive deal on an all-inclusive week-long group tour to Hong Kong in 2019&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When I landed in Hong Kong, a tour guide told me that the group had not arrived yet and I could spend a couple of days in Cambodia for free while I waited,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had nowhere to stay and I was nervous because I&#39;d never left Malaysia before, so I went to Cambodia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was in Phnom Penh for three days with the tour guide. Before leaving for their flight to Hong Kong, he asked if she could help take a bag back for him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I started to suspect something,” she recalled. “I kept asking, why do I have to take it?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said she asked customs officers in Phnom Penh International Airport to scan the bag twice because she was worried she was being set up, but they found nothing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;City&#39;s young smugglers told: your age won&#39;t stop you going to jail&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I thought everything was fine after that,” Parvati said. “I was just about to leave Hong Kong airport when customs officers stopped and searched my bag.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was arrested after they found 4kg of cocaine, and spent 30 months detained at Tai Lam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When her case went to court in 2021, her lawyer was able to present text message records between her and those alleged to have tricked her as evidence. The prosecution dropped the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;The real criminals get away&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lawyer Jonathan Midgley, 57, who has defended those accused of smuggling drugs into Hong Kong, recalled a Thai woman who was told she would never see her children again if she did not carry a bag of narcotics to Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Luckily she was acquitted,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Criticising the long sentences handed out to mules convicted of drug smuggling, he said: “Mules often get hit with a 20-year sentence, while the people who are behind it rarely get caught.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The rationale is that punishing mules severely acts as a deterrent but I doubt that it does, because many are tricked or forced to do so under duress.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his years of working with prisoners, Wotherspoon has learned of various drug syndicates shipping narcotics into Hong Kong from around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has travelled to Africa, South America, Malaysia and Thailand to urge syndicate members to stop tricking innocent people into moving drugs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I flew out to Sao Paulo in 2018 to find the drug lords there,” he said. “I&#39;d heard that they hung out in a canteen in the slums.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong works with Canada to curb cannabis smuggling at source&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Armed with just his travel bag, passport and a cross around his neck, he went to the canteen and began asking for the people he believed were involved in smuggling drugs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I approached one group and pleaded with them to stop tricking innocent people into smuggling drugs,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He recalled what one of them said to him: “If you value your life, you will leave now.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wotherspoon said the purpose of his trip was not only to confront drug lords and beg them to stop, which he admitted was unlikely to work, but also to retrace the steps of the people Voice for Prisoners was helping and gather evidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has previously used evidence gained and proof of his interactions with drug syndicates to write letters to judges overseeing cases that have ended in acquittal, most notably in the case of Li Dandan, a Chinese national who was tricked into smuggling 2kg of ice into Hong Kong via Kuala Lumpur.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman from Guangzhou was arrested at Hong Kong airport with the drugs in her backpack in 2015. She was acquitted in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wotherspoon said it was important to deter people from falling for the tricks of drug smugglers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To do this, his NGO asks prisoners arrested for smuggling drugs to write letters warning others not to do what they did.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who take part in this anti-drug campaign are sometimes offered reductions in their sentences, and the NGO is convinced it has helped discourage many from becoming drug mules.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jailed for months without trial, then given 48 hours to leave Hong Kong: 6 foreign nationals told &#39;get out&#39; after drug charges dropped&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Syndicates use a variety of methods to get people to carry drugs across borders for them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wotherspoon said it was much harder to help suspects caught after swallowing drug-filled pellets concealed in their bodies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have never seen someone in those cases get acquitted, it is too hard to prove that they were forced,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesman for Hong Kong customs said that in combating cross-boundary drug trafficking, the department had been closely monitoring global and local narcotics trends and adopted effective enforcement tactics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 26, customs officers at the airport stopped a 42-year-old woman who arrived from Kuala Lumpur with 14kg of suspected cocaine found in boxes of agar powder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just nine days earlier a 25-year-old woman who arrived from Brazil via Kuala Lumpur was arrested after officers found seven perfume bottles with false compartments used to conceal almost a kilogram of suspected cocaine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 14, a 62-year-old man from the United States, who arrived from Sao Paulo via Paris, was caught with liquid cocaine valued at HK$8 million soaked into 17 bedsheets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Swift adjustments on enforcement strategies and resources deployment have been made with a view to stepping up actions against all kinds of drug trafficking activities through different channels,” the spokesman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said members of the public could report suspected drug trafficking activities to the department&#39;s 24-hour hotline (2545 6182) or its dedicated crime-reporting email account (crimereport@customs.gov.hk).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;* Names changed to protect the identity of those interviewed&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea fires two missiles after US submarine arrives in South Korea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3228167/north-korea-fires-two-missiles-after-us-submarine-arrives-south-korea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 07:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/3b4c5661-bc58-45a9-b415-e7ea5fa4ba3e_309c8e58.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;North Korea launched two ballistic missiles eastward early on Wednesday, Japan&#39;s and South Korea&#39;s militaries said, just hours after a US ballistic missile submarine arrived in a South Korean port for the first time in four decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both of the missiles appeared to have fallen outside Japan&#39;s exclusive economic zone, the Japanese defence ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea&#39;s Joint Chiefs of Staff (JCS) called on the North to cease such launches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We strongly condemn North Korea&#39;s successive ballistic missile launches as grave provocative acts that undermine the peace and stability of the Korean peninsula as well as the international community, and are a clear violation of UN Security Council resolutions,” the JCS said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;North Korea threatens to shoot down US planes as it condemns nuclear moves&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US military said it was aware of the missile launches and was consulting closely with its allies and partners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The launches do not appear to pose an immediate threat to the United States or to its allies, but the events highlight the destabilising impact of North Korea&#39;s illicit weapons programme, the US Indo-Pacific Command said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first missile reached an altitude of 50km (31 miles) and covered a range of 550km, while the second one rose as high as 50km and flew 600km, Japanese Defence Minister Yasukazu Hamada told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan lodged a protest against the missile launches through diplomatic channels, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The firing comes nearly a week after North Korea tested its latest Hwasong-18 intercontinental ballistic missile, a launch Pyongyang said was a warning to the United States and other adversaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also on Tuesday, a US soldier facing disciplinary action fled across the inter-Korean border into North Korea. The soldier is believed to be in North Korean custody, Washington said, creating a fresh crisis between the two foes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“North Korea&#39;s latest firing of ballistic missiles is probably unrelated to an American soldier crossing the inter-Korean border, but such an incident doesn&#39;t help matters either,” said Leif-Eric Easley, a professor at Ewha University in Seoul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea “undoubtedly opposes” a new US-South Korea nuclear war planning group that met for the first time on Tuesday, as well as the visit of the US nuclear ballistic missile submarine, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Johnson & Johnson must pay US$18.8 million to man who says he got cancer from baby powder]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228168/johnson-johnson-must-pay-us188-million-man-who-says-he-got-cancer-baby-powder?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 07:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/599a27c5-86ce-42ce-9ca7-14b61f710cb3_bd64980f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Johnson &amp; Johnson must pay US$18.8 million to a California man who said he developed cancer from exposure to its baby powder, a jury decided on Tuesday, a setback for the company as it seeks to settle thousands of similar cases over its talc-based products in US bankruptcy court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jury ruled in favour of Emory Hernandez Valadez, who filed suit last year in California state court in Oakland against J&amp;J, seeking monetary damages. Hernandez, 24, has said he developed mesothelioma, a deadly cancer, in the tissue around his heart as a result of heavy exposure to the company&#39;s talc since childhood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The six-week trial was the first over talc that New Brunswick, New Jersey-based J&amp;J has faced in almost two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jury found that Hernandez was entitled to damages to compensate him for his medical bills and pain and suffering, but declined to award punitive damages against the company. Hernandez will not be able to collect the judgment in the foreseeable future, thanks to a bankruptcy court order freezing most litigation over J&amp;J&#39;s talc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J has denied that its talc products contain asbestos, which is linked to mesothelioma, or cause cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In closing arguments to the jury on July 10, J&amp;J&#39;s lawyers said there was no evidence either linking Hernandez&#39;s kind of mesothelioma to asbestos or proving that Hernandez was ever exposed to tainted talc. Hernandez&#39;s lawyers during closing arguments accused J&amp;J of a “despicable” decades-long cover-up of asbestos contamination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hernandez testified in June, telling jurors that he would have avoided J&amp;J&#39;s talc if he had been warned that it contained asbestos, as his lawsuit alleges. Jurors heard from Hernandez&#39;s mother, Anna Camacho, who said she used large amounts of J&amp;J&#39;s baby powder on her son when he was a baby and through childhood. She cried as she described Hernandez&#39;s illness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tens of thousands of plaintiffs have sued, alleging that J&amp;J&#39;s baby powder and other talc products sometimes contained asbestos and caused ovarian cancer and mesothelioma. J&amp;J has said its talc products are safe and do not contain asbestos, which has been linked to mesothelioma.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Record US$417m award in lawsuit blaming cancer on baby powder&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J subsidiary LTL Management in April filed for bankruptcy in Trenton, New Jersey, proposing to pay US$8.9 billion to settle more than 38,000 lawsuits and prevent new cases from coming forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the company&#39;s second attempt to resolve talc claims in bankruptcy, after a federal appeal court rejected an earlier bid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most litigation has been halted during bankruptcy proceedings, but US Chief Bankruptcy Judge Michael Kaplan, who is overseeing LTL&#39;s Chapter 11, let Hernandez&#39;s trial proceed because he is expected to live only a short time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hernandez&#39;s form of mesothelioma is extremely rare, making his case different from the vast majority pending against J&amp;J.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asbestos plaintiffs are seeking to have LTL&#39;s latest bankruptcy filing dismissed. They have argued the filing was brought in bad faith to insulate the company from litigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J and LTL have argued that bankruptcy delivers settlement payouts to plaintiffs more fairly, efficiently and equitably than trial courts, which they have likened to a “lottery” in which some litigants get large awards and others nothing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J said in bankruptcy court filings that the costs of its talc-related verdicts, settlements and legal fees have reached about US$4.5 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Marshall Islands seeks US apology and full compensation for damage from its 67 nuclear tests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228166/marshall-islands-seeks-us-apology-and-full-compensation-damage-its-67-nuclear-tests?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 07:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/20584455-c441-48d2-b43b-494a543284ef_b8a147d2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Marshall Islands on Tuesday called on Washington to pay “full” compensation for the health, environmental and cultural damage caused by 67 nuclear tests carried out by the American government, refusing to accept the Joe Biden administration&#39;s newest version of a strategic agreement that has steered bilateral ties for decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the people of the Pacific nation who played a major role in helping Allied forces capture Japanese invaders in the region during World War II, said Kenneth Kedi, speaker of the country&#39;s parliament, in testimony before an Indo-Pacific task force of the House Natural Resources Committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Narrating what he called a brief history of the sacrifices made by the Marshall Islands for the US, Kedi told the panel that, after the wartime fighting ended, it was the Marshallese who “without a choice” found themselves in the middle of the Cold War.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nuclear tests in question took place across the archipelago between 1946 and 1958, and the US made a “massive display of power” by detonating the bombs on the islands, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kedi testified that the tests “unfortunately” led to high rates of cancer and extensive environmental damage, explaining that both his parents died prematurely from cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And this is not a unique story for me or for the Marshall Islands. Most families have gone through the same.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Marshallese politician quoted a UN report in urging the US to go on record and apologise to his country, saying: “We are yet to get an apology.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Combined, the tests were “thousands of times as powerful as the bomb dropped on Hiroshima”, according to a 2015 report published by the Pulitzer Centre. Cancer is a leading cause of death on the Marshall Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As US sees future in Pacific islands, has China &#39;overplayed its hand&#39;?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kedi cited the findings of a nuclear claims tribunal set up between the US and the Marshall Islands “to adjudicate and pay substantiated and warranted claims”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the tribunal ran out of funds after paying a small fraction of the damages it awarded, with the total amount of unpaid awards standing at US$3 billion in current dollars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marshallese people had sacrificed significantly by giving their traditional land to the US for military use, Kedi testified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the event of “any war coming from, who knows where,” the Marshall Islands would be “the first shield of defence before anything”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As US Congress debates budget, Pacific island nations watch with concern&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The American military installation on the country&#39;s largest island, Kwajalein Atoll, has been described by the US Department of Defence as “an important asset that would be costly and difficult to replicate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After administering Micronesia, the Marshall Islands and Palau under a UN trusteeship after World War II, the US signed international treaties with each as sovereign Pacific nations in 1986 and 1994 under the Compact of Free Association or Cofa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pacts granted the US military access to each nation&#39;s land, air and sea in exchange for financial assistance and permission to legally live, work and go to school in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For decades following World War II, Washington did not regard the Pacific island region as a national security priority. But as China&#39;s economic and geopolitical influence in the Indo-Pacific grew, the US took more notice of the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We see the presence and influence of China on a daily basis,” Joseph Yun, President Joe Biden&#39;s special envoy for Cofa negotiations, told the panel on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun accused China of employing “coercive tactics” in Cofa states as well as in other Pacific nations like the Solomon Islands and Fiji, noting a security deal signed between Beijing and Honiara last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To take somehow our friendship with these compact states for granted will be a real mistake,” he cautioned the lawmakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Cofa pacts are set to expire this year and next. The Biden administration budget for 2024 has proposed more than US$7 billion for more than 20 years to extend the deals, the largest-ever congressional budget request for the region. Out of this total, US$2.9 billion would be earmarked for the Marshall Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Yun said the US had finalised compact terms with Micronesia and Palau and that he hoped the Marshall Islands would soon follow suit. However, the negotiations have dragged on.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China confirms signing of Solomon Islands security pact&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Biden administration&#39;s enhanced budget for the region also awaits congressional approval, with new Cofa promises extremely difficult to fulfil amid fierce partisan disagreements over federal spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun believed that if Congress was unable to pass the budget in a timely manner “our credibility will suffer enormous damage”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palauan President Surangel Whipps Jnr sounded a similar warning before the House committee on Tuesday, testifying that despite the US installing on Palau its closest early- warning radar to Asia, his country had remained “economically challenged”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He described access to federal programmes and financial assistance as “inadequate”, saying Palau and the US “are joined at the hip, and Palau recognises Taiwan&#39;s right to exist”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Continuation of the relationship”, Whipps added, “can&#39;t be taken for granted”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China says it will launch reusable spacecraft as soon as 2027]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3228139/china-says-it-will-launch-reusable-spacecraft-soon-2027?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/18/52670e97-7ea0-4830-b4af-70b731436461_e7894933.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s first reusable spacecraft will be launched as soon as 2027, according to the deputy chief engineering designer of the country&#39;s manned space programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Liwei, who was the first Chinese sent into space, also told Guangzhou Daily on Monday that the new spacecraft would be able to transport seven astronauts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will also play a critical role in future construction of China&#39;s space station and moon landing mission,” Yang was quoted as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the China Manned Space Engineering Office, the spacecraft will be reusable for both near-Earth orbit and deep-space exploration missions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A full-size prototype successfully completed a 67-hour test flight, carried by a Long March 5 rocket, in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It uses new materials and structures that take its heat resistance to three to four times that of China&#39;s Shenzhou spacecrafts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The materials can withstand temperatures as high as 3,000 degrees Fahrenheit during re-entry, while the weight of the heat-resistant structure has been reduced by more than 30 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The spacecraft has also been designed to be reused – the return capsule will be ready for the next mission once it is examined and its “coating” replaced. That means – theoretically at least – key parts of the spacecraft can be reused up to 10 times, significantly reducing launch costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Western companies drawn to China&#39;s lunar research station project&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Zhou Jianping, chief designer of China&#39;s manned space programme, told state broadcaster CCTV last month that the latest design retained a “blunt bullet-head shape” but the internal space is larger than previous versions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The design has been streamlined from three compartments to two, making it safer and more economical,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With capacity to carry seven astronauts, it will be comparable to the new generation of American manned spacecraft – SpaceX&#39;s Dragon V2 and Boeing&#39;s CST-100 Starliner. Nasa&#39;s Orion MPCV carries six.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 8.8 metres and weighing 21.6 tonnes it is also twice the size of the Dragon V2, which weighs about 9.5 tonnes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new spacecraft will be use for China&#39;s crewed moon landing programme, working with a separate landing spaceship, specialised lunar spacesuits, manned rovers and other equipment to achieve this goal by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has not yet been named. The China Manned Space Engineering Office said on its official WeChat page on Friday that a competition would soon be launched to name the new-generation spacecraft as well as the new lunar landing spaceship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office on Monday also put out a call to universities, research institutions and tech companies to submit scientific payloads to be taken to the moon with the lander by 2030.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>