<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Vietnamese video gaming and social media start-up VNG files to be country’s first tech firm to go public in US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3232109/vietnamese-video-gaming-and-social-media-start-vng-files-be-countrys-first-tech-firm-go-public-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 11:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/5f261cec-1242-461d-90af-3c065d7c9ac9_7f0f3f69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;互联网初创公司 VNG Ltd 在美国申请首次公开募股，它是第一家寻求在纽约上市的越南科技公司，随着股市解冻，该公司也加入到计划上市的多元化公司名单中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VNG 计划在 IPO 中发行近 2200 万股股票，在随后向美国证券交易委员会提交的文件中设定了拟议的价格范围。该公司在周三提交的文件中表示，VNG 将继续由其创始人 Le Hong Minh 和 Vuong Quang Khai 控制。 VNG 将拥有越南运营公司 VNG Corp 49% 的股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VNG Corp 前身为 Vinagame，于 2004 年作为游戏发行商起步。它开发和发行自己的游戏以及本地游戏。版本的国际流行歌曲，并逐渐扩展到广泛的服务，如音乐共享、视频流、消息、新闻门户和移动支付。它至少从 2017 年起就一直在探索在美国上市。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越南对腾讯着眼海外扩张的回应&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其消息应用程序 Zalo 赢得了 Meta Platform Inc 的 Facebook Messenger 的支持，自 2020 年以来成为越南最常用的聊天平台。根据一份声明，Zalo 每月有 7500 万活跃用户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们出生在战后，在一个和平与团结的国家，但仍在与不发达和孤立作斗争，”VNG 的创始人在招股说明书中致投资者的一封信中表示。 “当互联网在 20 世纪 90 年代中期登陆越南时，我们几乎不知道自己是多么幸运。世界神奇地突然为我们打开了大门。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继越南电动汽车制造商 Vinfast Auto Ltd 完成与空白支票公司 Black Spade Acquisition 的合并后，本月在美国首次公开募股后，VNG Ltd 也将进行 IPO。 Co 的交易估值为 230 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VNG 的上市将为时断时续的 IPO 市场增添动力。软银集团控股的芯片设计公司 Arm Holdings Ltd. 计划于 9 月上市，这将是今年最大规模的 IPO。据彭博社报道，总部位于旧金山的杂货配送公司 Instacart Inc 以及营销、数据自动化提供商 Klaviyo 和鞋类制造商 Birkenstock 也准备申请 IPO。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VNG 将游戏视为其全球扩张的先锋该公司首席执行官 Minh 在去年接受采访时表示，该公司计划实施这一计划，同时还寻求增加人工智能和云计算产品的收入。游戏部门 VNG Games 在海外拥有至少九款工作室游戏，包括泰国、新加坡、马来西亚、台北和中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次发行由花旗集团、摩根士丹利、瑞银集团和美国银行牵头.该公司计划其股票在纳斯达克全球精选市场交易，代码为 VNG。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China debt: Beijing warned opportunity costs are rising as it seeks comprehensive solution to local government crisis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3232066/china-debt-beijing-warned-opportunity-costs-are-rising-it-seeks-comprehensive-solution-local?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/c91c9bfb-906d-42bb-8969-0f558e0b0109_a595abc3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国正在考虑采取更强有力的措施应对地方政府债务危机带来的风险，但分析师表示，在遏制国家主导的金融体系中的系统性风险方面，机会成本正在上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去几年，金融体系已经受到房地产问题的压力，分析师警告称，如果北京方面行动不够快，无法解决房地产市场危机，成本可能会很高，这会对地方政府产生影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总而言之，虽然实际通胀紧缩会产生结构性后果，但Natixis 亚太区首席经济学家 Alicia Garcia-Herrero 本周表示：“房地产泡沫无法避免，中国政策制定者应重点限制对金融业的潜在溢出效应，从而限制系统性风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;”拖得越久，代价就越大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京已经认识到地方政府债务危机的紧迫性，并于上个月规定，有必要通过“综合解决方案”来解决这一问题。 ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑞银首席中国经济学家王涛表示，政策支持不能及时或有效地传递到更广泛的经济中存在风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别是，如何处理王说，当地方政府已经占到中国财政资源的 90% 时，地方政府支出效率低下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此外，[中央]政府还面临结构性挑战，包括人口老龄化和准入限制王本周补充道，“从国外引进先进技术，应该引导经济摆脱房地产和地方政府主导的增长模式，转向更可持续和高质量的增长模式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“内部审议可能需要时间，并导致有效政策反应的延迟。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“坚持现金”：中国潜在购房者选择等待房地产低迷结束&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;财新该杂志周六报道称，中国央行可能会与银行建立紧急流动性工具，向地方政府金融平台（LGFV）提供期限较长的低成本资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;LGFV 是混合实体，既是公共实体，也是公共实体。地方政府融资平台的创建是为了规避对地方政府借贷的限制，自 2008 年全球金融危机以来，此类融资平台数量激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们越来越担心地方政府偿还地方政府融资平台债务的能力，因为地方政府的收入来自于土地销售受到房地产市场低迷的挤压，尽管许多人继续借贷为昂贵的基础设施项目提供资金，以促进增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荣鼎集团中国市场研究合伙人兼总监 Logan Wright 表示财新描述的计划是“非常早的一小步”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他表示，这样的提议有可能给那些获得低额或没有再融资债券额度的省份或地区带来额外的市场风险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国荣鼎集团估计，截至 7 月份，地方政府融资平台贷款占中国银行贷款总额的 20% 至 25%，而地方政府融资平台债券占所有企业债券的 51%地方政府融资平台信贷覆盖了全系统金融资产的约 13%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大部分地方政府债务由国内投资者持有，银行业对地方政府融资平台的敞口被认为相当大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;荣鼎集团补充道，任何形式的债务解决都会导致整个系统的损失分担，其中很大一部分损失将由中国的银行和非银行机构承担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是北京的困境。地方政府投资仍占总投资的相当大比例，目前可能占国内生产总值 (GDP) 的 14% 至 15% 左右，”赖特说。 “因此，让地方政府投资大幅放缓显然会对经济增长产生影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们需要管理现有债务存量，并[建立]一个更可持续的机制来为地方投资融资2015-18年，经北京批准，地方政府发行了约12万亿元人民币的债券来置换表外债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着中国预示着房地产复苏，“风险”房地产还能拉动经济增长吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但地方政府融资平台债务很快再次堆积，国际货币基金组织在 2 月份发布的一份报告中估计，中国的地方政府融资平台债务总额已膨胀至今年创纪录的 66 万亿元人民币（9 万亿美元），是 2017 年报告的 30.7 万亿元人民币的两倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京的多位政策顾问，包括中国科学院院长刘尚希”刘在 7 月份对国家支持的《经济观察报》表示：“过去的改革已经过去了，不适合当前充满活力的社会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘将改革形容为“紧迫”，并表示中央政府应该接管一些改革。地方政府经济发展的责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地方政府级别越低，[协调跨区域经济政策]的能力就越低，”刘说。 “随着我国经济社会发展水平的提高，事权和支出责任也需要上移；否则，治理成本将呈指数级上升。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan Airlines named world’s best, ahead of Singapore Airlines, 5 other Asian carriers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/article/3232105/japan-airlines-named-worlds-best-ahead-singapore-airlines-5-other-asian-carriers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 11:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/6423a44c-f23d-4977-9bc3-c62fa0834c4c_e5da452a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;行李寄存公司 Bounce 公布了全球最佳国际航空公司年度排名8 月 2 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bounce 根据 2022 年出发总数分析了全球 52 家最大航空公司的数据。该公司根据以下 10 个因素对这些航空公司进行了评估： 、取消百分比、航班总数、免费随身行李限额、免费托运国内限额、免费托运国际限额、餐食、机上娱乐、座椅舒适度和员工服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;10 个最佳2023 年全球航空公司排名 – 香港国泰航空得分如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“航空公司的可靠性因公司而异，机上舒适度、服务和娱乐的质量也存在很大差异。 Bounce 在其网站上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位居榜首的是：日本航空，总分 8.28 分，荣获全球最佳航空公司称号。另一家来自亚洲的航空公司新加坡航空排名第二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Insider 将每家航空公司的得分纳入了四个标准——膳食、员工服务、机上娱乐和座椅舒适度——因为这些是许多乘客在预订航空公司时会考虑的因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：5.16/10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：2/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南航空获得四星级认证航空公司由航空排名网站 Skytrax 评选。在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上，它在 674 条评论中的评分为 6 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评价褒贬不一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐越南航空航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，他的商务舱座椅“舒适”，服务“无可挑剔”。另一位 7 月份乘坐该航空公司航班的乘客在网站上写道，他有过一次负面的经历。他说航班比预定时间晚了两个小时到达，并注意到机上餐食短缺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：5.16/10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐食：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;阿联酋航空被 Skytrax 认证为四星级航空公司。在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上，该航空公司的平均评分为 5 分（满分 10 分）（总分 2,291 分）。最近的评论是负面的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐阿联酋航空航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，尽管收取了 110 美元的转运费用，但航空公司对他的行李箱处理不当，他对此感到“失望”。另一位7月搭乘阿联酋航空航班的乘客称赞机上娱乐“出色”，但表示机上餐饮质量较差。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：8.28/10 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务： 3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蓝色航空公司被 Skytrax 认证为三星级航空公司。根据 93 条评论，该航空公司的平均评分为 6 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论很差。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐 Azul 航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，他的航班被取消了两次，并且只得到了旅行积分补偿。另一位 6 月份乘坐该航空公司航班的乘客表示，机上娱乐系统无法正常工作，客户服务也从未回复他的电子邮件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：5.4/10&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：2/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：3 /5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度航空被 Skytrax 认证为三星级航空公司。 Skytrax 客户评论网站上的 1,203 条评论中，该航空公司的平均评分为 4 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论很差。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐印度航空航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，“这架飞机似乎严重失灵”，而且机上娱乐系统也无法使用。另一位 7 月份乘坐该航空公司航班的乘客抱怨他的航班延误了 6 ​​个小时，而且机上服务“很差”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度航空希望通过 4 亿美元的改造来摆脱其破败的声誉&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：5.99/10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐食：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：2/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;座椅舒适度：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃塞俄比亚航空被Skytrax认证为四星级航空公司。 Skytrax 客户评论网站上的 570 条评论中，该航空公司的平均评分为 5 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论是负面的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名 7 月份乘坐埃塞俄比亚航空公司航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，他的行李箱被不当处理，并且没有得到任何赔偿。另一位 6 月份乘坐该航空公司航班的乘客表示，商务舱“还不错”，但他差点错过转机航班，因为他的首趟航班延误了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分： 10年6月23日&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：3/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全日空航空公司（ANA）被 Skytrax 认证为五星级航空公司。 Skytrax 客户评论网站上的 566 条评论中，全日空航空公司的平均评分为 8 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评价是积极的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 7 月份乘坐全日空航空公司航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，虽然他的商务舱座位感觉“过时”，但机上餐食很好。另一位 6 月份乘坐该航空公司航班的乘客表示，客服人员“当场”帮助她修改机票，效率很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本航空公司的失误导致飞往美国的商务舱机票售价为 550 美元&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：6.43/10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐食：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;座椅舒适度：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vistara 被 Skytrax 认证为四星级航空公司。在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上，该航空公司的平均评分为 7 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论褒贬不一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐 Vistara 航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，机上的食物很差，机上娱乐也不起作用。但另一位8月份乘坐该航空公司航班的乘客表示，服务“确实非常好”，航班准时到达目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：7.19/10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：7.19/10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：4/ 5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大韩航空被 Skytrax 认证为五星级航空公司。 Skytrax 客户服务网站上的 599 条评论中，该航空公司的平均评分为 7 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论是积极的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 7 月份乘坐大韩航空航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，服务很友好，飞机“一尘不染”。另一位 6 月份乘坐该航空公司商务舱的乘客表示，食物很好，机上工作人员“彬彬有礼、友好且乐于助人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：7.5/10 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务： 4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡塔尔航空被 Skytrax 认证为五星级航空公司。根据 Skytrax 客户评论网站的 2,252 条评论，该航空公司的平均评分为 7 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论褒贬不一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐卡塔尔航空商务舱的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，这次航班“非常出色”，机上餐食味道“棒极了”。但另一位 7 月份乘坐该航空公司商务舱的乘客表示，他最初的航班延误了一个半小时，导致他错过了转机航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡航空被评为全球第二大航空公司。国泰航空跌至第16位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：7.63 /10&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：4 /5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡航空（Singapore Airlines），简称SIA，被新加坡航空管理局认证为五星级航空公司天空特拉克斯。 Skytrax 客户评论网站上的 1,477 条评论中，该航空公司的平均评分为 7 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评价是积极的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 8 月份乘坐新航航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，他对新航的服务、机上娱乐和机上提供的食物“印象非常深刻”。但另一名 7 月份乘坐新航航班的乘客表示，尽管航空公司同意向他部分退款，但航空公司从未对他因处理不当而丢失的行李箱进行赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总分：8.28/10 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;餐饮：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机上娱乐：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座椅舒适度：4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工服务： 4/5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本航空（JAL）被 Skytrax 认证为五星级航空公司。根据 Skytrax 客户评论网站上的 401 条评论，该航空公司的平均评分为 7 分（满分 10 分）。最近的评论褒贬不一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 7 月份乘坐日航航班的乘客在 Skytrax 的客户评论网站上表示，机组人员“棒极了”，而且“食物非常好”。但另一名 6 月份乘坐该航空公司商务舱的乘客表示，她对机上提供的“糟糕的客户服务”和“乏味的餐食”感到“失望”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读原文：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jakarta’s ‘very bad’ air pollution to persist due to government foot-dragging, green groups say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3232088/jakartas-very-bad-air-pollution-persist-due-government-foot-dragging-green-groups-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/fca038a1-00fd-4be0-b49d-6d38f28ab1bf_2137b739.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚无法解决雅加达的空气污染问题，这意味着首都的 1000 万人口将继续遭受污染环保活动人士表示，要在未来几年应对雾霾问题，并将日益恶化的问题归咎于无效的立法、不可靠的排放数据和政客对燃煤电厂的兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，雅加达被宣布为世界上空气质量最差的城市。瑞士科技公司 IQAir 的质量评价 – 总统佐科·维多多 (Joko Widodo) 长达一个月的咳嗽甚至被归因于该市的污染水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;维多多已在下个月雅加达举行的东盟峰会之前召集部长们应对污染问题。与此同时，旅游部长桑迪亚加·乌诺(Sandiaga Uno)建议该市应该学习北京的清洁工作，北京在2013年花费了1000亿美元清除街道上的旧车辆，减少工厂排放，并用天然气代替煤炭发电。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“大雅加达地区的空气质量非常糟糕，”维多多上周在内阁会议上表示。 “过去三个月的旱季延长加剧了污染物水平。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管领导人发表了上述言论，活动人士仍对政府提出的计划能否显着改善该市的空气质量表示怀疑，他们指出&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 9 月，印度尼西亚一家法院裁定，包括维多多和雅加达前省长阿尼斯·巴斯韦丹 (Anies Baswedan) 在内的几名官员在处理该市空气污染问题时疏忽大意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法院没有实施任何处罚，只是敦促总统和其他人采取行动改善空气质量，包括加强监管、加强监督和测试车辆排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府向雅加达提起上诉2021 年 9 月向高等法院提起诉讼。当法院于 2022 年 10 月驳回这一裁决时，政府于当年 12 月向最高法院提起了新的上诉。呼吁仍在进行中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府最高层不想采取重要行动，”在 Baswedan 领导下担任雅加达气候变化特使的 Irvan Pulungan 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;许多活动家指责印度尼西亚环境和林业部拒绝承认问题的严重性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部使用的空气质量等级将远高于标准的空气污染等级划分为对人类安全的等级世界卫生组织使用的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们总是问他们是否意味着人类或其他物种的呼吸是安全的，”一位不愿透露姓名的活动家说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;即使获得雅加达空气污染主要来源的准确数据也很棘手。纽约一家关注全球公共卫生的非政府组织 Vital Strategies 的一份报告指出，汽车尾气是主要问题。研究发现，2018-19 年期间，汽车尾气在旱季污染中占 32-41%，在雨季污染中占 42-57%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，Lauri Myllyvirta，首席分析师，芬兰清洁能源研究中心（CREA）表示，雅加达邻近省份的燃煤发电厂可能在污染该市空气方面发挥了更大的作用。 CREA 2020 年的一份报告发现，在城市 100 公里半径范围内，有 136 个高排放工业设施，其中包括 16 个发电厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一项研究发现，当道路通车时，污染并没有下降太多。交通量减少了，但当风从大量燃煤发电厂集中的地区吹来时，交通量增加了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巴厘岛的“河流勇士”清理了印度尼西亚海滩和水道的废物&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;米利维尔塔表示，环境部似乎并不相信这个问题。在8月13日的简报中，它引用了卫星图像，显示风吹动了远离雅加达的爪哇岛西端万丹的一组植物产生的污染。然而，Myllyvirta 对此提出批评，称该部未能考察中爪哇省和西爪哇省雅加达上风口的工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 Myllyvirta 称，印度尼西亚煤炭公司的政治利益使该部很难至少三名印度尼西亚内阁部长和其他政界人士持有这些公司的大量股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部长普拉博沃·苏比安托 (Prabowo Subianto) 与私营 Nusantara 能源公司及其子公司 Nusantara Kaltim 煤炭公司有联系。旅游和创意经济部长桑迪亚加·乌诺 (Sandiaga Uno) 拥有投资公司 Saratoga Investama Sedaya 21.51% 的股份，该公司与煤矿公司 Adaro Energy 有关联。海事和投资部长 Luhut Binsar Panjaitan 拥有 TBS Energi Utama 8% 的股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论排放源和排放水平如何，印度尼西亚宽松的环境法规和薄弱的执法力度进一步加剧了处理问题的挑战污染。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国的低燃料和排放标准导致车辆燃烧更脏的发动机燃料，过滤污染物的能力较低。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们可以说我们拥有它们”：El尼诺现象可能会毁掉印度尼西亚的热带冰川&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两轮和三轮车辆约占雅加达 2180 万辆汽车的 80%，其标准特别低。环境组织 KPBB 执行董事艾哈迈德·萨夫鲁丁 (Ahmad Safruddin) 表示，印度尼西亚的摩托车排放的某些污染物是汽车的四倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前的法规往往执行不力。在雅加达，车龄超过三年的车辆应该每年接受排放测试。 2020年，时任雅加达省长阿尼斯宣布了对未通过排放测试的车辆司机进行抽查和罚款的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，罚款计划于2021年12月被放弃，部分原因是雅加达警方质疑其可行性欧文表示，对每天进城的数百万司机实施措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但数据表明，监管措施会鼓励驾车者遵守规定。 2021 年，当司机预计新规则生效时，自愿接受排放测试的车辆数量猛增约 3,700%，达到 481,047 辆。取消罚款计划后，此类测试的数量几乎减少了一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;省政府此前曾表示要在明年实施罚款，现在承诺对违规驾驶者的罚款将从8 月 26 日。违规者可能面临两个月监禁或最高 50 万卢比的罚款。轻便摩托车骑手将面临最高 25 万卢比的罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国能否认真对待气候问题，同时为印度尼西亚炼油厂付出代价？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于燃煤电厂来说，情况类似。印度尼西亚的排放标准明显低于其他产煤国。根据 CREA 的一项研究，印度尼西亚燃煤电厂合法排放的氮氧化物（“三大”空气污染物之一）几乎是中国燃煤电厂的六倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境部还2019 年对所有发电厂提出了严格的新排放标准。但由于现有发电厂和根据政府合同建设的发电厂被豁免，这些标准很快就被淡化了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“雅加达受到如此多关注的原因是其他城市，尤其是中国城市，[在应对空气污染方面]取得了很大进步。”Myllyvirta 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，有迹象表明情况可能会发生变化。环境部一个专注于解决大雅加达地区空气污染问题的工作组已任命了四名涉嫌违反空气污染法规的嫌疑人。嫌疑人包括一家经营铜冶炼厂的投资公司的董事，以及四名焚烧电子垃圾的经营者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8月18日，政府还宣布收紧排放标准，蒸汽发电站和重工业大雅加达地区的工厂必须开始使用洗涤器——用于去除对环境有害的物质的设备。不过，尚未具体说明时间表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于雅加达的电力和交通基础设施问题，当局面临的清理雅加达空气标准的任务具有挑战性，Yayasan Indonesia Cerah 的执行董事 Adhityani Putri 表示。支持印度尼西亚的能源转型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发展有点像一艘改变方向的大型油轮 - 一开始发生得非常缓慢，”Adhityani 说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea spy satellite launch ends in failure, again]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3232098/north-korea-spy-satellite-launch-ends-failure-again?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 08:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/78ab9dcc-16dc-4e3c-bb37-413b600576fc_4d066afb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;朝鲜最近一次将间谍卫星送入轨道的尝试以失败告终媒体周四称，就在平壤首次发射升空后不久坠入大海的几个月后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜领导人金正恩已将发展天眼作为政权的首要任务，朝鲜国家航天发展局“在新型卫星上第二次发射了侦察卫星 Malligyong-1” 8月24日凌晨，千里马一号运载火箭在平安北道铁山郡西海卫星发射场发射。”官方媒体报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“火箭第一级和第二级飞行正常，但由于第三阶段飞行期间紧急爆破系统出现故障，发射失败，”朝鲜中央通讯社官方报道补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它声称“相关事故的原因是不是一个大问题”，并誓言在调查问题并采取措施解决问题后，将在 10 月份进行第三次发射。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国参谋长联席会议表示，在当地时间凌晨 3:50 左右检测到了这次发射。 “朝鲜声称这是一枚太空运载火箭”，并称该弹丸已“穿越了黄海上空的国际空域”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我军正保持全面战备态势，并与美国密切配合”参谋长联席会议补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次发射首先是由日本政府发出的，日本政府称平壤使用了被禁止的弹道导弹技术，并且该弹丸飞越了该国附近的领空。冲绳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从确保受影响居民以及飞机和船只安全的角度来看，朝鲜最近的这次发射是非常有问题的，”日本最高政府发言人松野裕和表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;平壤周二告诉日本海岸警卫队，发射将于 8 月 24 日至 31 日之间进行，促使东京调动船只及其 PAC-3 导弹防御系统，以防有任何物体降落在其领土上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次发射是在华盛顿、首尔和东京领导人在美国戴维营会晤几天后进行的，也是在周一美韩举行大型联合军事演习之后进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被称为“乙支自由之盾”，这项年度演习一直激怒平壤，并已成为朝鲜黑客的攻击目标，演习将持续到 8 月 31 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国谴责此次发射，称朝鲜在“鲁莽的挑衅”上浪费资源。韩国青瓦台周四表示，在经济困境中，韩国正在为朝鲜采取进一步的军事行动做准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国周三敦促朝鲜不要采取进一步的威胁活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国周三敦促朝鲜不要采取进一步的威胁活动。美国国务院发言人表示，“太空运载火箭采用的技术与弹道导弹（包括洲际弹道导弹）所使用的技术相同且可以互换”，并批评朝鲜的最新投标违反了联合国安理会多项决议国际战略研究所研究员约瑟夫·登普西 (Joseph Dempsey) 表示：“虽然仍然失败，但这次飞行比之前的尝试取得了更大进展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“太空很难， with failure and lessons learned often part of the development of ultimately successful evolving designs,” he said, adding it was “unclear exactly what [North Korea] meant by emergency blasting system, possibly a reference to separation of the third stage.”&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;In May, Pyongyang launched what it described as its first military reconnaissance satellite, but the rocket carrying it, the “Chollima-1” – named after a mythical horse that often features in official propaganda – plunged into the sea minutes after take-off.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crash sparked a complex, 36-day South Korean salvage operation involving a fleet of naval rescue ships, minesweepers and deep-sea divers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s inaction on North Korea could backfire as US ramps up pressure: analysts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The retrieved parts of the rocket and the satellite were analysed by experts in South Korea and the United States, who later said it had no military utility as a reconnaissance satellite.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea&#39;s ruling party “bitterly” criticised the officials responsible for the crash in June, according to state media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations between the two Koreas are at their lowest point in years , and diplomacy is stalled after failed attempts in recent years to discuss Pyongyang&#39;s denuclearisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kim has declared North Korea an “irreversible” nuclear power and has called for ramped-up arms production, including tactical nuclear weapons.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters, Kyodo&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Victims of good student mentality’: urge to please sees rise of new China workplace phenomenon in which ‘model students’ face exploitation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231890/victims-good-student-mentality-urge-please-sees-rise-new-china-workplace-phenomenon-which-model?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/519ed95e-3a8b-4232-a974-76d0eec1b485_46e159bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A phenomenon has emerged in China in which people who gained academic success by strictly complying with their teachers and parents while at school are becoming more susceptible to exploitation in the workplace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These so-called “model students” are products of a traditional Chinese education system which emphasises obedience to teachers, compliance with parental commands, excessive self-reflection and a relentless pursuit of excellence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This seemingly positive pathway can inadvertently set the stage for challenges as an adult because of the struggle to break free from deeply ingrained obedience to authority.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The behaviour is often driven by the continual urge to complete tasks to earn praise and recognition from superiors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another characteristic is excessive self-reflection.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When faced with pressure to perform and criticism from their superiors, “model individuals” often believe any shortcomings their own fault.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some may even experience “leave shame” and avoid taking time off work, even to the extent that it adversely affects their health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such people are often derided on social media where they are referred to as the “chosen ones”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ironically, while at first blush they may appear ideal job candidates, in some cases they end up facing the most exploitation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January this year, a group of these “heartbroken” and bewildered individuals formed a community called “Victims of the Good Student Mentality” on Douban, a social networking service and China&#39;s best-known ratings site for books and movies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The community has grown rapidly, amassing more than 77,000 members on Douban in just seven months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the group&#39;s profile, members embrace the motto “Goodbye to being a goody-two-shoes student. I&#39;m awarding myself a certificate of achievement.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Members share their experiences of becoming “model students” and analyse how this mentality blocks career development and damages psychological well-being.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a post shared on August 18, one person suggested that unconditional obedience to authority could be a form of trauma.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What I find terrifying is that I have even chosen to cope by automatically completing tasks requested by others before they even issue the command! This way, I can avoid being commanded. This essentially amounts to self-mutilation and self-domestication,” the person said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So taking back autonomy is the key! Make your own decisions, take responsibility and regain a sense of control over your life,” they added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Fang , professor of psychology at Beijing Normal University, told The Beijing News: “From a psychological perspective, the fundamental cost of this mentality is the disappearance of one&#39;s true self.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Every individual is inherently valuable, but under prolonged conditioning, &#39;good students&#39; instinctively start believing that they only hold value when certain conditions are met,” said Wang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it is important for us to be aware of this in order to reclaim ourselves and rediscover the subjectivity we have surrendered to others. Such individuals should embrace self-acceptance, self-affirmation, self-care and self-love,” she added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America expert takes over as head of Chinese friendship association]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3232054/latin-america-expert-takes-over-head-chinese-friendship-association?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/e1cf4221-0d09-4fbb-8716-3e2e132149fe_b91dce05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A seasoned Chinese diplomat with a focus on Latin America is the new chief of a semi-official body tasked with promoting people-to-people exchanges with other nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Wanming, 59, was introduced as president of the Chinese People&#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries (CPAFFC) at a gathering it hosted on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was attending the opening ceremony of a five-day event aimed at boosting youth exchanges between China and Russia, according to a post published on the association&#39;s WeChat account on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang has replaced Lin Songtian, a veteran diplomat and Africa expert who had been president of the association since 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CPAFFC is a semi-official association whose mission – to expand friendly exchanges between China and other countries – is also part of Beijing&#39;s broader diplomatic strategy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has played a role in efforts to improve ties with the United States through people-to-people exchanges at a time when Beijing and Washington are at loggerheads over many issues, from trade and technology to the South China Sea and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That includes an event it organised in February 2022, which was attended by Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi and former US Treasury secretary Jacob Lew. It focused on the joint communique agreed to by the US and China in Shanghai 50 years ago that marked the start of a thaw in bilateral ties after two decades of confrontation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang&#39;s appointment comes as Beijing is seeking closer economic and security ties with nations in Latin America such as Brazil, moves which have been met with suspicion and concern in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is now Latin America&#39;s second-largest trading partner after the United States, according to data released in June by the Council on Foreign Relations, a US think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The region is also part of a diplomatic tussle with Taiwan, which Beijing claims as part of its territory. Honduras switched formal diplomatic recognition from Taipei to Beijing in March, leaving self-ruled Taiwan with just 13 official allies – seven of them in Latin America and the Caribbean.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s rising clout in Latin America setting off alarm bells: US general&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing has traditionally appointed public figures or diplomats well-versed in China&#39;s foreign policy to head up the CPAFFC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang&#39;s predecessor Lin was previously the Chinese ambassador to Liberia, Malawi and South Africa. Li Xiaolin, the daughter of former premier Li Peng, was CPAFFC president before him and did a stint in the US embassy in the 1990s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang has decades of experience in Latin American affairs. He was China&#39;s ambassador to Brazil, Argentina and Chile in the 2010s and had previously worked at the foreign ministry&#39;s Department of Latin American and Caribbean Affairs since the mid-2000s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April last year, Yang was named as the deputy director of China&#39;s top government agency overseeing Hong Kong affairs.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wagner boss Yevgeny Prigozhin joins list of Putin foes who suffered mysterious fates]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3232097/wagner-boss-yevgeny-prigozhin-joins-list-putin-foes-who-suffered-mysterious-fates?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 07:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/4f5a5d62-f5bc-4478-9ed4-5553ea08a347_e4e291b6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russian mercenary chief Yevgeny Prigozhin is believed dead after a private plane on which he was listed as a passenger crashed north of Moscow with no survivors on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wagner Group boss, 62, spearheaded a mutiny against Russia&#39;s top army brass on June 23-24, which President Vladimir Putin said could have tipped Russia into civil war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others who have opposed Putin or his interests have also died or come close to death under unclear circumstances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Here are some details about these mysterious incidents:&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s most prominent opposition leader, Alexei Navalny, was flown to Germany in August 2020 for medical treatment after being poisoned in Siberia with what Western experts concluded was the military nerve agent Novichok.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia has denied any involvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Navalny earned admiration around the world for voluntarily returning to Russia in 2021. He was immediately arrested on arrival. He is now serving sentences totalling 11½ years on fraud and other charges that he says are bogus. His political movement has been outlawed and declared “extremist”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Navalny had an extra 19 years in a maximum security penal colony added to his jail term recently.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A former Russian double agent who passed secrets to British intelligence, Sergei Skripal and his daughter Yulia were found unconscious on a bench outside a shopping centre in the English cathedral city of Salisbury in March 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were taken to hospital in critical condition, and British officials said they had been poisoned with Novichok, a group of nerve agents developed by the Soviet military in the1970s and 1980s. Both survived.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia has denied any role in the poisoning and said Britain was whipping up anti-Russian hysteria.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Alexander Litvinenko, an ex-KGB agent and outspoken critic of Putin, died in 2006 aged 43 after drinking green tea laced with polonium-210, a rare and potent radioactive isotope, at London&#39;s Millennium Hotel, British officials have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin probably approved the killing, a British inquiry concluded in 2016. The Kremlin has denied involvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An inquiry led by a senior British judge found that former KGB bodyguard Andrei Lugovoy and another Russian, Dmitry Kovtun, carried out the killing as part of an operation that he said was probably directed by Russia&#39;s Federal Security Service (FSB), the main heir to the Soviet-era KGB.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Litvinenko fled Russia for Britain six years to the day before he was poisoned.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Viktor Yushchenko, then a Ukrainian opposition leader, was poisoned during the campaign for the 2004 presidential election in which he ran on a pro-Western ticket against the pro-Moscow Prime Minister Viktor Yanukovich.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he was poisoned while having dinner outside Kyiv with officials from the Ukrainian security services. Russia denied any involvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His body was found to contain 1,000 times more dioxin than is normally present. His face and body were disfigured by the poisoning, and he had dozens of operations in the aftermath.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He won the presidency in a re-run poll after Ukraine&#39;s Supreme Court struck down results declaring Yanukovich the winner amid street protests dubbed the “Orange Revolution”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Anna Politkovskaya, a journalist who reported on human rights abuses, was shot dead outside her flat in Moscow on October 7,2006, after returning home from the supermarket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The murder of Politkovskaya, a 48-year-old mother of two, provoked an outcry in the West and underlined concerns about the dangers to reporters working in Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 44-year-old Russian was found dead near his luxury home on an exclusive gated estate outside London after he had been out jogging in November 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alexander Perepilichny sought refuge in Britain in 2009 after helping a Swiss investigation into a Russian money-laundering scheme. His sudden death raised suggestions he might have been murdered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;British police ruled out foul play despite suspicions he might have been murdered with a rare poison. A pre-inquest hearing heard that traces of a rare and deadly poison from the gelsemium plant was found in his stomach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perepilichny had enjoyed a large bowl of soup containing sorrel, a popular Russian dish. Russia denied involvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From Kuaishou to iQiyi, Chinese tech firms see stronger profits as they tout potential of generative AI]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3232070/kuaishou-iqiyi-chinese-tech-firms-see-stronger-profits-they-tout-potential-generative-ai?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/643e52df-8db0-45d9-bcda-571bf9d40b65_81c5eb7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese technology companies got back on track for growth in the second quarter, as they continue to pin high hopes on generative artificial intelligence (AI) services amid uncertainties in the macro environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Short-video app operator Kuaishou Technology on Tuesday posted quarterly revenue of 27.7 billion yuan (US$3.8 billion), up 27.9 per cent from the same period in 2022. The increase was primarily attributed to growth of its online marketing services, live-streaming and e-commerce business, the company said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Profit reached 1.48 billion yuan, compared with a 3.18 billion loss in the June quarter last year, marking the company&#39;s “first-ever group-level net profit in a quarter since our listing on the [Hong Kong] stock exchange in 2021”, Kuaishou said in its earnings report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like other Chinese Big Tech companies from Tencent Holdings to Baidu, Kuaishou is betting on advances in AI technology to improve its services. The company is set to join the sector&#39;s heated competition with the release of its own large language model KwaiYii this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng Yixiao, chief executive of Kuaishou, said in the post-earnings conference call that the company has begun an internal test of its chatbot &#39;Kuaishou AI conversation&#39; in Kuaishou&#39;s Android app, calling it the “first intelligent conversation product based on large language models in the short-video and live-streaming industry”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng expects KwaiYii to facilitate users in generating text, images, audio and videos during the content creation process, and help the company understand its users and make better recommendations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Generative AI has become a popular pitch among China&#39;s tech executives, as they try to convince investors about their growth potential under an uncertain economic environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gong Yu, chief executive of video-streaming giant iQiyi, said in a post-earnings call on Tuesday that the company had been using generative AI to improve the quality of scripts and the assessment process of online shows. The technology also helped generate advertising ideas, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been applying generative AI in content production, marketing and user interaction, and received encouraging initial results,” Gong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;iQiyi, majority-owned by search giant Baidu, reported a 17 per cent jump in second-quarter revenue to 7.8 billion yuan, driven by growth in subscription and advertising. Net income reached 365.2 million yuan, compared to a net loss of 214 million yuan in the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Netflix-style streaming platform posted its first quarterly profit in a decade in the March quarter last year following steep job cuts and cost control on content spending, but it swung back to losses in face of economic headwinds before managing to stay profitable for three consecutive quarters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;iQiyi&#39;s rival Bilibili also reported better results in the June quarter, posting an 8 per cent growth in sales to 5.3 billion yuan on the back of its strengthening advertising business. Losses narrowed by 23 per cent from a year ago to 1.5 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a call with analysts, Bilibili chief executive Chen Rui described AI generated content (AIGC) as a revolutionary technology that could improve the company&#39;s video and anime content. He added that the company had applied AIGC in various scenarios, including voice generation for virtual idols and content moderation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s low fertility rate shows urgency of creating a more family-friendly society]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231882/hong-kongs-low-fertility-rate-shows-urgency-creating-more-family-friendly-society?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/557a67cf-f25c-41ac-be26-af7aa4d7f8dc_4ca72961.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s population growth is facing significant challenges, the biggest being the city&#39;s low fertility rate and an ageing society. According to the government&#39;s latest population projections, the total fertility rate stood at 0.772 births per woman in 2021, well below the replacement level of 2.1, and is expect to decline further and remain at a lower level in the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest survey from the Hong Kong Family Planning Association also showed that the average number of children per married woman has dropped to a historic low of 0.9. The proportion of childless women has reached 43.2 per cent, more than doubling since 2017, replacing women with one child (27.4 per cent) as the mainstream in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the government has taken various measures to encourage childbirth, such as increasing the length of maternity and paternity leave, these measures appear to have had little impact. This is because young people in Hong Kong, as in other high-income Asian societies, must weight various factors when choosing marriage and childbirth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These include high housing and living costs, an increase in the proportion of women participating in the workforce, and higher levels of education. These factors make it more difficult for young people to afford the costs of childbirth and child-rearing, leading to low fertility rates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government has adopted a more optimistic outlook, estimating that total fertility rates will bounce back, to above 0.9 by 2026, which is unlikely given that fertility rates in the city have been falling for decades. This suggests that an additional 10,000 babies at least would be born in Hong Kong each year. However, we are in a low-fertility trap and have little chance of slowing the decline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, the government assumes our population will be replenished by net gains in migration that offset the natural decrease. In an era of globalisation, immigration is an important factor in population growth. In Hong Kong, an international city, immigration plays a crucial role in population growth and is also an important force in promoting cultural assimilation and social development. Immigration can bring new talent and innovation, promoting economic development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, it is also essential that these immigrants adapt and integrate well, or they may not stay long. This could even have a negative impact on attempts to build a better society and economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government&#39;s estimates for net gains from foreign talent and one-way permit holder arrivals are still fluid and uncertain. Even if the projections for births and migrants are accurate, Hong Kong would still face an acute ageing situation, with one in three people aged 65 or older by 2046. These trends will have far-reaching impacts on the city&#39;s economic and social development, necessitating a comprehensive response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of the negative effects will appear decades later but they can be felt even now with the closure of schools and kindergartens. The city&#39;s financial and economic development and sustainability face many difficulties. Piecemeal efforts will not be effective.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The course of Hong Kong&#39;s population is not set in stone as it is based on assumptions that could be wrong. Nevertheless, it gives us a glimpse of our future. If we want to avoid this scenario, we must take action to ensure the current projections do not become reality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We need a comprehensive response. To achieve sustainable and healthier population development, more incentives are needed for young people to have children. These could include expanding maternity leave, building more nurseries and kindergartens, and offering child allowances and tax reductions. Such measures can help alleviate financial and social barriers that young families face when considering having children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additionally, we must increase support for couples with children, such as by providing family allowances, reducing education expenses and offering more family medical services. These measures can help families raise their children, and will promote population growth and development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, we must promote policies that attract more high-quality professionals, boosting economic development and population growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;More Hongkongers say no thanks to marriage, babies&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, we must also ensure these migrants have a safe and comfortable environment in which to live and work. Efforts should also be made to slow the outflow of residents and make Hong Kong a place known for retaining talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ageing will become more acute and institutional care won&#39;t be enough. We need to promote community support and make it possible for more people to remain at home as they get older.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For those without someone to care for them, we need to build more nursing homes, offer better medical services and implement elderly care policies to ensure they can live a healthy and comfortable life. Achieving healthy population development requires the support of society and policy changes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s fertility rate is expected to keep falling amid the increasing prevalence to delay marriage and women remaining single, as well as the stable trend of low birth rates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Good family planning education and awareness is critical. We need to remove barriers to fertility for those who want to have children and create a more family-friendly social environment. There is no silver bullet for raising the fertility rate – but a caring, warm and happy living environment will certainly help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[High-stakes Zimbabwe election spills into day two as opposition alleges rigging]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3232096/high-stakes-zimbabwe-election-spills-day-two-opposition-alleges-rigging?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 06:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/344c2f8d-a833-4357-bb4d-03f2a6b8baff_181bd029.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Zimbabwe&#39;s president Wednesday extended voting by another day after long delays marred the start of balloting in key districts and sparked opposition accusations of “rigging” and “voter suppression”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As polling began to close in some voting stations, it was only starting in others, prompting opposition accusations of vote manipulation after a campaign marked by tension and a clampdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I do, by this proclamation in respect of the affected polling stations for the wards … fix the 24 of August 2023 as the last day of polling,” President Emmerson Mnangagwa announced in a presidential directive contained in a government notice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Less than a quarter of polling stations in Harare – an opposition stronghold – opened on time, according to electoral authorities, who blamed the problem on delays in the printing of ballot papers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is a clear case of voter suppression, a classic case of Stone Age, antiquated, analog rigging,” Nelson Chamisa, 45, the head of the leading opposition party, the Citizens Coalition for Change (CCC) told a press conference in the capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chamisa is the main challenger to Mnangagwa, 80, who came to power after a coup that deposed late ruler Robert Mugabe in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mnangagwa is seeking a second term in an election that came on a backdrop of widespread discontent at the southern African country&#39;s economic troubles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The poll is being watched across southern Africa as a test of support for the ZANU-PF party, whose 43-year rule has been battered by an economic slump and charges of authoritarianism.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, Zimbabwe seek stronger ties as Harare prepares for elections&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chamisa blamed the governing ZANU-PF party, which has ruled the country since independence, for the delays, saying it was “desperate” to cling to power and risking plunging the country into a “crisis”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The electoral commission blamed the problem on delays in the printing of ballot papers “arising from numerous court challenges”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Polling in Harare&#39;s oldest suburb of Mbare started closing at around 7pm, while opening at another station in a suburb west of Harare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is a way to frustrate Harare voters. A way to manipulate the election results,” voter Tafadzwa Dhlodhlo said at a Warren Park polling station.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ballots at a school serving as a polling station in a poor neighbourhood arrived only after 2.30pm, whereas polling had been scheduled to start at 7am.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am so disappointed,” said Linda Phiri, 53, a mother of three who had been waiting for eight hours. “I&#39;m sleeping here. I want to cast that vote so that we are liberated,” said Phiri.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chamisa lashed out at the problems, saying it was a “classic of voter suppression” targeting CCC strongholds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The fact they have targeted Harare … is an indication that they are scared of people in the urban areas.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Zimbabwe unveils &#39;majestic&#39; US$200 million China-built parliament&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;At least 6.6 million people were registered to vote, with more than a million living in Harare. Publication of the results is legally required within five days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To clinch re-election, Mnangagwa must win an absolute majority or face a run-off.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Casting his ballot in his hometown of Kwekwe in central Zimbabwe, a confident Mnangagwa – nicknamed the “Crocodile” for his determination – said: “If I think I&#39;m not going to take it, then I will be foolish.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The opposition has been hoping to ride a wave of discontent over corruption, high inflation, unemployment and entrenched poverty.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>