<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Suicides in Singapore surge to more than 2-decade high amid ‘unseen mental distress’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3226211/suicides-singapore-surge-more-2-decade-high-amid-unseen-mental-distress?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 11:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/43ee58a0-b7f1-46ad-9715-8239535166f1_59a89387.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;去年新加坡的自杀率上升近 26%，达到逾 10 年来的最高水平据当地一家非政府组织称，二十年来，这反映了这个城市国家“看不见的精神困扰”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10-29岁的年轻人和70-79岁的老年人的自杀率尤其令人担忧，新加坡撒玛利亚预防中心 (SOS) 在其包含有关这一问题的统计数据的年度新闻稿中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年共有 476 人自杀，这是“自 2000 年以来记录的最高自杀死亡人数”，高于 378 人SOS 发布的消息称，一年前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看到新加坡自杀人数空前上升，令人深感心碎，”资深精神病学家兼心理健康顾问 Jared Ng 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这一增长描绘了我们社会中看不见的精神困扰的景象，特别是在我们的年轻人和老年人中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“至关重要的是，我们对继续严重影响心理健康的紧迫问题保持警惕，如社会孤立和孤独。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这真的很痛苦”：韩国加大打击自杀力度&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自杀“仍然是 10-29 岁青少年死亡的主要原因”新闻稿称，连续第四年自杀”，占该年龄段所有死亡人数的 33.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，该年龄段共有 125 人自杀，增加了 11.6%根据世界卫生组织 (WHO) 的数据，在全球范围内，自杀是 15-29 岁人群的第四大死因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在新加坡，据 SOS 称，去年，70 至 79 岁之间自杀的人数激增至 48 人，比 2021 年的 30 人增加了 60%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个城市国家拥有世界上自杀人数最多的国家之一。生育率最低，人口迅速老龄化，预计到 2030 年，四分之一的新加坡人将年满 65 岁或以上，而三年前这一比例为六分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SOS 首席执行官 Gasper Tan 表示，自杀是一种“这是一个受多种因素影响的复杂问题，包括心理健康挑战、社会压力和经济不确定性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认识到形势的紧迫性，并致力于继续采取积极措施来解决不断上升的自杀人数问题并为有需要的人提供支持。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界卫生组织称，全世界每年有超过 70 万人死于自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您有自杀念头，或者您认识某人，可以提供帮助。在香港，请拨打 +852 2896 0000 联系 The Samaritans，或 +852 2382 0000 联系自杀预防服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国，请拨打国家自杀预防生命热线 +1 800 273 8255。如需列表其他国家的求助热线，.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[United CEO apologises for taking private jet as airline cancels 750 flights, stranding thousands]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226209/united-ceo-apologises-taking-private-jet-airline-cancels-750-flights-stranding-thousands?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 10:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/37ec73c1-4a51-4ba2-b93d-08e78c1bb2b5_3fcab906.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国联合航空首席执行官斯科特·柯比 (Scott Kirby) 周五因跳上私人飞机离开而道歉由于该航空公司取消了新泽西州纽瓦克的大量航班，数千名美联航乘客被困在纽约地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“乘坐私人飞机是一个错误的决定，因为它对我们的客户不敏感。等待回家，”柯比在航空公司发布的一份声明中说。 “我真诚地向我们的客户和我们的团队成员致歉，他们连续几天夜以继日地工作（通常是在恶劣的天气下）来照顾我们的客户。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kirby 最后承诺“更好地表达我对我们团队成员的奉献精神和客户忠诚度的尊重。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，柯比搭乘从新泽西州泰特波罗飞往丹佛的私人航班，当时美联航取消了 750 趟航班 – 其中一-当天日程的第四个。该数字不包括联合快运 (United Express) 的航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合航空本周取消了近 3,000 架航班，其中纽瓦克自由国际机场枢纽航班取消数量最多，该机场本周大部分时间都遭受雷暴袭击。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;柯比将上周末纽瓦克的混乱归咎于联邦航空管理局空中交通管制员的短缺。他在给员工的一份说明中表示，“坦率地说，美国联邦航空管理局降低了飞机到达和离开机场的速度，让我们失望了”，而美联航是该机场的主要航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联航在整个过程中继续苦苦挣扎。本周，美国联邦航空管理局 (FAA) 所属部门的运输部长皮特·布蒂吉格 (Pete Buttigieg) 在 Twitter 上表示，“除美联航外”，航空公司已从风暴中恢复过来。他通过一个条形图将美联航的取消率与业内其他公司的取消率进行了比较，从而强调了这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自周中以来，美联航的运营有所改善。根据跟踪服务 FlightAware 的数据，取消航班的比例从周三的 26% 下降到周四的 18%，到周五晚上则下降到 8%。然而，即使在周五，美联航仍连续第七天在取消航班方面领先所有美国航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联航发誓要在 7 月 4 日假期周末及时修复其运营，该周末有望在全国机场的繁忙景象周四，超过 270 万人在运输安全管理局检查站接受了检查，周五预计也会有类似的人群，而且规模可能更大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联航乘客在社交媒体上向记者谈论了机场排长队和航班取消后在机场睡觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;代表航空公司飞行员和空乘人员的工会也加入了批评行列，指责美联航管理层规划不善，安排了太多航班。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong will never be a globally relevant sporting city if it treats sport with such wilful disregard]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/opinion/article/3226156/hong-kong-will-never-be-globally-relevant-sporting-city-if-it-treats-sport-such-wilful-disregard?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/45d2c9d4-0646-462d-89fd-af06a1a01f07_7c13cf31.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;政府拟收回香港高尔夫球部分控制权的消息粉岭的俱乐部没有任何明确的下一步计划，对于我们这些一直关注其体育整体态度的人来说，应该不会感到惊讶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提供休闲和文化如果不是完全符合城市对重大体育赛事的矛盾态度，那么服务部门对一个不知道如何管理的场地的责任将令人惊讶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的启德体育公园是一个完美的选择一个典型的例子：有 50,000 个座位的白象等待发生。体育场预计将于2025年全面竣工，目前我们所知道的是，新的零售大厅将有足够的空间容纳200家企业，为“游客和市民提供一站式的运动休闲、娱乐、餐饮和购物体验” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为在这座城市，你不可能不去古驰或蒂芙尼专卖店，就需要更多的购物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当谈到体育赛事、音乐会时，或任何填充体育场的计划，一片沉默。康文署在接受《华盛顿邮报》询问时表示，这不是他们的责任，而启德官员至少在五次不同的场合拒绝回答任何问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与其说香港是一个梦游之地，不如说是一个无关紧要的地方。官员们可能会将目光投向 2025 年的全运会，预计这座城市将举办多项赛事，其中包括具有讽刺意味的是，高尔夫。但这是除了国际七人榄球赛之外，该市未来几年举办的最盛大的活动。残酷的事实是，在中国之外，全运会并不是一场盛​​大的赛事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题就在于此。尽管香港曾举办过壁球、帆船、铁人三项和其他体育项目的亚洲锦标赛，但对于在该地区范围之外注册的赛事，香港却没什么可提供的。它有七人制橄榄球赛、两场高尔夫锦标赛、两场网球锦标赛，还有一场马拉松比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在香港高尔夫球场建造住房的备受争议的计划下一步是什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;其中，它正面临失去高尔夫球场以及唯一能够举办精英赛事的球场的严重危险，而政府似乎既不知道也不关心这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;粉岭俱乐部的命运是注定的引起争论。根据您的观点，它要么是对城市受压迫者的住房问题漠不关心的富裕精英的游乐场，要么是几十年来举办高水平高尔夫锦标赛的历史悠久的场地，通过赞助和旅游业吸引了数亿美元.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些在此基础上扩建的人指出，与保留的 46 个洞相比，被收回的面积相对较小，而故意忽视了着眼于发展的 8 个洞在举办重大赛事方面所发挥的重要作用.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后是马拉松比赛——由于有数以万计的人在 10 公里和 5 公里赛道上奔跑，其参赛人数大幅膨胀——它的声望远不及伦敦举办的顶级赛事，东京或纽约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论以何种标准衡量，国际七人制橄榄球赛都是皇冠上的明珠——所有参赛国家都想赢得比赛，所有支持者都想参观这项赛事。这是一项举世闻名的标志性赛事，为经济创造了数亿美元的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这是一个例外，男女精英网球的回归也是如此，对此负责的人应该承担责任&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此相比，新加坡除了壁球、羽毛球、铁人三项和七人制橄榄球赛之外，还有一级方程式赛车、欧洲巡回赛和 LIV 高尔夫，以及多个举办这些赛事的球场、Sail GP 和一些来自英超联赛、德甲联赛和意甲联赛的最大俱乐部将在今年夏天来到这里举办一场足球盛宴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与城邦国家的比较似乎有些陈词滥调，并且可以预见的是，当权者会因此而予以驳回。媒体炒作，或者更糟糕的是，只是作为一种吸引在线点击的方式，但在这种情况下，它们不仅合法，而且完全不可避免。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡可能会关闭其唯一的赛马场，但它比香港有更多的体育运动即使是印度尼西亚，其体育场破旧，足球流氓行为猖獗，安全标准值得怀疑，但在被剥夺举办权几个月后，也被认为有资格举办国际足联 17 岁以下世界杯。 20 岁以下版本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果香港没有什么其他可提供的，情况就会有所不同，但这是通往东方的门户，也是一座拥有无与伦比的传统的城市 - 非常适合吸引世界各地的年轻人顶尖的体育天才，但这似乎对此没什么兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这很奇怪，考虑到体育运动投入的资金数额，即使对其去向缺乏监督。香港体育学院每年获得 7 亿港元（8,900 万美元），其精英运动员在过去十年中获得了约 130 亿港元的回报——除了张家朗和西奥布汉·豪伊——仍在进行中。委婉地说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然其他国家政府为年轻运动员提供了发展道路，但香港仍然补贴一位靠着过去的辉煌过日子的 35 岁体操运动员，而她的继任者是一位 16 岁的澳大利亚运动员。从未在这座城市接受过指导。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，如果资金是一个问题，那么应该有足够的企业支持。国泰航空和汇丰银行支持七人榄球赛，渣打银行帮助利物浦来到新加坡，友邦保险赞助商托特纳姆热刺队和 3 Mobile 对这项运动并不陌生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果管理机构能够效仿橄榄球和网球的榜样，康文署和启德可以承担一些责任，除了金钱或负面影响之外，世界的目光没有理由不转向香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，也许事实是&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港在吸引游客和人才方面的蹩脚尝试充满了绝望&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为一个作为金融中心，任何人都不能说这座城市无关紧要，但如今这还不够。作为一个体育和娱乐目的地的无关紧要——酷玩乐队、泰勒·斯威夫特和碧昂丝跳过香港，但后街男孩却没有——是有原因的——可能很快就会导致成为一潭死水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府可能很高兴如果启德一年中有 51 周空置，那么它应该将所有土地交给开发商，专注于创造更多利润，让我们所有人摆脱真正成为体育城市的幻想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乔什·鲍尔 (Josh Ball) 是《华盛顿邮报》的体育新闻编辑&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader John Lee vows to win public trust with concrete actions and results as he marks first year in office, warns against ‘soft resistance’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226210/hong-kong-leader-vows-win-public-trust-concrete-actions-and-results-he-marks-first-year-office-warns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 10:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/e29b4b16-dd75-4936-8d5d-d5048d47aa2a_6e787c79.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港特首周六誓言将以实际行动和成果取信于民他庆祝了他就职的第一年，但警告说，香港仍必须警惕威胁国家安全的“软抵抗”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在纪念香港回归中国统治 26 周年的演讲中，行政长官李约翰 (John Lee)家超还表示，香港现正走上疫情后恢复正常的“快车道”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府将继续致力于务实努力、取得成果。我们将努力以行动赢得信任，以结果缩小差距，以成绩建立互信，团结社会各界。”李在湾仔会展中心举行的酒会上表示。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;李先生表示，他的政府在过去一年带领香港走出阴影，与世界和中国大陆重新建立联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出经济终于在四个季度出现逆转今年首季录得正增长，旅客入境人数在短短五个月内突破1,000万人次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对香港充满信心，但我们必须保持警惕，”他警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港李家耀上任一周年：看看他更具争议性的举动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他指出，香港基本稳定，但表示一些国家错误地判断了中国的“和平” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“利用‘软抵抗’的破坏性力量……仍然潜伏在我们的城市里。我们必须保持警惕，积极主动地维护国家安全，并全面忠实地贯彻‘一国两制’的原则。”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官承诺，他和他的官员将继续频繁出访内地和其他国家，与各界人士组成“强队”，为来年香港争取更多机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港特首反驳“唱衰” &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他亦借此机会盘点团队的成果，称各项人才计划五个月内已获批五万份申请，而“轻型公屋”计划则在5个月内批准了5万份申请。建造 30,000 个临时公寓还旨在将公共住房的等待时间缩短至 4.5 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李补充道，还推出了有关创新和技术、青年和初级医疗保健的不同蓝图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在附近金紫荆广场举行升旗仪式后不久，他向政界、商界和社区领袖发表讲话，高级官员出席了升旗仪式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李的侧翼包括前领导人梁振英，现任副主席国家最高政协委员、北京中联办主任郑彦雄，以及首席法官张居能和立法会主席梁君源。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的约翰李发誓要战胜住房危机，但表示这需要 10 年时间&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这是自 2020 年以来第一个没有任何流行病规则和社交距离限制（之前包括禁止聚会）的移交周年纪念日。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》早些时候报道称，将在全市各地部署 6,000 多名警察，并加强政府大楼、火车站和繁忙购物区的安保。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;领导人表示，香港已准备好重返国际舞台李约翰称&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;没有任何反对派组织寻求批准在当天举办集会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;疫情前一年一度的7月1日游行的组织者公民人权阵线已解散2021 年 8 月，即北京实施国家安全法一年后。维多利亚公园是年度示威活动的聚集地，今年的周年纪念展览占据了维多利亚公园的大部分区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hongkongers turn out for free tram, ferry rides to soak in celebratory mood marking 26th anniversary of handover]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3226208/hongkongers-turn-out-free-tram-ferry-rides-soak-celebratory-mood-marking-26th-anniversary-handover?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 09:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/a289cb65-9245-4091-b81a-48ef3bcc4934_bfb56e43.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港人于周六搭乘免费电车和渡轮开启了周末，标志着 26 日的到来这座城市回归中国统治周年纪念日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市还暂停了一些公共交通的票价，并免费开放主要博物馆，并举办文化活动来纪念 7 月 1 日。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;73岁的餐饮业退休雇员叶丹丽一大早出门，在铜锣湾家附近搭电车，几站后到健身房与朋友一起锻炼身体。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;她说她很喜欢免费乘车，因为她通常乘坐有轨电车出行，因为它们既方便又便宜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;叶补充说，她当天的行程是去喝茶，或者“喝茶” ” – 和朋友一起，下午第一次前往香港故宫文化博物馆和西九文化区艺术中心的 M+，因为在 7 月 1 日的促销活动下，这些景点免费入场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;她说：“我们很高兴庆祝7月1日的回归周年纪念日。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居住在铜锣湾的50岁司机曾志伟(Patrick Tsang)也乘坐电车到坚拿道上班。早上7.30左右到达西站。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“香港已走出政治泥潭，不应再走错路”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;曾荫权表示，他每天乘电车上下班，周六则免费乘车总共可以为他节省港币 6 元。他补充说，他计划下班后趁机乘坐有轨电车到处走走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“免费乘车很好，可以省钱，”他说。 “如果我今天早下班，天气好的话，我就会乘坐有轨电车出行，因为这是免费的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月1日至5日，居民可以免费乘坐城市有轨电车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;天星小轮尖沙咀至湾仔航线、置富小轮中环至红磡航线以及连接尖东、湾仔、中环和西区的水上的士也于周六免费开放九龙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月1日生日的乘客可免费乘搭屯门-东涌-沙螺湾-大澳及北角-观塘-启德渡轮航线。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;早上8点30分，湾仔渡轮码头约有50人等待搭车前往尖沙咀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括43岁的Peter Yang，他在航运业工作。周六，他带着9岁的女儿和朋友12岁的儿子出去感受节日气氛。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为期两个月的购物节会提振香港的零售、餐饮业吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;身穿红衣庆祝回归周年的杨先生说，他很早就和孩子们一起出去，观看码头附近的合唱团，并乘坐免费渡轮欣赏维多利亚港的景色。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;香港零售商将提供1.5亿港元的折扣、优惠让人们微笑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们正在体验和享受7月1日的庆祝气氛，”来自中国大陆的杨说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港政府高度重视回归纪念日，市民也感受到了节日气氛。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了电车和渡轮外，除东铁线沿线服务外，港铁公司运营的轻铁列车和巴士也提供免费乘车服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，当局还为居民提供免费乘车服务。 M+及西九文化区香港故宫文化博物馆七个专题展览。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“恨不能选择”：香港人对7月1日杂货折扣冷淡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;包括遗产博物馆、科学博物馆和艺术博物馆在内的各个公共博物馆的特别展览以及科学博物馆和太空博物馆的常设展览也是免费入场的，但太空剧院的演出除外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他优惠还包括免费使用公共休闲设施、餐厅用餐折扣、商场促销以及一系列社区庆祝活动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will China’s experiment to promote low-carbon living to its 1.4 billion people work?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226076/will-chinas-experiment-promote-low-carbon-living-its-14-billion-people-work?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/7357a2e4-1517-440a-b4d8-9968e7912b13_f8c2c50d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;过去两个月，北京大学二年级学生Mandy Chen技术专业的她总是在淘宝上发布自己的照片，包括在星巴克前拿着可重复使用的杯子摆姿势、爬楼梯和关灯的照片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几分钟之内，她就从购物应用程序中获得了十几分作为奖励。根据淘宝人工智能算法，陈的行动通过使用可重复使用的杯子减少了15.7克碳排放，通过不乘电梯减少了19.5克碳排放，通过节省电费减少了65.50克。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经过前7天的勤奋发帖陈女士用积分兑换了淘宝上的十几卷可降解垃圾袋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只要坚持下去，就能得到源源不断的免费垃圾袋。”现在正在拯救她的陈女士说道。积分可以换取更好的东西，例如现金券、零食和水瓶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈利用 Carbon88 来帮助超过8亿淘宝用户采取可持续的生活方式。该平台列出并奖励用户 70 多种低碳行为，从乘坐公共交通工具到购买二手物品。它还推荐其认为环境可持续的产品，并为用户购买积分提供积分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国全力以赴兑现2030年温室气体排放达到峰值、2060年实现净零排放的承诺从增加可再生能源的使用到建立全球最大的碳交易市场，地方政府和企业都在努力实现个体层面的减排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国公民人均年生活方式碳排放量为5根据柏林智库 Hot or Cool Institute 2021 年的一份报告，该机构研究了芬兰、英国、日本、巴西和印度等 10 个国家，2019 年的产量仅为加拿大平均产量的三分之一多一点。然而，全国14亿人口使得2019年中国整体生活方式的碳足迹是加拿大的13倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这导致了像Carbon88这样基于更大碳排放量开发的个人碳核算平台的兴起。碳普惠是汉语中“碳”和“普惠制”的组合，由中国南部广东省政府于 2015 年首次推出。鼓励个人、家庭和中小企业脱碳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;个人居民可以通过在地方政府和公司开发的网站和应用程序上设立帐户来参与碳普会。与Carbon88一样，这些项目会奖励他们选择可持续生活方式的积分，这些积分可用于折扣或公共服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社区和中小企业也可以通过发起植树造林计划等碳减排项目来参与碳普汇。屋顶太阳能装置。一旦这些项目获得批准，他们可以使用获得的积分来抵消自己的排放，或者将其出售给需要碳抵消的其他人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“数字化是碳普汇的基础。”总经理陶兰说北京碳普汇解决方案提供商 Green Inclusive 帮助市政府在微信上开发了一款小应用程序，以在去年冬奥会期间促进可持续发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着应用程序渗透到日常生活的方方面面，从数字支付到陶说，对于网上购物，个人不可避免地会留下数字痕迹，这使得微信和支付宝等无处不在的超级应用程序很容易收集与其碳足迹相关的个人数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的快速城市化和生活水平的提高报告显示，2017年，城镇居民因用电直接排放二氧化碳2.7亿吨，农村居民直接排放二氧化碳2.89亿吨。中国能源基金会于 2021 年发布的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于美国的非营利组织估计，中国公民的直接碳排放量将在 2037 年达到峰值 6.73 亿吨，比国家目标晚 7 年，之后下降至 441 吨到 2050 年，排放量将达到 100 万吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该基金会的数据，2017 年，与商品和服务消费相关的人口间接排放量约为 41.5 亿吨。预计2030年将增至约50亿吨，到2050年将逐步下降至32.2亿吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“消费已成为制约中国经济整体绿色转型的重要方面，”该基金会表示。并补充说，社会的低碳转型将有效减少排放，为国家净零目标做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到这一点，越来越多的企业和地方政府正在开发自己的碳普汇应用程序。去年5月，平安银行推出了“个人碳账户”，根据客户的消费习惯计算个人减排量，并对用户的绿色行动进行奖励。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到目前为止，中国几乎所有的城市和城市都已推出“个人碳账户”。上海、北京、山东等省市政府已推出“探普会”应用程序或宣布计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不可否认，探普会对于提高公民气候变化意识具有积极作用，因为它鼓励人们关注气候变化。”改变生活方式以减少碳足迹，”绿色和平组织驻北京气候与能源项目负责人刘俊彦说。 “但不太可能达到该机制预期的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;书面记录和审计如何帮助中国对抗洗绿祸害&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;专家表示，普及探普汇的一个明显挑战是数据安全说。获得用户同意让应用程序跟踪每个人的碳足迹并保护大量数据将是一项艰巨的任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个挑战是验证用户的低碳行为。例如，Carbon88 只需要一张照片。如果用户选择上传一张关闭空调的照片来赚取碳信用额，然后立即将其重新打开，则没有实际的减排量，平台也无法发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开发刘认为，科学方法来计算某种可持续行为的确切排放量也是一个重大挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要计算个人的低碳行为，找到‘基线’碳足迹至关重要，并看看他们的行为变化是否会产生额外的排放赤字。”她补充说，找到基线极其困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与工业部门相比，个人行为和选择很难预测，而且相关的排放源也很复杂。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;探普汇应用程序是否真正鼓励用户减少排放尚不清楚。在被称为“小红书”的中国流行社交媒体应用程序小红书上，与碳普汇相关的最受欢迎的讨论不是可持续行为，而是如何快速赚取碳信用额和兑换产品的技巧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “如果消费者受到参与碳普汇计划所获得的现金券的激励，购买更多他们不一定需要的产品，这实际上会产生更多的消费排放，”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeff Chen总部位于上海的碳管理公司妙盈科技副总裁表示，探普汇应用程序的激增可能会导致同一碳减排行动在不同平台上多次注册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前缺乏“国家监管机构自上而下的指导，而地方政府和企业都有自己的探普汇平台。”陈说。他自己的公司在 2021 年推出了探普汇应用程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些气候专家的批评更为严厉厦门大学中国能源政策研究院院长林伯强表示：“无论是地方政府还是大型互联网公司主导的，这都是一场闹剧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;林指出，通过提供奖励来鼓励公民参与环保行为并不是实现目标的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，林说他希望看到一个上限和-为个人设定碳预算的贸易模式，允许他们交易未使用的排放配额，类似于欧盟碳市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，在国家或欧盟层面上个人碳配额方面几乎没有发生什么in Europe, according to Tina Fawcett, associate professor at the Environmental Change Institute at the University of Oxford.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Introducing mandatory tradeable personal carbon allowances is difficult in China and elsewhere, not only practically but philosophically, unless the scheme is carefully designed and fair to everyone, said Fawcett.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, if personal carbon schemes remain voluntary, with no penalties for high emissions [and] only rewards for lowering emissions, then the effect is likely to be limited compared with carbon reductions needed to meet national and international targets,” Fawcett said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the challenges that need to be addressed, incentives like Tanpuhui could still be a valuable addition to the current carbon-reduction policies, Fawcett said, adding that it could encourage companies and authorities to provide more low-carbon options.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some countries are experimenting with similar programmes on smaller scales. For example, the Finnish city of Lahti trialled a project from 2018 to 2020, developing a model for personal carbon trading and an application that enabled real-time tracking and visualisation of one&#39;s transport carbon footprint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With China still far behind developed countries on lifestyle emissions and eager to grow its economy, consumption-related emissions still have room to grow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So what can individuals do to reduce carbon emissions?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The key is to continue to increase awareness and use the power of the masses to hold governments and enterprises accountable, according to Greenpeace&#39;s Liu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citizens should realise they have the power to take part in grander climate change topics and demand bigger changes even on the policy front, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think this is something we need to talk about in addition to promoting and advocating individual behavioural changes; we as a part of society can call for more systemic changes.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Chen said Carbon88 has helped her become environmentally conscious and made her adopt a greener lifestyle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I didn&#39;t know that my actions could produce such carbon emissions,” she said. “Now I feel good for what I&#39;m doing to make this world a tiny bit better.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How US deals with ‘natural partner’ India could boost defence, tech cooperation amid China tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3226171/how-us-deals-natural-partner-india-could-boost-defence-tech-cooperation-amid-china-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/0d92b0ff-ed77-4b05-a6a9-da42a691be32_8786cbcf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s defence capabilities are set for a boost following a series of deals signed with the United States, in what experts say is also an indication of Washington&#39;s desire to draw New Delhi closer to counter China&#39;s influence in the Indo-Pacific region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreements, signed during Prime Minister Narendra Modi&#39;s meeting with US President Joe Biden in Washington last week, spanned everything from clean energy to medicines. Two on defence and technology stand out as they are likely to mark a departure from Delhi&#39;s years of dependency on Russia for arms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the linchpin of the agreements is the defence framework to make India strong and augment its deterrent capabilities,” said Ashok Mehta, a retired lieutenant general in the Indian army and an independent defence analyst.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Americans have been constantly suggesting that India wean itself of dependence on Russia for military equipment and therefore the current agreements are indicative of that.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In particular, a deal between US firm GE and India&#39;s state-run Hindustan Aeronautics Limited to co-produce GE-F414 jet engines is a high point as it envisages technology transfers in equipment currently available only to Russia, Britain and France.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The engine deal is expected to equip India&#39;s home-grown Tejas light -combat aircraft, which are meant to replace many the of Russian-made planes that for decades have formed the bulk of the Indian Air Force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delhi has been struggling to build its own fighter-jet engines since the eighties and the Americans&#39; willingness to part with the technology – though subject to conditions – showed the relationship had come a long way, Mehta said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India also plans to purchase General Atomics&#39; MQ-9B High Altitude Long Endurance (HALE) unmanned aerial vehicles, to aid its efforts patrolling maritime and land borders amid tensions with China ever since a border clash three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 70 per cent of the combat aircraft in India&#39;s air force are of Russian make and design, such as the Sukhoi Su-30MKI fighter jet. Most of the tanks in India&#39;s army are Russian-made T-72s and T-90s. Several of India&#39;s naval frigate warships, too, are Russian-made, as is one of the country&#39;s two aircraft carriers, the INS Vikramaditya.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But defence ties between the two nations have come under strain as Moscow has prioritised supplies of spare parts to its own forces to fight the war with Ukraine, which has hit operations of a number of India&#39;s main Su-30 fighter aircraft, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Indian Air Force says it needs 42 aircraft squadrons to protect the country from simultaneous attacks from Pakistan and China, but it only has 31. Over the past seven years, it has been introducing the Indian-designed Tejas powered by US-made F-404-GE-IN20 engines to replace an ageing fleet of MIG-21s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The F-414 engine is expected to equip Tejas Mark 2, a bigger and more powerful aircraft than its predecessor. It will also be used in India&#39;s next-generation HAL Advanced Medium Combat Aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delhi has stepped up efforts to manufacture defence equipment at home ever since its border clash with China three years ago, and raised the foreign investment limit in the defence industry to 74 per cent from 49 per cent for granting automatic approvals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The GE-HAL deal to co-produce F-414 engines in India will need US government approval. It is expected to take three years to build the factory, and at least four to five years before the first engine rolls out, which means it will not be able to help India reduce its dependency on Russia soon, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, India&#39;s purchases from the US and other Western nations have grown from strength to strength, especially over the last decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India contracted to buy 22 Apache helicopters and 15 Chinook helicopters from American manufacturer Boeing in September 2015 and had received both shipments by 2020. Delhi also signed a US$4.1 billion contract with Boeing for C-17 planes and away from the US, signed a deal with France and Dassault Aviation in 2016 to buy 36 Rafale fighter planes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts say the strategy reflects India&#39;s desire to spread its bets rather than shift its dependency to the West, noting that the country has continued scooping up discounted Russian crude oil despite Western criticism and sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Delhi has also stopped short of condemning Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine while advocating for a peaceful resolution, again inviting Western scrutiny because it is a member of the Quad, an informal security group that includes the US, Australia and Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a joint statement with the US during Modi&#39;s visit, the two sides emphasised the importance of a “rules-based international order”, saying “the contemporary global order has been built on principles of the UN charter, international law, and respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity of states”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The measured tone of the joint statement on Russia reflected Washington&#39;s eagerness to cement its strategic alliance with India in order to have a foil to China, especially in the Indo-Pacific region, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US is systematically creating a ring of alliances in an effort to contain China. The key strength of US versus China is its alliance network. India is a natural partner because of long ongoing tensions between India and China,” said Pushan Dutt, professor of economics at INSEAD.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;India&#39;s topmost priority is peace&#39;, Modi says in US of Russia stance&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Other parts of the ring included the four-nation Quad as well as Aukus, the security partnership between Britain, Australia and the US, he said. Washington has developed closer defence ties with South Korea and Japan, and signed a pact with Papua New Guinea, with the same objective, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China looms large in all calculations,” Dutt said, noting that the focus on defence and semiconductor technology in partnership with India were because these were “the two sectors that the US explicitly wants to stymie their development in China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delhi embarked on a programme to shore up its manufacturing base including electronic goods three years ago, and offered financial incentives worth billions of dollars. It also launched a programme to build semiconductors to cut imports valued at around US$25 billion a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Two US semiconductor companies said this week that they would invest in India. Micron Technology, maker of memory chips, said it would invest up to US$825 million in a chip assembly and test plant in Gujarat, while semiconductor toolmaker Applied Materials plans to invest some US$400 million in a new engineering centre in India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Incentives from India&#39;s federal and state governments “are likely to range from 70 per cent to 125 per cent of the investments in semiconductor manufacturing in India, which are likely to attract more investments into the country”, said Saurabh Agarwal, a tax partner at professional services firm EY.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The semiconductor industry has a complex value chain that can be roughly broken up into three major sections: design; fabrication; and assembly and testing. India is already a hub for the research and design of semiconductors, which require software capability, but lags in the two other areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The investments by the US firms could catalyse other companies to also make chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India currently meets all of its needs with imports from places such as Taiwan, but policymakers are keen to establish a semiconductor base in the country because chips power everything from mobile phones to sophisticated flight systems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Modi&#39;s visit deepened technological cooperation in other areas as well. Tesla CEO Elon Musk said after a meeting with Modi that his company was looking to invest in India “as soon as humanly possible”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk has been trying to break into the Indian market since 2017, but the plan has been delayed by Tesla&#39;s efforts to negotiate lower import duties – a proposal that has so far been rebuffed because officials want the company to make cars before discussing tax breaks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is likely that they [Tesla] will come now. There is enough push for them,” said an industry executive, who did not want to be identified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other companies were already making inroads before Tesla&#39;s expected entry. American firm International Battery Company has said it would invest in a lithium-nickel-manganese-cobalt cell manufacturing plant in the southern Indian state of Karnataka.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Big tech firms have also warmed up, with Google CEO Sundar Pichai promising to invest US$10 billion in a digitisation fund for India to foster artificial intelligence company, while Amazon said recently that it will ramp up investment in the country to US$26 billion by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The moves have come on the heels of reports that Apple may move nearly one-fifth of its global iPhone production to India in the next two years. India currently has just 14 Apple vendors, compared with 151 in mainland China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US government is keen on strengthening ties with India and encouraging companies such as Apple and GE to invest there is a key part of this strategy,” said David Bach, a professor of strategy and political economy at the International Institute for Management Development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many companies are looking to reduce their dependence on China by testing the waters to see if India is a viable alternative in terms of the size of its market, workforce and the country&#39;s sprawling digital network, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet a legacy of bureaucracy, regulations and red tape that date back to the socialist era before India&#39;s economic liberalisation in 1991 remain a hurdle. Complex processes have vastly improved, but many potential investors still have to feel their way through.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gautam Mahajan, a former president of the Indo-American Chamber of Commerce, said too much fuss was made about the red tape issue in India. Foreign companies who had done their homework well could easily establish their operations, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trend of US and European firms ramping up their operations in India is only expected to increase in the coming months, as ancillary units come up to support bigger production ventures such as the GE-F414 jet engines, industry executives say.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indian airlines&#39; record plane deals &#39;would be serious threat to Mideast hubs&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Indian carrier Air India&#39;s record order of 470 jets from Boeing and Airbus, as well as Indigo&#39;s 500-aircraft order from Airbus, are also significant as these are expected to spawn a number of new manufacturing companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manoj Joshi, a distinguished fellow at the Delhi-based Observer Research Foundation think tank, said the investments were materialising because the US was focusing on supply chain resilience and it viewed India as a partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The depth of relations is not on the defence side alone, but there is an overall economic shift,” he said. “Globalisation 2 is happening and we see certain advantages in close association with the US, just like China had seen in Globalisation 1.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Stop hitting him’: China’s child protection laws under scrutiny after boy jumps 5 floors to flee mother who was beating him with a stick]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3225768/stop-hitting-him-chinas-child-protection-laws-under-scrutiny-after-boy-jumps-5-floors-flee-mother?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/02143f94-4cfe-431d-ac45-88fbabf92c67_cf49cd17.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A shocking incident involving a boy who jumped from the fifth floor of a block of flats in China to escape his abusive mother has turned the spotlight on the country&#39;s child protection laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A video recorded on June 25 in eastern China&#39;s Anhui province shows a desperate child, who appears to be about six years old, jumping from the top of an external air conditioning unit on a residential block after someone inside the unit struck him several times with a stick.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The person recording the video and other onlookers can be heard screaming at the person to stop striking the boy. Then, with nowhere to go, the boy jumps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video has had more than 10 million views on Weibo, the Chinese version of Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to local police who are investigating the incident, the boy, surnamed Yan, was rushed to hospital in a non-life threatening condition but with several bone fractures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, a brief report posted to the police department&#39;s official Weibo account sparked public fury when investigators said the boy&#39;s mother hit him with the stick to “persuade” him to go back inside, out of concern that he might fall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, a member of staff from the local branch of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation claimed that the mother was “bluffing” with the stick, and that the boy fell from the building accidentally, according to a report by Jiupai News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Public responses to the incident online have ranged from disbelief to outrage, with at least one person calling the official explanation of the events a “cover-up”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others have said that the authorities&#39; attitude to the case highlights shortcomings in the country&#39;s laws to prevent child abuse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He was more afraid of his mother than jumping,” one person commented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People were already screaming &#39;stop hitting him&#39; downstairs, and the mother still didn&#39;t stop. I don&#39;t understand,” said another.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among many questions raised, one person asked: “Where are the child protection laws?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China Newsweek reported that Yan&#39;s father works in another city, and the boy lives with his mother.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a survey by the Beijing Teenagers Law Aid and Research Centre, which examined Chinese media reports on violence against children, between 2008 and 2013, 75 per cent of the attacks were by birth parents, and in 10 per cent of cases step-parents or foster parents were responsible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s legal protections make it difficult for authorities to punish parents who are violent to their children, and to protect them from further abuse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A child protection law stipulates that local governments or police should warn or reprimand a child&#39;s guardians if they infringe upon the rights of minors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under China&#39;s current public security rules, a standard penalty for a person who abuses a family member is five days in custody, if the abused person requests it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A legal provision introduced in 2014 was intended to allow authorities to take custody of children from abusive parents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, local government workers have been reluctant to act on the rules, since they still feel bound by traditional values like “spare the rod, spoil the child”, and notions that domestic violence is a “family matter”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, a Chinese mother sparked a public outcry after kicking her three-year-old daughter, a child model, on the set of a photo shoot.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was later revealed that the same woman had beaten her daughter at other filming locations in attempts to force her to pay attention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother disappeared from the public eye after posting an unconvincing apology on Weibo saying that she had only been trying to teach her daughter and had no intention of hurting her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A month later, Phoenix New Media reported that the woman and her daughter had resurfaced in the child modelling business. She never faced any legal consequences for beating her child.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blinken’s China trip boosts Asean nations’ efforts to ease Sino-US tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225703/blinkens-china-trip-boosts-asean-nations-efforts-ease-sino-us-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/4a2940c7-12b8-484e-8a88-fe93521372a0_18c994b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“Antony Blinken, effectively, threw Taiwan under the bus,” lamented Rebekah Koffler, a former US defence intelligence officer, shortly after the US secretary of state&#39;s visit to Beijing, where he made it clear Washington does not support Taiwan independence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The outspoken Fox News contributor went so far as to claim that “Xi Jinping will almost certainly be emboldened by Blinken&#39;s announcement … now Beijing will feel more confident that Washington will not even put up a major fight and assist Taipei.” Michael Pillsbury, another former defence official and staunch Republican, criticised Blinken&#39;s trip as a “huge mistake”, claiming the Biden administration should not appease Beijing and risk its credibility among regional allies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the most part, China hawks and US conservatives were deeply critical of Blinken&#39;s June visit to Beijing. Crucially, however, the trip has raised hopes of restoring bilateral institutionalised dialogue and was largely welcomed by regional states, especially in Southeast Asia, which has been at the centre of US-China rivalry over the past decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If anything, key Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean) members are stepping up their efforts to bolster Sino-US detente. Indonesia, the current Asean chair, chose to relocate a proposed naval drill with fellow Southeast Asian nations away from areas overlapping Beijing&#39;s territorial claims to help ease regional tensions. The Philippines, a US treaty ally, is pursuing improved relations with Beijing after hosting a Chinese naval contingent in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aware of criticism at home, the Biden administration was quick to emphasise the significance of Blinken&#39;s visit, during which he met top Chinese officials, including President Xi Jinping. Southeast Asian nations appeared to be the White House&#39;s target audience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To begin with, there was an element of urgency. In the past month alone, there have been at least two major close calls between US and Chinese armed forces, one in the skies over the South China Sea, the other in the Taiwan Strait. The virtual absence of direct military-to-military dialogue, evident during the recent Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore, has only reinforced fears of accidental clashes in Asian waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his meeting with Blinken, Xi reportedly underscored how “the two sides have agreed to follow through the common understandings President Biden and I had reached in Bali”. The Chinese president was referring to his much-vaunted meeting with his US counterpart on the sidelines of the Group of 20 (G20) summit in Indonesia last year, where both nations agreed to cooperate in spite of inevitable disagreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Encouragingly, Biden and Xi may meet in person later this year, possibly on the sidelines of the G20 summit in India in September, and also at the Apec summit in the US in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, the Biden administration was quick to reassure allies against any fears of abandonment. Daniel Kritenbrink, US assistant secretary of state for East Asian and Pacific affairs, emphasised how any Sino-US detente is “critically important” for regional security as it is crucial to “prevent the risk of miscalculation”. He also reassured regional allies such as the Philippines that “we will stand up to and we will counter a range of concerns that we have with Chinese activities, including in the South China Sea and including those directed at some of our key partners and allies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Far from fearing abandonment, Asean nations welcomed Blinken&#39;s visit for three key reasons. First, despite their apprehensions about China&#39;s growing naval assertiveness in adjacent waters, key Southeast Asian nations have been critical of US measures aimed at containing China&#39;s rise. In particular, there are growing concerns about the unintended consequences of the Biden administration&#39;s sanctions on certain critical sectors of China&#39;s economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asean&#39;s US-China defence diplomacy hopes rest on getting its house in order&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Recognising China&#39;s role in regional production networks, Singaporean Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan has publicly warned against US economic sanctions. During a high-profile conference last year, he called for nothing short of a new non-aligned movement to ensure regional states are insulated against the impact of a US-China tech and trade war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second reason is the unwillingness of even the US&#39; oldest military ally in Southeast Asia to align against China. While welcoming an expanded US military presence on its soil, the Philippines is intent on maintaining robust ties with Beijing and avoiding a fully fledged conflict between its security ally and top trading partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, the Philippines is in no mood to take on China amid rising tensions in the South China Sea. This explains why, as Blinken visited Beijing, the administration of Ferdinand Marcos Jnr declared that progress had been made over fisheries issues in the contested areas of the South China Sea. Just days earlier, Manila also welcomed a goodwill visit by the Chinese navy in an effort to enhance military-to-military diplomacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, Southeast Asian nations are seeking to enhance maritime security in the region without alienating China. It&#39;s perhaps no coincidence that, shortly after Blinken&#39;s visit, Indonesia announced that the Asean naval drills planned for later this year will be relocated away from the North Natuna Sea – where China claims historic fishing rights – to an area less prone to controversy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just weeks earlier, Indonesia also hosted both US and Chinese naval contingents during exercises to aid regional military diplomacy. In short, key Asean states are not fearful of abandonment by the US but instead are more intent on facilitating a thaw in US-China regional rivalry on their own terms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s state financial sector braces for ‘one of the toughest years’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3226117/chinas-state-financial-sector-braces-one-toughest-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/58b9d5b8-b7db-4530-8283-5a3bab812234_31182b02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Executives working in China&#39;s state-owned financial institutions say they are bracing for “one of the toughest years” they have seen, as Beijing seeks to tighten its grip on the sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That means no more wining and dining, as belt-tightening and pay cuts become the norm, along with long hours of compulsory ideological training.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Morale has plummeted since the overhaul of the sector was announced in March, according to four executives working at state financial institutions. President Xi Jinping initiated the plan, which aims to fight corruption in the sector and bring it under more direct control of the ruling Communist Party.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese anti-corruption watchdog says crackdown will continue&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The executives, who declined to be named, said the campaign was now the top priority at their companies and was expected to run well into autumn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They described the uncertainty brought by the “relentless” ideological and anti-corruption drives, and sharp pay cuts in the range of 15 to 20 per cent of their basic salaries, with annual bonuses set to be slashed by at least 30 per cent this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A manager at a state-owned securities firm in Shanghai said a recent ideological study session at the company was on the Red Army&#39;s Long March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Probably our party secretary wants us to be mentally prepared for tougher times ahead,” he said. “State-owned financial companies aren&#39;t an exception. They&#39;re also part of China&#39;s austerity drive at a time when the economy isn&#39;t doing well, and as many civil servants get their pay cut too.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said pay cuts in the financial sector were in line with Xi&#39;s “common prosperity” goal to narrow the wealth gap in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has vowed to put an end to extravagance among what it calls “financial elites” in the state sector, as Xi tries to push its institutions to comply with his vision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And with tensions rising between China and the West – in particular the United States – Beijing is urging its state banks to allocate more money to areas seen as priorities for the nation, such as technology self-reliance projects and advanced manufacturing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing is also closely watching its bankers and financial regulators for any sign of collusion with foreign financial institutions on facilitating large outflows of Chinese funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is also concerned about ballooning local government debt and wants lenders to exercise caution on loans, while at the same time keeping an eye on the weaker financial institutions amid a banking crisis in the US, and as it tries to revive the economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s overhaul of the state financial sector is part of efforts to control risks and – in a typical move from Xi&#39;s playbook – aimed at strengthening the party&#39;s control over financial policymaking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The creation of a new Central Financial Commission will be key to this goal, with 400 trillion yuan (US$55 trillion) of banking and insurance assets placed under the party&#39;s watch. The commission was established under the Central Committee, the party&#39;s top decision-making body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A powerful new financial regulator has also been set up. The National Financial Regulatory Administration has replaced the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission and taken on some duties of the central bank&#39;s supervisory body as well as the securities regulator.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s crackdown on high-flying bankers sends jitters across brokerage industry&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ideological training has also become a priority in the overhaul. One middle manager at a leading Chinese investment bank said its top executives had been asked to return to the company&#39;s Beijing headquarters at the end of May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They all had to supervise week-long study sessions for middle managers,” he said. “We studied President Xi&#39;s original works and his instructions on the financial sector and spent hours soul-searching and writing reports on the main takeaways [from the sessions].”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said managers had received a memo from the bank&#39;s chairman saying the education campaign was the top priority and the sessions could not be skipped. An inspection team from the party was supervising the campaign at the bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The campaign to instil Xi&#39;s political philosophy is widespread throughout party and state organs, but in the financial sector the focus is on stamping out corruption and extravagance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party&#39;s graft-buster has stepped up a sweeping anti-corruption drive, with the vast and opaque financial sector in its cross hairs. It has taken disciplinary action against 87 state bankers, insurers and financial regulators in the first six months of the year – more than the 77 for all of 2022, according to a tally by the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June alone, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced action had been taken against 23 people in the sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Here are 3 anti-corruption tools in China&#39;s arsenal that may be underutilised&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Guo Shuqing, party chief of the People&#39;s Bank of China (PBOC), the central bank, last week told a top-level meeting that the financial sector still “lagged behind on anti-corruption work”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He urged cadres in the sector to “keep a clear head and learn profound lessons” from previous corruption cases, especially former PBOC deputy governor Fan Yifei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan was expelled from the Communist Party and dismissed from public office on June 9 after being placed under investigation by the disciplinary body in November. He is the most senior central banker caught up in the corruption crackdown in the past two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guo&#39;s deputy Pan Gongsheng – who is also party secretary and director of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange – told the same meeting that anti-corruption measures should be strengthened for young cadres in key positions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A PBOC official who attended the meeting said Xi had “a very bad impression” of the financial sector from hearing details of previous corruption cases. “The message is very clear – if we don&#39;t buck up when it comes to discipline, we risk losing his trust.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tencent apologises after plan to charge higher fees on some higher education payments via WeChat Pay stirs up trouble]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226166/tencent-apologises-after-plan-charge-higher-fees-some-higher-education-payments-wechat-pay-stirs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/316ccc2e-014a-4103-b993-f3e4b507f6fa_2ab38a2a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese internet giant Tencent Holdings has apologised after facing a public backlash over higher fees for WeChat Pay transactions on university campuses in the country, and has pledged to take no charges on non-profit payments, such as tuition fees and canteen items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent, which runs one of the country&#39;s two biggest digital payment services, found itself in hot water on Thursday after a number of Chinese universities said they would end usage of WeChat Pay on campus after the company signalled it would start charging fees on payments for some items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one example, Northwest University in Xian, capital of Shaanxi Province in central China, issued a statement saying it would suspend WeChat Pay from June 30 “to protect the interests of teachers and students” as Tencent had signalled it would start charging a 0.6 per cent transaction fee from July 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid the building furore, Tencent issued three consecutive statements on Thursday, apologising for “misunderstandings and confusion” and pledged to maintain its zero-rate policy for non-profit payments, such as tuition fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the continuous growth in the number of campus use cases and merchants, we found that some for-profit scenarios, such as e-commerce and hotel and tourism transactions, have [remained in] the zero-rate education subsidy [category], resulting in increasing costs,” said the Shenzhen-based company in one of those statements.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Alipay applies for patent on palm payments to rival Tencent&#39;s WeChat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It added that the intention of making some adjustments was to rectify some payment areas, where fee rates were below the market average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its final statement of the day, Tencent said that it planned to increase the rate targeting for-profit transactions to 0.2 per cent, from which the company would take 0.1 per cent, with the remaining 0.1 per cent going to third-party partners who supply the payment technology. The company denied that it had planned to charge a 0.6 per cent handling fee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The controversy comes as Tencent and other Big Tech companies in China are being pressed by shareholders to find new revenue streams in a weaker economic environment, with cost-reduction measures and job cuts also in play.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also reflects the difficulties for payment services like WeChat Pay and Ant Group&#39;s Alipay, which have turned into quasi public services due to their market dominance. Users and merchants are quick to complain at the mention of higher fees. Ant Group is an affiliate of Alibaba Group Holding, which also owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent reported an 11 per cent jump in revenue to 150 billion yuan (US$21.4 billion) for the first quarter of 2023. Revenue from fintech and business services rose 14 per cent year on year to 48.7 billion yuan in the period, with accelerated growth in fintech services driven primarily by the recovery of commercial payment activities, the company said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;WeChat is a ubiquitous app in China with 1.3 billion monthly active users, and its e-wallet – together with Alipay – dominate Chinese mobile payment services, including for utility bills, food, dining, shopping and many other things.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For merchants, WeChat Pay fee rates range from 0.2 per cent to 1 per cent, depending on the industry and product categories, and it does not charge for certain payments in schools, universities, public hospitals and charities.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>