<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Dug himself a hole’: con of ‘rich gentleman’ Chinese fraudster who fleeced 8 women out of US$415,000 unravels on highrise window ledge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226125/dug-himself-hole-con-rich-gentleman-chinese-fraudster-who-fleeced-8-women-out-us415000-unravels?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/b6fd5b01-0fcf-46b0-b830-aeaf678757f2_adf05d83.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名中国骗子从中国偷走了超过 300 万元人民币（415,000 美元）八名妇女在试图逃跑时被困在23楼窗台上，结果被抓获。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男子姓聂，来自中国中部的安徽省，他在一个在线交友网站上认识了受害者，他在网上假扮成一位先生在省会合肥拥有一家成功的家居装修公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新闻《四川观察》的一篇报道称，他从 2019 年到 2023 年与 8 名女性建立了关系，在此期间，他骗取了她们更多的钱。总计超过300万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从他与该女子的网上对话记录来看，聂某通过在线支付应用程序向其转账数千元，从而赢得了她们的信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，有一次，信任建立后，他开始借钱，并永久拖延还款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在微信上与一名受害者的对话截图中，他为拖延辩解说：“公司账户无法转账这么大笔钱一次性收到一笔钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的账户里没有任何钱了。今天所有的提款都用来支付工资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及他声称拥有的钱时，他回答一位女士：“我已经说过数千遍了。如果我没有钱，我还谈什么买房吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，一名张姓女士失去了耐心，要求偿还贷款，这个骗局就破裂了。聂某欠下她30万元，试图从所在单位的窗户逃走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他被困在23楼的窗台上，不得不报警求助，结束了他精心策划的爱情骗局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;聂已被拘留，案件正在调查中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一消息在中国社交媒体上引起了广泛震惊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人问：“这个男人到底有什么魅力，能让几个女人借给他几百万？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他真是给自己挖坑了”，还有人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，我国爱情诈骗案件呈上升趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中新网报道，2019年至2021年，北京一区法院共审理此类案件45起，其中8起涉案金额过百万&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管中国公众对爱情诈骗的认识不断提高，但许多受害者却羞于报警。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;红星新闻今年4月报道称，一名男子卷入了爱情诈骗案。 2017年以来，此类骗局已发生20余起，受害人被骗金额超过70万元，但报警的只有两起。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese ‘GaN’ semiconductor technology pioneer Innoscience dragged into IP dispute in US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3226412/chinese-gan-semiconductor-technology-pioneer-innoscience-dragged-ip-dispute-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/03/b2f3d4f3-94cb-41ab-b386-a8a91bef791a_37e90396.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国领先的氮化镓 (GaN) 半导体技术公司之一正在接受调查美国国际贸易委员会 (USITC) 在美国竞争​​对手提出知识产权投诉后，对 Innoscience 发起调查，该公司生产硅基氮化镓 (GaN-on-Si)上周，高效功率转换 (EPC) 指控这家中国公司侵犯了与 GaN 晶体管设计和制造相关的四项专利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;氮化镓是传统硅基半导体技术的一种有前途的替代品。 EPC于5月向美国国际贸易委员会和美国加州地方法院提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“EPC提起的调查和诉讼与事实不符，动机和目的不纯”，中国Innoscience 5 月份 EPC 提交文件时表示，并补充说将采取法律措施为自己辩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为 [EPC] 此举是非法的 [步骤]......旨在破坏 Innoscience 的竞争优势该公司补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，Innoscience 没有回应美国国际贸易委员会决定对此事展开调查的置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于珠海的 Innoscience 成立于据中国媒体报道，2015 年，罗巍巍曾担任美国国家航空航天局 (NASA) 的科学家。 2018年，英诺科学在中国多个部级机构主办的创业创新大赛中荣获一等奖。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;ASML机器出口新规再次打击中国芯片野心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;公司生产晶体管（一种用于放大或切换电信号和功率的半导体器件），并生产晶圆（制造晶体管和集成电路的原材料）。 Innoscience表示，其拥有全球最大的专用8英寸硅基氮化镓晶圆制造能力，每月可生产10,000片晶圆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据公司信息，截至去年，Innoscience在亚洲拥有1,400名员工欧洲和美国，并提供市场上最低的硅基氮化镓器件价格，用于充电器、智能手机、笔记本电脑和数据中心等产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EPC 正在寻求损害赔偿、停止使用停止令并禁止 Innoscience 在美国销售涉嫌违反专利规则的 GaN 产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据法院文件，总部位于加利福尼亚州的 EPC 与共同创立于2007 年，由 Alexander Lidow 共同发明，HEXFET 功率 MOSFET 是一种开创性的晶体管。文件称，在 Lidow 的帮助下，EPC 于 2009 年成为第一家将基于 GaN 技术的晶体管投入商业化的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其产品成功申请专利后，EPC 指控 Innoscience 通过以下方式非法获取公司机密： 2017年招聘了一名工程师担任公司首席技术官，并聘请了一名驻中国的EPC员工作为销售和营销主管。 Innoscience 否认了这些指控，称员工的一些工作变动并不构成抄袭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家公司均表示，他们的 GaN 晶体管比传统硅基晶体管表现出巨大的性能优势。半导体的进步通常需要在单个芯片上安装更多的晶体管，但随着该工艺达到极限，GaN 晶体管已证明能够以更小的尺寸生产并提高效率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，该技术提供了巨大的潜力涉及下一代设备的开发，例如尖端智能手机、计算机、汽车、卫星和服务器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国商务部和海关总署周一宣布，中国将实施出口管制随着北京加强对战略材料的控制，从 8 月 1 日起，将建立包括 GaN 芯片在内的 GaN 技术系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据估计，2022 年至 2027 年间，GaN 半导体器件市场预计将增长超过 50 亿美元全球技术研究和咨询公司 TechNavio。因此，在中美地缘政治紧张局势加剧以及华盛顿采取措施限制中国芯片开发的情况下，GaN技术可能会陷入更多跨境商业纠纷。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong national security law: who are the 8 targeted with HK$1 million bounties? Calls for sanctions, links to 2019 protests among alleged offences]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3226444/hong-kong-national-security-law-who-are-8-targeted-hk1-million-bounties-calls-sanctions-links-2019?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/03/9f83eb94-504f-4ff2-8aaa-6ab0ac086f28_a681e1ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;证据显示八名逃犯被悬赏100万港元（127,600美元）人头警方表示，他们继续威胁国家安全，并寻求通过呼吁国际制裁来“摧毁香港并恐吓官员”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这七名男子和一名女子年龄在 26 至 74 岁之间，包括知名人士在 2019 年社会动荡最严重时期以及北京于 2020 年对香港实施国家安全法之后离开香港的名字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继周一警方宣布悬赏金后，《华盛顿邮报》进一步调​​查了这些人的情况。审查逃犯在香港期间和离开后的背景、涉嫌犯罪和政治活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;任建锋，46岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据称于11月会见海外官员&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任志强和其他志同道合的香港法律界人士共同在前一年的占领抗议活动之后，于 2015 年成立了进步律师团体。该组织表示，其目的是发出当地法律从业者的声音并维护民主价值观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任在去年八月停止撰稿之前，曾在中文日报《明报》上撰写专栏。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;The Progressive Lawyers Group 于 2021 年解散。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任现为英国组织 The 29 原则的董事会成员，根据其网站，该组织“主要由香港人组成”生活在准流亡状态”和“支持在独裁政权下工作的人权律师”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，任去年返回澳大利亚。根据他的 Facebook 页面显示，他现在住在墨尔本，该页面有 6,947 名关注者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他一直是在线平台的定期撰稿人。上周，他在绿豆媒体发表的纪念国安法实施三周年的文章中表示，自国安法实施以来，香港司法机构的质量已经恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一篇分析文章中上周，任在在线平台 The Freethinker 上讨论了西方活动人士如何向香港人学习，他们在处理中国国家控制问题上搁置了分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任有一个活跃的 Twitter 帐户，约有 11,300 名粉丝.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港第 23 条“对国家秘密的定义应与中国大陆不同”&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;郭永亨，45 岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据称于 2021 年 9 月表示支持外国政府对中国大陆和香港实施制裁并从事敌对活动。据称，他去年12月还呼吁对香港实施金融制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭氏是香港反对党公民党的创始成员，并于2012年当选为法律界议员。在赢得立法会席位后这位埃德蒙顿人放弃了加拿大护照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在立法会任职直至 2020 年 11 月，当时他和其他三名泛民主派人士因违反效忠义务或从事非法活动而被剥夺立法会议员资格。威胁国家安全的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后几天，他宣布退出香港政坛。后来他与家人搬到加拿大，并计划重新获得公民身份。次年，他宣布退出公民党。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学校获得国家安全问答套件，供学生在暑假掌握&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他曾因可能的原因接受警方调查郭先生于 2019 年和 2020 年主持立法会内务委员会会议时被指控公职人员行为不当。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭现在是 Elliott Kwok Levin &amp; Jaroslaw（纽约）的合伙人，也是该公司的执行董事兼联合创始人。智库中国战略风险研究所，任先生也是该机构的顾问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭还是“29条原则”的董事会成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的 Facebook 页面上有大约 87,000 名关注者，在他的推特账户上有 5,672 条评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在伦敦亚非学院中国研究所最近为纪念《国家安全法》三周年而发表的一篇文章中，郭表示该立法威胁到了香港作为金融中心的地位。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;许志峰，41岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据称发起了2021年香港宪章，并主张香港和台湾独立。涉嫌在社交媒体上发布帖子，敦促海外政府在2021年1月至2022年12月期间对内地和香港实施制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前民主党立法会议员许志安于2020年与其他反对派议员一起辞职，以抗议北京此举驱逐了四名同僚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许正恩因与 2019 年社会骚乱有关的指控而处于保释候审中，随后他在法院许可下离开北京前往丹麦。他表面上是为了参加气候变化会议，结果却宣布他决定在英国进行自我流放。他还退出了自己的政党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来发现，几位丹麦政客帮助他编造了一个幌子，使他能够逃离香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，他现在住在澳大利亚阿德莱德他的社交媒体页面。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;像爱德华·斯诺登这样的举报人在香港还有一席之地吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港反腐败机构于 2021 年对许因呼吁举报而发出逮捕令居民在社交媒体上抵制或投空白票，抗议立法会选举。这次民意调查是北京改革选举制度、只允许“爱国者”掌握政治权力后举行的首次全市范围内的民意调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他最近支持一项敦促人们举报香港警察的运动。想要通过要求移民当局取消其申请资格来申请移民或旅行签证的官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他仍然活跃在 Twitter 和 Facebook 上，分别拥有约 13,800 名和 107,000 名粉丝，同时还维护着一个 Patreon 帐户。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他与其他海外活动人士推出《2021香港宪章》，敦促海外香港人继续反对香港和北京政府。该运动还呼吁“解放”这座城市和结束中国的一党统治，并要求国际社会“团结起来，在极权主义的威胁下维护民主价值观”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国应“暂时解除对亚太经合组织香港代表李家超的制裁”&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;袁公义，74岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据称要求外国在2020年7月至2020年7月至2020年7月期间对地方官员和司法人员实施制裁2023年5月。据称发起全民公投组建“香港议会”，以实现自决并颠覆国家政权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁是反对党人民运动前主席袁美明的父亲力量。他也是新民党建制派立法会议员容海恩的岳父。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，这位商人从 2019 年开始更加活跃于政坛。据说他已移居至&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他与独立派活动人士、前当选立法会议员梁颂恒等人一起，宣布计划于2022年8月组建议会- 流亡并于 2023 年底举行首次普选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几天后，容在当地一家报纸上刊登了四分之一版广告，称她将与她的父亲断绝关系- &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁在推特上发表了他对当地政治的看法，他在推特上有大约 88,300 名粉丝。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;蒙少达， 51&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;涉嫌去年6月在一次海外会议上抹黑中央和地方政府，并主张香港从中国分裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙是现已解散的香港工联会行政长官已有十年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该联合会由前工党立法会议员李卓人于 1990 年共同创立，李卓人目前因国家安全指控而入狱等待审判。该组织也被认为是反对派阵营的关键力量，也是香港每年 6 月 4 日天安门广场烛光守夜活动以及此前每年举行的 7 月 1 日游行背后的主要参与者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港女性被捕，23 人在曾举办 6 月 4 日守夜活动的公园附近被拘留&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;成员投票决定在 2021 年解散该组织。投票前，蒙告诉媒体，他已经从联合会辞职，并以安全为由离开了这座城市&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他自称流亡英国，现任英国关注组织香港劳工权益监察组织的执行董事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nathan Law kwun-钟，29&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据称在2020年7月至2022年11月期间呼吁外国对国家和香港实施制裁或从事敌对活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法律是支持香港的重要声音2014 年占领抗议期间，该市的反对派和一名学生领袖。后来，他于 2016 年与他人共同创立了本土主义政党“众志”，并担任主席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着北京通过香港国家安全法，众志于 2020 年 6 月 30 日解散，党内领导层辞职。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;23岁时，他当选立法会议员，成为立法机关历史上最年轻的立法会议员。当局对他首次出席立法会时所作的有争议的宣誓提出质疑，导致他于 2017 年 7 月被取消资格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在 2020 年国家安全法颁布前逃离香港，并在英国获得政治庇护。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从离开香港后，罗先生经常受邀会见西方政客并出席议会听证会谈论民主。 2021年，他还受邀在美国总统乔·拜登的民主峰会上发表简短讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他被当局指控“散布有关城市和国家的政治谎言”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他被当局指控“散布关于城市和国家的政治谎言”。 >;&lt;p>;罗先生参与了《香港宪章》的制定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他运营 Twitter 和 Facebook 帐户，分别拥有 332,000 名和 215,000 名粉丝。罗还为他的追随者开设了一个 Patreon 账户。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Finn Lau Cho-dik，29 岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据称呼吁外国对大陆和香港实施制裁，同时参与其他活动2020 年 7 月至 2021 年 6 月期间的敌对活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘是一名政治活动家，以其“南洲”抗议策略而闻名。“南洲”是一个粤语术语，指的是相互毁灭的概念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他曾只在类似 Reddit 的平台 LIHKG 在线论坛上以用户名“I Want Laam Chau”为人所知。后来他引起了更多关注，这一概念在2019年在抗议者中流行起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘于2019年创立了“香港自由”和“与香港站在一起”团体，通过社交媒体招募成员。该组织后来发起了一系列活动，寻求国际社会对抗议运动的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他于 2020 年前往伦敦，据报道，他在继续活动的同时，在那里担任测量员。 2021 年，他声称自己将成为一名专注于香港问题的全职政治活动家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;天安门广场博物馆在香港博物馆关闭两年后在纽约开幕&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;郭安娜凤仪，26岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;涉嫌在2021年9月至2022年2月期间出席海外会议和活动，会见外国政要和官员，要求实施制裁，同时还从事针对内地和香港的敌对活动。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;郭是香港民主委员会的执行董事，这是一个总部位于美国的非营利机构，致力于扩大中国的自由。她声称自己的使命是通过美国政治游说香港的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2019 年社会动荡期间，她担任“自由香港”的在线组织者，该组织为 G20 峰会和其他地方的抗议活动提供众筹.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，她于2020年1月前往美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在2023年5月的国会听证会上，她敦促美国为香港人民提供更多人道主义途径，以帮助“政治犯”。她还呼吁美国政府关闭香港在美国的三个贸易办事处，她声称这些办事处便利了对香港人的监视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Willa Wu的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s talent hunt is giving its property market a needed boost]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226385/hong-kongs-talent-hunt-giving-its-property-market-needed-boost?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/03/233220ae-f39e-46c6-aff7-c071e4459354_919a711b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最近企业界和整个社区有很多令人担忧的议论，香港作为金融和旅游中心以及主要商业中心的辉煌时代已经结束。 Covid-19 大流行和随后的边境关闭实际上将这座城市从世界其他地方驱逐出去，整个经济部门都遭受了巨大的、有时甚至是灾难性的损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但大陆边境在 2 月份重新开放后，隧道尽头的光立刻变得明亮了许多。俗话说，香港灭亡的报道言过其实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据香港旅游发展局统计，今年一月至五月，入境游客总数已突破千万人次。休闲游客数量不断增加，零售销售和酒店需求均大幅增长，会议、奖励旅游、会议和展览活动不断增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最重要的是，专业人士和毕业生涌入最近推出的顶尖人才通行证计划为租赁市场带来了福音。根据该计划，年收入 250 万港元（319,000 美元）或以上或毕业于世界排名前 100 的大学之一并拥有至少三年工作经验的人士，有资格获得两年工作签证。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;扩大的香港人才名单揭示了可享受签证快速通道的职业&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据政府数据，截至 4 月 18 日，至少有 15,000 份申请已获得批准。虽然绝大多数申请者来自内地，但来自世界其他地区的人数预计将会攀升，特别是在劳工及福利局五月份扩大人才领域名单，将创意产业、建筑、环境技术和更多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，传闻证据表明专业人士开始回归。中小型大众市场公寓的租金保持相当稳定，但豪华公寓的租金自一月份以来一直在攀升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们自己的数据也表明了同样的情况。今年上半年约70%的租赁咨询和交易来自外籍人士，20%来自香港人，只有10%来自中国大陆，其中70%来自家庭。毫不奇怪，对半山和南区房产的需求最强劲，那里的许多公寓都已满员或空置率较低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管市场发展方向积极且人气似乎有所改善，但挑战仍然存在。 1000 万游客听起来不错，但这一数字比 2017 年至 2019 年同期下降了约 40%。区域竞争、全球经济不稳定、汇率波动和航空公司运力对这里和许多其他地方的旅游业产生了负面影响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管租赁数量强劲，但由于开放边境和移民计划，2023 年剩余时间里，整体销售市场可能会出现波动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高利率资金成本使机构投资者变得谨慎，而同样的利率也给住宅行业带来压力。旅行限制的取消给大众市场带来了帮助，但推出新项目的开发商被迫提供大幅折扣，以抵消不断上升的融资成本。这些因素推动该行业比前一年增长了 120%，但二级市场仅增长了 19%，而且销售额普遍低于市场价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奢侈品行业已经事实证明，该行业相当有弹性，但在 1 亿至 2 亿港元范围之外，该行业显然正在等待急需的高净值内地买家的回报。香港市场正在复苏，但尚未完全复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们很可能在几周后才知道香港住宅物业走出困境的程度。夏季是一年中仅次于农历新年的最不活跃的时间，大多数奢侈品买家都会外出度假。在可预见的未来，租赁仍将是市场的核心，因为新来者会选择租房，直到他们获得更好的土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们有理由乐观。政策制定者正在将香港打造成亚洲首选之地，而新加坡的租金、物价和印花税却在飙升。此外，香港是大湾区的基石。这座城市还没有脱离生命维持系统，但它似乎已经脱离了危急状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong office rents and rental values expected to decline further amid uncertainties about global, Chinese economies, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226425/hong-kong-office-rents-and-rental-values-expected-decline-further-amid-uncertainties-about-global?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/03/880c64f3-b3e9-4403-9224-2a612fc7cdcd_01568eb3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港写字楼租金及应课差饷租值预计因空置率高及新增供应下跌分析师表示，全球经济的不确定性以及企业裁员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然高级管理人员希望员工重返办公室 — — 并且亚太地区在这方面继续领先美国和欧洲 — —据世邦魏理仕称，灵活办公作为一种选择在香港越来越受欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于全球经济前景长期存在不确定性，写字楼租赁势头在近几个月仍然缓慢，”Marcos Chan 表示。世邦魏理仕香港研究主管。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 表示，2023 年上半年空置率上升至 15.7%，并且随着新开发项目竣工并进入市场，空置率将继续上升，并补充说，租金预计下半年将再小幅下跌1%至2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;内地游客回流提振香港零售物业市场&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;写字楼租金下降反映在应课差饷租值上，差饷物业估价署估计的年租金值。中原地产的数据显示，去年 33 座基准写字楼中有 24 座（即 72.7%）的应课差饷租值低于 2013 年的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港甲级写字楼的应课差饷租值中原地产表示，2019 年与去年相比下降了 26.7%，其中美国银行大厦 (Bank of America Tower) 降幅最大，达 35.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中原地产预计 2019 年整体应课税值将进一步下滑 10%。 2023年“由于写字楼空置率高以及大规模甲级高层建筑竣工，造成租金下行压力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;租赁策略将继续谨慎世邦魏理仕 6 月下旬发布的亚太写字楼市场报告显示，短期来看，“尽管取消了与疫情相关的限制并恢复了正常生活，但经济不确定性仍然存在”世邦魏理仕的报告称，通胀和利率上升，以及中国大陆的复苏慢于预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡因写字楼租金和入住率不断攀升而脱颖而出&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;因此，根据世邦魏理仕的报告，预计占用者在短期内将对租赁保持保守立场，通过续租、重新谈判、调整规模和提高租赁灵活性等方式选择。占用者正在特别密切地关注更灵活的扩张和收缩选项以及中断条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世邦魏理仕报告补充说，占用者还打算探索通过行使租赁到期和整合地点来减少空间的方法。寻求转租空间的大型租户的需求继续导致澳大利亚、新加坡和香港的影子空间水平上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博资讯赞同香港写字楼租金在下半年可能继续下降的观点，因为一些公司可能会通过采用轮用办公桌安排来进一步缩小办公室规模。这可能会进一步压低房东的办公室租金收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么香港购物中心运营商竞相安装电动汽车充电器&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;全球金融不确定性可能会限制需求，特别是来自银行业的需求，彭博资讯表示。由于许多新建筑的激烈竞争，主要房东可能很难填满现有的办公空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管与许多其他门户市场相比，香港员工对上班的态度不那么犹豫，因为距离较短陈说，然而，灵活工作作为员工的一种选择已经变得越来越受欢迎，特别是在跨国公司中。这也是公司 ESG 政策的一部分，旨在促进灵活性和工作与生活的平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高力集团 6 月下旬的一份报告表示，公司不应将仅限办公室的规定纳入其战略，而是需要承认回归需要理由和动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据彭博资讯称，许多香港人可能会要求更高的工资，以抵消在家工作灵活性的损失。这也可能促使大公司继续提供此类安排，以避免人才流失。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Senegal President Macky Sall rules out re-election bid after violent unrest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3226450/senegal-president-macky-sall-rules-out-re-election-bid-after-violent-unrest?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 07:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/d540d5ee-3b92-45e4-9dbc-9466ad21790f_53f024a4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;塞内加尔总统麦基·萨尔在明年不会竞选连任，他在周一的一次演讲，结束了有关他将寻求第三个任期的广泛猜测，批评者认为这是非法的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有关萨尔将试图延长他的执政期限的传言加剧了自 2021 年以来的一系列骚乱，其中数十人被杀，动摇了塞内加尔在这个动荡地区的平静声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于我在这次选举中的最终候选人资格有很多猜测和评论，”萨尔在电视讲话中说。 “2019 年任期是我的第二个也是最后一个任期。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经过仔细考虑，我的决定是不作为候选人参加 2024 年 2 月 25 日即将举行的选举。而且，尽管宪法规定，授予我权利，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;萨尔的声明可能会平息人们对塞内加尔民主倒退的担忧。 Some had worried he would follow other regional leaders, including in Ivory Coast and Togo, who used changes to the constitution as an excuse to reset their mandate and extend their hold on power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regional leaders including the presidents of Niger, Mohamed Bazoum, Guinea Bissau&#39;s Umaro Sissoco Embalo, and the African Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat, praised Sall&#39;s decision, while Bazoum added that it will ease tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sall&#39;s decision will trigger a search for a successor to lead the ruling party just months before the February polls. It is unclear who will run for many of the main parties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Supporters at his party headquarters in an upscale neighbourhood in the capital were divided on Monday evening after Sall&#39;s speech. Some applauded, while others cried.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Pregnant Senegal MP kicked in belly during parliament brawl, could lose baby&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s his choice, and he is our leader. We accept his decision, and we will support whoever he designates,” a female supporter said in tears.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unrest last month was sparked by the sentencing of popular opposition leader Ousmane Sonko to two years in jail on charges stemming from an alleged rape – accusations he denies and says were politically motivated to stop him from running in the elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rioters, angered in part by what they saw as Sall&#39;s serial sidelining of opponents, torched buildings and vehicles and threw stones at police, who responded with tear gas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least 16 people were killed in the clashes, some whose relatives said that security forces opened fire with live rounds.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[About 1 million Hongkongers who haven’t replaced smart ID cards face long waits for appointments]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3226408/about-1-million-hongkongers-who-havent-replaced-smart-id-cards-face-long-waits-appointments?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/49ad83e2-e5d1-4768-9d06-e18a201686de_8b8d3b58.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;About 1 million Hongkongers who did not replace their identity cards during a four-year exercise which ended in March must now wait more than three months for an appointment to do so.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A check by the Post on Monday showed all appointment slots fully booked through to October 26, and it took more than an hour of queuing to enter the government website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The replacement programme started in December 2018 to give residents new smart ID cards with improved security features. Nine special centres set up for the purpose closed when the exercise ended on March 3.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Transgender activists call for approval of Hong Kong ID card sex change requests&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But residents may still apply for their new IDs at six Registration of People (ROP) Offices in Wan Chai, Cheung Sha Wan, Kwun Tong, Sha Tin, Yuen Long, and Tuen Mun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Immigration Department told the Post that about 6.84 million residents had replaced their IDs during the programme, accounting for 85 per cent of those eligible, leaving more than 1.2 million who had not done so as of March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said appointments at ROP offices had been tight in recent months, since normal travel resumed and there was a surge in demand by residents returning to Hong Kong and others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Assuring Hongkongers that the older ID cards were still valid, it said the authorities would monitor the progress of ongoing replacements before deciding when to declare the old cards invalid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ROP offices offer around 18,000 appointment slots per week for ID replacements, fewer than the 7,700 a day at the nine centres during the exercise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Accountant Rainbow Leung, 30, who works in Canada, managed to apply for her new ID card last Tuesday after booking her slot in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She had hoped to replace her card last year, but Hong Kong&#39;s ongoing Covid-19 restrictions for travellers put her off returning to the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung said she waited online for 1½ hours to get an appointment. She first tried booking a slot at the ROP&#39;s Wan Chai office, but it was fully booked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other offices had available dates only after a month. She finally got an available slot in June at the Kowloon Office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People who enter the system each day are allowed to make a booking for the next 96 working days.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Student gets suspended sentence for forging ID card over &#39;ugly&#39; photo&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Design director Wayne Leung, 40, who works in Singapore, said he was also deterred by the travel restrictions and did not return earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was eligible to make an appointment between January and April last year, when both Hong Kong and Singapore had quarantine requirements for international travellers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It would have wasted too much time for me to quarantine for a week in Hong Kong and another week in Singapore,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overseas based Hongkongers returning to the city should apply for their replacement ID within 30 days of arrival. The new ID cards are issued seven working days after application.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Applicants wishing to travel outside the city before collecting their new IDs may use other valid travel documents such as passports and Hong Kong Re-entry Permits for immigration clearance.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;ID check leads to seizure of HK$7 million worth of heroin in Hong Kong flat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Secretary for Security Chris Tang Ping-keung told the Legislative Council last week that 750,000 holders of expired Hong Kong passports had yet to apply for renewal, and another 260,000 passports would expire or become invalid by the end of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the Immigration Department had boosted resources and manpower to deal with an increase in applications, and was considering extending the period for booking appointments for passport appointments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A check by the Post on Monday found a 55 minute wait to enter the website to book an appointment for obtaining a travel document, but the quotas were full at all offices until August 3.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Applications filed online, by post or via self-service kiosks and drop-in boxes at eight immigration offices are not subjected to quota limits.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Bank of China pips HSBC in arranging Hong Kong bond deals as IPO bankers stare at Sars-era collapse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3226409/bank-china-pips-hsbc-arranging-hong-kong-bond-deals-ipo-bankers-stare-sars-era-collapse?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/8f95afa3-906b-42b6-8740-28950f1f8cd3_4447476d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Bank of China, the nation&#39;s largest overseas lender, overtook HSBC for the first time in more than eight years in arranging bond sales in Hong Kong, as investment bankers jostled for a slice of an expanding market while equity offerings slumped to a 20-year low.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bank of China (Hong Kong) was credited with roles in 110 deals worth HK$49.4 billion (US$6.3 billion) in the first half of 2023 including self-led deals, according to Bloomberg&#39;s ranking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bond bankers at the lender, one of the three currency note-issuers in Hong Kong, helped arrange Hong Kong Mortgage Corp&#39;s HK$800 million issue and China Construction Bank&#39;s HK$900 million certificate of deposits last quarter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HSBC, the biggest banking group in the city, had a role in 128 bond deals, helping companies including Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of Montreal collect a total of HK$49.2 billion of proceeds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BOCHK&#39;s ranking was boosted by its prolific second-quarter performance, when it surpassed HSBC for the first since the final quarter of 2015, according to Bloomberg data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong is a major international financial centre with a highly liquid and active bond market, making it very attractive to bond issuers in the Asia-Pacific region and global investors,” a spokesperson for BOCHK said in a written reply to the Post. The bank said it expects the issuance methods for Hong Kong-dollar bonds to become more diverse in the second half, and it will continue to contribute to the development of the city&#39;s debt market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There was a notable rise in self-led bank issuances in the first half of the year,” said HSBC&#39;s Asia-Pacific co-head of debt capital markets Daniel Kim. “Excluding these, HSBC retains its market leading position and we remain committed to supporting our clients with their HKD financing needs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The growth of the local-currency bond market underscores the city government&#39;s push to deepen and enrich the liquidity of the capital market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strategically, “the development of a modern bond market, along with the development of the equity market and the banking sector, will facilitate the efficient allocation of funds, thereby promoting financial stability, strengthening Hong Kong&#39;s status as an international financial centre and promoting economic development,” the Financial Services and the Treasury Bureau said in an August 2022 plan to develop the bond market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Corporate bond sales in the city rose 38 per cent to HK$243 billion this year, as companies turned to fixed-income investors for more capital. A slump in stock prices, marked by the Hang Seng Index&#39;s 4.2 per cent retreat, sent new offerings crashing to US$2.2 billion, the least since Sars (severe acute respiratory syndrome) struck the city in 2003.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong IPO fundraising drops to 20-year low in first half of year&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Companies also rushed to lock in long-term borrowing costs as global central banks continued to raise the spectre of higher interest rates to tame inflation. Despite a pause in the June policy meeting, traders are betting on at least two more hikes this year, from as soon as this month, according to odds compiled by CME Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US Federal Reserve has raised its key rate by a cumulative 5 percentage points since the lift-off in March 2022. The Hong Kong Monetary Authority follows its US counterpart in lockstep in deciding the city&#39;s base rate, an obligation under its linked exchange rate system to preserve the local currency peg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese lender Bank of Communications sold HK$2.7 billion of two-year notes in February, the biggest local issue so far, according to Bloomberg data. BOCHK and HSBC helped arrange the deal with 11 others. Standard Chartered&#39;s self-arranged HK$1.9 billion of three-year notes in April was the next largest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Corporate bonds dominate Hong Kong&#39;s bond market, according to the Asian Development Bank. There were HK$1.4 trillion of such notes outstanding on March 31, or almost half of the market. Exchange Fund bills and notes, the city&#39;s main liquidity management tools, accounted for 43 per cent, while government bonds made up the rest.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Health fears for Georgia’s jailed ex-leader Mikheil Saakashvili after TV footage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226449/health-fears-georgias-jailed-ex-leader-mikheil-saakashvili-after-tv-footage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 06:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/04/9f79872f-5acc-46fb-a68f-9111fe65647e_a52667de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former Georgian president Mikheil Saakashvili appeared on television for the first time in months on Monday, looking frail and emaciated, fuelling concerns over the detained politician&#39;s treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 55-year-old – who before jail was a large man – was almost unrecognisable and looked like a ghost of his former self. The images prompted war-torn Ukraine – of which Saakashvili is a citizen – to summon the Georgian ambassador, asking him to go to Tbilisi to help “save” Saakashvili.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leader of the Caucasus country from 2004 to 2013, Saakashvili was jailed after returning from exile on abuse of power charges that rights groups denounce as politically motivated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Doctors have said Saakashvili risks dying from conditions he has developed while in custody, though Georgian authorities say he is being given adequate medical care.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appearing via video link for a court hearing on the “abuse of office” charges, Saakashvili, 55, lifted his shirt to show his ribs protruding from his chest, a hollow abdomen, and skin clinging tightly to his bones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A totally innocent man is being kept in custody,” he said in coverage carried live on several independent television channels. “I did not commit any crime.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He is being held at a civilian hospital, where he was transferred last year after staging a 50-day hunger strike to protest his detention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Putting me in jail will not break me. I am going to be actively involved in Georgian politics,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jailed Georgia ex-leader Mikheil Saakashvili &#39;tortured in custody&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Kyiv, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said the Georgian ambassador to Kyiv would be asked to “leave Ukraine within 48 hours to hold consultations with his capital” on Saakashvili&#39;s treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky wants Saakashvili – whom he made a Ukrainian citizen in 2019 – to be transferred to a clinic in Ukraine or the West. He called on Georgia to “hand over” Saakashvili to Ukraine and “save this man”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not immediately clear if the ambassador was being formally expelled. Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba that the ambassador would arrive at his offices on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Tomorrow morning, the Georgian ambassador will be at the Foreign Ministry, we will have a tough conversation with him, he will go to Georgia,” Kuleba said on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kyiv, which has been battling a Russian invasion for 16 months, has accused Tbilisi of increasingly cooperating with Moscow. Zelensky accused Russia of “killing” Saakashvili “at the hands of the Georgian authorities”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two groups of doctors – one set up by Georgia&#39;s rights ombudsperson, another consisting of US-based doctors – have said that Saakashvili&#39;s health continued to decline well after he ended his hunger strike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group of US-based doctors, who examined Saakashvili in person, said his deteriorating health was the result of “torture” in custody, saying he needed an immediate transfer to a medical centre abroad.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jailed Georgia ex-leader Mikheil Saakashvili &#39;tortured in custody&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The politician, who once weighed more than 100kg (220 pounds), has lost around 60kg while in prison, the doctor groups say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European Union and the United States have urged Georgia to ensure that Saakashvili is provided medical treatment and that his rights are protected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amnesty International has branded his treatment as “apparent political revenge”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why China should maintain open and inclusive debate about its economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226380/why-china-should-maintain-open-and-inclusive-debate-about-its-economy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/1c08c06e-1073-4c57-8a62-ee87b6eebe52_0573f09d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Debates about the Chinese economy have always been lively. While Beijing has set many red lines for discussions about the country&#39;s political system and ideology, discourse relating to economic affairs has been open and inclusive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese economists are generally not shy about sharing their views on the nation&#39;s economic health and offering advice on what authorities should do. There have been countless seminars, symposia and conferences in places like Beijing and Shanghai focused on China&#39;s economic prospects, challenges and strategies, and these discussions have often been open to the public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Beijing has encouraged the expression of different opinions about its economic policies and welcomed input from “non-official” researchers. It has become a routine for the Chinese premier to listen to economists at foreign investment banks, and senior government officials are often happy to join debates as “common scholars” in venues such as the Economists 50 Forum, a Beijing-based club.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The open and candid exchanges have helped authorities find the right balance. For instance, officials were quick to roll out a massive fiscal stimulus in 2008 to help its economy amid a global financial crisis, but the country was also honest in acknowledging its debt hangover and other problems stemming from that effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for the general public, they have the chance to learn in a free market of economic ideas and make their own financial choices, such as whether it is time to buy a flat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A number of opinion leaders have emerged from these active debates: some of them gained popularity for their sensational comments, while others won followers for their honest assessments of the economy and their ability to explain complicated issues in plain language.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there are signs that the situation may change, as apolitical economic issues are increasingly being perceived through a political lens. In an unhealthy change, chest-thumping about the unstoppable rise of the Chinese economy is hailed as “positive energy”, while critical analyses over specific problems are sometimes discouraged because they are seen as “painting a bleak picture” or “spreading fear and panic”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the latest case, China suspended the Weibo account of Wu Xiaobo, a prominent financial writer, for “disseminating negative and harmful information” about the country&#39;s economy. According to a vague statement from the platform, Wu and two other accounts were accused of “hyping up the unemployment rate”, “smearing the development of the security market”, and attacking China&#39;s economic policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The silencing of Wu is particularly shocking because he has been a long-time cheerleader of China&#39;s economic and business rise in books such as China Emerging: 1978-2018. If Wu can be censored for simply citing China&#39;s official unemployment figures or the Shanghai stock index, public economic debates could be shut down entirely in the world&#39;s second-largest economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That would do China no good. Warnings, doubts and bad news about the country&#39;s economy have only helped the nation become stronger. Bad-mouthing has never been a real problem for China. When former premier Wen Jiabao said in 2007 that the country&#39;s growth was “not stable, not balanced, not coordinated and not sustainable”, what people saw were honesty and Beijing&#39;s commitment to address challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s development will continue to be dogged by a long list of problems, including an excessive debt burden, a quickly greying population, weak household spending, and geopolitical headwinds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The starting point for handling these challenges is to face them head on and analyse the underlying reasons. There is no way that these problems, along with China&#39;s weak stock market and high youth unemployment, will disappear if people stop talking about them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Furthermore, the root problem of China&#39;s economic woes these days is the loss of confidence. Many entrepreneurs, investors and ordinary wage earners are wondering whether their economic interests still matter for the country and whether their concerns can be heard by policymakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silencing debate by suppressing unwanted narratives or even facts will only damage confidence further and make policymakers blind to the real problems on the ground.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can China’s deep-sea fishing feed the people, or will it just bring back expensive fish?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3226404/can-chinas-deep-sea-fishing-feed-people-or-will-it-just-bring-back-expensive-fish?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/cca7e5b2-e979-4cab-859f-95843f410cd9_c1034997.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Looking to reduce its reliance on foreign suppliers for critical foodstuffs, China is growing more bold and innovative. The second story in this two-part series looks at advancements and challenges in deepwater aquaculture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Being able to get protein from the ocean ultimately saved Tom Hanks&#39; marooned character from starvation in the movie Cast Away, even if he couldn&#39;t save Wilson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And, as China sees it, there&#39;s a lot of ocean to go around, with its abundant marine life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To that end, leadership is hoping that ocean-sourced food will play a more sustainable role in helping feed the nation&#39;s 1.4 billion people at a time when global and domestic uncertainties have exposed and created new risks to ensuring a stable and sufficient food supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those uncertainties and risks have become worrisome enough that President Xi Jinping deemed food security “a national security issue of extreme importance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As it happened: China&#39;s economy growing faster, premier tells &#39;Summer Davos&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Following Xi&#39;s repeated urgings to “ask not only the land but also the ocean for food”, China has doubled down on distant-water mariculture in recent years in the hope of building what Xi calls a “blue granary”. He last reiterated that sentiment on a trip to Guangdong province in April, according to provincial state media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, eight ministries jointly issued the country&#39;s first national guidelines in developing deepwater aquaculture to seek new growth further offshore as inland and coastal resources are depleted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The directive, issued in June, encourages the establishment of large fish farms in deep-sea areas – those more than 20 metres (65 feet) underwater or 10km (6.2 miles) away from the coast – with a breeding volume of at least 10,000 cubic metres.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some experts say that such farms will become important sources of protein as Beijing pursues dietary diversity to meet growing food demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the world&#39;s largest exporter of aquatic animal products, the country is aiming to build a full supply chain surrounding the sector, as part of a broad effort to upgrade the fishery industry, according to the directive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A series of prominent home-made offshore aquaculture facilities have appeared in official propaganda in recent months, with the world&#39;s first 100,000-tonne floating fish farm, a ship now known as the Conson 1, celebrating its first full year of operation last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its owner, Qingdao Conson, a local state-owned conglomerate in Shandong province, has plans to operate a fleet of 50 vessels with varying dimensions and capacities with the same purpose – offshore fish farming, according to an article on its website in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has also put into use a slew of smart, deep-sea mariculture platforms in the past couple of years, including the Haixia 1 and Genghai 1, as well as a large fully submersible fish cage called the Shenlan 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ningde 1, a deep-sea semi-submersible farming platform that&#39;s the largest of its type in the country so far, is said to be ready for operation after being towed to designated waters near Fujian province on June 27, according to the People&#39;s Daily.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a breeding volume of 65,000 cubic metres, the fully framed platform is expected to produce more than 100 million yuan (US$13.8 million) worth of large yellow croaker annually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Humans have developed from hunting to farming on the land. Now we have a dream that we can realise the same transition on the sea,” said Xu Hao, former head of the Fishery Machinery and Instrument Research Institute under the Chinese Academy of Fishery Sciences, which spearheaded the design of the Conson 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China needs to move aquaculture farther offshore as demand for high-quality animal protein rises while inland and coastal fishery has little room to grow, explained Xu, who is still active in fishery machinery research and was involved in the development of the vessel before retiring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s an issue of food security because sea fish provide good-quality protein, which is seeing increasing demand as people&#39;s living standards improve,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As fishing resources get scarcer after decades of exploitation, farming is the only way to ensure production, but traditional aquaculture is under mounting pressure amid environmental concerns that induced tightened policies, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For coastal fish farms, our breeding density has been way higher than the global average. So, we have to seek new space for growth,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese authorities have limited wild catching and have reduced vessel numbers on inland and coastal farms since 2017 amid growing ecological damage, including algal blooms and dead zones. They have issued tough policies including a 10-year fishing ban in all key waters of the Yangtse River from the start of 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though still ranked at the top globally, inland fishing volume in China dropped by a third from 2017 to 2020, and the number of vessels dropped by 47 per cent from 2013 to 2020, according to a 2022 report on the world&#39;s fisheries by the UN&#39;s Food and Agriculture Organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike deep-sea cages – a popular means of offshore aquaculture – large farming ships allow the fish farms to move around in pursuit of the best temperature for the fish in different seasons. They also allow for a greater degree of mobility, so the vessels can seek shelter in case of typhoons, which have long threatened China&#39;s coastal fishery efforts, Xu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calling them “a future protein-production base on the sea”, he said such floating farms can also better control fish pollutions and limit disease compared with the cage culture, because fish are bred in closed tanks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In general, we&#39;re just starting out in distant-water aquaculture, as you can tell from the name of all those floating farms and cages, which often include the number one, meaning the first of the kind. So, we have a lot to improve in the future,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How China&#39;s vast and aggressive fishing fleet is kept afloat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One major challenge is the high cost of building such vessels. Conson 1, which cost 450 million yuan, had farmed 1,200 tonnes of yellow croaker by its one-year anniversary in May, far from its designed capacity for 3,700 tonnes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it&#39;s already a good start, according to Xu. “We expected the payback period to be 10 years, and judging from current circumstances, it might just take eight or nine years,” he said. “The survival rate of fish bred on the ship turns out to be better than expected – we originally aimed for 85 per cent, and it&#39;s actually over 95 per cent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the ship is designed with a lifespan of more than 30 years, it should be commercially sustainable as long as there&#39;s a steady, long-term production of aquatic animals and a solid supply chain, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Wang Yamin, from the Marine College of Shandong University, Weihai, noted that cost control is highly important for such giant offshore breeding facilities, as the sector is still in the early stages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It won&#39;t work if they sell the aquatic products at a low price, and they must control labour costs and other operating costs via technological innovation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;High prices have also fuelled doubts over whether the growth of offshore aquaculture could help ensure food security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The economics of operating in exposed offshore environments necessitates focusing on high-market-value fish species that low-income consumers cannot afford, even if significant technological advances are made, according to a research paper published in Nature in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Market participation is also a concern, as China&#39;s water-farming endeavours are currently supported mostly by state capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At this stage, the market often adopts a wait-and-see attitude. So, there should be more risk assessment and government incentives such as tax cuts and subsidies. Which species to breed also needs to be carefully studied,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite promising economic returns, private breeders are mostly reluctant to set foot in distant-water aquaculture, as it&#39;s too risky, according to Lin Ming, a member of the Chinese Academy of Engineering.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A company might lose everything if there&#39;s a strong thunderstorm, and commercial insurance comes with strict rules in compensation claims, he wrote in an article published in the official Journal of Management World in December, citing a meeting with local farmers in Guangdong province in the southern part of China&#39;s 18,000km coastline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many companies call the government &#39;a coach on the river bank&#39; … local governments tend to talk more than they actually invest,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While some see deepwater mariculture as the next frontier for the sustainable production of highly nutritious fish, others are worried it will only bring pollution farther into the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Centre for Food Safety, a US non-profit organisation, called offshore aquaculture a “false solution to overfishing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Just like factory farms on land, aquaculture operations are large sources of pollution with little regulation in place to keep their discharge in check,” it said on its website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pollutants – including nutrients, various pesticides and other toxic chemicals used to keep the fish healthy and enclosures clean – may escape into the surrounding water. Fuel consumed by boats transporting fish to and from offshore farms also leads to additional emissions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s carbon dioxide emissions set to hit all-time high in 2023: report&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Chinese officials and industry watchers have vowed that the environmental impact would be limited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, the professor, defended the practice by saying that the self-restoring capacity among fish populations is greater in the open sea, and that it would be fine as long as farming activities are kept below certain levels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In fact, it&#39;s not necessarily a bad thing to add some nutrients into the distant sea, because it lacks minerals like iodine and phosphorus there. What matters is we do things within the line of environmental capacity,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest government guidelines issued late last month called for healthy and eco-friendly farming, stressing that farmers should determine what and how to breed based on carrying capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were also ordered to use feed and veterinary medicine approved by state-level government agencies to ensure the safety of the aquatic animals produced.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>