<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Our love is not worth US$53,000?’: man breaks up with girlfriend of 8 years after parents seek high bride price for ‘pretty’ daughter]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3223121/our-love-not-worth-us53000-man-breaks-girlfriend-8-years-after-parents-seek-high-bride-price-pretty?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/4abc39d9-f909-4c65-bc0f-1e02b990c86e_da4d64b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个中国东部的男人，因为父母要新娘而与女友分手380,000 元人民币（53,000 美元）的价格是抵制这种越来越昂贵的传统习俗的最新案例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对来自浙江省的身份不明的夫妇计划在八年的关系结束之前结婚，当时男子无法据中新网报道，女方父母要求的彩礼是当地的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体上的一段视频显示，女方的女友在得知婚外情后在一家餐厅内崩溃结束了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道说，这名女子一直在愉快地准备她的婚礼，不知道她的父母希望得到多少钱，也不知道她的男朋友和他的父母会反对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这名男子的父母预留了 25 万元人民币（35,000 美元），认为这笔钱可以支付他女朋友父母要求的任何价格。当得知彩礼为38万元，几乎是当地平均水平20万元的两倍时，他们感到震惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子和他的家人试图说服女友的父母降低价格，但他们拒绝了。他们说他们“漂亮”的女儿活该付高价，除非付清这笔钱，否则他们拒绝同意这桩婚事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男友的父母已经支付了房产的首付，供这对夫妇结婚后居住。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的独生子女政策于 2016 年结束，由于重男轻女的性别歧视态度，出生的男性远远多于女性，并造就了一代人男性多于女性。随着这些孩子到了结婚年龄，女性的彩礼因男女人口差距而大幅上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年中国男性人口为7.2206亿，而女性人口为6.8969亿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报道没有透露前女友对彩礼的看法，但表示她觉得男友如果爱她，应该想办法让她父母满意，而且有信心。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;然而，她和朋友在餐厅吃饭时，收到男友的短信，说因为父母的无理要求，男友决定分手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她立即打电话给他请他澄清，被拍成视频发到网上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“怎么回事？你为什么要跟我分手？” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们八年的感情，不值38万吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了解释自己买不起彩礼，他就挂断了电话。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;此事在内地社交媒体上引起广泛讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人评论：“她家卖女儿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她的父母想掏空他的孩子”家人的口袋，不是吗？”另一位人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于奢侈彩礼的故事在中国越来越普遍。本月初，中国东部一名男子开着一辆装甲车参加订婚仪式，车上载有 998 万元人民币（140 万美元）现金和金条作为聘礼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 3 月，一名 27 岁的中国男子在拒绝支付 88 万元人民币（12.3 万美元）的彩礼后与女友分手，成为热门新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China-led team finds first evidence of oldest stars in the universe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3223436/china-led-team-finds-first-evidence-oldest-stars-universe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/b6ff43c9-b96a-47ab-9287-92cd5edf8428_7b19698d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一项由中国牵头的研究首次获得了生命和死亡的观察证据– 我们宇宙中最古老的恒星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自中国、日本和澳大利亚的科学家利用世界上最大的两个陆地的综合能量，在银河系的光晕中发现了恒星独特的化学足迹&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的发现——来自北京附近的大天空区域多目标光纤光谱望远镜 (LAMOST) 和夏威夷的斯巴鲁望远镜——表明，所谓的第一代恒星——亮起大爆炸后大约 100 到 2.5 亿年的宇宙——可能是太阳质量的 260 倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们周三发表在《自然》杂志上的研究还提供了第一个基于观测的证据恒星在一次不寻常的爆炸中结束了它们的生命，这与我们今天所知道的超新星完全不同，直到现在才在理论上预测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛大学理论物理学家 Avi Loeb，他没有参与这项研究，勒布称赞这一发现“对于证实我们关于第一代恒星的理论观点极为重要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;勒布说，第一代恒星是宇宙中最大的未解之谜之一。科学家们预测，它们是由大爆炸后的原始气体形成的，仅由氢和氦组成，没有后来巨星核心合成的较重元素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天文学理论还表明，这些古老的天体的质量可能相当于数百个太阳，并在死亡时经历了一次独特的局部爆炸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一代恒星的寿命很短，而且很难被发现，仅在其内部留下了化学特征&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了他们的开创性研究，中国国家天文台的赵刚和他的同事筛选了 LAMOST 收集的超过 500 万颗恒星的光谱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些信息包括化学成分、温度、亮度和其他关键特性，科学家们将这些特性进行了比较，直到他们找到了一个候选者，称为 LAMOST J1010+2358。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约是太阳质量的一半，距离地球约 3,300 光年在银河晕中，这颗恒星的钠和钴等金属含量极低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团队将这颗恒星的光谱与理论模型进行了比较，得出的结论是，它很可能形成于以第一代恒星的残余物，质量相当于 260 个太阳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loeb 解释说，与后来宇宙中的恒星爆炸不同——恒星爆炸发生在恒星耗尽燃料并坍缩成中子星或黑洞——LAMOST J1010+2358 母星的爆炸涉及电子及其对应的反物质正电子的产生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电子-正电子对降低了支持如此大质量恒星对抗自身所需的内部辐射压力重力。这导致部分坍塌，引发热核爆炸，只留下一团气体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天文学家还预测，这一过程将导致奇数和偶数电荷离子丰度的巨大差异勒布说，数字——例如钠/镁和钴/镍。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国天文卫星发现了宇宙中最强的磁场&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这正是研究人员用 LAMOST 和斯巴鲁观测到的– 正如该论文的合著者邢千帆所说的“明显的奇偶效应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周三的新闻稿中，赵说没有直接证据表明这种巨大的金属超新星爆炸- &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“希望我们的工作能够对元素起源、早期宇宙中恒星形成以及星系化学演化的研究产生积极影响，”他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;黑洞图像激发想象力，激发中国新视野&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;赵说，团队打算继续寻找具有不寻常化学成分的恒星，以帮助更好地了解第一代恒星如何运作银河系内外均已形成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们计划将 LAMOST 的能量与将于明年晚些时候发射的哈勃级望远镜——寻天太空望远镜结合起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国同轨光学太空望远镜模块的视场将是哈勃望远镜的300多倍。其广阔的视野将使寻天能够在 10 年内绘制多达 40% 的天空，使用一个巨大的 25 亿像素相机。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blocking Google? Hong Kong internet providers express concerns over enforcing possible protest song ban]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3223452/blocking-google-hong-kong-internet-providers-express-concerns-over-enforcing-possible-protest-song?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/4e18320d-baa4-48ce-8b31-6c401947a31d_7f7a38a5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港互联网服务提供商 (ISP) 表示担心对政府寻求的抗议歌曲实施潜在禁令的责任将落在他们头上，而法律专家表示，谷歌等外国科技巨头不太可能遵守未决禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市居民可能会被裁员一个行业组织表示，如果供应商有义务屏蔽“香港荣耀”，则完全关闭 Google。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律政司司长林廷国周一向高等法院提交了一项前所未有的举措该曲调被视为 2019 年反对现已搁置的引渡法案的反政府抗议活动的非官方国歌。该令状要求法院禁止怀有犯罪意图的人“以任何方式广播、表演、印刷、出版、销售、要约销售、分发、传播、展示或复制”歌曲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，其目标是针对任何意图煽动他人的人根据早先的声明，将香港与国家分开，或通过传播抗议歌曲来侮辱国歌《义勇军进行曲》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“光荣归于香港”，而不是中国国民国歌，已出现在“香港国歌”的谷歌搜索结果中。在国际体育比赛中发生一系列混乱之后，该问题于去年年底曝光。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港必须让谷歌解决国歌结果问题：体育机构&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据美国大律师 Craig Choy Ki 认为，谷歌和其他美国公司无视香港法院下达的命令可能有多种原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禁令的目的在技术上可能无法实现他说，或者科技公司可能会拒绝基于保护言论自由等企业价值观的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，这些公司还面临着在美国国会受到盘问的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;《光荣归香港》抗议歌曲被禁？政府向法院提交禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“美国公司面临的不仅仅是商业环境，”他说。 “他们的政治考虑之一是，是否冒着让他们的首席执行官向美国国会解释为什么他们选择迎合如此小的市场 [当局] 提出的要求的风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一直是两党合作的国会山的目标，最近的例子是民主党和共和党立法者周三发出的一封信，敦促国务院禁止行政长官李家超在 11 月访问旧金山参加亚太经合组织峰会。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;香港互联网服务供应商协会主席 Lento Yip Yuk-fai 对谷歌回避禁令的前景表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该命令如果获得批准，也将禁止任何人从“协助”、“导致”、“协助”或“明知允许”他人进行或参与与传播抗议歌曲有关的特定行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;叶说，提及“协助”引起了&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;谷歌香港国歌搜索结果经过优化后有所改善：孙东&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自国安法生效近三年以来，香港的互联网服务提供商一直被要求执法部门阻止本地用户访问某些网站，包括发布与 2019 年社会动荡相关信息的网站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yip 表示，香港的网络提供商可以根据 IP 地址阻止对整个网站的访问，但他们在技术上无法看到互联网用户在搜索引擎和流媒体平台上查看的内容，因为数据流是加密的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“依靠 ISP 来识别和阻止特定内容在技术上是不可能的。即使是中国大陆的防火长城也做不到，”他说。 “我们无法维持对某些内容对用户可见而其他内容对用户不可见的网站的访问。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果执行歌曲禁令成为香港 ISP 的责任，互联网用户可能他说，无法访问部分或所有谷歌服务，因为提供商可能不得不阻止访问网站下的 IP 地址以确保完全合规。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“阻止谷歌将对香港产生重大影响。互联网服务提供商可以不承担后果吗？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专注于技术法的香港律师 Joshua Chu Kiu-wah 同意，ISP 也有可能被要求遵守禁令，他坚持的细节是受法院酌情决定权的约束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港法院可能对可从香港访问的内容具有管辖权，但 Chu 表示，很难对海外实体在其他地方的服务器上托管的内容执行禁令。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;香港橄榄球陷入困境后如何解决国歌失误&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“如果获得禁令，获得禁令是一回事。另一方面，该命令的有效性完全是另一个主题，很大程度上取决于相关辩护人是否充分协助法院阐明该命令的正确条款，以便于执行和执行，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;抗议歌曲也可以在各种流媒体和社交媒体平台上找到，包括 Facebook、Spotify 和 Apple Music。在政府宣布寻求法院命令后，不同版本的歌曲在 iTunes 上登上了香港排行榜的榜首。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港冰球队的“管理不善”导致国歌混淆：运动身体&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;谷歌和拥有 Facebook 和 Instagram 的 Meta 均拒绝置评。邮报还联系了 Apple 和 Spotify 寻求回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 前大中华区公共政策负责人乔治陈舒表示，该禁令将增加科技巨头留在中国的合规成本和复杂性。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果[公司]选择无视[挂起的订单]，他们可能会面临法律后果，否则如果平台不遵守并且政府不采取进一步行动，政府将失去面子”陈补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高等法院将于下周一听取政府的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Natalie Wong 的补充报告&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump says he’s been indicted in Mar-a-Lago documents probe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223464/donald-trump-says-hes-been-indicted-mar-lago-documents-probe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 07:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/08e4feac-427c-418c-b636-74a4752c85a5_c1e49e51.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，唐纳德·特朗普表示，他因在他的办公室处理机密文件不当而被起诉佛罗里达庄园，引发联邦起诉，这可以说是对前总统寻求夺回白宫的多重法律威胁中最危险的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“腐败的拜登政府已通知我的律师，我一直似乎是因为 Boxes 恶作剧而被起诉，”特朗普在他的平台 Truth Social 上写道，同时他打破了他第二次被指控的重磅新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司法部没有立即公开证实&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普目前在新泽西州贝德明斯特。一位未获授权公开讨论此事的知情人士表示，在特朗普宣布对 Truth Social 提起诉讼前不久，检察官联系了特朗普的律师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普表示，他将于周二下午在迈阿密出庭。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他写道：“我从没想过这样的事情会发生在一位美国前总统身上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多家媒体称这位前总统已被起诉与他处理机密文件和妨碍司法有关的七项罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普宣布这一消息的前一天，美国媒体称联邦检察官已通知这位前总统的律师，他是对其处理方式进行调查的对象的机密文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普通过视频出现在封口费案中，审判日期定在 3 月&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他已经是第一位被指控犯罪的前总统或现任总统 – 在他的选举前夕向一位自称与他有染的色情明星支付封口费的案件。该起诉书于 3 月下达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由总检察长梅里克·加兰任命的特别检察官杰克·史密斯一直在调查特朗普离开白宫后存放在海湖庄园住所的机密文件缓存白宫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FBI 在 8 月对 Mar-a-Lago 执行搜查令后带走了大约 11,000 份文件，而特朗普在花费数月时间抵制收回这些宝藏的努力后可能面临妨碍司法的指控.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普一再否认有任何不当行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他可能会在另外两起案件中被起诉——关于他推翻佐治亚州 2020 年选举结果的努力以及他在煽动2021 年国会大厦暴徒袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联社、法新社和路透社&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What lies beneath the surface of Hong Kong’s cheery giant rubber ducks?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223258/what-lies-beneath-surface-hong-kongs-cheery-giant-rubber-ducks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/3874b320-c899-4103-ab15-d9d9dd108c77_3d08312d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;荷兰艺术家 Florentijn Hofman 和当地创意工作室 AllRightsReserved 是否决定将他的两个巨人橡皮鸭去香港是因为他们认为这座城市对幸福的需求是十年前他那只巨大的水禽造访时的两倍？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可能吧。早在 2013 年，《华盛顿邮报》网站上年度阅读量最高的 10 篇香港故事是关于一个 5 岁的孩子在地铁列车内小便而惹恼了其他乘客——与这些新闻中的内容相比，这是一个纯真的时代&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月10日，霍夫曼18米高的“双鸭”将在维多利亚港下水。 “双鸭子就是双倍幸运，”这位艺术家在一份新闻稿中说道，其中充满了像鸭子一样膨胀的语言。 “‘双鸭’不是追忆过去，而是一起享受当下！”总而言之，他们蹒跚前行与政府的“欢乐香港”运动完美同步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果两只鸭子总比一只鸭子好，那 5,002 只怎么样？五千只（较小的）橡皮鸭将被放置在大屿山大佛脚下，因为港铁公司旗下的昂坪360缆车是赞助商之一。电车和 18 个港铁车站也装饰有橡皮鸭装饰——从电梯门和自动扶梯到巨大的架空悬架。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到同样由港铁运营的机场快线已经在其图片中被覆盖卡通吉祥物“KT Chai”（KT 听起来像机场快线的粤语），一进入港铁网络，基本上就陷入了少年地狱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AllRightsReserved，由林树锦创立 –更广为人知的名字是 SK Lam – 是举办和营销此类奇观的专家，包括由美国艺术家 Kaws 设计的巨型充气卡通人物的国际巡回演出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他成功地抓住了全球趋势已经看到艺术收藏家花费数百万美元购买卡通人物的绘画和雕像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，我们也看到越来越家长式的政府无处不在地包装公共信息，好像目标观众我们都是三岁的孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我们发现自己被比平常更坚持的“你不应该不快乐”的信息击中时，我们中的许多人可能会从围栏外面看”。还有原材料的不当之处：如果快乐的符号是可生物降解的，它们会带来更多的快乐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;请注意，很多人告诉我他们对黄色的快乐大使感到兴奋，积极性。他们不花我们任何钱（当然，我们购买商品时除外），他们说，香港需要振作起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位艺术治疗师朋友说，她在与孩子们一起工作时经常使用橡皮鸭因为它们毫无意义，被视为完全没有威胁，这有助于她的年轻客户敞开心扉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但鸭子真的那么被动吗？我想提出替代读物，也许这会让他们（稍微）更容易被其他脾气暴躁的人接受。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕竟，“Double Ducks”听起来与“double Dutch”并没有什么不同，一个英国表达胡言乱语。也许这是来自荷兰艺术家的恶作剧信息，要超越表面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍夫曼的巨型橡皮鸭被带到了最不可能的地方，大概是基于它们真正普遍的假设——你可能还记得阅读关于 2014 年在中国贵州省的一场洪水中被冲走的那幅画。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;也许这位艺术家是在表达美国文化霸权的观点。毕竟，它之所以成为这个地区童年怀旧的象征，是因为吉姆汉森布偶厄尼在广为流传的儿童电视节目《芝麻街》中总是和他的橡皮小鸭一起洗澡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;想想还有它被用作抗议标志的频率：2016 年巴西的反政府抗议者和 2020 年曼谷的民主集会都采用了它。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你猜怎么着？这位艺术家表示，他希望他的鸭子能够重新定义公共空间，吸引相遇和交谈。人们聚集！如果这不是香港激进的集会口号，我不知道那是什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，看来鸭子不仅仅是让我们陷入集体失忆的快乐玩具。但它是艺术吗？正如愤世嫉俗者可能会说：躲开那个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cheap diabetes drug cuts risk of long Covid by 40 per cent, study shows]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223463/cheap-diabetes-drug-cuts-risk-long-covid-40-cent-study-shows?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 07:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/4b2cb0c1-3dcd-48bb-8aeb-61abdd42d8d2_b3ca7c5e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在 Covid-19 检测呈阳性后服用廉价糖尿病药物的人有 40周五，一项基于美国的研究表明，Covid 长寿的风险降低了 %。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一发现被誉为对抗这种仍鲜为人知的疾病的潜在“里程碑”，世界卫生组织认为据估计，十分之一的人感染了新冠病毒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究称，这是第一个随机、安慰剂对照的 3 期试验——被认为是研究中的黄金标准——表明服用药物可以预防长期新冠病毒.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它测试了一种名为二甲双胍的药物，这种药物最初是从法国丁香花中提取的，几十年来一直是全世界治疗 2 型糖尿病最常用的药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这意味着该药物被认为是安全的，而且价格低廉且可广泛使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究涵盖了美国 1,126 名超重或肥胖的人，其中一半接受二甲双胍治疗，一半接受安慰剂治疗在 Covid-19 检测呈阳性后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10 个月后，服用二甲双胍的参与者中有 35 人被诊断出患有长期 Covid，而安慰剂组为 58 人，这表明风险降低了 40%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该试验是在 2020 年 12 月至 2022 年 1 月之间进行的，这意味着它包括 Omicron 变体，研究表明该变体导致长期 Covid 的比率低于以前的菌株。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;70%调查发现，香港 Covid 受害者有长期后遗症&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Covid-Out 试验背后的团队此前表明，二甲双胍可将冠状病毒患者的急诊就诊、住院和死亡风险降低超过40%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明尼苏达大学的研究员、这项新研究的主要作者 Carolyn Bramante 说，他们的数据表明二甲双胍“减少了患者体内的 Sars-CoV-2 病毒数量”。该研究发表在《柳叶刀传染病》杂志上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛医学院的医生 Jeremy Faust 没有参与这项研究，他在一篇链接的评论文章中说，如果得到证实，这些发现“意义深远，可能具有里程碑意义” 长期Covid。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伦敦国王学院流行病学教授弗朗西斯·威廉姆斯指出，564人不得不服用这种药物“以预防23个假设病例”。她说：“这意味着 24 人需要服用二甲双胍来预防 1 例长期 Covid 病例，”并补充说，要阻止这种知之甚少的病症，需要使用很多药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员警告说，他们没有在已经被诊断患有长期 Covid 的人身上测试二甲双胍，因此这些发现并不意味着它可以用来治疗这种情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究还发现抗寄生虫药物伊维菌素，这是整个大流行期间的错误信息的主题，以及抗抑郁药氟伏沙明并不能预防长期的 Covid。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据估计，数以千万计的人患有长期的 Covid，其中许多有时使人虚弱的症状会持续或复发感染三个月后可能会持续数年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最常见的症状包括疲劳、呼吸困难和称为脑雾的思维不清晰。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: Chinese manufacturers brace for the impact of Japan’s semiconductor export curbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3223419/tech-war-chinese-manufacturers-brace-impact-japans-semiconductor-export-curbs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/26e7232b-63c2-46de-bf28-e62e0260d24d_02d427c7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国公司正在争先恐后地寻找本地替代品以减少对日本供应商的依赖根据公司声明和分析师的说法，了解东京对半导体设备和材料的出口限制的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在日本经济产业省 (METI) 公布的更严格的出口限制下，23 种类型的日本供应商从 7 月开始，半导体设备需要获得事先出口许可证才能向中国销售。此前，美国、日本和荷兰就限制向中国出口先进芯片制造设备达成协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国政府敦促东京撤销限制措施，许多中国上市公司已经根据已发布的公司声明，通过表示这些措施对其运营的影响有限，并且他们正在加大努力寻找国内替代品来解决投资者的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国抨击日本的半导体技术出口管制&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;全球销量第二大的电视机制造商TCL科技向投资者表示，公司正在迅速扩大国内供应链以确保稳定运营，并表示将密切关注限制措施的变化，并及时做出调整。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最大的显示面板制造商京东方科技集团表示，尽管限制影响不大，但该公司已加倍努力确保供应链安全，并正在推动原材料本地化以将风险降至最低.这家在深圳上市的公司表示，它已经支持数十家上游材料和设备合作伙伴努力开发本地替代品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一家显示器制造商，在深圳上市的维信诺，也告诉投资者，它将“加强创新”，推动产业链上下游国产化，确保“供应链安全可控”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧洲意法半导体在重庆成立32亿美元芯片合资企业&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中文日资企业占全球显示面板产能的一半以上，但制造面板所需的核心技术和设备——如真空蒸镀机——大多掌握在日本企业手中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，PNC Technology Group，a上海上市芯片工艺设备供应商表示，日本的限制不会影响其湿法清洗产品，但对其他设备的影响仍不确定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司补充说，它一直在积极“寻找和培育”本地供应商，以替代日本和韩国的进口，并将“努力不断提高国内供应商的市场份额”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本计划出口管制是对中国芯片驱动的重大打击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;根据华金证券最近的一份报告，中国的芯片制造商高度依赖日本的光刻、蚀刻和热处理设备。报告援引中国海关数据称，去年日本进口的光刻步进机、离子蚀刻系统和热处理设备分别占这些进口总值的 28%、31% 和 59%。 /p>;&lt;p>;日本的限制措施被一些行业分析师视为当地芯片公司推动技术创新的机会，这与中央政府实现该行业自力更生的更广泛目标相一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;中信证券在最近的一份备忘录中表示，日本对中国这一日本芯片设备供应商的主要创收地区之一的限制，从长远来看可能会削弱日本的市场份额优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s cruise liner breakthrough marks crowning glory, but ambition to climb high-value chain faces challenges]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3223398/chinas-cruise-liner-breakthrough-marks-crowning-glory-ambition-climb-high-value-chain-faces?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/d6d828ab-1735-491a-a80b-a77118034030_8b4be40d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的造船商更接近于将最后一颗也是最珍贵的珍珠放在上面“the crown of shipbuilding” this week, while also accelerating a shift in high-quality development that will take the world&#39;s second-largest economy to new waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luxury cruise ships, together with liquefied natural gas (LNG ) vessels and aircraft carriers, have long been considered “the three pearls of the crown” as they represent the highest levels in vessels carrying passengers, cargo and military equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And with the undocking of China&#39;s first home- grown large cruise liner on Tuesday in Shanghai as the 135,500-tonne, 323-metre-long (1,060-foot) Adora Magic City moved to the final stage of debugging ahead of two trial trips in July and August after nearly four years of construction, the final piece in the country&#39;s shipbuilding puzzle is almost in place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Construction of a second luxury cruise ship, which is larger and heavier, is also under way in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Already a world leader in terms of ship orders received, China is now aiming for world-leading shipbuilding capabilities as its economy shifts from rapid growth to high-quality development, something that the authorities have said will be reliant on high-end manufacturing.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;However, making cruise ships and developing an industry from scratch is no small undertaking for China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Few domestic suppliers have the necessary experience to make specific cruise ship parts, nor are they familiar with international industry standards, so some supplies assembled on the ship need to be imported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have beaten South Korea and Japan in terms of conventional ships, but still lag behind in high-value-added ones,” said Xu Mingqi, a professor of international economics at the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But we&#39;re making more technical breakthroughs as we boost investment in research and development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why is China&#39;s first home-grown large cruise liner a breakthrough?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the first four months of the year, China accounted for 44.9 per cent of global output, 65.5 per cent of new orders and 51.3 per cent of orders on hand in terms of deadweight tonnage – a measure of how much a ship can carry – according to the China Association of the National Shipbuilding Industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China delivered 48 per cent of the world&#39;s merchant ships last year in terms of compensated gross tonnage – a measure of the amount of work involved in building a ship – with South Korea accounting for 25 per cent, according to British shipping market analyst Clarksons Research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The order book backlog at Chinese yards is estimated to be US$132 billion, the firm&#39;s managing director Stephen Gordon said, while South Korean yards are sitting on orders worth US$107 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But South Korea still has “the largest market share and a very strong position in LNG, although the Chinese share has been growing in the past 12 months,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Korea is also stronger in [liquefied petroleum gas carriers]. Traditionally Korea had a very strong tanker position, but the gap has narrowed and in order book terms is closer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China has developed a position in cruise [ships], although mainly for smaller luxury vessels, where there is stronger demand at present.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese shipyards have been promoting breakthroughs in building various types of vessels in recent months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four 93,000 cubic metre (3.3 million cubic feet) ammonia carriers – the world&#39;s largest of the type and the first for China – are being made by the Shanghai-based Jiangnan Shipyard after it received orders from the Singapore-based Eastern Pacific Shipping, the two companies announced early last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of March, a 155,000-tonne dynamic positioning shuttle tanker – China&#39;s first Suezmax vessel of its type – was also delivered by Dalian Shipbuilding Industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China has made breakthroughs in many types of ships, not just because it has caught up in building capability, but also because its outstanding performance over the past years has improved domestic and international shipowners&#39; confidence in Chinese shipyards,” said Penny Peng, senior business development executive at vessel valuation and information analysis firm VesselsValue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They are now willing to have a try in China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Peng, around 1,900 merchant ships have been delivered globally so far this year, with around 900 built by Chinese shipyards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of Chinese-made high-valued-added types, such as LNG and liquefied petroleum gas carriers, has also increased significantly, Peng added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s future, she said, lies not only in the improvement of its building capacity, but also in the development of a complete industry chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The point is whether it can stop relying on imports for key equipment, so that shipowners&#39; confidence in China-made equipment will improve,” Peng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s high-end manufacturing drive also saw it recently debut its first domestically developed narrow-body passenger jet – the C919 – which took its maiden commercial flight at the end of May.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korea steals No 1 spot from China for global ship orders in February&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China has high hopes that the C919 will reduce dependence on foreign technology as ties with Western countries deteriorate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is designed to compete with Boeing&#39;s 737 and Airbus&#39; A320, however, most parts used for the C919 are imported from foreign manufacturers, including the engine, avionics, control systems, communications and landing gear.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A series of systems used in shipbuilding are among “chokepoints” that left China dependent on other countries for key technologies, said a Beijing-based industry observer from a state-owned company, who asked not to be named as they are not authorised to speak to the media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cargo containment systems for LNG carriers, which ensure a super-low temperature, are a typical example, they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is China&#39;s C919 passenger jet and can it take on Airbus, Boeing?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re paying a lot of money in patent fees to France in this respect, and we&#39;re quite a way from creating our own, which will also cost a lot,” the industry observer said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shipbuilding industry association secretary general Li Yanqing said China had stepped up its manufacturing of other technologies and their use in Chinese-made vessels in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the one hand, the application rate of home-made equipment, such as the main engine, marine boiler, crane, gas supply system, has been growing,” he said, according to the Communist Party mouthpiece, the People&#39;s Daily, in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the other, we have improved in the research and development of high-end steel for ships – all crack arresters [that are a form of hull reinforcement] on large vessels have been replaced by home-made ones, and over 90 per cent of duplex stainless steel used in chemical tankers is made by domestic manufacturers, compared with less than 50 per cent previously.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite adequate orders, a majority of shipyards in China are running at a loss. Most of the publicly listed companies under the China State Shipbuilding Corporation are struggling to make a profit due to increased component and labour costs, according to a performance briefing by the companies at the end of May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four yards, including Waigaoqiao and Jiangnan, were running at full capacity, with orders scheduled until 2026, they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Hudong–Zhonghua Shipbuilding, another subsidiary of the state-owned corporation, production plans have been extended to 2028, a senior manager told the People&#39;s Daily in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As shipping emission rules have gradually tightened to fight climate change, subsidiaries are also increasing their investment in eco-friendly vessels, Shipbuilding Corporation deputy general manager Tao Jian told the briefing last month, according to Caixin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stringent emission regulations mean conventional ships, which may be heavy polluters, will be retired and replaced by vessels with low or zero emissions powered by LNG, methanol or other fuels, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Demand for such vessels means higher requirements for shipyards&#39; technology and building capacity,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Those which are able to produce low-emission products will be more competitive.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China stands a good chance of winning global competition in the building of ships powered by new energy, Han Qianting, an analyst with the China Merchants Bank Research Institute, said in a report in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Foreign countries have accumulated a century of experience in traditional heat engines and controlled patents in core technologies, but they are at the same starting line with us when it comes to new energy,” she wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China still world&#39;s No 1 shipbuilder, but global orders plunged in January&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But for smaller yards, the transition to being smart and eco-friendly is more of a challenge, said Mu Huaili, general manager of Yangliuqing Ship Factory in the northern port city of Tianjin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It may take a decade to knock out all the diesel-powered vessels” he said. “After all, new energy ones are still poor in terms of endurance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Due to overcapacity and stricter safety and environmental protection rules since the 2007-08 global financial crisis, up to 80 per cent of medium-and small-sized industry players in China have been eliminated, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having survived bankruptcy, Yangliuqing Ship Factory is now focused on vessels for domestic lakes and rivers, which has strong growth potential, according to Mu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now that the coronavirus pandemic has passed, the authorities have been urging the opening up of more stretches of the ancient Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal to navigation, and there&#39;s pent-up demand for travelling, so things don&#39;t seem too bad for us,” he added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US House panel reviewing university with Pentagon contract for ties to Chinese programmes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3223461/us-house-panel-reviewing-university-pentagon-contract-ties-chinese-programmes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 04:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/b45a95c2-03df-4ab9-9d94-f0eaf60bea64_691251f5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A university in upstate New York receiving millions of dollars in federal funds for hypersonic missile research has come under congressional scrutiny for hosting a Confucius Institute and partnering with a Chinese university that allegedly conducts classified research for the Chinese military.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You are funding advanced hypersonic weapons-related research at an American university that actively partners with a Chinese university that performs similar research for the PLA,” Representative Mike Gallagher, the chairman of the House select committee on China, said in a letter to US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin on May 31.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gallagher sought more information from the Defence Department regarding the “alarming matter” and “efforts to safeguard sensitive US military research”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A department spokesperson said on Thursday that the Pentagon would respond to Gallagher as “appropriate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located in upstate New York, Alfred University features a leading school in ceramics, which helped it secure a five-year research contract last year with the US Army Capabilities Development Command and the Army Research Laboratory. Under the agreement, the school is scheduled to receive $13.5 million in federal grants through 2027.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US hypersonic missile test marred by flaw as China, Russia maintain edge&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The research focuses on “improving the performance of ceramic materials used in weapons (ie, cruise missiles), which must be able to withstand the extreme temperatures that result from travelling at hypersonic speeds”, Alfred&#39;s president Mark Zupan wrote in a blog post in May 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Zupan said in an email that the university was “in the midst of certain internal and external conversations on the matter” and that he would issue a statement in a few days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Gallagher&#39;s letter to Austin, he said that the Pentagon had awarded the contract despite the “looming deadline” under a section of the 2021 National Defence authorisation Act that prohibited the department from “providing funds to institutions of higher education that host a Confucius Institute” after October 1, 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gallagher said that Alfred hosts a Confucius Institute and has also been in partnership with the China University of Geosciences in Wuhan since 2009.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Founded in 1952, the China University of Geosciences is a national university overseen by the Chinese Ministry of Education. According to the Washington-based Foundation for Defence of Democracies, it participates in classified defence projects, including research and training in “application of geology to warfare and the peacetime practices of the military”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The committee seeks all documents and correspondence between Alfred University and Pentagon staff and contractors responsible for performing due diligence, and all corporate, personal and financial documents pertaining to Alfred&#39;s Confucius Institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has also directed Alfred to submit all emails, letters and electronic documents regarding its agreement with the geoscience university.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Confucius Institutes are Beijing-backed language and cultural centres that China says are a bridge of friendship to the rest of the world. In recent years, though, the US has accused these schools of spreading propaganda, interfering with freedom of speech and spying on students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A bipartisan congressional report in 2019 found “no evidence that these institutes are a centre for Chinese espionage efforts or any other illegal activity”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gallagher suggested that Beijing employs Confucius Institutes to facilitate the pairing of Chinese universities with their American counterparts to gain access to sensitive tech and military research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Foundation for Defence of Democracies, Alfred received more than US$540,000 in grants from the Chinese government non-profit that runs Confucius Institutes from 2009 to 2021.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden and Rishi Sunak sign ‘Atlantic Declaration’ pact on AI, clean energy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223460/joe-biden-and-rishi-sunak-sign-atlantic-declaration-pact-ai-clean-energy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 03:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/2d864a80-5ea3-4472-87ed-35c8bf194e3f_dd7fa20a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden and British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak on Thursday agreed to deepen close economic ties between their countries, pledging to accelerate the clean energy transition and strengthen critical mineral supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two leaders also discussed their “unwavering support for the people in Ukraine”, Biden told reporters at a joint news conference with the British leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden and Sunak signed the “Atlantic Declaration”, which Sunak described as a first-of-its-kind economic partnership that mapped out future cooperation on issues such as artificial intelligence, and other economic and commercial relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know some people have wondered what kind of partner Britain would be after it left the EU,” Sunak said. “我会说，以我们的行为来评判我们。 We&#39;re as committed to our values as ever, as reliable of an ally as ever, as attractive an investment destination as ever.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two leaders shared laughs and more sober sentiments in the Oval Office about the close relations between prior leaders from the two countries as they previewed topics for the meeting, including AI and Northern Ireland, as well as joint economic and security interests, including in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting, their fourth in as many months, came as Western officials sought to ascertain whether Russia was responsible for the destruction of the Nova Kakhovka dam, which has displaced thousands of people and caused major economic and environmental damage. Ukraine and Russia have traded blame for the dam&#39;s destruction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden and Sunak fielded questions at the joint news conference after their meeting, an opportunity not afforded to every world leader who visits the White House, and will also issue a joint statement, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s daunting to think of the conversations that our predecessors had in this room, when they had to speak of wars that they fought together, peace won together,” Sunak told Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China to get new AI legislation ready for review this year&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Again, for the first time in over half a century, we face a war on the European continent, and as we&#39;ve done before the US and the UK have stood together to support Ukraine.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunak joked that he would not create the same imposition on Biden that World War IIo-era British Prime Minister Winston Churchill did by allegedly wandering around the White House residence in the middle of the night when he was a guest of President Franklin D. Roosevelt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunak brought Biden two gifts, a personalised Barbour jacket and a book written by an ancestor of Biden&#39;s in the 19th century.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden and Sunak last met in Hiroshima, Japan, at the Group of Seven summit last month. They also met in Belfast in April and in San Diego in March at a trilateral event marking the defence partnership between the United States, Australia and Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thursday&#39;s discussion touched on artificial intelligence safety, Sunak told reporters, saying Britain would host the first summit on the issue this autumn to discuss how the risks of AI can be mitigated through internationally coordinated action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunak had pushed to strengthen trading ties between Britain and the United States, keen to show some progress after the Biden administration quashed any speedy prospect of a post-Brexit free trade agreement between the two countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the absence of a bigger trade deal, Britain has cemented deals with individual states and is hoping to reach other such “targeted agreements”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Biden, business and baseball on UK PM Rishi Sunak&#39;s agenda in US&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sunak was also expected to try to win Biden&#39;s backing for defence minister Ben Wallace&#39;s bid to become the next secretary general of Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The British leader visited the US Capitol on Wednesday, where he met Republican and Democratic congressional leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunak said on Wednesday a new alliance would help London and Washington protect supply chains and navigate a global economy where new powers are “manipulating global markets, withholding crucial resources and trying to establish a stranglehold over the industries that will define our future”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US feels pressure to respond to China’s expanding nuclear capability: senior Pentagon official]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3223459/us-feels-pressure-respond-chinas-expanding-nuclear-capability-senior-pentagon-official?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 02:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/a5e5f2f5-01e2-4e0d-a09e-97f0a5d36805_ab5f33d3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As China and North Korea dramatically increase their nuclear weapons capabilities, the US has come under pressure to respond by modernising its own atomic arsenal and mapping out an expanded nuclear umbrella and contingency planning, a senior Pentagon official said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, which has declined to join non-proliferation talks, could have 1,500 nuclear warheads by 2035, up from some 400 managed by the People&#39;s Liberation Army, according to a Defence Department report released late last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, its total is still a fraction of the estimated 5,977 held by Russia or the 5,428 held by the US, according to the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s no secret the PLA is in the midst of a major nuclear modernisation,” said Ely Ratner, assistant secretary of defence for Indo-Pacific security affairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ensuring that we have the capabilities we need to maintain deterrence remains a number one priority for the United States as it relates to our allies and partners.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One pillar in response to the changing dynamic in northeast Asia has been funding America&#39;s nuclear modernisation. In 2021, the Congressional Budget Office estimated that Washington would spend US$634 billion over the next decade to upgrade its nuclear arsenal, a 28 per cent uptick compared with a previous 10-year projection.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The projects include ongoing development of a new W76-2 low-yield nuclear warhead for some submarine-launched ballistic missiles and longer-term development of a new nuclear submarine-launched cruise missile.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other nuclear priorities, particularly regarding North Korea, include strengthening potential responses to Pyongyang&#39;s gamesmanship and expanding Indo-Pacific deterrence alongside South Korea, Japan, Australia and other countries with whom the US is “extending nuclear umbrellas in the region”, Ratner added, without elaborating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ratner, recently back from the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore earlier this month, followed by consultations in India, voiced confidence that the Biden administration&#39;s focus on allies and partners was effective in countering China&#39;s growing footprint.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China should set up US communication channels: top Biden aide&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s no secret that China&#39;s assertiveness and coercion have really underscored the importance of working together,” said Ratner, formerly with the State Department, Rand Corporation and the National Security Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s my firm belief right now that the forces of stability are outpacing the forces of aggression and coercion.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the gathering in Singapore, China&#39;s defence minister declined an invitation to meet Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin as the deep chill in military-to-military relations continues. Beijing has accused Washington of forging multilateral alliances to try to contain China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ratner said developments in the Philippines illustrated America&#39;s coordination, with Manila recently agreeing to grant the US access to four of its bases, without any plan to build US bases in the country. Cooperation is under discussion in other areas as the island nation becomes an increasingly important ally rivalling Japan and South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similarly, Japan has agreed to double its national security budget over the next five years and station US Marines on its southwest islands near Taiwan. And the US is working with India to better align New Delhi&#39;s weapons-building and industrial expansion ambitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US &#39;using international law to provoke China&#39; after Taiwan Strait incident&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While Ratner did not address New Delhi&#39;s ongoing historical ties with Russia and its extensive reliance on Russian weaponry, this initiative is seen as a way to wean India away from Moscow in the wake of Russia&#39;s 2022 invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he added that the push for closer integration of weapons systems, intelligence and personnel with Indo-Pacific allies was forcing the US to confront counterproductive American export controls and the Pentagon&#39;s often sclerotic bureaucracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We can all have aspirations … to deepen our alliance partnerships, work on technology cooperation. That all sounds very flashy, as a concept,” Ratner said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s going to be required in the US-India relationship. It&#39;s going to be required in the US-Japan relationship. It&#39;s going to be required as it relates to a number of our alliances and partnerships … We are in the middle of really a revolutionary change inside of the US system.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>