<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[2 Hong Kong taxi drivers arrested for alleged overcharging amid police crackdown on industry malpractice]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3230871/2-hong-kong-taxi-drivers-arrested-alleged-overcharging-amid-police-crackdown-industry-malpractice?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 10:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/da55a868-5270-44e2-bd56-2e6a0dc05b19_029afbfe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两名香港的士司机周五晚因涉嫌多收费在尖沙咀被捕警方对无视计价或拒绝乘客的无良出租车司机进行了打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方还向在代号为“Firststrike”的行动中违法的八名出租车司机发出了总共 10 张交通传票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从周三至周五，中环的旅游热点地区也采取了类似的针对出租车违规行为的行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的士行业代表、顾问对于如何阻止出租车司机过度收费存在分歧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本周早些时候，一名中国大陆游客在社交媒体上发布的一段视频中透露，他从中环到铜锣湾的乘车报价高达 200 港元（25.58 美元），是计价表的三倍多。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据警方透露，便衣人员在广东道冒充游客，发现两名出租车司机（年龄分别为32岁及55岁）索要不合理车费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两名司机其后因涉嫌多收费及不出示出租车计价器而被捕，已获准保释，但须下个月向警方报到。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西九龙及油尖区交通部警队将继续行动再过几天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方在一份声明中表示，“警方高度重视的士涉嫌多收费行为，并提醒公众，这是严重违法行为。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它警告说，被判多收费的出租车司机最高可被处以1万港元的罚款和六个月的监禁。警方表示，将继续采取“果断执法行动”，严厉打击违法行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方还呼吁乘客，如发现出租车，请记下时间、地点、的士车牌、司机姓名和路线。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的士司机向中国大陆游客报出三倍计程表费用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在为期三天的单独行动中，该行动结束了周五，警方还向三名据称拒绝乘客的出租车司机发出传票，并向出租车司机发出了另外 28 张定额罚款单，这些司机的违规行为包括未正确设定计价器、在禁区接送乘客或非法停车。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，政府提出了一项法案，加强对该市私人出租汽车行业的监管，其中包括一项扣分计划，如果出租车司机违反 11 项违规行为中的任何一项，将处以 3 分、5 分或 10 分的处罚.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多收费、故意拒绝或忽视接受载客将被扣 10 分，而使用除最直接路线之外的路线以及拒绝载客等行为将被扣 5 分和 3 分。要求的乘客人数，前提是总数在车辆容量之内。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的士司机因涉嫌向警务人员多收费而被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果司机在两年内累积积分15或以上，其将被取消三个月经营出租车资格。随后的资格将被暂停六个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持该提案的旅游部门代表表示，这将有助于阻止出租车司机的不良行为，但出租车工会警告说，积分制度将重复现有的惩罚措施并施加压力关于守法司机。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Philippine senate steps up bipartisan support for stronger stance against ‘brazen’ China: ‘stop bullying us’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230852/philippine-senate-steps-bipartisan-support-stronger-stance-against-brazen-china-stop-bullying-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/212ce500-15e9-46a1-8104-4d35ec8ff4f2_18cff3f1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;菲律宾立法机关的上议院由该国一些最著名的政治人士组成数字，但这个由 24 名成员组成的机构长期以来一直在表达有关外交政策的观点时采取经过校准的方法，遵守两党安静的共识，即该领域主要是现任总统的领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8 月 1 日，然而，参议院采取了一个具有象征意义但值得注意的举动，令观察人士大吃一惊：参议院主席胡安·米格尔·祖比里（Juan Miguel Zubiri）跨越党派界限，与反对党参议员里萨·洪蒂维罗斯（Risa Hontiveros）一起“谴责”中国在有争议的南海针对菲律宾渔民和船只的行动。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;随后，全体参议院一致通过了由祖比里和洪蒂维罗斯共同发起的参议院第 79 号决议，“强烈谴责中国海警和民兵船只对菲律宾渔民的持续骚扰以及对争议海域的持续入侵” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几天前，中国海警在仁爱礁的 BRP 马德雷山脉上拦截了试图向菲律宾军队运送食品、燃料和水的菲律宾船只，并向其发射了高压水枪。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这艘二战时期的船只于 1999 年被菲律宾故意搁浅，以阻止中国在争议激烈的海域前进，长期以来一直是马尼拉和北京之间的冲突点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的事件还发生在观察人士所说的菲律宾对北京的官方政策及其对海域的主权主张加强之后——每年通过该海域进行的贸易额约为 3 万亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马科斯可以学习杜特尔特的对华策略，正如他的北京之行所示&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年接替中国鸽派罗德里戈·杜特尔特 (Rodrigo Duterte) 的总统小费迪南德·马科斯 (Ferdinand Marcos Jnr) 表示，他不会让中国践踏菲律宾的海洋权利，并寻求加强与前总统的防务关系殖民统治者和美国的长期盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8 月 7 日，祖比里在会议现场告诉他的同事，参议院在前一周史无前例地获得两党批准 SR 79，这是“本届参议院的决定性时刻” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;祖比里 SR 79 的合著者洪蒂维罗斯 (Hontiveros) 告诉《亚洲周刊》：“自从我成为参议员（2016 年）以来，这是唯一一项专门针对西菲律宾海问题的决议。主要由参议院议长和一名反对派参议员撰写。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾要求联合国干预南海争端的呼声越来越高&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;参议院基本上忽视了海争端，认为这是一个严重的问题。杜特尔特于 2016 年就任总统时提出了这一问题，并对中国采取了比其前任贝尼尼奥·阿基诺三世友好得多的态度 — — 阿基诺三世迫使海事争端在海牙常设仲裁法院进行仲裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仲裁法庭是根据《联合国海洋法公约》解决争端的一种方式，驳回了中国对该海域（以九段线为特征）的巨大主张。北京方面表示，该裁决不公平，并指出其根据国际法不具有约束力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪蒂维罗斯将参议员们最近迫于公众压力以及中国海岸警卫队针对菲律宾船只和渔民的行动而做出的戏剧性转变归功于他们。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国最近的行为太厚颜无耻，太令人遗憾，不容忽视，因此在这个问题上保持沉默是不明智的，”她说。 “2022 年的一项调查还显示，89% 的菲律宾人希望政府维持我们 2016 年的仲裁裁决，因此参议院作为一个整体可能不得不再回应我们人民的情绪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这确实证明当一项事业得到公众的大力支持时，机构将很难不倾听。”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SR 79 的令人惊讶的支持者包括参议员 Christopher “Bong” Go，杜特尔特前助手，华裔；参议员艾伦·彼得·卡耶塔诺 (Alan Peter Cayetano)，杜特尔特的前外交秘书；总统的姐姐参议员伊米·马科斯 (Imee Marcos) 继续敦促与中国建立更密切的关系，并重新审查与美国的安全关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴甚至公开告诉中国“停止欺负我们”。伊梅·马科斯没有解释她的投票，但卡耶塔诺试图软化他的投票，提出“‘和平’应对中国并结束在西菲律宾海针对菲律宾海岸警卫队的一系列侵略的五种方式”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;卡亚塔诺的建议包括与中国“真诚对话”、追求行为准则以及“与中国共同勘探石油和天然气，因为资源互惠互利才能带来和平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，他们的投票背后也可能有政治​​考虑。现任总统马科斯在南海问题上与中国疏远了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴和马科斯都有望在 2025 年连任，而祖比里最近推动马科斯当选参议院议长，其能力受到质疑。尽管已批准的措施存在严重错误，但还是签署了 Maharlika 主权基金法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前参议院多数院领袖奥兰多·梅尔卡多 (Orlando Mercado) 解释了参议院及其 24 名成员对关键国家问题的影响。他说，“首先，上议院是全国选举产生的”，就像总统一样。 “因此，当参议院作为一个整体发言时，它就具有说服力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然外交政策属于马科斯总统的职权范围，但宪法规定参议院在外交政策中发挥作用，例如通过梅尔卡多说，批准各部门的条约和预算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回顾说，在科拉松·阿基诺担任总统期间，“马来西亚要求菲律宾放弃沙巴主权主张，以换取总理马哈蒂尔·穆罕默德参与”东盟会议在马尼拉举行。他说：“参议院不同意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回顾说，1991 年 9 月 16 日，参议院以微弱多数否决了拟议的《俄罗斯联邦-美国友好、合作与安全条约》，参议院也发挥了历史性作用。扩大了美国在该国的军事基地的存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;南海：菲律宾国防部长驳斥了北京的九段线&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管全国选举将举行，但还是做出了拒绝次年 1992 年举行，菲律宾人是坚定的亲美人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅尔卡多说，参议院举行了听证会，并公开广泛地辩论了这个问题。虽然萨隆加在 1992 年竞选总统失败，但梅尔卡多表示，他和维格伯托·塔纳达 (Wigberto Tanada)、埃内斯托·马塞达 (Ernesto Maceda) 和特奥菲斯托·金戈纳 (Teofisto Guingona) 等一些拒绝主义参议员仍然获胜。参议员约瑟夫·埃斯特拉达（Joseph Estrada）甚至拍摄了一部针对美国基地的电影，赢得了副总统职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院在南海问题上的统一立场的直接影响可以体现在对明年国防支持的增加上。预算和报纸头版上更多的反华言论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院主席祖比里本周建议抵制中国公司和商品。周一，他还在会议上发表了特权演讲，说道“中国，为什么成为你的朋友如此困难，爱你如此困难”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们如何让我们相信他们”有一天，他们在北京向我们的前总统（杜特尔特）表示赞扬和保证，然后不久之后，第二天，他们向我们的船只发射高压水枪，这是真诚的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;祖比里说，他很清楚外交事务是菲律宾总统的特权。 “但是，当保护我们边境并处于危险之中的军队一直在表达他们的厌恶时，我们怎么能不发声呢？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国政府很早就意识到参议院对外交政策的影响。它三次邀请参议院议长访问中国：1995年，中国军队不顾马尼拉的抗议，加固美济礁后不久； 2004年，就在北京和马尼拉同意进行联合石油勘探且参议院没有反对之前不久； 2017 年，李克强总理访问马尼拉前不久，两国同意深化双边关系，包括联合石油勘探。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I just shot my wife. I won’t be in tomorrow’: California judge Jeffrey Ferguson charged with murder]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230872/i-just-shot-my-wife-i-wont-be-tomorrow-california-judge-jeffrey-ferguson-charged-murder?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 10:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/148e2c57-92aa-4135-a9d8-4700c250f8d9_2bdba523.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;奥兰治县高等法院法官杰弗里·弗格森因枪杀一名男子而被指控犯有谋杀罪上周，他的妻子在阿纳海姆山的家中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 72 岁的法官于 8 月 3 日被捕，当时他的儿子打电话给紧急调度员，说他的母亲 65 岁的谢丽尔·弗格森 (Sheryl Ferguson) 被枪杀。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官被拘留，在监狱里待了一晚，并缴纳了 100 万美元保释金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据检察官周四晚间提交的文件，凶杀案发生当晚，弗格森和他的妻子在一家餐馆吃饭时发生争执，他“用枪指着她的手势”威胁她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当这对夫妇回到家时，争吵仍在继续，谢丽尔在那里弗格森说：“你为什么不用真枪指着我呢？”检察官在法庭文件中称，或类似的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官喝醉了，然后从脚踝皮套中拔出一把格洛克 0.40 口径手枪，向她的胸部开枪，子弹从她的背部射出，击中了她的胸部。检察官称，她身后的墙。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“令人震惊的统计数据”：2023 年上半年美国记录了 28 起大规模杀戮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法官成年的儿子拨打了 911 并试图进行心肺复苏检察官称，他的母亲说他的父亲喝得太多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官本人后来拨打了 911，说他的妻子需要护理人员，但当被问及他是否开枪射杀了她时，他说他没有检察官说，他不想谈论这件事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，据地区检察官办公室称，法官给法庭书记员和法警发短信说：“我刚刚失去了它。我刚刚开枪打死了我的妻子。明天我不会来。我将被拘留。我很抱歉。”检察官称，接收者最初认为该短信是一个玩笑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官称，当警方将弗格森拘留时，他浑身散发着酒气，而且还穿着空的脚踝皮套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他据检察官称，他要求警察开枪射杀他，并发表了一些言论，这些言论被警方的随身摄像机捕捉到：“我真是个混蛋”，“哦，伙计，我不敢相信我做到了这一点”，“我我想我已经完成了一段时间了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;枪击事件发生七小时后，警方抽取了法官的血液样本来测量其酒精含量，此时测得的酒精含量为 0.06%，低于法定限度根据法庭文件，弗格森的儿子告诉警方，他的母亲曾经劝说法官不要开枪自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官将要求法庭强制执行弗格森的额外保释条件。他们的担忧之一是失踪的步枪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管阿纳海姆警方在搜查法官家时没收了 47 支枪支以及 26,000 多发弹药，但侦探们无法找到一支 0.22 口径步枪，该步枪是据地方检察官办公室称，他的名字登记在他的名下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方在搜查法官家时又遗漏了另一支步枪，地方检察官说，尽管弗格森的辩护律师后来找到了它并将其移交。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在额外的保释条件中，检察官将要求弗格森交出他的护照和携带隐藏武器的许可证，不持有枪支并佩戴脚踝监视器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在动议中设置周二，在弗格森的提审中，副地区检察官克里斯·亚历克斯要求法庭限制被告与其成年儿子之间的接触，法庭文件称他是凶杀案的唯一目击者，“以防止对儿子造成任何程度的风险或不当影响。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官还将要求法官完全避免饮酒。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;犹太教堂枪击案凶手因美国历史上最致命的反犹太主义袭击而被判处死刑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管其检察官出现在法庭面前直到上周，奥兰治县地方检察官办公室正在处理此案，并援引州总检察长办公室的决定，认为不存在冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗格森本人担任当地检察官超过一年距离 2015 年成为法官还有 30 年的时间，如果目前的指控被定罪，他将面临 40 年至终身监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对整个弗格森家族来说是一场悲剧。据城市新闻服务报道，弗格森的律师约翰·巴尼特和保罗·迈耶在一份声明中表示：“这只是一次意外，仅此而已。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s eastern economic powerhouse provides national snapshot; declining workforce, demand and wages plague Jiangsu]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3230826/chinas-eastern-economic-powerhouse-provides-national-snapshot-declining-workforce-demand-and-wages?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/fc52934b-16e2-462a-be18-e4b3e5269bb9_c8060ab3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国东部经济强国江苏显示劳动力紧缩，制造业需求减少和外国企业，除了持续不断的年轻人失业，凸显了严峻的经济前景和疲弱的复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于一系列令人失望的经济指标，市场对下周发布的中国经济数据的预期较低，北京方面&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“6月末，制造业企业从业人员比去年同期减少11.9万人，一线实际工作时数减少。”省发改委上周发布的一份报告称，生产线工人减少了，工资也下降了。该报告已于周五从官方网站上删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;最糟糕的时期已经过去了吗？ 7月份中国通货紧缩忧虑加剧的4大要点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为中国第二富裕省份的江苏指出，市场需求萎缩、出厂价格下跌、利润和预期疲软，迫使制造商报告还指出，今年前六个月，近70%的大型外贸企业报告出口订单下降， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月末，外贸企业和外商投资企业从业人员较去年同期分别减少13万人和14.7万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，报告补充说，今年前六个月服务业以及研究和技术行业的劳动力需求有所增长，表明复苏不平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着全球经济停滞、地缘政治紧张局势加剧、供应链迁移趋势巩固，中国作为世界工厂的地位受到挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月份出口降幅创2020年初以来最大幅度，较去年同期下降14.5%上年同期跌至 2,817.6 亿美元，连续第三个月下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的生产者价格指数（反映工厂向批发商收取的产品价格）也连续第 10 个月下降，此前下降了 4.4%。 “主要发达经济体通胀水平持续高位，持续加息抑制投资和消费需求，外需持续疲弱报告补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国出口在 2024 年之前将保持疲软：7 月贸易数据的 4 个要点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;世界贸易组织预测全球货物贸易量将下降今年我国用工增速为1.7%，明显低于过去12年2.6%的平均增速。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际国内经济形势对外贸企业用工需求持续构成压力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，上半年江苏新增就业岗位超过70万个，位居中国各省份之首。但严峻的经济形势反映了国家的整体前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江苏还报告称，由于“青年[愿望]与劳动力市场需求不匹配，结构性失业挑战，青年失业前景严峻” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月份全国16-24岁年龄段失业率创21.3%新高预计7、8月份将进一步上升，进入劳动力市场的大学毕业生将达到创纪录的1158万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;展望未来，由于全球电子产品更新换代，部分制造业的劳动力需求可能出现季节性上升。报告称，尽管一些制造商可能会在秋季进行迭代，但一些制造商的正常劳动力需求可能会增加一倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，结构性挑战仍然存在，因为随着自动化水平的发展，公司越来越多地寻求技术熟练的工人，尽管劳动力过剩普通工人，高级技术人员的资源有限。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China debt: these 3 regions have the most daunting debt piles. So what can be done about it?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3230828/china-debt-these-3-regions-have-most-daunting-debt-piles-so-what-can-be-done-about-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/ab48f78b-8a34-4db8-948b-2e53b407389f_bf6f5dc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;经过多年的经济快速增长，中国各地地方政府所掌握的资源已经在经济复苏慢于预期和全国房地产市场低迷的情况下，房地产市场的下滑令人担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国政治局（共产党内的权力中心）首次在会议上规定上个月，有必要通过“综合解决地方政府债务”来化解地方政府债务风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明凸显了中央政府更加关注欠发达地区面临的财政困难，因为惠誉国际评级8月6日发布的研究报告显示，今年以来，公众对地方政府融资平台所售债务违约的担忧日益加剧（地方政府融资平台）是公共和企业的混合实体，其创建目的是为了规避地方政府借贷的限制，自 2008 年全球金融危机以来数量激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;评估债务水平&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“不过，我们认为中央政府将避免对陷入困境的地方政府融资平台进行救助，因为这可能会产生‘道德风险’风险。省级政府有许多现有工具来帮助地方政府融资平台，包括使用债务互换。其他解决方案可能包括帮助[较小的]地方和地区政府处置地方政府融资平台的资产、向地方政府融资平台注入运营资产、请求[省级当局]提供财政支持以及银行贷款重组，”这家美国评级机构表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央政府认为救助地方政府存在“道德风险”，因为这种做法可能会鼓励地方政府以牺牲纳税人利益为代价的鲁莽支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就国内生产总值而言，中国一些最贫困的省份去年，他们的土地出让金（GDP）下降了一半以上。穆迪投资者服务公司 8 月 9 日的一份报告显示，吉林、天津、青海、黑龙江、辽宁、云南和甘肃的收入均出现大幅下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其他地区，历史上收入较高的地区穆迪表示，山东省和福建省等地方政府融资平台的降幅也很大。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国顶级银行向地方政府融资平台提供 25 年期贷款，以避免信贷紧缩&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;基于穆迪投资者服务公司 (Moody&#39;s Investors Service) 的一份报告使用 2022 年的数据，考察了中国债务与 GDP 比率最高的三个省份，该报告将每个地区的债务金额与经济规模进行了比较。债务部分包括省级政府及其地方政府融资平台持有的公共债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这个位于中国北方、渤海之滨的沿海城市，曾经是中国最发达的城市之一工业和制造中心。但随着多年来经济增速下滑，天津的财政状况一直举步维艰。它是没有将实际 GDP 增长目标设定为高于 2023 年 5% 国家目标的四个地方政府之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国港口城市天津正在失去对欧洲企业的吸引力&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;根据香港贸易发展局的数据，2022年天津的实际GDP增长率仅为1%，其外商直接投资也从2015年的211.3亿美元稳步下降至2021年的53.9亿美元。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;继 2018 年以来发生一系列违约之后，天津市政府于 2021 年出台了措施，改善负债累累的国有企业的财务状况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆迪预计，天津的地方政府融资平台将有一半以上尽管明年到期的地方政府融资平台债券的财政收入覆盖率相对较低，但其债券将在未来 12 个月内到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国南方山区内陆省份 – 闻名遐尔广受欢迎的茅台白酒品牌——经过多年的巨额基础设施支出，一直在积累债务。然而，尽管价格高昂，但并非所有项目都带来了地方政府所希望的效益。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;病毒视频引发了人们对“鲁莽”的 57 亿美元建设热潮的质疑&lt;/h3>;&lt;贵州目前正在建设横跨峡谷的花江大桥，预计耗资20亿元人民币（2.766亿美元）。该大桥预计将于 2025 年竣工，将开辟一条横跨北盘江的新路线，北盘江是大珠江流域的一部分。据当局称，这座桥全长 2,890 米（1.8 英里），桥面高出河流 625 米，将成为世界上最高的桥梁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;遵义路是贵州省地方政府融资平台之一贵州省政府和桥梁建设集团去年与债权银行谈判达成了一项重组协议，延期了 156 亿元人民币的贷款，以减轻其债务负担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贵州省官员 4 月份的评论称，该地区无法根据收入来管理债务偿还，引发了人们的广泛担忧，即地方债务危机可能比之前预期的更为严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;负债累累的贵州省向北京寻求帮助，但帖子很快就消失了&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2022年甘肃西北地区的GDP总计为1.12万亿元人民币，但人均收入仅为45,000元人民币（6,233美元）——是中国所有地区中最低的，据粤开证券研究所首席宏观分析师罗志恒测算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我省财政收入规模较小，对中央转移支付的依赖程度较高；传统产业贡献税收比重较高，省内财政收支差距较大；政府的债务负担也比较大。偿债压力逐年加大。”罗在6月发布的甘肃债务问题研究报告中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们不欠投资者一分钱”：甘肃将双倍举债且不违约誓言&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;西北省会兰州的一些地方政府融资平台几年来已经陷入财务困境，损害了当地政府在资本市场筹集资金的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;穆迪预计，与财政收入相比，甘肃已背负大量地方政府融资平台债务，同时面临资金外流，甘肃将面临更大的困难来适应土地出让收入大幅减少的情况。此外，穆迪表示，甘肃省还出现了地方政府融资平台债券融资净流出，说明其再融资困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;4。青海（105.8%）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5.重庆（101.3%）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6.浙江（101.2%）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7.云南（101%）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8.四川（100.3%）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9.吉林省（95.6%）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10.江西（92.8%）&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Clock ticks down for China-US science deal amid tech theft fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230799/clock-ticks-down-china-us-science-deal-amid-tech-theft-fears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/6713a513-ecb5-4ec9-b0d4-88b1023ee2b1_d399ccaf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;拜登政府正陷入困境，有不到一个月的时间做出决定.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只剩下几周时间，白宫将决定是否续签四十年前由时任美国总统吉米·卡特和中国最高领导人邓小平签署的具有里程碑意义的科技协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;中美科学技术协议于 1979 年生效，每五年更新一次，除非政府采取行动使其继续有效，否则将于 8 月 27 日自动到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议制定了政府间科学合作的条款，为学术和企业互动开辟了道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但一些美国立法者警告不要延期，理由是担心知识产权被盗和给企业带来意想不到的好处。中国军方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[中国]将最大程度地利用民用研究伙伴关系用于军事目的，这不足为奇，”众议院中国问题特别委员会主席、国会议员迈克·加拉格尔 (Mike Gallagher) 说。共产党，在六月份写给美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯的信中表示，反对更新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着美国努力阻碍中国在核心技术方面的进步，同时努力寻找合作的共同点，拜登的助手和官员对自己的意图守口如瓶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责美方协议执行的美国国务院也是如此。在回应置评请求时，它表示“不会对悬而未决或潜在的国际谈判或有关谈判的内部审议发表评论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京方面已表现出恢复甚至修改长达数十年的合作的意愿。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大使馆发言人刘鹏宇表示，北京一年前曾与美方联系“讨论”续签事宜，“据我们所知，美方仍在就续签协议进行内部审查” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着形势的不断发展，双方可能会考虑对原来的协议进行调整，”刘说，并补充说，中国准备讨论合作的“内​​容和形式”。 “平等互利的基础”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，中国“希望”美国“在协议到期前加快内部审查”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不安全、不受欢迎：美国一些专家表示同意，称美中合作长期象征的再次延伸将符合美国的利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库战略与国际研究中心黛博拉·塞利格松表示，作为两国关系正常化后签署的首份协议，该协议具有“巨大的历史意义”。 p>;&lt;p>;“美国不应因为北京方面的意愿而延长协议，而是因为这样做显然符合美国的自身利益，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seligsohn 表示该协议产生了“许多具体的科学技术成果”，从出生缺陷和流感研究合作到对抗空气污染和艾滋病毒/艾滋病预防，这些成果使美国和世界其他国家受益匪浅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the years scientists on both sides had also worked together on almost 100 protocols and annexes under the agreement, “specifically, a number of changes to intellectual property protections”, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seligsohn said nonrenewal could complicate recent attempts to find areas of cooperation, including the “the types of people-to-people connections and educational exchanges” that Blinken agreed to promote during his visit to Beijing in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a real risk that any such improvements, including access to key health information and the ability to train the United States&#39; next generation of China experts, will be put at risk if the agreement lapses,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Suttmeier, a US-China science and tech cooperation expert at the University of Oregon, said letting the agreement lapse would not be “productive for finding the right terms for the larger relationship with China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One could imagine the two sides finding other ways to cooperate on these global problems, and scientists themselves are often finding ways to cooperate on matters of mutual interest,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The absence of an agreement, however, adds levels of difficulty to these interactions and may reduce the public goods benefits in the absence of a government to government framework.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;with China emerging as a scientific superpower, the flow of knowledge is going in both directions,&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;The issue is complicated by national research and innovation but mutually beneficial cooperation is “certainly not impossible”, according to a US-China Economic and Security Review Commission report published in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report, written by Suttmeier, also pointed out that activities such higher education opportunities in the US and transfers of American technology that “played a major role in development of Chinese wealth and power” were “largely outside the terms” of the agreement.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Suttmeier acknowledged that China had been the biggest beneficiary of the agreement – “largely because the US had been so far ahead of China in science and technology; there was less to learn from China than China could learn from the US”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nevertheless, the US benefited in a variety of ways,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, however, with China emerging as a scientific superpower, the flow of knowledge is going in both directions, so, in principle, the benefits to the US could be greater.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suttmeier said it would probably be a mistake to let the deal lapse and the two countries needed to come up with an agreement that reflected the “realities of the third decade of the 21st century”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Current deliberations in Washington are occurring in a politically fraught time, which makes executive branch action a matter of some delicacy,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A short-term renewal would make sense if both parties committed to negotiate an agreement more suitable for current conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There certainly are risks associated with renewal, there are also significant risks by not renewing.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Number of Hong Kong students at English state schools surges 400 per cent in past 2 years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3230859/number-hong-kong-students-english-state-schools-surges-400-cent-past-2-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/aa7b3c23-bb21-4f5e-b242-459aff65eee1_95e2de72.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The number of Hong Kong students at English state-funded schools has surged more than 400 per cent over the past two years after the UK launched its pathway to citizenship for city residents, a British government survey has found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Britain&#39;s Department of Education said the latest data showed 5,400 Hong Kong pupils were studying in schools in England during the 2022-23 academic year, but noted the figures were not reflective of the true number as the annual poll was voluntary.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;BN(O) migration scheme for Hongkongers to stay for now: British diplomat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“This means that any count we provide of pupils known to be of Hong Kong origin will be an undercount to an unknown degree,” said Ann Claytor, a statistician with the department&#39;s school census statistics team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She also stressed that schools could just identify pupils within the wider “Chinese” grouping without specifying if they were from Hong Kong, Malaysia or Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey also only covers schools in England.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the figures, the number of “Asian-Chinese” pupils at state-funded nurseries and schools rose from 37,943 in 2020-21 to 48,396 in 2021-22, before increasing to 58,731 a year later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The census team told the Post that the number of Asian-Chinese students from Hong Kong stood at 1,081 in 2020-21, when the UK introduced the British National (Overseas) visa scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The figure increased to 3,068 the next year and rose to 5,423 in 2022-23.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Number of Hongkongers in independent UK schools up nearly fivefold in 2 years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The visa scheme was launched in January 2021 in response to Beijing&#39;s imposition of the national security law on Hong Kong in 2020 and allows city residents to apply for citizenship after spending five continuous years in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UK&#39;s Home Office had received up to 172,500 BN(O) visa applications as of March this year. Earlier figures showed about 27 per cent of candidates were below the age of 18.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, department data also showed that education authorities in Birmingham recorded the largest contingent of Hong Kong nursery and school pupils, at 795.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UK-based lawyer Catherine Lam Hoi-ying, who runs a Facebook group called “Hong Kong people in Birmingham” that has more than 10,000 members, said the area&#39;s affordable housing prices had attracted many young families and led to high demand for schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are lots of young parents speaking Cantonese and carrying their young kids aged about 10 in Birmingham&#39;s Chinatown. They probably just came from Hong Kong,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But she noted that the surge in Hongkongers going to Birmingham meant competition for highly prized schools had intensified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of people joining the social media group, which Lam set up in 2015, surged after Britain introduced the BN(O) visa scheme, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hongkongers voice concerns over UK plan to raise BN(O) fees, health surcharge&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As the UK&#39;s second-largest city, Birmingham could offer Hongkongers spacious homes at lower prices and desirable schools, Lam noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hongkongers moving to the UK would like to live in the big cities rather than remote regions,” she said. “But property prices in inner London are unaffordable for most, while outer London and suburban areas are also expensive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Renting a decent house with two to three bedrooms in [Birmingham&#39;s] suburban areas only costs £1,000 to £1,500 [US$1,272 to US$1,908] a month.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam added that those settling in the city generally found it easier to acclimatise since it shared some features with Hong Kong, citing ease of travel without relying on cars and an influx of eateries hoping to cater to the new arrivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The census data also showed Nottinghamshire in the East Midlands and Barnet in northwest London ranked second and third respectively in terms of Hong Kong pupils, boasting about 500 each.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Over 1,000 adult children of Hong Kong BN(O) holders eye expanded UK scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Essex, a county northeast of London, and Salford in Manchester logged the fourth- and fifth-largest contingents at 400 and 200 pupils.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A further breakdown of the survey indicated that about 35 per cent of the 5,400 Hong Kong pupils were studying at Key Stage Two, referring to forms in English schools for those aged eight to 11.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A quarter of the Hongkongers were studying at Key Stage Three, which covers students aged 12 to 14, while another 15 per cent were enrolled in Key Stage One for those aged five to seven.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Really harmonious’: father in China defends video of daughter, 4, asleep with ‘tame’ Burmese python around waist after ‘ignorant’ criticism]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/environment/article/3230492/really-harmonious-father-china-defends-video-daughter-4-asleep-tame-burmese-python-around-waist?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/09/31934773-acd1-4e40-9e3d-5a0e2dbc2532_52710917.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A video of a four-year-old girl hugging a large golden Burmese python as she falls asleep has stunned mainland social media observers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl&#39;s father, surnamed Zheng, took the video at an animal shelter in Fujian province in southeastern China on August 7, Star Video reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Burmese pythons are carnivores and they use constriction to kill small mammals and birds.然而，大型蟒蛇可以捕食猪和山羊等更大的猎物。这种爬行动物原产于亚洲，体长可达 5 米，未经证实的报道称有些体长可达 7 米。 The golden form is popular as a pet due to its usual colour variation caused by a loss of pigmentation, leaving its skin white and yellow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the video, the daughter is seen falling asleep, leaning against a chair, with the large python around her waist. Later she is shown awake and playing with the reptile.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zheng said that his daughter is fond of animals, and he took her to the animal shelter where a friend of his works to see the animals including the python at least once a week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that his daughter enjoyed spending time with a variety of animals, such as parrots.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the video of his daughter handling the python was taken, the pair had helped staff give the reptile a bath.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to Star Video after the video trended online where he was criticised for being “ignorant” by allowing his daughter to handle a wild animal, Zheng said that the snake was tame and did not pose a threat to humans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s really harmonious,” he described the scene of his daughter and the snake.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video has sparked widespread debate in China between those who said the father was supporting his daughter&#39;s love of animals safely and those who claimed he was ignorant of the danger.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Only children who grow up this way can be spiritual,” said one supportive commenter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another was sceptical: “Wow, how come the father is so confident? No animal can be tamed completely.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dangerous animals kept as pets in China are uncommon but not unheard of and have caused problems in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May this year, a 17-year-old secondary school student in eastern China was bitten at home by a pet oriental pit viper, a venomous snake native to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, a man in southwestern China was investigated by local police after his pet crocodile attacked a neighbour.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia state polls: voting begins as PM Anwar Ibrahim faces first major popularity test]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230866/malaysia-state-polls-voting-begins-pm-anwar-ibrahim-faces-first-major-popularity-test?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 07:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/8fe08036-5f87-49ea-8de3-96b0a153c4a7_9e55ffbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Polls opened in six Malaysian states on Saturday in what may be the first serious political challenge to Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim, who is hoping to prove the Malay-Muslim majority has not deserted his unity government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around 9.7 million people are eligible to vote to choose the next governments for the six states – the opposition Perikatan Nasional (PN) is seeking to hold Kedah, Kelantan and Terengganu in the north, while the government parties dominate Negeri Sembilan, Penang and Selangor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The results of the state contests will have little direct bearing on Anwar&#39;s hold on federal power. But they are seen as a barometer of support for him and his rag-tag administration of political allies and former foes, especially among the Malays who made a significant shift towards the Malay nationalist PN in last November&#39;s general election.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can TikTok dominance give opposition the edge in Malaysia state polls?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;PN has targeted that Malay base in its campaign strategy, with micro-video sharing platform TikTok a key tool in its outreach to voters in Malay heartland areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At dozens of campaign stumps and over social media, PN has kept its message simple: Anwar and his unity government consort with corrupt leaders and have failed to rescue Malaysians from soaring living costs and persistent inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A recent TikTok live session featuring the controversial chief minister of Kedah, Muhammad Sanusi Md Nor, and political commentator Wan Muhammad Azri Wan Deris – better known as Papagomo – drew more than 62,000 views and 16 million likes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Muhammad Sanusi on Thursday said voters are well acquainted with the “true face” of Anwar, who he said had made countless lofty promises for over two decades to better the lot of all Malaysians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For twenty-five years he was begging to be made PM. After he was given the mandate, eight months later nothing has happened,” Muhammad Sanusi said at a youth gathering in Kedah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These six states will become a referendum, a sign … for &#39;Papa Non&#39; and his lackeys to pack up their things in Putrajaya,” he said in a TikTok video of his campaign speech, referring to Anwar and the administrative capital of Putrajaya.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anwar&#39;s Pakatan Harapan (PH) and partner Barisan Nasional (BN) are hoping social media uptake does not play out in the polls on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;November&#39;s national election saw Malay voters in the peninsula create a “green wave” – so-called to reflect the party colour of Islamist party PAS – that gave the opposition PN a significant all-Malay minority share of the country&#39;s 222-seat parliament.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anwar has been at the forefront of his administration&#39;s efforts to turn the tide of Malay support in their favour, criss-crossing the country to reach as many Malay-majority areas as possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a campaign stop on Friday in his home state of Penang, the prime minister pleaded with Malay voters to give him their support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Be it an issue involving padi [subsidy], rubber [smallholders], military houses, civil servant salary, [survival of] fishermen, we are trying to maximise improvement within these eight months,” Anwar was quoted as saying by national newswire Bernama.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Imagine we continue to govern for another five years, Insya-Allah Malaysia will become a great nation in Asia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anwar&#39;s efforts, however, may not have brought the intended results.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Research firm Ilham Centre on Thursday released the findings of a July survey, said just one in four Malays among over 2,400 respondents across the six states said they were satisfied with the prime minister&#39;s performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts have forecast the outcome of Saturday&#39;s polls to result in the status quo being held, albeit with PN gaining ground in government stronghold states of Penang and Selangor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Independent pollster Merdeka Center said in a survey report on Friday that PH and BN have a task on to convince their core supporters to come out in force if they hope to slow PN&#39;s advances in the country&#39;s two richest states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Non-Malay voters remained firmly in support of Pakatan Harapan, but questions abound on their turnout rate,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysia&#39;s unity government &#39;won&#39;t erode&#39; Malay power: DAP&#39;s Anthony Loke&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Malay voters may seek a new platform to represent their identity politics after roundly rejecting former ruling party and BN linchpin Umno in the November polls, experts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite finishing with just 28 seats, Umno managed to find a way back into government after the king picked Anwar for the top job, on condition that he form a unity government that included both his political allies and adversaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Election Commission on Friday said it expected voter turnout to exceed 85 per cent by the time polling closes on Saturday evening.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Simply fixing our degraded soil could have a huge climate impact]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230685/simply-fixing-our-degraded-soil-could-have-huge-climate-impact?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/10/733cdf56-91c5-4152-b9bd-45f8292a712e_8b812480.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As the summer sizzled, UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres warned that “the era of global boiling has arrived”. What can we do about that?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fighting climate change requires a systems change that will be tough – if not impossible.已故的系统思想家和 1972 年《增长的极限》报告的合著者达纳·梅多斯 (Dana Meadows) 认为，改变复杂系统的关键方法是找到正确的杠杆点，在这个杠杆点上，微小的改变可以产生巨大的影响。 So what&#39;s the obvious, common factor in climate boiling?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scientific answer is carbon emissions.大气主要由氮气和氧气组成，但是当阳光照射到大气中更多的碳颗粒时，地球就会变暖。 Before human life, there was a more balanced carbon cycle, with plants and microbiological life capturing carbon through photosynthesis, keeping the temperature balance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As humans learned to till the soil and burn fossil fuels, we accelerated carbon emissions and climate warming, melting the ice caps and permafrost that trapped carbon dioxide and methane, causing sea levels to rise.这正在威胁我们的食物和水供应、生物多样性，并最终威胁人类的生存。 Food, water and energy shortages can trigger war and conflict, which only further damage the environment, like the Ukraine war has destroyed many of its farmlands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So what is the leverage point when it comes to food production, water supply and carbon capture?答案是：土壤。海洋也很重要，但我们大部分人口生活在陆地上并依赖农业。 Of the three biospheres – land, ocean and the atmosphere – soil arguably offers us the best chance to fix things.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mismanagement has degraded more than a third of the world&#39;s soil.联合国粮食及农业组织估计，如果不采取任何措施，到 2050 年，土壤退化率可能上升至 90%。 The more land degradation, the less food there is for our growing population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most rural communities grow their own food but urban societies, which make up more than half of mankind, rely on large-scale, industrial food production. A 2019 EAT-Lancet Commission report found the world&#39;s faulty food systems had left about 1 billion people hungry and 2 billion people eating too much of the wrong food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 40 per cent of adults (2.1 billion people) are now overweight, while 3.1 billion people cannot afford a healthy diet.工业生产的食品往往包含转基因生物以及大量既不健康也不营养的化学品和防腐剂。 Between 30 and 40 per cent of food in America is wasted during production and delivery, uneaten or thrown away due to poor logistics or overbuying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Increasingly, industrial food production and agricultural land is concentrated in the hands of very large corporations. Their monoculture farming, such as for palm oil or soybean, may be efficient in the short run but ends up hurting biodiversity, increasing inequality by driving out small farmers, and can mean paying insufficient attention to carbon capture and environmental sustainability issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deforestation exposes the top soil and allows it to be leached of nutrients.在最基本的层面上，土壤由细菌、真菌、蠕虫和微生物组成的复杂生态系统组成，可以保护生物多样性、节约用水和捕获碳。 Saving the soil literally preserves our future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Increasingly, there is awareness that a farmer-centric effort to regenerate soil and food production can not only tackle our food crisis and water shortages but also capture carbon. Europe has formed a coalition to explore a farm-centric agriculture regenerative initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the grain and fertiliser supply shocks arising from the Ukraine war, developing countries were further alarmed last month when India announced it would limit its rice exports. Suddenly, food self-sufficiency is high on the policy agenda – politicians are aware that high food prices are socially destabilising.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We should pay more policy attention to domestic farmers and the use of permaculture in regenerative farming to produce crop diversity and soil regeneration.重新造林等农业实践也可以捕获碳，并可以通过销售碳信用额创造新的收入来源。 Unfortunately, the global carbon market is not yet functioning evenly, so developing countries are not benefiting fully from higher carbon prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recent archaeological finds in the Amazon showed the presence of terra preta, a nutrient-rich composted soil.用堆肥改善退化土地可能是恢复土壤质量和多种作物种植的更便宜、更有机的方式。 In short, technology is available to increase food production organically to help raise not just rural incomes but also food quality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The regeneration of soil, forests and water sources are social impact projects, as important as public infrastructure such as roads and ports, offering high social benefit but low financial return.这些正是社会证券交易所和慈善机构应该支持的项目类型。 Even in cities, vertical farming using organic compost and fertilisers can boost food self-sufficiency and cushion supply disruptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is this all pie in the sky?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Solving climate change and social injustice is about doing more for many with less.再生土壤意味着改善有限的资源，为更多的人生产更有营养的食物，减少我们相互竞争的需要。气候变化是环境的变化。那些系统思考、本地化行动和适应的人将会生存下来。 Those who deny change will not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Signs of Chinese business life return to Afghanistan 2 years after the Taliban’s takeover]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230359/signs-chinese-business-life-return-afghanistan-2-years-after-talibans-takeover?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/f4a443cb-e1da-4d38-b898-8f53e68b2421_f3b59f71.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Duan Yi, a Chinese gemstone trader who moved to Afghanistan about 18 months ago, has noticed clear changes on the streets of Kabul in recent months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foreign tourists – mostly from Europe and the United States, and now an increasing number of Chinese – are back to the once deserted capital city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xijing has seen the same trend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a director of Kabul&#39;s Chinatown, Li has greeted dozens of Chinese businessmen making tentative steps back into the city. Journalists, from Britain to Japan, have also knocked on his door since spring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Chinatown] is getting crowded,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the Taliban took control of the war-torn country in 2021, Afghanistan&#39;s economy and security has not collapsed as some had expected. Instead, the central Asian country has begun to slowly pick up the pieces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for Chinese businessmen who have chosen to return and stay, they know to take the good news with a grain of salt, and to be patient. While the Taliban regime has brought security since coming to power, terrorist attacks have not stopped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, the international community, including China, is yet to recognise the regime, with human rights – particularly while severe restrictions are imposed on women and girls – among concerns cited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, China&#39;s then-foreign minister Qin Gang said Beijing hoped the Afghan Taliban would heed the concerns of the international community and resolve issues relating to women&#39;s rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, he said that while the issue of women&#39;s rights and interests was very important, “it is not the whole of the Afghan issue and nor is it the core or root cause of the Afghan issue”, according to a ministry statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While most businesses on the street are back to normal as the Taliban promised, the country&#39;s economy still suffers as a result of foreign sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Afghanistan is not as scary as it was portrayed in the media, but you are always on edge,” Duan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li, as an executive in Kabul&#39;s Chinatown, said his growing contact with businessmen in recent weeks was a sign of recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located in Kabul&#39;s city centre, the Chinatown community is the first stop for most Chinese people who are new to the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But when the Taliban took control of Afghanistan two years ago, only about a dozen Chinese chose to stay. Li said that in the whole of Afghanistan, fewer than 20 Chinese people remained.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China announces land link with Taliban-controlled Afghanistan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“In the past two years, when it comes to Afghanistan, the Chinese people always think that there are wars and terrorist attacks, but more are coming back now,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Chinese people began to look to do business and invest in the country again, Li said they “need to choose the right way or method”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the absence of normal diplomatic relations between countries, businesses are cautious about investing,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China may not have formally recognised the Taliban regime, but senior Chinese officials have held high-level meetings with their Afghanistan counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jennifer Brick Murtazashvili, founding director at the University of Pittsburgh&#39;s Centre for Governance and Markets, said China was hesitant to establish formal ties with the regime because of concerns about its stability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Neighbours [of Afghanistan] are most familiar with Afghanistan&#39;s history and governance dynamics, and they recognise that without a more inclusive government, Afghanistan will be unstable for years to come.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu Yongbiao, a professor in Lanzhou University&#39;s school of politics and international relations, said security remained China&#39;s biggest concern.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At this stage, the essential problem [for China] is to urge Afghanistan to draw a line with terrorism,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, China issued its most comprehensive position paper on Afghanistan since the Taliban took power, listing 11 points on the regime.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Female Afghan judges are in hiding and living in fear of being found by Taliban&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s Position on the Afghan Issue” appealed to the Taliban government to “adopt moderate and prudent domestic and foreign policies”, and three of the 11 points in the paper referred directly to the Taliban&#39;s counterterrorism activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The paper highlighted the East Turkestan Islamic Movement (ETIM), a Uygur separatist group that Beijing has blamed in part for ethnic tensions in its far western Xinjiang region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Murtazashvili said Uygur separatist groups remained China&#39;s key worry in its counterterrorism ambitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China wants Afghanistan to be able to eliminate the terrorist groups, especially the small Uygur groups that have remained in the country. These groups are the biggest threats to China from a strategic perspective,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond the separatist groups of concern to Beijing, Chinese people in Afghanistan also felt threatened by Isis-K, or Islamic State Khorasan, an Isis affiliate in Afghanistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Five Chinese nationals were seriously wounded in an attack by Isis-K by Kabul&#39;s Longan Hotel in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, the militants reportedly targeted members of the Chinese delegation in another suicide bomb attack outside the foreign ministry in Kabul that officials said killed at least five people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isis-K was also known to be responsible for other attacks at the Russian and Pakistan missions in the capital city last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun Fei, a 37-year-old trader who lives in Kandahar, said Chinese still lived under the shadow of attacks despite an overall improvement in security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Security has got better, but [the terrorists] have started to pick on the Chinese and Russians more,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Sun, there were widespread rumours about terrorist attacks from Kabul to the southern city of Kandahar a month before the Longan Hotel attack.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The discrimination [directed at Chinese] is so obvious,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nishank Motwani, a fellow with the Harvard Kennedy School&#39;s Edward S. Mason programme, said that by carrying out the attacks, the militants wanted to undermine the Taliban&#39;s legitimacy and sow doubts about security among foreign investors, diplomats and governments.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Who will be the midwives?&#39;: Shut out of jobs, Afghan women retrain as nurses&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Isis-K is likely to execute more attacks against soft targets, which include Chinese nationals, because it amplifies their propaganda, humiliates the Taliban and undermines the security environment that helps them grow.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Murtazashvili said she believed that attacks against Chinese people would continue, even as security in Afghanistan improved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After two years of Taliban rule, Afghanistan does not have as much widespread fighting … A big reason for this is that the Taliban now controls the government,” she said. “The Taliban itself was the source of most of the insurgent violence we saw in the country.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, after the deadly attack, Taliban spokesman Suhail Shaheen promised Chinese nationals would be safe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The current government reiterates its obligation to maintain the safety of Chinese nationals and all other nationals who are coming to Afghanistan, either for investment, business or tourism,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese gem trader Duan, who has also lived in Pakistan, is cautiously optimistic about safety in Kabul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To be honest, terrorist attacks targeting Chinese were even more dangerous in Pakistan [than in Afghanistan] but it doesn&#39;t mean that we are not worried,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun cited the cheaper airfares between Kandahar and Kabul and more road traffic in the past year as signs that security in the country had improved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The reason more people are driving is because there are no bomb attacks or terrorist groups roaming the highways now,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But without international recognition and a stable security environment, Afghanistan&#39;s economic recovery will remain difficult and take years, if not decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s economy appears to have benefited from the reopening. According to the World Bank, Afghanistan&#39;s government revenue collection for the first quarter of this year increased 8 per cent year on year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taliban leader claims Afghan women have &#39;free, comfortable, prosperous life&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Zhu said that while the data showed signs of stability or even improvement, it was largely achieved because of international aid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is still a huge hole in the entire budget of the Taliban, which is partly supported by foreign aid, and the country&#39;s own economic programmes are largely undeveloped,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Due to the risk of sanctions and security, Chinese companies are still reluctant to invest in Afghanistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Most companies – after they come and have a real look – will become less interested in investing. And that&#39;s actually normal following the rules of economics.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Business talks between Chinese state-owned companies and the Taliban are continuing, but according to Zhu, nearly all negotiations face long delays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, the privately run oil company Xinjiang Central Asia Petroleum and Gas Co (CAPEIC) signed a contract to extract oil from the Amu Darya basin, the first major extraction deal the Taliban administration had signed with a foreign company since retaking power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAPEIC will invest US$150 million a year in Afghanistan under the contract, increasing to US$540 million in three years under the 25-year agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are optimistic about the future of Afghanistan. After all, it is still a country after [being] at war for so many years,” Li said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He recalled a meeting with Taliban officials in Kabul after they returned to power two years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All the foreigners have run away, but only you Chinese – you have been here for 20 years – are still here,” he quoted a Taliban official saying at the time.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>