<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Bitter punisher: critics round on Chinese company which makes underperforming workers eat pungent raw melon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224579/bitter-punisher-critics-round-chinese-company-which-makes-underperforming-workers-eat-pungent-raw?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/19/425f1e9b-a0da-404f-b298-e193789ada62_132c329d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一家中国公司在被曝光强迫员工在生吃苦瓜未能达到绩效目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于中国东部江苏省的教育培训公司苏州大澳方城实信息咨询有限公司强迫十几名员工每人生吃一整颗苦瓜作为惩罚，一名姓钟的员工于 6 月 15 日在网上发布了一段视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司发言人告诉媒体机构百星观注，这种做法是设计奖惩计划的一部分 –并由视频中显示的员工团队达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们自然会避免痛苦并追求快乐。如果他们不想吃苦瓜，他们会努力工作，”该发言人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的在线反应一直坚定地站在员工一边。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“当我听到这是‘自愿的’时，我真的笑了。我们生活在一个如此艰难的时期，”一位人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我宁愿公司解雇员工，也不愿以这种侮辱性的方式惩罚他们，”另一位评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很多人分享了自己被雇主非理性惩罚的经历，例如被强迫吃芥末和辣椒，喝花露水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 10 月，中国东部浙江省的一家公司在惩罚员工后走红谁在销售比赛中让他们吃苦瓜和芥末一起输了。一名工作人员将处罚过程拍下来分享到网上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“苦瓜的苦只是一时的，人生的苦却是永远的。公司的处罚激励我们更加努力地工作。作为惩罚，她不得不穿着高跟鞋跳 50 下蛙跳，导致她肌肉受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德恒律师事务所劳动法律师袁亚阳告诉《早报》，视频中的处罚违反了中国的劳动法.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;劳动法还规定，员工有权就他们认为不合适的合同和规则进行谈判，但员工很少这样做，因为担心失去工作。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3224737/chinese-scientists-use-quantum-computing-simulate-black-hole?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/9a2cef24-e577-4a12-a404-63db22e977ca_fd65bd33.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个由中国领导的科学家团队表示，他们已经使用&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员表示，霍金辐射实验为使用超导量子芯片模拟黑洞的量子效应开辟了一条新途径，标志着“朝着创建具有类似特性的量子系统的方向迈出了一步” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;科学家说，冲击波可以解释为什么黑洞会向太空喷射粒子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;黑洞是太空中的一个区域，该区域的引力非常强，即使是光无法逃脱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当粒子落入黑洞视界并且视界阻止粒子返回时，它就不可能逃脱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是当考虑到量子效应时，黑洞内部的粒子会逐渐向外逃逸，导致霍金辐射。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国理论物理学家史蒂芬·霍金于1974年提出的理论是指辐射，即传播的能量以波或粒子的形式，理论上从黑洞的视界或边界之外发射。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过霍金辐射，黑洞失去能量并最终蒸发。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“这个新构建的模拟黑洞进而有助于进一步研究黑洞的其他相关问题，”来自中国科学院、天津大学、北京量子信息科学研究院和日本理化学研究所先导研究集群的研究人员日本在本月发表在同行评议期刊《自然通讯》(Nature Communications) 上的研究结果中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然在天体物理学中很难直接观察到真实黑洞的量子效应，但通过该团队说，因为这些效应非常微弱，因此需要进行实验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的几年中，科学家们使用浅水波、玻色-爱因斯坦凝聚体（一种物质状态，其中所有组成粒子都在其中）来测试该理论处于最低能级 - 以及光学超材料和光。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在观察模拟霍金辐射的最新研究中，该团队开发了一种超导处理器，该处理器由 10 个量子比特链组成，相互作用耦合由 9 个可调谐控制&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;黑洞图像激发想象力，激发中国新视野&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“结果表明，模拟黑洞内部的准粒子总是有一定的概率通过事件视界，其辐射概率满足霍金辐射的性质。通过测量视界外的所有量子比特来验证这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的结果将激发更多人对使用带有可调谐耦合器的可编程超导处理器探索黑洞相关特征的兴趣，”该团队写道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Not just business: EU firms in China aim to de-risk as they reassess ‘how many eggs to keep’ there]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224778/not-just-business-eu-firms-china-aim-de-risk-they-reassess-how-many-eggs-keep-there?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/a2fb49e4-338a-4201-8876-5aeb393ec565_69dc61a7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;供应链从中国转移的势头越来越大，这种转变反映了外国根据一家领先的欧洲贸易协会的最新调查结果，投资者对中国市场的信心正在减弱，而东盟市场的吸引力正在上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟商会最新的商业信心调查在中国的调查显示，11% 的受访成员已经将部分投资移出中国，计划今年在世界第二大经济体扩张的公司数量创历史新低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着去风险策略的出现，投资开始从中国转移，”商会周三发布的最新报告称，该报告基于 2 月至 5 月期间对 570 家公司的调查——46% 的回复率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;此消息发布之际，李强总理正在访问欧盟，这是他担任总理后的首次出访，着眼于促进与欧盟主要大国的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国总理访问德国以巩固“混乱”中的关系和变化”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最新报告还表示，另有 20% 的人正在考虑将投资转移到其他地方或推迟做出任何此类决定，因为他们正在等待观察 2023 年中国商业环境的演变情况。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“面对越来越大的风险和更加动荡的经营环境，欧洲公司仍在重新评估在他们的中国篮子里放多少鸡蛋，”报告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚国家联盟的成员国正在报告称，这两个市场将成为供应链搬迁的主要目的地，其次是欧洲市场，因为这两个市场占搬迁计划的 48%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，十分之一的欧洲公司在中国，他们表示已经或计划将其亚洲总部迁出大陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡 (43%) 和马来西亚 (17%) 是新总部的前两个选择, 报告称，在有意搬迁的人群中，香港占 9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;需要增强弹性、应对地缘政治风险并减轻国内政策（例如中国的自给自足计划）的影响是影响公司供应链决策的三大因素，它说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这表明企业正在考虑将投资主要用于降低风险和建立弹性，而不是纯粹出于商业原因，”商会写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对中国市场的信心进一步削弱，因为只有 55% 的受访公司认为中国是未来投资的前三大目的地——低于 2022 年的 68%，这也是创纪录的低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管中国在 12 月取消了限制性的零 Covid 控制，但根据商会的调查结果，将继续看到近三年政策的挥之不去的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;统一的国内市场有助于解决中国经济增长问题？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;航空航天行业以及医疗器械行业最不愿意扩大在中国的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称：“零 Covid 已经结束，但必须谨慎应对即将出现的挑战，以恢复商业信心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2016 年以来，商会接受调查的公司中首次有不到一半的计划今年将扩大在中国的投资，从 2022 年的 62% 下降到 46%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管企业并未完全放弃中国市场，但脱钩也在加剧，供应链战略继续演变为报告称，对冲监管不确定性和地缘政治紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四分之三的受访者审查了过去两年的供应链战略，近四分之一打算进一步或完全将在岸供应链引入中国.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“欧洲企业在中国经营时面临的挑战越来越多，这促使许多企业将其在中国的业务本地化并孤立起来。越来越多的人正在创建两个独立的系统，一个用于中国，一个用于世界其他地区——包括供应链、数据和信息技术 (IT) 系统以及人员配备——这是一种昂贵且低效的解决方案。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报告表明，在过去两年中，27% 的受访公司发现其总部与中国业务脱钩，高于去年的 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“公司总部与中国业务之间的脱节中国业务有可能进一步损害对中国市场的信心，引发分歧的恶性循环，”报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京今年加强了魅力攻势以吸引海外投资者，但外国商人继续重申长期以来，人们一直抱怨“承诺疲劳”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟商会指出，“市场开放仅迈出了一小步”，因为两分之一的公司认为市场准入没有变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;模糊的规章制度、不可预测的立法环境和市场准入障碍导致数量“惊人”的欧洲公司表示他们已经错失商机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据报告，创历史新高的 62% 的欧洲公司报告说失去了商业机会，比去年的 42% 大幅上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府有机会证明亲商其领导层最近做出的承诺不仅仅是口头上的，”报告说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese consumers remain cautious on spending, chase bargains and discounts amid slowing economy: study]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3224786/chinese-consumers-remain-cautious-spending-chase-bargains-and-discounts-amid-slowing-economy-study?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/1789a446-bedf-4f1c-826e-e7766f67a72b_d8f29ffe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国消费者在放松钱包方面仍持谨慎态度，许多人倾向于淘便宜货全球咨询公司贝恩公司和市场研究公司凯度消费者指数的联合研究显示，在经济前景黯淡的情况下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告显示，中国内地快速消费品 (FMCG) 的平均售价在北京从其零 Covid 策略转变为与病毒共处之后，中国第一季度同比下降 0.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消费品总支出增长 1.9%，而销量小幅增长报告显示 2.7%，但没有透露绝对数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2020 年开始的价格通缩趋势一直持续到 2023 年第一季度，但各类别之间的差异更大，”Jason Yu，周二，凯度大中华区董事总经理在媒体吹风会上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在经过三年的严格疫情遏制后于 1 月重新开放经济，这增加了人们对国内消费快速复苏的希望。然而，内地消费者对就业前景和收入增长感到不安，他们控制了支出，导致从瓶装水生产商到面巾纸制造商的消费品制造商都在努力提高销售额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bruno Lannes，a上海贝恩资本合伙人警告说，零售额增长需要时间才能回升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“快速消费品行业在 2 月份开始了增长轨迹，[但]全面复苏需要时间，我们认为第一个季度数字跟踪良好，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，中国消费者似乎更愿意在餐饮和旅游等服务上花钱，而不是在消费品上花钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; “被低估”的中国消费类股即将迎来转机：摩根士丹利&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第一季度，家庭护理产品的增幅最高，支出同比增长 13%，平均售价上涨 3.2%，报告显示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们不一定会购买最便宜的商品，但他们会一丝不苟地寻找既能满足他们需求又能以相对较低的价格提供的产品，”Kantar 的 Yu 说。 “当品牌在大促销期间降价时，一些人会购买大量商品，例如日常必需品。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份，中国的居民消费价格指数 (CPI) 同比仅上涨 0.2%数据提供商万得资讯在上海进行的一项分析师调查显示，低于 0.3% 的预测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国央行行长易纲在实地考察时告诉企业高管本月早些时候，上海宣布 CPI 将在年底前升至 1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝恩资本上海的另一位合伙人 Derek Deng 表示，中国政府的刺激政策将恢复消费者信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“政府已经实施了刺激消费的刺激政策，预计还会有更多，”他说。 “快速消费品行业继续展现出韧性，消费者、品牌和零售商也在适应不断变化的环境。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong handover anniversary: 1,000 food spots to dish out discounts on July 1, expect up to 20 per cent boost in business]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3224806/hong-kong-handover-anniversary-1000-food-spots-dish-out-discounts-july-1-expect-20-cent-boost?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/6a92e762-8e6a-4d58-b388-ab6e6b92beb2_31583f96.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港约有 1,000 家食品店（从咖啡店到餐厅）同意参加庆祝活动行业负责人透露，通过提供折扣来庆祝 7 月 1 日的交接周年纪念日，并有望在正常的周末或公共假期享受 15% 至 20% 的业务增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Simon Wong Ka-wo，总裁香港餐饮联业联会周二晚告诉邮报，食品和餐饮业希望通过加入该倡议获得一剂强心针。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港提供免费乘车服务和博物馆7 月 1 日回归纪念日的访问&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超周二上午宣布了一系列活动和免费赠品，以纪念 7 月 1 日香港回归中国统治 26 周年，包括 29% 的餐厅折扣，或“支付 71% 的价格”。图为“7/1”，指的是7月1日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很多本地人在过去的几个公共假期都选择出国旅游，所以这往往是一个相当困难的时期为了我们。我们期待这些折扣能给我们带来提振，”Wong 说，他预测业务将增长 15% 到 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 1 日是香港的公众假期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时也是餐厅经理协会发言人的南区区议员 Jonathan Leung Chun 表示，这与其说是数字，不如说是振奋精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是自限制以来的第一个 7 月 1 日他说：“疫情已经缓解，所以我们希望庆祝并尽自己的一份力量。”所有人都可以自由地以他们喜欢的方式展示 29% 的折扣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它可以是一顿饭中的一杯饮料或一道特定的菜，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位与政府关系密切的消息人士表示，庆祝活动可能会促进消费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》已联系行政长官办公室征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着香港人出行和中国大陆游客的到来，餐馆陷入困境待在家里&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中文大学亚太商学院名誉研究员、经济学家李少波表示，他认为餐厅提供的折扣不会产生可观的额外收入。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“在任何一家香港餐厅用餐都不便宜，”他说。 “许多人可能会选择去海外旅行和消费。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出周二发布的年度世界竞争力报告显示，香港在 2023 年的 64 个经济体中排名第七，比一年前下降了两个等级，主要是因为价格上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，这位经济学家表示，这将是几年来第一次没有 Covid-19 大流行阴影的交接庆祝活动，预计会充满欢乐。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;香港最后一个公众假期是 5 月 26 日佛诞。根据入境事务处的数据，5 月 24 日至 26 日期间，有 877,298 名居民离开香港，而包括本地人和游客在内的 835,116 人入境。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Diving robot joins search for Titanic submersible, as only 40 hours of oxygen remain]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224812/diving-robot-joins-search-titanic-submersible-only-40-hours-oxygen-remain?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 06:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/eab3c006-c1d0-4132-a34f-167f3fcd5fe4_8fe6e42c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国正在派遣一艘专业船只协助营救在北方失踪的潜水器大西洋正在潜入泰坦尼克号的残骸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Atalante 研究船有一个潜水机器人，正前往该地区寻找正在前往泰坦尼克号残骸的潜水器，作为救援人员与时间赛跑，因为可呼吸的空气量下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;隶属于海洋研究所 Ifremer 的法国船只已经在执行任务，但定于周三晚上抵达法国政府所在地据广播公司 BFMTV 的报道，海洋部长埃尔韦·贝尔维尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接受过操作潜水机器人培训的专家，该机器人可以下沉到更深的深度，从法国南部的土伦出发，领导对他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与北约协调中心联络的安排仍在继续，我们正在与美国当局保持联系，”伯维尔说。他补充说，机器人的操作员将于周三早上抵达加拿大纽芬兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Victor 6000 机器人通过长达 8 公里的绳索从研究船远程控制，Ifremer 将其描述为“水下作业的旗舰设备”，BFMTV 说。该机器人可以部署在最深 6,000 米（约 20,000 英尺）的深度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;失踪的潜水器上的人员包括法国研究员和前海军军官保罗-亨利·纳吉奥莱特，他因其专业知识而被称为“泰坦尼克号先生”在沉船上。其他人是英国商人 Shahzada Dawood 和他的儿子 Suleman，以及 OceanGate Expeditions 的首席执行官兼创始人 Stockton Rush。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的潜水器在周日被报告失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;谁是在失踪的泰坦尼克号旅游潜水器上？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这艘法国船只将加入不断扩大的国际舰船和飞机舰队，搜索该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国海岸警卫队官员表示，搜索范围达 26,000 平方公里（10,000平方英里），但到目前为止还没有发现被称为泰坦的潜水器的迹象。尽管他们计划继续寻找，但时间已经不多了，因为船上只剩下不到两天的氧气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一次非常复杂的搜索，统一的团队正在夜以继日地工作，”船长波士顿第一海岸警卫区的杰米·弗雷德里克 (Jamie Frederick) 在新闻发布会上说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗雷德里克 (Frederick) 说，截至周二中午，船员的氧气还剩大约 40 小时。他补充说，有人推动将打捞设备运到现场，以防找到潜艇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国军方的三架 C-17 也被用来从美国运送一家商业公司的潜水器和支持设备美国空军机动司令部的一位女发言人说，纽约布法罗到纽芬兰圣约翰斯协助搜索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局报告说，这艘碳纤维船周日晚上逾期未到，于是开始在水域进行搜索在圣约翰以南约 700 公里（435 英里）处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 OceanGate Expeditions 的顾问 David Concannon 说，这艘潜水器在周日早上 6 点左右出海时有 96 小时的氧气供应，该公司负责监督使命。这意味着氧气供应可能会在周四早上耗尽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CBS 新闻记者大卫波格去年乘坐泰坦号前往泰坦尼克号，他说这艘船使用两种通信系统：来回发送短信到水面舰艇，每 15 分钟发出一次安全信号，表明潜艇仍在工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;失踪的泰坦尼克号潜艇的老板曾称他的行业“非常安全”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两者这些系统中的一部分在泰坦淹没后大约 1 小时 45 分钟停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只有两件事可能意味着。要么他们失去了所有动力，要么船体发生了船体破裂并立即内爆。 Pogue 周二告诉 CBC，这两种方法都毫无希望可言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这艘潜水器有七个备用系统可以返回水面，包括沙袋和可掉落的铅管以及一个充气气球。 Pogue 说，即使船上的每个人都失去知觉，一个系统也能正常工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿德莱德大学造船中心主任 Eric Fusil 说，还有其他可能导致通信中断的情况，包括电气火灾这可能会产生有毒烟雾并使船员失去知觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fusil 说，另一种可能性是 Titan 与泰坦尼克号的残骸纠缠在一起并被困在那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我会他说，我喜欢相信……土卫六遭受了电力损失，但他们仍然可以返回水面”并被飞机和水面舰艇发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，救援人员面临着严峻的挑战。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伦敦大学学院海洋工程教授阿利斯泰尔·格雷格 (Alistair Greig) 说，潜水器通常有一个落锤，这是“在紧急情况下它们可以释放的质量，使它们浮出水面” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果出现电源故障和/或通信故障，这可能会发生，然后潜水器会在水面上漂浮，等待被发现，”Greig 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;首次全 3D 扫描捕获沉船时，泰坦尼克号“有故事可讲”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一种情况是耐压船体泄漏，在这种情况下，预后不佳，他说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“如果它已经沉入海底并且不能靠自己的力量爬起来，选择就非常有限，”格雷格说。 “虽然潜水器可能仍然完好无损，但如果它超出了大陆架，那么很少有船只能够到达那么深，当然也没有潜水员。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次探险是 OceanGate 的第三次年度航行编年史泰坦尼克号的恶化，它于 1912 年撞上冰山并沉没，大约 2,200 名乘客和船员中只有大约 700 人遇难。残骸于 1985 年被发现，并一直在慢慢地死于食金属细菌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate 的网站将 2023 年探险的“任务支持费”描述为每人 25 万美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Pogue 回忆起自己在泰坦号上的旅行时说，这艘船掉头寻找泰坦尼克号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“水下没有 GPS，因此水面舰艇应该通过发送短信将潜艇引导到沉船处”，Pogue 在“CBS 周日早上”播出的一个片段中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是在这次潜水中，通讯不知何故中断了。潜艇从未找到沉船。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;dpa 和美联社&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China jobs: record youth unemployment ‘unsolvable for a while’, fifth job crisis since 1978 seen only getting worse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3224762/china-jobs-record-youth-unemployment-unsolvable-while-fifth-job-crisis-1978-seen-only-getting-worse?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/8871e629-e44f-42a5-bf9f-918ebfc4898e_97e5bb7a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的年轻求职者面临着中国几代人以来最困难的就业市场，他们经济学家表示，需要为未来更艰难的时期做好准备，因为短期内困难不会消失，最糟糕的情况尚未到来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自那以来，16-24 岁年龄段的失业率逐渐攀升2020年并创近两个月新高，对北京的疫情后恢复工作构成挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而且从季节性趋势来看，预计7月和8月青年失业率将进一步上升，随着创纪录的 1158 万大学毕业生将离开校园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国正处于自 1978 年‘改革开放’以来青年就业最困难的时期，”北京大学中国研究院院长卢峰说。宏观经济研究中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“问题不会在短期内消失，而是暂时无法解决，”他在上周接受经济观察报采访时补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5 月，16-24 岁年龄组的失业率创下 20.8% 的历史新高，高于 4 月创下的 20.4% 的高点。然而，城镇调查失业率总体上与 4 月持平，为 5.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管这一数字创历史新高，但国家统计局新闻发言人付令辉上周表示，“一些人一直在误解我们人数的总数量”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，在 16-24 岁年龄段的 9600 万人中，目前只有 3300 万人能够找到工作，因为其中许多人是学生。他说，在这 3300 万人中，约有五分之一找不到工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青年失业率自 2020 年以来一直居高不下，自 2021 年 5 月以来一直未低于 14%。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;卢认为，青年失业率至少需要两三年时间才能下降到平衡状态，因为大量的大学毕业生只会增加已经因经济复苏乏力而加剧的就业压力。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;北京大学教授卢说，自已故最高领导人邓小平于 1978 年开始经济改革开放以来，中国此前经历了四次重大的就业危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一次危机发生在1980年初，大约500万以前下放农村的知青回到了家乡。压力导致了一系列改革，特别是北京取消了允许个体经营者开展业务的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着青年失业率创下新高，中国经济数据的 6 个要点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第二个发生了1989-90 年间，中国经济增长放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1998 年北京决定重组低效和亏损的国有企业，导致数百万工人下岗。 40、50 岁的一代主要受第三次危机的影响，但随着 2001 年加入世界贸易组织，中国蓬勃发展的私营部门逐渐吸收了剩余劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1500 万至2008 年全球金融危机期间，由于缺乏工作，2000 万农民工离开了沿海工厂，北京迅速实施了 4 万亿元人民币（5590 亿美元）的刺激计划，以在第四次危机中支持就业市场并提振经济增长。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“今年经济反弹乏力，导致对劳动力需求缺乏信心，尤其是中小企业，企业宁愿增加员工加班时间，也不愿迅速增加新岗位，”卢说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，他补充说，在冠状病毒大流行期间失业或留在过渡性工作岗位的人将重新进入就业市场，进一步加剧竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据媒体报道，刚毕业的求职者失业人数可能超过数百万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢指出，要更加重视适时适度的“逆周期调整”，提高对民营经济的信心，通过解决他们的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雇用了 80% 以上城市劳动力的私营部门上个月经济活动放缓，表明信心疲弱和势头放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何有助于青年就业的措施都是好的。当然，[政府]政策应该尊重年轻人的喜好和诉求，”卢补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府还应该尽量减少政策影响，确保政府监管透明，卢说，并补充说监管打击在私人补习、房地产和互联网行业严重影响了年轻人的就业形势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，国有企业和公共部门也应继续扩大招聘，作为临时解决方案。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Macquarie Group 首席中国经济学家 Larry Hu 上周在一份报告中表示，持续居高不下的青年失业率表明存在自我实现的信心问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“企业不愿招聘，因为消费者需求疲软，而消费者由于劳动力市场疲软而不愿消费，”胡说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，政策是现阶段唯一的游戏规则改变者。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[LME had options to avoid cancelling trades during last year’s nickel crisis, funds say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224793/lme-had-options-avoid-cancelling-trades-during-last-years-nickel-crisis-funds-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/2a7989af-c697-4c9b-9ca7-0cab641c238f_97eb2472.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The London Metal Exchange (LME) made a “wholly unprecedented decision” to cancel nickel trades in March 2022 when it had other less extreme options at hand after a surge in nickel prices forced it to suspend trading last year, according to two funds suing the bourse in London.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among its options, the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX)-owned bourse could have set the margin price at the closing nickel price on March 7, the day before it suspended trading, according to Elliott Associates and Jane Street Global Trading. That would have avoided potentially billions of dollars in margin calls, the funds said in a court filing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is really no exaggeration to say this decision sent shock waves through the commodities markets here and elsewhere,” Elliott&#39;s lawyer Monica Carss-Frisk argued in the first day of a three-day judicial review hearing in London&#39;s High Court on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Elliott and Jane Street are seeking nearly US$472 million in combined damages, arguing the bourse&#39;s actions violated their rights under the European Convention on Human Rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The closely watched trial comes just over 15 months after the nickel market descended into chaos in March of last year as the metal&#39;s price soared more than 270 per cent over a three-day period following Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine, triggering nearly US$16 billion in margin calls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rapid price movement squeezed dozens of short-sellers, including the world&#39;s largest stainless steel producer, Tsingshan Holding Group of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 146-year-old bourse suspended trading and cancelled billions of dollars of transactions in the early-morning hours of March 8, 2022, in a move that has sparked a series of legal actions and an enforcement inquiry by British regulators over the LME&#39;s response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The actions taken by the LME on March 8, 2022 averted significant and systemic damage to the nickel market as well as other metals markets and derivatives markets more widely,” a LME spokesperson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can HKEX-owned LME rebuild its reputation a year after nickel chaos?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“In more than a year since the LME took action, no other viable alternative response has been suggested or identified by the claimants that was not considered and rationally rejected by the LME at the time. In pressing and extraordinary circumstances, the LME at all times acted in accordance with its rules and regulatory obligations and in the interests of the market as a whole.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of her arguments on Tuesday, Carss-Frisk said the price of nickel had already fallen from its highest levels on March 8, 2022, when the bourse ultimately decided to cancel trades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a court filing, the LME&#39;s lawyers argued that Elliott and Jane Street have failed to identify any “sufficient basis” for the court to set aside the bourse&#39;s decision-making and said the case raises “serious questions” about the viability of regulated exchanges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Exchanges are legally required to maintain market order and to have the power to cancel trading activity in response to exceptional market events. It is almost inevitable that any exercise of those powers will be controversial and will have serious financial consequences for those affected,” the bourse&#39;s lawyers said in a court filing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;LME to overhaul margins, introduce new nickel contract in market revamp&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It is also likely that the powers will be exercised (as they were here) in urgent circumstances, in response to unfolding events,” they added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, Elliott and Jane Street argued that the LME unexpectedly suspended its “price bands” for nickel on the morning of March 8, 2022, which allowed the price of nickel to rise quicker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a court filing, the LME said the bands exist as a control mechanism for “fat finger” errors or rogue algorithmic trading, but the rapid price rises on March 8, 2022, made the bands ineffective. They were ultimately suspended after several attempts to adjust them to keep pace with the rapid price increases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bourse also admitted that LME CEO Matthew Chamberlain was unaware the bands had been suspended that morning, but said that was not a relevant factor in his decision-making to suspend trading that day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The market disorder would have occurred, and would have been clearly apparent to Mr. Chamberlain, even had the price bands remained in place,” the LME&#39;s lawyers said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[41 women dead in gang violence at Honduras female prison]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3224811/41-dead-gang-violence-honduras-womens-prison?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 05:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/83c31f91-acf2-480c-96dd-59abfcdef184_ce0886a3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Clashes between rival gangs at a women&#39;s prison in Honduras left at least 41 people dead on Tuesday, according to police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The violence took place at a prison some 25km (about 15 miles) north of the capital Tegucigalpa, according to police spokesman Edgardo Barahona, who put the “preliminary” toll at 41 women, though it was unclear if they were all inmates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Delma Ordonez, who represents family members of the prisoners, members of a gang had entered the cell of a rival group and set it on fire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That part of the prison was “completely destroyed”, she told media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CEFAS correctional facility in Tamara held some 900 inmates, Ordonez said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy security minister Julissa Villanueva on her Twitter account vowed a tough response to the violence and announced a state of emergency as well as “immediate intervention with firefighters, police and military”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Honduras is a country wracked by corruption and gangs that have infiltrated even the top levels of government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Along with neighbours El Salvador and Guatemala, Honduras forms Central America&#39;s so-called “triangle of death” plagued by the murderous gangs called maras that control drug trafficking and organised crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Honduras ex-president extradited to US on drugs, weapons charges&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Drug trafficking groups and gang members are largely responsible for the soaring rate of homicides in Honduras, which at 40 murders per 100,000 inhabitants last year was four times higher than the world average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many young people have given up hope of a better future and think only of migrating to the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Honduras is a major transit country for Colombian cocaine and other narcotics headed mainly to the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former Honduran president Juan Orlando Hernandez was extradited to the United States on drug charges in April 2022 – just over a year after his brother Tony was sentenced in New York to life in prison. US prosecutors say Hernandez turned Honduras into a “narcostate” involving the military, police and civilians in drug trafficking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May last year, former national police chief Juan Carlos Bonilla was also sent to the United States to stand trial for allegedly supervising drug trafficking operations on behalf of his boss, Hernandez.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s new president, leftist Xiomara Castro, has vowed to tackle criminal gangs, last year temporarily lifting certain constitutional guarantees to allow police to make arrests without warrants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One objective of the crackdown, Castro said, was to rein in rampant extortion by gangs, which she described as “one of the main reasons for migration and the shuttering of small and medium enterprises” in Honduras.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In neighbouring El Salvador, President Nayib Bukele has led a “war” on gangs that has rounded up more than 60,000 suspected members so far.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Narendra Modi arrives in US, White House says invitation ‘is not about sending a message to China’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3224810/narendra-modi-arrives-us-white-house-says-invitation-not-about-sending-message-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 05:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/249d4d8a-a9d2-412f-91d3-8e3c57881672_59831111.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A White House official hailed the significance of Washington&#39;s partnership with New Delhi on Tuesday as Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrived in New York for his first state visit to the United States. His trip comes as President Joe Biden&#39;s administration looks to forge closer ties with India to counter China&#39;s rising political and economic clout in Asia and beyond.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calling India a “key and important partner, not just in the Indo-Pacific but globally”, US National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said the US-India relationship was “one of the most defining and important bilateral relationships in the world now”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The remarks came a day after Secretary of State Antony Blinken concluded high-level meetings in Beijing as the US tries to prevent rising tensions with China from spiralling into a wider conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kirby responded with a terse “no” when asked if the invitation to Modi was also a message to Beijing. “This state visit is not about China. And it&#39;s not about sending a message to China,” he said, adding that it was about “sending a message to the Indian people that we put a premium on this relationship”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said that Washington was looking to “deepen”, “broaden” and “improve” defence cooperation with New Delhi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In New York, Modi will meet with Tesla CEO Elon Musk about plans to open a manufacturing base in India as US firms look to shift supply chains away from China. On Thursday in Washington, Modi will hold talks with Biden and address a joint session of Congress. The day will conclude with a state dinner at the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two leaders are expected to announce several defence industrial cooperation agreements, including the joint manufacture of F414 jet engines and India&#39;s acquisition of 31 MQ 9B drones worth US$3 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Such collaboration will also help India bridge the massive gap in military capabilities with China with strong support from the United States,” C Raja Mohan, a non-resident senior fellow at Carnegie India, wrote in a report published by the Asia Society, a New York-based think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can India be &#39;Global South champion&#39; amid US-China rivalry in the Pacific?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said both New Delhi and Washington have a “strong interest in stabilising the Asian balance of power and coping with the geopolitical churn triggered by China&#39;s rise and Beijing&#39;s assertiveness in Asia”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Ashley Tellis of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, a Washington-based think tank, said that New Delhi&#39;s “underlying objective is to secure technological autonomy” and that it had “prioritised Washington&#39;s support for its defence industrial ambitions in tandem with similar partnerships forged with France, Israel, Russia and other friendly states”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Manjari Chatterjee Miller of the Council on Foreign Relations called India&#39;s reliance on Russian oil and weapons one of the major challenges to US-India relations. Washington “worries about India&#39;s commitment to the norms of the current global order and its perceived reluctance to rock the geopolitical boat”, she said in the Asia Society report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kirby would not speak about Washington trying to wean New Delhi off Russian arms, although he said “we certainly hope” that India “will continue to purchase oil inside the cap”. In December, the Group of Seven countries – the US, the UK, France, Germany, Italy, Canada and Japan – along with Australia, imposed a price cap on imports of Russian oil by non-Western countries that they say have been funding Moscow&#39;s war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s narrative of Modi&#39;s state visit has been shadowed by some Democrats&#39; concerns about the Indian leader&#39;s record on human rights and press freedom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s shameful that Modi has been given a platform at our nation&#39;s capital – his long history of human rights abuses, anti-democratic actions, targeting Muslims &amp; religious minorities, and censoring journalists is unacceptable”, Representative Rashida Tlaib, a Democrat from Michigan, said on Twitter. She said she would boycott his address to Congress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representative Pramila Jayapal, a Democrat from Washington state, and Senator Chris Van Hollen, a Democrat from Maryland, sent a letter with more than 70 other lawmakers asking Biden to “discuss the need to protect human rights and democratic values in India” as he meets with Modi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked about the rolling out of the red carpet for Modi – who was once denied a US visa after riots killed 1,000 people, mostly minority Muslims, under his leadership as the chief minister of Gujarat province in 2002 – Kirby said Biden would not hesitate to bring up difficult issues with his guest.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;India gets a &#39;free pass&#39; on rights concerns as US-China rivalry deepens&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“President Biden has never shied away from raising concerns over human rights, and he&#39;s not going to start shying away from it this week,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International on Tuesday screened a BBC documentary on the 2002 violence. The film was banned by the Indian government in June as a “propaganda piece, designed to push a particular discredited narrative”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rights groups have raised concerns about the persecution of minorities in India as well as the treatment of critics and journalists under Modi&#39;s Hindu-nationalist government.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US nears deal to make jet engines in India as allies close ranks against China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A report this year by Freedom House, a US government-funded non-profit organisation, described India as “partly free” for the third year in a row, adding that “democratic rights in India remain under pressure, particularly for marginalised groups”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When asked if Biden would host a joint news conference with Modi, who has not held a single press conference since taking office in 2014, Kirby was non-committal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can tell you that we&#39;re still working our way through some of the aspects of the agenda, and that&#39;s one of them,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blood-red Mormon crickets invade US town, as residents fight back]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224809/blood-red-mormon-crickets-invade-us-town-residents-fight-back?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 03:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/73dc682e-762d-44e0-a39c-71138b26f9e3_41e50128.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;达娜·多兰 (Dana Dolan) 以为自己遇到了一个血腥的崩溃。 Elko 所在的 80 号州际公路周围的地面看起来像是被鲜血覆盖了。随着红色的变化和移动，她意识到这是一种蟋蟀的渗入，有些比她的拇指还大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这几乎就像圣经中的瘟疫，”Dolan 笑着说，并嘲笑了这种情况的荒谬她已经在埃尔科生活了六年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数以万计埋在土壤中约一英寸深的摩门教蟋蟀卵在 5 月底和 6 月初开始孵化。长期担任该州昆虫学家的杰夫奈特说，几周来，红色小动物一直在入侵内华达州北部的大片地区并造成混乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;食人蟋蟀的入侵在小镇埃尔科造成的打击尤其严重爱达荷州和犹他州附近约有 20,000 人，以金矿开采而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;红色的大虫子留下一种非常可怕的恶臭，类似于燃烧的肉体，迫使居民在开车时堵住鼻子。这些小动物粘在轮胎和鞋底上，它们的尸体无处不在，甚至在体育馆里也是如此。多兰说，当它们移动时，听起来像是在下雨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居民和工作人员曾尝试使用扫帚、吹叶机、高压清洗机和扫雪机来消灭蟋蟀，结果它们又回来了。州政府官员在整个埃尔科县竖起了标志，警告司机注意光滑的高速公路，这是昆虫的热门聚集地，它们不会三思而后行地吃掉它们死去的朋友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;红色的生物覆盖着高速公路，并在障碍物上穿梭，寻找食物。 Spring Creek 的耶利米·摩尔 (Jeremiah Moore) 说，它们在卡车的车轮下发出噼啪声和爆裂声，形成类似浮油的东西，他的车辆在高速公路上遇到摩门教蟋蟀后滑出公路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我……回家时，当我转过拐角时，我来得太快了，差点掉进满是水的沟里，”摩尔说。 “这非常激烈。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么蝗虫会蜂拥而至：科学家发现可以用作武器的气味&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一家医院甚至雇用了四名临时兼职员工，他们的主要职责是清除校园里的蟋蟀足够长的时间让病人进入大楼。该组织自称为板球巡逻队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们只是想让他们继续前进，”东北内华达地区医院的发言人史蒂夫·伯罗斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当Burrows 说，Cricket Patrol 没有值班，其他医院员工介入了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;心脏病科的医务人员仍然穿着黑色手术服，在看病人的间隙走出医院的救护车区Burrows 说，用扫帚把蟋蟀赶走。以及帮助清理工作的 IT 专家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从内华达州、蒙大拿州到爱达荷州，整个西部的历史上都记录了原产于大盆地和西部山间地带的摩门蟋蟀的爆发、犹他州和俄勒冈州。根据昆虫学家 Knight 的说法，有可追溯到 1930 年代的虫害记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传说当这些昆虫开始破坏搬到犹他州盐湖谷的摩门教定居者种植的农作物时，它们就得名了，奈特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“定居者祈求救济，”奈特说。 “那是以海鸥的形式出现的。海鸥吃蟋蟀……这也是它们成为犹他州州鸟的原因。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在俄勒冈州，州立法者近年来拨款数百万美元来评估这个问题，并建立了一个摩门教蟋蟀和蚱蜢“抑制”计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;咸蟋蟀、巧克力甲虫：昆虫零食机在日本大受欢迎&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;摩门蟋蟀不是真正的蟋蟀，而是盾背螽斯。奈特说，它们不会飞，但会成群结队地一起旅行，面积从 5 英亩（2 公顷）到数百英亩不等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，今年对埃尔科的入侵并非史无前例&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于内华达州北部特别潮湿的春季和白雪皑皑的冬季，蟋蟀的孵化时间远远晚于它们通常的春季出生时间，Knight 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每只春天——在这种情况下是夏天——当年出生的蟋蟀将交配并在土壤中产下新一代的卵。奈特说，这些卵本应在次年春天孵化，但有些卵会在土壤中休眠长达 11 年。鸡蛋可以在泥土中积聚多年，直到干旱来临时，引发昏昏欲睡的鸡蛋立即孵化。然后循环重复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奈特在内华达州农业部工作了近 40 年（其中 32 年担任州昆虫学家），他说他可以回忆起四次入侵。他说，2000 年代初期的虫害“在我看来印象最深，从整体范围来看”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奈特记得有一次在 80 号州际公路上从里诺开车到犹他州，被一群蜂拥而至几乎整个车道都是红色的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然后我们可以走了将近 10、15 年，几乎看不到任何东西，”奈特谈到蟋蟀时说。 “大约从 2008 年开始，我们几乎没有蟋蟀，直到大约 2019 年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Elko 的新红居民至少要到 8 月中旬才会搬走，这让每个人都感到非常失望。但是蟋蟀离开后去了哪里？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它们死了，Knight 说。交配后的雄性蟋蟀。产卵后的雌蟋蟀。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>