<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Grow old in Hong Kong’: global movie icon Chow Yun-fat tells of love for home city and its ‘charming and arrogant’ Cantonese dialect, thrills fans]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3226645/grow-old-hong-kong-global-movie-icon-chow-yun-fat-tells-love-home-city-and-its-charming-and-arrogant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/7aef98f8-540a-4cae-9217-2521ffa259d6_c1bcb45a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国际知名香港巨星周润发表达了对他的深情厚意&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据媒体 HK01 报道，这位电影传奇人物在 YouTube 节目《叔叔的爱》的新一集中发表了上述言论。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周星驰的标志性地位和辉煌的职业生涯远远超出了香港，他在李安的《卧虎藏龙》中的出色表演在国际上引起了共鸣。这部电影于 2001 年创造了历史，成为第一部获得奥斯卡奖的华语电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他与约翰尼·德普合作的《加勒比海盗：世界的尽头》在全球收获了超过 9.63 亿美元的票房收入，成为全球票房最高的影片。 2007 年票房冠军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周星驰在银幕之外也因其慈善事业和平易近人的举止而受到钦佩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2018 年接受香港电影网站 JayneStars 采访时，周星驰分享道他计划将自己的全部财富——惊人的 56 亿港元（7.16 亿美元）——捐给慈善机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他也被称为“自拍之王”，因为他愿意接受粉丝的自拍要求”，他在 YouTube 节目中将其描述为个人的“社会责任”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港人认为，既然周润发喜欢与人自拍，看到他时不与他自拍似乎会显得很尴尬。就很丢面子了。这在某种程度上已经成为我的社会责任。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;YouTube 采访还涵盖了最近香港居民移居其他地方的趋势，周先生重申了他对这座城市及其独特语言的深厚感情.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很多人都忘记了香港美丽的风景。我在南丫岛长大，对当地文化有很深的感情。我不认为有必要住在其他地方。在香港长大真是太好了，”周说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“粤语有一种亲切感。现在很多孩子从幼儿园开始学英语，却不会说广东话，我觉得有点可怜。粤语有韵律魅力，狡猾又傲慢。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次采访让周星驰在全球的众多粉丝感到高兴，不少人在社交媒体上附和他的观点。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;不少人留下“香港风景独特美丽”、“粤语真好听”等评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这并不是周星驰第一次表达对香港的喜爱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;2021年，他回顾了自己数十年的职业生涯，并将自己的成就归功于这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周在香港浸会大学接受荣誉人文博士学位时说：“每个电影角色都具有挑战性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了谋生，我被迫学习和努力。所以我感谢香港人的鼓励、包容和爱。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“感谢香港给了我这么多的知识、耐心和爱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A ‘happy’ Hong Kong campaign is not enough to tackle increasing rates of depression among residents, experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226976/happy-hong-kong-campaign-not-enough-tackle-increasing-rates-depression-among-residents-experts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/f961e611-4b1a-4b11-a62f-cdcc0f639265_73240b27.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港需要的不仅仅是一场“快乐”运动来应对日益上升的抑郁症发病率专家表示，官方数据显示，在过去五年里，公立医院患有这种疾病的患者增加了 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;流行病的死亡凸显了这种疾病的风险。明星李玟周日自杀未遂，周三。她的家人证实她几年前被诊断出患有抑郁症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李去世的同一天，一名 42 岁的妇女在法庭认定她杀死了自己 16 天大的婴儿后被判处缓刑。受产后抑郁症影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港天后李玟去世；姐妹们说：“她的光芒永远长存”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“政府如何让香港的整体气氛变得更好？”香港大学自杀研究及预防中心主任叶兆辉教授周五问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[快乐香港运动]当然比没有好……但这些都是一切都是暂时的……从长远来看，政府应该关注如何让香港成为一个幸福的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府于四月发起这项运动，旨在提升三年后居民的精神。 Covid-19 大流行对日常生活造成的干扰。但叶表示，该活动的福利和活动并不能解决问题的根源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，首席执行官李家超表示，他的大部分关键绩效指标都取得了进展。上任第一年制定的政策，很多都是为了改善居民的生活，但叶质疑这些政策是否已经解决了基本需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果完成10项任务后仍然存在这么多问题，这意味着这些策略并没有解决公众的担忧。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月份公布的官方数据显示，被诊断患有抑郁症并在医院管理局辖下的设施接受治疗的患者人数增加了19人。心理健康促进会会长、精神科医师陈松茂医生表示，2019年的社会动荡，加上Covid-19 导致居民的心理健康状况恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有情绪问题都与压力有关，”Chan 说，“当你的压力较大且持续时间较长时，你患抑郁症的机会就会增加。”香港精神健康协会创始人兼会长林美玲博士表示，她亲眼目睹患有抑郁症或焦虑症的人数增加了约 20%。与大流行之前相比，过去两三年她的诊所出现了焦虑感。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;李玟的悲剧是对抗最残酷疾病的呼声&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港的情况与世界卫生组织的全球预测一致，即到 2030 年，抑郁症将成为高收入国家的主要疾病负担。全球范围内，估计有 5% 的成年人患有抑郁症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每个人都有感受快乐、不快乐或焦虑，”林说。 “但如果症状变得严重并持续影响我们，则可能是临床抑郁症。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多种症状都可能是抑郁症的征兆，包括心烦意乱、不断哭泣、睡眠困难和娱乐困难她说，有自杀念头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林补充说，有这些症状的人可以首先尝试联系朋友和家人，或者通过确保充足的睡眠、均衡的饮食和锻炼来采取更健康的生活方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“如果[症状和体征]持续超过两周，您应该考虑寻求专业帮助——与辅导员、社会工作者、心理学家或精神科医生交谈——以便您得到全面的评估和适当的干预“”有助于预防抑郁症，例如每周至少锻炼三次，保持社交活动，避免吸烟、饮酒、吸毒和垃圾食品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;获得足够的阳光也很重要，因为它可以促进内啡肽的产生他说，这是一种与幸福相关的激素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您有自杀念头，或者您认识的人有自杀念头，可以寻求帮助。对于香港，请拨打 +852 2896 0000 联系撒玛利亚人，或拨打 +852 2382 0000 联系预防自杀服务。在美国，请拨打 988 自杀和危机生命热线 988 或 +1 800 273 8255。有关其他国家/地区的帮助热线列表，请参阅此。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Huawei taps into computing power shortage in China, touts self-developed AI tech amid ChatGPT craze]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226981/huawei-taps-computing-power-shortage-china-touts-self-developed-ai-tech-amid-chatgpt-craze?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/f7d643d7-2134-41b7-8da5-0902b29a6f33_2f0ecccf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国科技巨头华为技术有限公司推出了新版本的人工智能 (AI)该模型由内部处理器提供支持，希望能为一个努力获得先进的美国人工智能芯片的国家提供急需的计算能力，以满足其对 ChatGPT 式服务的渴望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其云端周五在中国南部东莞市举行的开发者大会上，华为推出了盘古人工智能模型 3.0 版本，重点关注煤矿、金融和政府等各个行业的工业用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于深圳的华为该公司表示，希望通过自主研发的Ascend人工智能处理器和支持盘古的底层技术MindSpore人工智能框架，帮助客户构建和训练自己的人工智能模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的计算能力很难跟上随着需求的激增，许多公司正在支付高价购买 Nvidia 图形处理器，而且交货时间很长。”华为云首席执行官张平安在发布会后的媒体吹风会上表示。 “我们希望在人工智能计算能力方面提供另一种选择。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿去年八月实施了新的出口限制，阻止中国公司从美国半导体供应商超微和英伟达购买最先进的人工智能芯片。后者几乎垄断了用于训练人工智能系统的 GPU。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着美国政府考虑限制中国公司使用美国云计算服务，中国的人工智能野心正面临新的打击，这将阻碍中国大陆的发展据《华尔街日报》本周早些时候报道，客户不得使用亚马逊网络服务和微软等公司提供的先进人工智能芯片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为本身目前已被列入美国贸易黑名单，该名单禁止该公司不得在未经政府批准的情况下从美国企业购买技术。张说，华为必须依靠自主研发的技术生存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然其他人可以使用业界最成熟的 GPU 和软件，但华为需要依靠我们自己的人工智能基础技术，”他&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为表示，其Ascend AI集群可实现比业界主流GPU高1.1倍的训练效率。它没有详细说明用于将其技术与竞争对手进行比较的基准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为盘古模型的最新版本将加剧中国大型科技公司之间的人工智能竞赛，这些公司已推出约 80 种模型到目前为止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国互联网搜索巨头百度于 3 月份成为第一家推出 ChatGPT 挑战者 Ernie Bot 的中国大型科技公司，并计划将其人工智能模型集成到云和其他企业服务中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团首席执行官张勇表示，《南华早报》的所有者阿里巴巴集团于四月份推出了“统一钱文”聊天机器人，旨在将其与公司的所有产品融合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;与其他中国科技巨头相比，华为淡化了盘古和ChatGPT之间的比较，强调其只针对企业客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的盘古AI模型不会写诗；不会写诗；不会写诗。”我们只做生意。我们将扎根行业，为行业带来价值。”华为云首席执行官张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国贸易制裁使其一度利润丰厚的智能手机陷入困境后，华为一直在加倍加大企业业务力度，寻求新的收入来源。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为于2021年推出了盘古的第一版，并已将其应用于各个行业，例如帮助检测地下矿井的异常情况以及识别铁路和货车的故障。华为云表示，其AI技术已在不同行业的1000多个项目中实施，其中包括8个煤矿。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK to sign Pacific trade deal in Auckland next week, shifting focus to China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3227002/uk-sign-pacific-trade-deal-auckland-next-week-shifting-focus-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 08:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/3df805f7-20c9-4395-9fec-0714ac503391_7f03cbe2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国将于下周末在奥克兰签署太平洋贸易协议，正式成为这是该框架生效以来的第一个新成员，并将注意力转向以中国为首的其他申请国名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;签署将在全面与进步协定成员国部长级会议上进行。根据新西兰外交和贸易部的新闻稿，由新西兰主办的跨太平洋伙伴关系协定。该活动预计将于 7 月 15 日至 16 日举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“英国加入 CPTPP 与我们的双边自由贸易协定相结合，确保新西兰出口商能够前所未有地进入世界第六大经济体”，新西兰贸易和出口增长部长达米安·奥康纳 (Damien O&#39;Connor) 在周六的一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰支持与中国进行“艰难对话​​”，以管理“复杂”关系&lt;/h3>;&lt; CPTPP一度被视为平衡中国在亚太地区日益增长的影响力的一种方式。美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普于 2017 年让美国退出该协议，缩小了美国规模，让日本成为该协议的主导经济体。东京不断敦促美国回归。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是下一个申请加入该组织的国家，在 2021 年英国提交申请仅几个月后，其次是台湾、厄瓜多尔、哥斯达黎加、乌拉圭和乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现有成员有：澳大利亚、文莱、加拿大、智利、日本、马来西亚、墨西哥、新西兰、秘鲁、新加坡和越南。根据国际货币基金组织的数据，一旦英国加入，这个拥有 5 亿人口的欧元区的 GDP 将占全球 GDP 的 15%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Hong Kong’s population ages, attention to oral health will go a long way]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226801/hong-kongs-population-ages-attention-oral-health-will-go-long-way?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/af8d4119-b14c-4fe7-bb43-6cfb2f30a200_4fceb450.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港的预期寿命全球最长，但老年人不一定生活得更健康。目前，该市约有五分之一的人口年龄在 65 岁或以上，预计未来三十年这一比例将增加至三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府的初级医疗保健蓝图指出，到 2039 年，预计香港将有300万人患有慢性病。 2017 年心理健康审查引用的研究显示，香港患有痴呆症的人数为 10 万人，预计到 2039 年这一数字将增加两倍，达到 30 万人以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人口老龄化带来的医疗负担增加仍然是一个问题城市面临的最大挑战，影响个人生活质量并导致生产力和财务成本的大幅损失。为此，政府在去年发布的《基层医疗卫生蓝图》中强调了疾病预防的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在老年医学方面，糖尿病、高血压等非传染性疾病备受关注。近年来，口腔健康仍然被忽视。尽管口腔通常被视为身体的一个孤立区域，但口腔问题既会影响整体健康，也会受到整体健康的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际研究的系统回顾表明，牙齿脱落与认知障碍和痴呆症独立相关，并且认知能力下降的风险随着牙齿脱落的增加而增加。这令人担忧，因为痴呆症是香港第七大常见死因，会导致严重的残疾，给患者、护理人员和社会带来压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于牙齿缺失如何影响大脑，有三个关键解释。牙齿较少会使进食变得更加困难，尤其是咀嚼较硬的食物，这可能会导致营养缺乏和认知受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次，牙齿由机械感受器固定在牙槽中，机械感受器在工作时向大脑发送信号。动物研究发现，当牙齿脱落时，大脑的感觉反馈会减少，这可能会加速认知能力的下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，牙齿脱落的最常见原因是严重的牙周炎，这是一种牙龈炎症性疾病。牙周炎可以通过与其相关的牙龈卟啉单胞菌直接影响大脑，也可以通过使身体遭受慢性、低度炎症来间接影响大脑。众所周知，较高水平的炎症会影响多个器官系统，包括中枢神经系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，香港首次调查了牙齿缺失的心理社会后果与认知障碍之间的联系香港大学牙医学院的老年人口研究。拥有天然牙齿的参与者的认知功能明显高于那些根本没有牙齿的参与者，这证实了国际研究结果。有趣的是，在这项试点研究中，发现牙齿脱落会显着影响老年人的亲密关系和性满意度，而这与他们的认知功能相关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牙齿脱落是城市的一个常见问题。最新的 2011 年口腔健康调查发现，65 至 74 岁的非收容人口中，40% 的剩余牙齿少于 20 颗，这被认为是功能性牙列的最低数量。鉴于社会联系对于良好健康的重要性，牙齿脱落不仅可能影响老年人的认知功能，而且会导致该人群中心理健康问题的普遍发生，令人震惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牙齿问题，例如牙龈疾病和蛀牙在很大程度上是可以预防的。然而口腔健康调查发现，三分之一的香港老年人没有每天刷牙两次，超过四分之三的人没有按照牙科专业人士的建议清洁牙缝。超过 75% 的人没有定期去看牙医。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于健康的口腔在日常功能中的重要性，世界卫生组织的健康不仅仅是没有疾病的原则也非常适用于口腔健康，例如由于改善口腔健康的机会存在于整个生命周期，因此必须将近期预防的重点扩展到口腔。一种开始方法是接受口腔是整体健康不可或缺的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;护理人员应接受教育，了解如何帮助家属进行口腔护理，以及口腔卫生和定期牙科检查的重要性-应该强调ups。不应将牙齿脱落视为衰老的必然结果，而应鼓励老年人保持牙列，并解决弱势群体口腔保健的障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;照顾牙齿可以帮助您保护牙齿大脑，无论是生理上还是情感上，因为没有口腔健康就没有健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US has fully destroyed its stockpile of chemical weapons, Joe Biden says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227001/us-has-fully-destroyed-its-stockpile-chemical-weapons-joe-biden-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 07:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/b8cc0e4a-59cf-42e9-b6b6-5a01ecac1981_3f54a4ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登周五宣布，美国已经彻底摧毁了几十年来——化学武器旧库存，履行了在已有三十年历史的《化学武器公约》下的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天，我自豪地宣布，美国已安全销毁了该库存中的最后一批弹药 -拜登说：“我们离建立一个没有化学武器恐怖的世界又近了一步。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国是《化学武器公约》签署国中最后一个完成销毁其“申报”库存任务的国家，尽管其中一些被认为保留了化学武器的秘密储备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这标志着国际机构首次核实已宣布的一整类大规模杀伤性武器已被销毁，”拜登在一份声明中表示。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;不要。不。不要做的事：拜登警告普京不要使用核武器&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这一消息是在肯塔基州的美国陆军设施蓝草军械库最近完成了为期四年的消除约 500 吨致命武器的工作之后发布的。化学制剂，美国军方持有的最后一批化学制剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几十年来，美国一直储存含有芥子气、VX 和沙林神经毒剂以及起泡毒剂的炮弹和火箭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此类武器在第一次世界大战战场上使用并造成可怕后果后受到广泛谴责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但许多国家在随后的几年中保留并进一步发展了它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 1993 年达成并于 1997 年生效的《化学武器公约》规定美国在今年 9 月 30 日之前销毁其所有化学制剂和弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公约的其他签署国已经销毁了其持有的化学武器”，禁止化学武器组织 (OPCW) 负责人费尔南多·阿里亚斯 5 月份表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，现在只剩下美国来完成这项任务了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“世界上超过 70,000 吨最危险的毒物已在禁化武组织的监督下销毁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美国军备控制协会的数据，1990 年美国持有近 28,600 吨毒物。化学武器，是仅次于俄罗斯的世界第二大储存库。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着冷战的结束，超级大国和其他国家联合起来谈判《化学武器公约》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登大力支持瑞典北约在峰会临近之际提出消除库存的计划，这是一个双重危险的过程，因为这意味着不仅要中和化学制剂，还要中和它们所包含的弹药，这是一个缓慢的过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯2017 年完成销毁自己申报的库存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到 2022 年 4 月，美国还有不到 600 吨剩余化学武器需要销毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登敦促继续保持警惕，确保世界各地的所有化学武器并表示，少数尚未加入该公约的国家应该加入该公约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“俄罗斯和叙利亚应该重新遵守《化学武器公约》，并承认其未申报的计划，这些计划已被用来实施明目张胆的暴行和袭击，”拜登说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Honduras seeking Chinese investors for US$20 billion transoceanic rail line]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227000/honduras-seeking-chinese-investors-us20-billion-transoceanic-rail-line?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 06:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/30840de2-b6e5-477f-8cc3-a0950882e168_113fa32a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;洪都拉斯政府周五告诉中国官员，它正在寻求投资者帮助资助建设拟议耗资 200 亿美元的铁路线连接该国大西洋和太平洋海岸，这是两国贸易和投资推动的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪都拉斯经济发展部长弗雷迪斯·塞拉托 (Fredis Cerrato) 表示，洪都拉斯还讨论了与水坝和能源发电相关的基础设施项目&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们向（中国官员）介绍了洪都拉斯有兴趣获得融资的项目，这些项目对我们国家的发展至关重要，”塞拉托说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们塞拉托说：“我们谈论的是修建水坝、修建跨洋列车，这也与我们的发电系统有关。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平誓言支持洪都拉斯经济，强调“一个中国原则” ”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他补充说，世界第二大经济体中国的官员对使用公共和私人资金开发的项目表现出了兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部长补充说，拟议的铁路线可能会大约 15 年内准备就绪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪都拉斯与中国于 3 月建立外交关系，此前这个中美洲国家放弃了与台湾的长期关系，转而支持中国大陆及其经济影响力。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesian Gibran Huzaifah who grew up in poverty builds US$1.4 billion fish start-up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3226956/indonesian-gibran-huzaifah-who-grew-poverty-builds-us14-billion-fish-start?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/e1213df7-30b3-4138-ba3d-7245745d20bd_4f998364.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一家农业科技初创企业，由雅加达一名贫困居民的前居民共同创立在筹集了 2 亿美元新资金后，EFishery 成为罕见的印度尼西亚独角兽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在阿布扎比 42XFund 领投的一轮融资后，EFishery 的估值达到 14 亿美元，是其之前 4.1 亿美元估值的三倍多。首席执行官 Gibran Huzaifah 表示，到 2022 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司为印度尼西亚 70,000 名鱼虾养殖户提供服务，在裁员、首席执行官辞职和估值暴跌的情况下，该公司在一年内突破了 10 亿美元大关。科技行业占据了头条新闻。经济放缓、利率上升和通胀水平上升促使全球风险投资者撤资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EFishery 在其网站上表示“未来是水产养殖”，计划利用这笔资金扩大在这位首席执行官表示，我们将在两年内在美国或印度尼西亚进行首次公开​​募股，然后再在印度尼西亚和印度进行首次公开​​募股。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望在未来五年内成为全球领导者，并在某个国家进行首次公开​​募股。”点”，他说。 “最早是在 2025 年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;水产养殖是一个快速增长的商业部门，也是动物蛋白的提供者，具有最有效的饲料转化（而不是过度喂养或喂养不足），可以为粮食安全做出重大贡献。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;33 岁的胡扎法 (Huzaifah) 在雅加达东部的贫民窟附近长大，父亲是建筑工地工头，父亲是家庭主妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的母亲从未完成高中学业，鼓励他学习。他在学业上表现出色，最终考入万隆理工学院，这是一所当地以培养工程师而闻名的精英大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当他进入大学后，他的父亲失去了父亲，他的家庭经济状况开始恶化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有家里的钱，也没有在新城市的熟人，他每天晚上都得找个地方睡觉。他说，有时是校园，有时是清真寺。有一次，他三天没吃东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来一次偶然的机会，生物专业的胡扎法参加了水产养殖课程。他对教授关于鲶鱼养殖的讲座着迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;确信水产养殖是食物的未来，也是他摆脱贫困的道路，他立即租了一个池塘来养殖鲶鱼。三年后的2012年，他经营着76个池塘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那段时间，他亲身经历了行业的挑战，例如高昂的饲养成本导致利润微薄，中间商要求的鱼价低廉。购买他的捕获物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一位有技术背景的朋友的帮助下，他利用物联网技术构建了一个原型自动喂食器，以消除鱼喂食过多或不足的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;然后在2013年，他推出了eFishery。他的方法是双管齐下的：做你理解的事情，不要随波逐流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司的业务从此发展到包括为鱼虾养殖户和买家提供市场。它还与金融机构合作，为农民提供融资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最新一轮融资之后（国家养老基金 Kumpulan Wang Persaraan、ResponsAbility Investments AG 和 500 Global 以及现有支持者）加入了 Huzaifah 及其公司- 创始人持有的股份每份价值超过 1 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huzaifah 表示，他的生活并没有太大改变。不过，他说，“这感觉很好，因为我不需要担心成长过程中的经济问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US targets Asean partnership to ‘push back’ on China actions in South China Sea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226998/us-targets-asean-partnership-push-back-china-actions-south-china-sea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 06:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/aa85fdf3-3f53-4101-9551-09f7bc8cb2dc_430a59d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;华盛顿希望与东南亚国家密切合作，“反击”“美国国务院一名高级官员周五表示，当其最高外交官下周参加一系列地区活动时，北京在南海的“无益、胁迫和不负责任”行动将呈上升趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯将前往印度尼西亚雅加达出席一系列会议，包括年度美国-东盟外长会议。这些会议预计将于 7 月 13 日至 15 日举行，并将在布林肯与美国总统乔·拜登前往英国和立陶宛参加北约峰会之后举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不是让各国加入美国的问题美国负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔·克里滕布林克(Daniel Kritenbrink)在谈到布林肯在雅加达的目标时说道。 “这是与我们的东盟伙伴合作，推进我们对该地区的共同观点和愿景的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这需要伙伴关系“抵制违背这一愿景和原则的行为，他补充说，包括我们在过去几年和过去几周看到中国所采取的许多不负责任的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度尼西亚举行的会议将重点讨论建立美国伙伴关系和“加强与美国的合作”。我们的关系”，克里滕布林克说。华盛顿并不是要求各国做出选择，而是“只是确保各国有选择并有能力在不受胁迫的情况下做出自己的主权决定”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我们都认为各国应该将其海上基地作为基础claims in international law, that maritime disputes should be resolved peacefully, that all countries should enjoy freedom of navigation and freedom of overflight and unimpeded commerce,” the senior envoy added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Founded in 1967, Asean comprises Brunei, Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam. The intergovernmental organisation collectively represents 650 million people, who together rank as the world&#39;s fifth-largest economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite successfully promoting economic integration among members, Asean has struggled to coordinate a response to China&#39;s territorial claims in the South China Sea, which oppose those of Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines and Vietnam.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, Vietnam reaffirm pledge on South China Sea &#39;code of conduct&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last month, Philippine Foreign Affairs Secretary Enrique Manalo during his visit to New Delhi said negotiations among the claimants to establish a code of conduct for the South China Sea had been under way over the past four to five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We may not be seeing light at the end of the tunnel, but we see the tunnel and that&#39;s where we are,” he said of the effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, the Philippine military&#39;s western command said 48 Chinese fishing vessels were seen “swarming” a reef south of Recto Bank in the South China Sea during an air patrol at the end of June. Two Chinese naval vessels and three Chinese coastguard ships “are regularly loitering” a nearby shoal, the military added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recto Bank holds “immense potential for the country&#39;s energy security and economic growth” and has been a focal point in “rising concern over China&#39;s recent behaviour”, the Philippine military&#39;s western command said on its Facebook page.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The South China Sea contains about 11 billion barrels of untapped oil and 190 trillion cubic feet of natural gas reserves, according to an estimate by the US Energy Information Administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin in a readout released on Thursday after a call with his Philippine counterpart, Gilberto Teodoro, called Beijing&#39;s conduct in the sea “coercive and risky”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this week, the Philippine coastguard said its vessels were “constantly followed, harassed and obstructed” late last month by bigger Chinese ships in the South China Sea. China&#39;s foreign ministry responded by saying its ships&#39; manoeuvres were “professional and restrained”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese and Philippine ships nearly collided in the disputed waters in April, with each side accusing the other of intrusion and provocation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Washington, a mutual defence treaty ally of Manila, does not have any territorial claims in the region, it asserts the right to innocent passage under the freedom of navigation. Beijing says US actions violate international law due to the use of military ships and aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Blinken says he told Beijing officials US does not seek to &#39;contain&#39; China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lately the region has become a geopolitical battleground for the US and China. Since becoming president, Biden has made significant efforts to deepen ties with Asean countries to counter China&#39;s widening influence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May last year, the American president hosted a first-ever US-Asean special summit at his official residence in Washington. But he failed to reach consensus with Asean leaders on countering what his administration has called China&#39;s growing assertiveness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, seven Asean countries – Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam – decided to participate in the Washington-led, 14- member Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, an initiative aimed at reducing dependency on China for strategic supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, the group announced its first-ever deal to build sustainable and resilient supply chains focused on strategic items including critical minerals and semiconductors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deal does not cover expanding market access or free-trade agreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indonesia hosts great-power rivals China, US in rare joint naval exercises&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China has been Asean&#39;s largest trading partner since 2009, while the group became Beijing&#39;s largest trading partner for the first time in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, China is a member of the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership, a free-trade agreement involving the 10 Asean member states along with Japan, South Korea, Australia, and New Zealand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Jakarta, Blinken will emphasise Washington&#39;s commitment to Asean “centrality and support” for its partnership with the US, according to a State Department statement on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken will also take part in the second US-Indonesia strategic dialogue alongside his Indonesian counterpart, Retno Marsudi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia, which is Asean&#39;s current president in the group&#39;s rotating leadership, is home to the world&#39;s largest reserves of nickel, a key raw material used in making batteries for electric vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, Indonesia&#39;s minister for maritime affairs and investment, Luhut Pandjaitan, said Jakarta would propose a “limited” free-trade agreement for some minerals shipped to the US. However, many Chinese companies have invested in refining facilities since 2020, when Indonesia banned exports of nickel ore.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 06:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Dutch prime minister resigns after ruling coalition fails to agree on migration policy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226997/dutch-prime-minister-resigns-after-ruling-coalition-fails-agree-migration-policy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 05:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/08/811f7b64-1832-4d92-8a81-29e8077b5dc3_04dc7811.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Dutch government collapsed on Friday as Prime Minister Mark Rutte resigned because of irreconcilable differences within the four-party coalition about how to rein in migration, a divisive issue that has split nations across Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The resignation of Rutte, the longest-serving premier of the nation, means the country will face a general election later this year. Rutte and his government will remain in office in a caretaker capacity until a new ruling coalition is chosen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is no secret that the coalition partners have very different views on migration policy,” Rutte told reporters in The Hague. “And today, unfortunately, we have to draw the conclusion that those differences are irreconcilable. That is why I will immediately … offer the resignation of the entire cabinet to the king in writing”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opposition politicians wasted no time in calling for fresh elections even before Rutte formally confirmed his resignation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Geert Wilders, leader of the anti-immigration Party for Freedom, tweeted, “Quick elections now.” Across the political spectrum, Green Left leader Jesse Klaver also called for elections and told Dutch broadcaster NOS: “This country needs a change of direction.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rutte had presided over late-night meetings on Wednesday and Thursday that failed to result in a deal on migration policy. At one final round of talks on Friday evening, the parties decided unanimously that they could not agree and, as a result, could not remain together in the coalition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision underscored ideological divisions that existed from the day the coalition was sworn in just over 18 months ago between parties that do not support a strict crackdown on migration – D66 and fellow centrist party ChristenUnie, or Christian Union – and the two that favour tougher measures – Rutte&#39;s conservative People&#39;s Party for Freedom and Democracy and the Christian Democrats.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US and Netherlands set to hit China&#39;s chip makers with one-two punch&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Similar discussions are going on across political divides elsewhere in Europe as migrants fleeing conflict or seeking a better life make perilous sea crossings from northern Africa to reach the continent. Hundreds of thousands of people also have fled the grinding war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Migration is set to be an essential theme of European Union parliamentary elections next year, but the issue hit early in the Netherlands, a nation that has long been torn between a welcoming international outreach and increasing resistance to foreign influences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rutte&#39;s coalition tried for months to hash out a deal to reduce the flow of new migrants arriving in the country of nearly 18 million people. Proposals reportedly included creating two classes of asylum – a temporary one for people fleeing conflicts and a permanent one for people trying to escape persecution – and reducing the number of family members who are allowed to join asylum seekers in the Netherlands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, hundreds of asylum seekers were forced to sleep outdoors in squalid conditions near an overcrowded reception centre as the number of people arriving in the Netherlands outstripped the available beds. Dutch aid agencies provided help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just over 21,500 people from outside Europe sought asylum in the Netherlands in 2022, according to the country&#39;s statistics office. Tens of thousands more moved to the Netherlands to work and study.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The numbers have put a strain on housing that already was in short supply in the densely populated country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rutte&#39;s government worked for a law that could compel municipalities to provide accommodation for newly arrived asylum seekers, but the legislation has yet to pass through both houses of parliament.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4,000-year-old &#39;Dutch Stonehenge&#39; site unveiled in the Netherlands&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The prime minister also promoted European Union efforts to slow migration to the 27-nation bloc. Rutte visited Tunisia last month with his Italian counterpart and the president of the EU&#39;s executive commission to offer more than €1 billion in financial aid to rescue the North African nation&#39;s teetering economy and to stem migration from its shores to Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rutte&#39;s coalition government, the fourth he has led, took office in January 2022 following the longest coalition negotiations in Dutch political history.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The election for the lower house of the Dutch parliament later this year will take place in a polarised and splintered political landscape – there are 20 parties in the 150-seat lower house.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During provincial elections earlier this year, a populist pro-farmer party put Rutte&#39;s party into second place. The defeat was seen as a possible incentive for Rutte to do his utmost to hold together his coalition until its term ends in 2025.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Taiwan’s KMT is likely to stay with presidential pick Hou You-ih against all odds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3226979/why-taiwans-kmt-likely-stay-presidential-pick-hou-you-ih-against-all-odds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/80b8c912-1b40-46d0-bfd0-61c943755147_7aa5dec5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s main opposition Kuomintang is expected to keep the faith in Hou You-ih and a “pro-peace” cross-strait agenda for next year&#39;s presidential race, despite his lack of popular support and divisive effect on the party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou, mayor of New Taipei City since 2018, received a record low support rate of 17 per cent in the most recent survey by pro-independence pollster Normal Country Promotion Foundation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vice-president William Lai Ching-te, the candidate for the ruling independence-leaning Democratic Progressive Party (DPP), has a clear lead in the race, according to the poll results released on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai garnered 34 per cent support in the poll, followed by Ko Wen-je of the new and relatively pro-Beijing Taiwan People&#39;s Party with 25 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan is due to vote for a new president in January, with both Beijing and Washington watching the outcome closely. The stakes this time are particularly high, as Beijing reacts to Taipei&#39;s closer US ties with unprecedented cross-strait military pressure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To Beijing, Taiwan is a breakaway province awaiting reunification, by force if need be, and with no right to official exchanges with other governments. While the US does not view the self-ruled island as independent, it is opposed to any forcible change to the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;KMT is by far Taiwan&#39;s largest opposition party and Beijing&#39;s best hope of taming spiralling tensions amid worsening US rivalry. It is also the Taiwanese party with the most frequent cross-strait interactions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan&#39;s KMT to send delegation to mainland China forum despite warnings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the poll trends threaten to upend what has for decades been a two-party contest between the independence-leaning DPP and the KMT, leader of the pro-unification “blue” camp.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts put Hou&#39;s poor poll showing down to divisions within the KMT regarding his candidature, such as his less-than-ideal public speaking skills and perceived deficiencies as a leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With barely six months to go for the presidential vote, the KMT is still struggling with internal divisions and has failed to fully support the nominated candidate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang Wu-ueh, director of the Tamkang University Cross-Strait Relations Research Centre, said the poll results showed that “there were still different views of him within KMT”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hou has never been highly consistent in support for the party, and many are still dissatisfied with him,” Chang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For instance, Hou did not back former Kaohsiung mayor Han Kuo-yu when he ran for president as the KMT candidate in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The KMT national congress on July 23 will be “an important date” for Hou, Zhang said, citing speculation that his candidacy might be revoked, though he does not think that would happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think that is unlikely, because there is no other appropriate candidate … and if he wins the final nomination [at the congress], many KMT members will come back to support him,” Chang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;KMT leader Eric Li-luan Chu has ruled out the possibility of Hou being replaced. He said on Wednesday that the party “fully supported” Hou&#39;s policies, including on cross-strait relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other notable party members, including former vice chair Hung Hsiu-chu and former legislative head Wang Jin-pying have also sought to dispel notions of any change in candidacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ni Yongjie, director of the Shanghai Institute of Taiwan Studies, echoed Chang in saying Hou was up against obstacles within the KMT, apart from having to tackle campaign “attacks” from the DPP – flag bearer of Taiwan&#39;s pro-independence “green” camp.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The blue camp is not well integrated, there is not enough support for Hou, and there is not enough unity,” Ni said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou also has some personal shortcomings, such as “being better at implementation rather than policymaking”, due to his background as a police officer, and he is not an eloquent speaker compared to the likes of Ko, Ni said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the “unfavourable” support rate was a “temporary” matter and Hou “still had a chance” of winning, Ni said. “The blue camp needs to understand that it has to speed up support mobilisation for him.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How William Lai&#39;s &#39;deep green&#39; Taiwan politics became a red line for Beijing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There has also been speculation that billionaire Foxconn founder Terry Gou might join the presidential fray as an independent candidate, after failing to secure the KMT nomination. Ni said this has also affected Hou&#39;s support rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, for the first time after being picked as the KMT candidate, Hou revealed a clear stance on cross-strait relations, which is at the centre of the 2024 presidential race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou said he endorsed the 1992 Consensus in line with the Constitution of the Republic of China, Taiwan&#39;s formal name for itself, but was against its interpretation as “one country, two systems” as declared by Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “1992 Consensus” is a tacit agreement that there is only “one China” but the two sides may disagree on what that refers to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing responded quickly to Hou&#39;s remarks, with its Taiwan Affairs Office reaffirming its willingness “to maintain positive interactions with all political parties on the island, including the KMT, on the common political basis of adhering to the 1992 Consensus”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang at Tamkang said Hou had long remained vague on the cross-strait issue, and his recent remarks would help him “win support within the KMT”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hou has to have a better stance and a clear position on cross-strait affairs. [As] the 1992 Consensus may not be the consensus of the Taiwanese people, but it is the consensus within the party.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>