<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong woman dies in flat fire after quarrel with sisters over sale of property]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3228803/hong-kong-woman-dies-flat-fire-after-quarrel-sisters-over-sale-property?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 11:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/08863378-121c-465f-afbe-26b54cc956f c_d64c77bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名女子因出售房产与三姐妹发生争执，导致香港公屋失火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;慈云山慈乐村乐信楼的58岁租户于周一晚上11时34分被证实死亡，她在火灾发生前一天被送往威尔斯亲王医院。&lt;/p据警方称，她姓黄，是四姐妹中年龄最大的。她全身 70% 被烧伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二姐和三姐分别为 53 岁和 51 岁，据说截至周一晚间情况危急。最小的46岁，据说受了重伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;四姐妹在香港平火中被严重烧伤，据称还有一人在争吵后被刺伤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方发言人早些时候表示，姐妹们为出售房产而发生争执后不久，火灾就爆发了。据称黄用刀袭击了她的一个姐妹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方于周日以伤人罪逮捕了黄。当时表示，已将案件转介社会福利署跟进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消防处表示，火警面积为六米乘五米（20英尺乘16英尺），客厅、浴室及厨房在大火中严重受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据部门发言人表示，起火原因可疑，案件已交由警方调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump maintains commanding lead in poll, Vivek Ramaswamy on the rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228806/donald-trump-maintains-commanding-lead-poll-vivek-ramaswamy-rise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 11:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/989cc3ae-fa09-4226-a25c-d822147a15dc _1a5b7b3a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尽管存在悬而未决的法律纠纷，但最近的民意调查显示，美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普继续在共和党初选中占据主导地位，尽管一位政治局外人显示出越来越受欢迎的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据哈佛大学美国政治研究中心最近对 2,000 多名登记选民进行的一项调查，特朗普继续保持大多数共和党选民的支持，而商人维维克·拉马斯瓦米开始在保守派中出名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管失去了一些优势，但特朗普在未来的共和党初选中显然是最受欢迎的；民意调查机构写道：“德桑蒂斯仍然位居第二，但动力输给了拉马斯瓦米。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 7 月 19 日至 20 日进行的调查，这位在纽约面临悬而未决的联邦文件案和另一起商业记录案指控的前总统，在 52% 的保守派中拥有影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这比上个月下降了 7 个百分点，但仍领先下一位领先的共和党人、佛罗里达州州长罗恩整整 40 个百分点德桑蒂斯的支持率为 12%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国第 45 任总统在分享哈佛民意调查后不久，在他的 Truth Social 媒体平台上写道，“人们了解罗恩·德桑蒂斯的支持率越多，他的民意调查就越低”，他使用了阳光之州共和党州长的昵称。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在 2024 年共和党民意调查中，特朗普领先德桑蒂斯 36%&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;特朗普没有提及 Ra马斯瓦米是来自辛辛那提的哈佛和耶鲁大学毕业生，他似乎已经接受了这位前总统失去的支持，他的支持率飙升了 8 个百分点，达到 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据这位 37 岁的竞选团队的说法，这次民意调查是拉马斯瓦米满足共和党全国委员会的筹款和辩论资格投票标准所剩下的一切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的竞选团队表示，他早在 5 月份就达到了筹款要求，并且十多名共和党人都在争夺提名，而这位崭露头角的候选人在辩论舞台上的地位几乎已经确定，拉马斯瓦米以这次民意调查为契机，发表了一份声明，为他的保守派同僚划清了界限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共和党全国委员会的辩论阶段标准严格但公平。我是一名首次候选人，一开始的身份非常低，没有政治捐助者，也没有预先存在的筹款名单。如果一个局外人可以清除障碍，那么有政治经验的候选人也应该可以：如果你不能在八月下旬之前达到这些指标，你绝对没有机会在大选中击败乔·拜登。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前还不清楚特朗普是否会参加共和党全国委员会或任何其他组织举行的任何辩论。他经常表示他可能不会打扰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，这位前总统利用他的社交媒体平台分享了其他人的主张，他应该在第一场辩论的晚上与前福克斯新闻主持人塔克·卡尔森进行一对一采访。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有趣吗？很多人都提出了这个建议，”他写道，但没有提供进一步的例子。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkey deals with Saudi Arabia, UAE herald new security ties amid US shift to counter China, Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3228724/turkey-deals-saudi-arabia-uae-herald-new-security-ties-amid-us-shift-counter-china-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/05225e7f-8f09-4bd5-8076-aa1ccf122 6dd_438bbbc0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯和阿拉伯联合酋长国的一系列协议使土耳其成为海湾君主国重要的新安全伙伴，而此时美国正在中东撤军，以配合其外交政策重点转向遏制中国和俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;土耳其总统雷杰普·塔伊普·埃尔多安上周对海湾地区进行了具有里程碑意义的访问，并在获得 11 美元后返回安卡拉。阿联酋提供 50 亿美元的财政援助，以帮助支撑土耳其枯竭的外汇储备、快速贬值的里拉货币和不断扩大的预算赤字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔多安还与阿联酋和沙特阿拉伯达成协议，与拥有北约第二大军事力量的土耳其建立联合国防生产计划。土耳其国防制造商Baykar从沙特阿拉伯获得了最大的海外订单，用于技术转让和联合生产其军用无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔多安访问期间在海湾签署的协议代表着自2020年以来两国关系的迅速转变。土耳其和沙特-阿联酋联盟在整个2010年代一直处于争执之中，因为他们支持埃及、利比亚和其他地区国家的对立双方，这些国家在本世纪初的阿拉伯之春革命引发了内战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;总部位于华盛顿的地缘政治风险咨询公司海湾国家分析公司首席执行官乔治·卡菲罗 (Giorgio Cafiero) 表示：“导致一些海湾合作委员会国家感受到土耳其外交政策威胁的许多因素已经发生了巨大变化，让利雅得和阿布扎比更有理由将安卡拉视为危险行为体。”卡菲罗表示：“但我相信，随着所有地区行为体适应更加多极世界的现实，中东国家在华盛顿方面获得更多代理权和自主权，这些海湾国家和安卡拉可以建立持久的战略伙伴关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;沙特阿拉伯在土耳其央行存入 50 亿美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在伊斯兰主义者埃尔多安的领导下，土耳其及其富裕的海湾盟友卡塔尔支持埃及、利比亚和土耳其出现的民选穆斯林兄弟会政府。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这引起了沙特和阿联酋君主国的警惕，他们认为民粹主义伊斯兰政治运动是对阿拉伯世界既定专制秩序的生存威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的回应是支持这些国家的反政变和反叛派系，包括2013年推翻埃及穆斯林兄弟会政府的军事政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着阿拉伯之春的气氛现在大大减弱，人们对阿拉伯之春的程度产生了怀疑。伊斯坦布尔分析师优素福·埃里姆表示，在美国的持续支持下，海湾和土耳其“最近确实从意识形态角度转向了更加现实的政治立场”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这使得土耳其及其海湾阿拉伯竞争对手能够“走到一起，能够从更务实的角度讨论地区发展”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们看到了这一结果导致了该地区更广泛的大融合”，从而导致了重大地缘政治变化，包括土耳其的正常化”他们明白，他们需要针对地区问题采取本地解决方案，因为未来美国的援助将会减少。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这有助于营造一种氛围，解决安卡拉、利雅得和阿布扎比之间的地缘政治紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当双方审视彼此之间的分歧以及共同的经济、政治和安全利益时，“他们认为合作比相互竞争更有利可图”，埃里姆说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种基于现实政治的做法这反映在埃尔多安与沙特王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼和阿联酋总统穆罕默德·本·扎耶德·阿勒纳哈扬达成的战略协议中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据周二发布的联合声明，沙特阿拉伯和土耳其“表达了加强国防和军事工业合作与协调的决心”，并“以服务和实现两国共同利益并为实现地区和世界安全与和平做出贡献的方式”启动协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，埃尔多安对阿布扎比的访问达成了一项协议，旨在建立一个“战略委员会”，以加强土耳其和阿联酋之间的关系，并达成一项制定联合国防生产计划的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总价值达 507 亿美元的投资协议进一步强化了这一点——与 2021 年底阿联酋在土耳其累计投资 78 亿美元相比，这是一个巨大的飞跃。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;海湾竞争对手在沙特峰会上达成和解，结束了长期的和解。与卡塔尔的裂痕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新协议将被添加到两国3月份签署的全面经济伙伴关系协议的框架中，根据该协议，两国的目标是在未来五年内将双边非石油贸易额增加一倍以上，达到400亿美元以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，阿布扎比财富基金ADQ同意购买价值85亿美元的土耳其债券，为土耳其南部和中部地区在2月份遭受大地震破坏的房屋建设提供资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; ADQ 还同意向寻求向阿联酋和其他海外市场出口商品和服务的土耳其公司提供 30 亿美元信贷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然土耳其和沙特阿拉伯周一在吉达达成的多项特定行业经济协议的财务和项目细节尚未披露，但其中还包括向安卡拉提供财政援助和投资的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;合资企业和举措将成为目前正在制定的双边协调委员会框架的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Obama family chef drowns near ex-president’s home on Martha’s Vineyard]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228800/obama-family-chef-drowns-near-ex-presidents-home-marthas-vineyard?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 10:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/8e474e4d-6a4b-4526-9fad-c22b6766ee ec_d2c37c7b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国前总统巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 的私人厨师在玛莎葡萄园岛的家附近溺水身亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马萨诸塞州警方证实，周一在埃德加敦大池塘 (Edgartown Great Pond) 发现的桨板运动员的尸体是来自弗吉尼亚州邓弗里斯 (Dumfries) 的 45 岁塔法里·坎贝尔 (Tafari Campbell)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎贝尔 (Campbell) 受雇于奥巴马一家，当时正在探访玛莎葡萄园岛。事故发生时，奥巴马夫妇不在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一份声明中，前总统和他的妻子米歇尔·奥巴马称坎贝尔是“我们家庭中心爱的一员”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们第一次见到他时，他是白宫一位才华横溢的副主厨，对食物充满创意和热情，并且具有将人们凝聚在一起的能力，”这对夫妇说。 “在接下来的几年里，我们认识到他是一个热情、有趣、非常善良的人，他让我们的生活变得更加光明。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就是为什么当我们准备离开白宫时，我们邀请塔法里留下来和我们在一起，他慷慨地同意了。从那时起，他就成了我们生活的一部分，他的离去让我们心碎。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，一名桨板运动员同伴报告说，失踪的桨板运动员在水面上挣扎，沉入水下，再也没有浮出水面，搜寻工作于周日开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;搜索工作在周日晚些时候暂停，但周一州警方表示，一艘船上的声纳在距离岸边约 30 米（100 英尺）、水深约 2.4 米的地方发现了尸体。警方称，坎贝尔没有穿救生衣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥巴马夫妇表示，坎贝尔身后留下了他的妻子和双胞胎儿子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥巴马家族于 2021 年从波士顿凯尔特人队老板威克利夫·格鲁斯贝克 (Wycliffe Grousbeck) 手中购买了位于玛莎葡萄园岛的近 7,000 平方英尺的豪宅。该住宅毗邻沿海池塘，该池塘通过狭窄的屏障海滩与大西洋隔开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan bakes as residents warned of once-in-a-decade, life-threatening temperatures]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3228770/japan-bakes-residents-warned-once-decade-life-threatening-temperatures?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/613f0165-9ab2-43ab-8739-5ff888c83a1 2_e0336f6a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本已发布紧急天气警报，警告该东亚国家大部分地区的气温将在周三达到十年一遇的高点，而令人窒息的高温将至少持续到 8 月初。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月初气温异常飙升，7 月 11 日在 57 个地点达到至少 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度）。由横跨群岛大部分地区的高压系统造成。日本中部城市桐生市的温度计最高温度为 39.7 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，日本有记录以来的最高气温为东京北部埼玉县熊谷市的 41.1 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据日本气象厅称，由于雨季（通常为六周的大雨和潮湿期）逐渐结束并于周六结束，月中出现了短暂的平静。 。这个季节影响日本大部分地区的灰色天空现在已经被晴朗的天空和热浪所取代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构警告说，日本 47 个都道府县中，除了四个都道府县之外，所有都将出现反常的高温——唯一避开最酷热天气的地区是该国北部日本海沿岸的地区。预计局部气温将接近 40 摄氏度，而局部气温可能会远远超过该阈值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构的一位官员表示，今年夏天气温高于平均水平与影响太平洋海洋温度和天气系统的厄尔尼诺现象有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本为应对中暑死亡人数上升而制定的新计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该机构已就高温和高湿度组合可能产生的影响发布早期预警，指示公众通过剩余的水合物采取预防中暑的措施d、使用遮阳伞，尽量避免阳光直射，家里使用空调。人们还被要求检查老年邻居的健康状况，以确保他们的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公共广播公司 NHK 发布中暑警报，警告人们注意“危及生命”的高温，并建议人们尽可能呆在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于天气太热，我们已经在家打开空调一个多星期了，”来自横滨的家庭主妇细村加奈子说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我的儿子去学校时，我很担心。”公园或打棒球，因为阳光太强烈了，”她说。 “我会尝试在太阳落山后去购物，因为天气会凉爽一些。但即便如此，当我第一次上车时，车子就像一个烤箱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧急服务部门正在为大量需要治疗的人做好准备。去年5月至9月底，日本各地有71,029人因中暑入院寻求治疗，今年夏天的人数可能会超过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧急服务部门也在为更多周五放暑假的孩子们做好准备，让他们涌向海滩、河流和山里玩耍和纳凉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这也有其缺点。上周，三名六年级女孩于同一天在福冈县犬鸣河溺水身亡。上周末，至少有 18 人在水中或徒步旅行事故中丧生，其中包括 7 月 16 日在岛根县出云市海滩试图营救两个孩子时溺水身亡的父亲。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Awesome! Movers in China wear  exoskeleton suits for heavy lifting, boosting efficiency, reducing injury as technology expands across nation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3228465/awesome-movers-china-wear-exoskeleton-suits-heavy-lifting-boosting-efficiency-reducing-injury?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/e179f9f4-a5e9-4dca-911d-ef48f261763b_c62e0ffe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A number of Chinese movers which are using wearable exoskeleton robots to boost efficiency and prevent muscle strain have trended on mainland social media after videos of the devices were posted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCTV2 reported this month that more mainland moving companies have started to provide intelligent wearable exoskeleton robots for their workers to meet the demand for services in the peak summer season, with companies in Beijing, Shanghai and other cities using the technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Movers Hong Yanming and Nian Jihong appeared in a video wearing the exoskeleton suits while carrying two boxes each and climbing stairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is able to relieve the pressure on my shoulders,” Nian told CCTV2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong said that two-thirds of their orders came from tenants living in buildings without lifts and that before the exoskeleton robots, the work was strenuous, especially while climbing stairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The robots record and analyse data from the wearers and make intelligent response decisions that generate force to help the wearer move about with less effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lin Xichuan, the chief technology officer for an AI company that was not named in the report, said that the robot suits could transfer and lighten weights borne by the wearer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It can prevent movers from suffering strain of lower back muscles or other aches,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nian said the robot suit gives an extra push to the knees while Hong said that since using the suit he is struggling less than before, and his work efficiency has improved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previously they could only complete two moving orders a day, but now they are likely to finish up to four.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My earnings have increased as a result,” Hong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has drawn public interest on mainland social media after going viral.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person commented: “Technology makes life better.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person said: “How wonderful if it can be used in other industries like healthcare and transport.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In China, exoskeleton technology is expanding to a variety of industries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2021, a company with a focus on robotics, rehabilitation medicine and artificial intelligence in eastern China used robotic exoskeleton technology to help paralysed people walk again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese logistics providers such as SF Express and YT Express have adopted exoskeletons in their warehouses, from lower back support exoskeletons for heavy lifting to chair-like reinforcement for standing workers.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Western sanctions and distrust draw China, Russia closer in the Arctic]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228477/western-sanctions-and-distrust-draw-china-russia-closer-arctic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/9d48e79a-abd6-47ec-95d8-0cb28402ef0 1_03ed8b86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着气候变化开启了一条可行的北方航道的前景，并使极地地区成为美中竞争的另一条战线，中国和俄罗斯一直在加强从能源、科学到国防的北极合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰战争后欧盟的制裁迫使莫斯科为其原油寻找新市场，目前其大部分出口通过苏伊士运河漫长而昂贵的南方航道销往中国和印度。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但融化的海冰有可能开辟一条更有利可图的通道，据了解，俄罗斯正在测试一批穿越北冰洋的原油，预计将于 8 月 12 日抵达中国东部山东省日照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果成功，与途经苏伊士运河相比，该合资企业将把欧洲和东北亚之间的海上距离缩短 30%，并大幅降低货运成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国 — — 中国也有成为“极地大国”的雄心俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京在三月份与中国领导人习近平会晤时表示，近年来，通过与北极国家（特别是俄罗斯）的科学研究和经济联系，我们在该地区取得了立足点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为与中国合作伙伴在开发北方海航线过境潜力方面的合作前景广阔。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们准备成立一个开发北方海航线的联合工作机构。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Desp华盛顿智库北极研究所的高级研究员帕维尔·德维亚特金表示，更多石油从俄罗斯北极流向中国“只是两国之间加强能源合作的最新迹象”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德维亚特金表示，北京一直在利用与莫斯科的科学和经济关系来加强其在该地区的立足点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“例如，中国积极开展科学合作，与北极国家的科学家一起参加国际北极研究考察。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北极理事会是该地区政府和原住民的政府间论坛，俄罗斯与中国的伙伴关系因此进一步加强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该理事会的八个成员中的七个——美国、加拿大、芬兰、丹麦、冰岛、挪威和瑞典——正在抵制其会议，以回应俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国冰上丝绸之路的下一步是什么专家表示，普京的战争引发了北极冰冻？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北极理事会（中国作为观察员国参与其中）与俄罗斯之间日益紧张的关系促使莫斯科加强与北京在该地区相关行动中的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 9 月，美国海岸警卫队在阿拉斯加附近遭遇了在阿拉斯加附近进行联合行动的中国和俄罗斯军舰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，两国在日本海或东海（主要海域）举行了联合海空军演习。北极大学政治学副教授马克·兰泰涅 (Marc Lanteigne) 表示，中国也在“重组和重新考虑其北极政策”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lanteigne 表示，北京正试图在不疏远其他北极国家政府的情况下支持莫斯科，但近年来中国与其中一些国家的关系恶化，并推动了中国与俄罗斯的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国在该地区的行动能力已变得更加受限。如果北极理事会无法正常运作，中国可能不得不更多地利用与北极国家的双边合作。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“可能会有更多与俄罗斯合作的例子……他们开始寻找其他合作选择，以防北极理事会无法正常运作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;挪威国防研究所教授莉塞洛特·奥德加德表示，中国与俄罗斯在北极地区的密切战略伙伴关系是一把“双刃剑”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;“[中国]确实在该地区的所有西方国家都有投资，但由于北约国家越来越多地对中国说不，它无法进行许多战略投资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据奥德加德称，中国已进入众多科学和环境合作机构和观测站，并参加了许多向该地区以外国家开放的多边科学考察活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;与俄罗斯的友好关系是中国实现北极愿望的关键：报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是她指出，人们越来越认识到这些资源也可用于军事战略目的，例如态势感知和情报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“多年来，他们从中受益匪浅，但现在人们开始注意到他们的存在正在停止，”奥德加德说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国与俄罗斯的接触以及通过试图购买或建造具有潜在军事用途的资产来追求在北极的战略存在，使该地区的欧洲和北美国家更加关注。对中国投资持谨慎态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京在斯瓦尔巴群岛和冰岛设有永久研究站，支持海洋生态和大气物理等领域的广泛研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在 2019 年，中国于 2016 年在瑞典北部基律纳建造的第三个研究站，用于传输北极地区的图像，因涉嫌与中国人民解放军有联系而受到审查，引发人们担心它可能被用于军事情报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;同年，由于丹麦对其与在格陵兰岛拥有空军基地的美国结盟感到担忧，国有中国交通建设公司撤回了在格陵兰岛建设价值 4.2 亿美元的机场项目的投标。 2017年，哥本哈根拒绝了中国矿业公司一般尼斯集团的要约，因为安全问题，中国开始建造冰破冰船，该公司开始建造破冰船，该公司可能在2018年到2018年的2025年海底&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;在2018年，上海政府机构，在中央政府的活动中，该地区的活动是一定的。土地，芬兰北部。赫尔辛基在华盛顿的压力下暂停了该交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究所在 6 月份宣布准备在北冰洋大规模部署水下设备，用于冰下通信、导航和定位，这进一步引起了华盛顿的不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国反对此举，因为它有可能用于在极地冰层下导航和隐藏核潜艇。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北极声学？中国计划在北极建立大规模监听网络&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库战略与国际研究中心中国力量项目研究员布赖恩·哈特(Brian Hart)表示，中国缺乏透明度，一再引发人们对其科学研究可能为军事或情报活动打开大门的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在研究方面，民用和军事之间的界限往往很模糊，中国的情况当然如此，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着即使是合法的科学研究也有可能成为潜在的威胁。”被中国军事和情报部门用于非民用目的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈特表示，中国与俄罗斯强有力的外交、经济和军事关系的部分目的是为了增强中国在北极的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他补充说，莫斯科可能会对中国在北极的军事活动范围保持警惕，俄罗斯认为北极是其战略后院，拥有最敏感的军事资产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据挪威研究所的奥德加德的说法，而北京的目标并不是为了通过单枪匹马的行动成为北极军事强国，中国正试图通过支持俄罗斯在该地区的存在来加强与莫斯科的战略联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，中国希望与欧洲保持合作关系，但西大陆在与美国的战略竞争中处于“错误的一边”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于[中国]来说，首要任务将是俄罗斯能够继续威胁北约，跨越从北极到地中海的界限，”奥德加德说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“重要的是，俄罗斯能够继续成为威胁并承担重任。 [中国]自己不想这样做……相反，它对帮助俄罗斯有着巨大的兴趣……它拥有俄罗斯所缺乏的经济和技术资源。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北极大学的兰泰涅表示，中国将继续将自己描绘成该地区的利益相关者。他表示，美国航母 65 年来首次访问挪威，是这一趋势的一部分，表明该地区不再是“无军事活动区”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯的制裁会冻结亚洲在北极的气候变化研究吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“北京的说法，特别是最近，是‘不，实际上是北约在将该地区军事化’，而且没有提到俄罗斯。因此，现在肯定有很多相互矛盾的说法。”兰泰涅说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于安全局势变得更加复杂，中国在北极问题上必须更加保守。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot;最佳&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese games shine at Bilibili’s ACG event as local content begins to eclipse the allure of Japanese anime]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3228765/chinese-games-shine-bilibilis-acg-event-local-content-begins-eclipse-allure-japanese-anime?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/3fc572da-3aea-4ab8-b1f4-8f57da8976f4_62efef6d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Home-grown anime, comics and games (ACG) content, led by the rise of domestically-developed video games, has put similar material from Japan in the shade at an exhibition staged by Bilibili in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bilibili, a video streaming and gaming platform, began hosting the anime-themed event in 2017 as a community for fans of Japanese cartoon and comic subculture. But amid the rising popularity of domestic anime-style games and increased scrutiny of foreign materials in recent years, Japanese-made content has faded from view at the BilibiliWorld event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bilibili, which began life in 2009 as a platform for Chinese teenagers to watch Japanese cartoons, has evolved into one of the largest video sharing platforms in China for ACG fans and the younger generation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s own anime-style games, including Genshin Impact and the Honkai series from Shanghai-based studio miHoYo as well as Arknights by HyperGryph, drew most of the attention from Chinese fans at this year&#39;s event, which ran from Friday to Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;More joy for Chinese video gamers as regulator approves 86 new titles in April&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;MiHoYo, a rising video gaming champion that is now competing with Tencent Holdings and NetEase, set up five booths at the exhibition, occupying a central position in the video game section, the largest area at the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese ACG fans, many of whom dressed up in colourful cosplay outfits, lined up in long queues to meet up with online influencers and to collect game-related merchandise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exhibition is expected to be one of the largest ACG events in China this year, as the country gets back to normal after the lifting of strict zero-Covid policies last December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to information provided by Bilibili, this year&#39;s event attracted nearly 100,000 people, a record for the exhibition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the booth for Arknights, a popular anime-style game released by Shanghai-based HyperGryph in 2019, the organisers were forced to put up “sold out” signs for merchandise by midday on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had prepared more than a thousand free gift bags for fans every day, and they were all given out in just two hours, with many fans queuing up early just to collect the official merchandise,” Xiao Kun, who worked on the booth for miHoYo&#39;s Honkai Impact 3 during the three-day event, said on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bilibili CEO to take direct control of video gaming unit, people say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Over at the Genshin Impact booth, a staff member who only gave his screen name as “Pikagu”, said there was a much higher number of visitors to the game&#39;s stall this year compared with 2021 when the game last joined the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Genshin Impact has changed the whole industry,” said Xiao at the Honkai booth. “Now the concept of ACG has expanded a lot in China to include the domestic anime-style games, compared with earlier exhibitions which were dominated by Japanese anime titles.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rise of China&#39;s self-developed games has been led by the phenomenal global success of Genshin Impact, which was launched in September 2020. The open-world action role-playing game had bagged US$4 billion in global revenue by the end of 2022, making it one of the most successful game titles of all time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bilibili, which once heavily relied on the revenue from Fate/Grand Order, a Japanese-origin anime-style game before the company went public in the US in 2018, has also stepped up its own games development in the genre. It secured a licence from Beijing for Higan: Eruthyll in May, a month after the game was first launched in the overseas market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I came all the way from Shanxi province just for Genshin Impact merchandise,” said Bo Jiang, who was holding two large bags full of the game&#39;s merchandise. Jiang said he had been playing the game since it was launched in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;miHoYo&#39;s revenue surges on back of Genshin Impact and Honkai: Star Rail success&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;ve spent over 40,000 yuan (US$5,560) in Honkai Impact 3 and Arknights,” said Hua Xu, an 18-year-old student from southern Hunan province. He said he now splits his time across four anime-style games – all developed by Chinese studios. “They totally dominate my life and I barely have any time for other non-ACG genres such as Elden Ring.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, a few iconic Japanese ACG titles, such as Pokemon, One Piece and Detective Conan, also had their own booths at the exhibition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the booth for Hatsune Miku, a popular virtual idol and singer developed by Crypton Future Media in Japan, over a hundred fans gathered in front of the stage on Sunday afternoon to shout and sing with the virtual avatar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I do think Chinese ACG games have gathered more of an audience now, but they are at an early stage. Japanese elements still dominate the major areas including anime and music,” said Si Mu, a 17-year-old student from eastern Zhejiang province, as she waved her hands enthusiastically at the Hatsune Miku gathering.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese University saga: 877 sign petition backing counterproposal to reform Hong Kong varsity’s governing body]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3228783/chinese-university-saga-877-sign-petition-backing-counter-proposal-reform-hong-kong-varistys?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/467d2a3a-2ca5-43c0-8f17-541a127e3102_a0e408fc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;More than 800 people have signed a petition supporting an alternative proposal to reform the governing council of the Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), including one of its vice-presidents, in response to a controversial bill by three lawmakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The appeal was backed by former government officials, business leaders, past and current staff. The petition also slammed the lawmakers behind the private members&#39; bill for “ignoring” the opinions of university employees, students and alumni.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We three CUHK alumni, Kelvin Yeung Yu-ming, Enders Lam Wai-hung, Heung Shu-fai hope to appeal to all concerned friends of CUHK to sign to support &#39;The win-win proposal to reform the Chinese University of Hong Kong council&#39;. Your support will be the biggest thing you can give back to CUHK,” the trio wrote in a statement alongside the petition.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Legco blocks Hong Kong public hearing on changes to Chinese University council&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;They accused the lawmakers and fellow council members Tommy Cheung Yu-yan, Bill Tang Ka-piu and Edward Lau Kwok-fan of ignoring the proposal endorsed by a university-established task force that reviewed the governing body&#39;s composition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The petition, which called for a modified version of the task force&#39;s proposal, has received 877 signatures as of 10pm on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Current university vice-president Eric Ng Shu-pui, as well as alumni Greater Bay Airlines chief executive Stanley Hui Hon-chung and Lingnan University president Leonard Cheng Kwok-hon have all signed the petition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng told the Post that reforming the university&#39;s governing body was necessary, but the three lawmakers should not have tried to force an amendment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no need to force an amendment of the CUHK Ordinance on the university, which should only be considered in the extraordinary situation that the university has stubbornly refused to reform the ordinance,” Cheng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But such an extraordinary situation does not exist. Quite to the contrary, CUHK has already proposed sensible amendments to its ordinance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The private members&#39; bill aims to reduce the number of council spots from 55 to 34 and increase the ratio of external representatives to internal appointees to 2:1. The latter group currently accounts for half of all the body&#39;s seats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposal also seeks to increase the voting threshold for appointing university heads from the current simple majority to three-quarters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The task force&#39;s counter-proposal, which was published in April, agreed with reducing the number of council seats but the revised size ranged from 25 to 34, while the ratio for external and internal members would stand between 1:1.64 and 1:2.13.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also called for the voting threshold to be increased to somewhere between two-thirds and three-quarters, as well as calling for a review of the number of lawmakers on the council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the modified proposal featured in the petition suggested cutting the three seats each held by university&#39;s official alumni group and lawmakers to two aside. But it would preserve the six spots nominated by Hong Kong&#39;s leader and raise the threshold for appointing the vice-chancellor and president, as well as provost, to two-thirds.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese University council member urges Hong Kong lawmakers to delay overhaul bill&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lingnan University president Cheng said lawmakers should work with the university to introduce the appropriate amendments. Any discrepancies between the proposals could be discussed respectfully by the legislator and council members, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fellow signatory Wong Pok-hon, a former council chairman of the university&#39;s now-defunct student union, slammed the reduction of seats on the governing body under the private members&#39; bill as “too much”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposal featured in the petition was more reasonable since it cut a place for lawmakers alongside a seat held by members of the alumni group, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The reform is a major event for the university and it should be up to the council. It will not be a problem for lawmakers to get enough votes to pass their bill nowadays, but we still want our voices to be heard,” Wong said. “That is why I signed the petition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted that CUHK could not explicitly speak out against the bill as it faced political pressure and needed grants provided by the Legislative Council, meaning university members and alumni need to come together and voice their concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong bill to cut size of university&#39;s council to go to Legco on Thursday&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, lawmaker Tang took to social media to defend the private members&#39; bill and argued it would boost the legitimacy of selected university heads.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also stressed that the changes were mild and that past reform plans had failed to take the impact of the 2019 anti-government protests into consideration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post has reached out to Tang and Lau, while Cheung has refused to comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bill is seen as the pro-establishment bloc&#39;s response to the controversial reappointment of Professor Rocky Tuan Sung-chi, who will stay on as university president until 2026.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuan was accused by some pro-Beijing figures of being sympathetic to protesting students during the social unrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is Rocky Tuan a patriot? Chinese University of Hong Kong head addresses criticism&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A Legco bills committee scrutinising the proposal on Friday denied a request for a public hearing despite some lawmakers saying it would increase transparency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Details of the bill will be reviewed at another meeting on Friday of this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked to comment on the petition, a spokesman for the university on Monday only said it would “look forward” to a special meeting of its council on August 1.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Small-scale dip’? China downplays FDI inflow decline that may be having a big impact on confidence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228745/small-scale-dip-china-downplays-fdi-inflow-decline-may-be-having-big-impact-confidence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/603dbdf4-f16f-4bab-9a2b-697b68ec25ab_346c4ac1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;This is the third on how a tumultuous first half of 2023 featured economic pitfalls and headwinds that have left China struggling to shake off years of Covid-induced rust.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s all-out efforts in recent months to defy Western calls to “de-risk” while cementing China&#39;s footings in the global supply chain appear to have been compromised by a drop in foreign direct investment during the first half of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foreign direct investment in China fell by 2.7 per cent from January to June, year on year, to 703.65 billion yuan (US$98 billion), according to fresh figures from the Ministry of Commerce, which has not yet published the number in US dollar terms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first five months of 2023, the US-dollar-denominated total had fallen by 5.6 per cent from a year earlier to US$84.4 billion, including a year-on-year fall of 18.4 per cent in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We believe short-term fluctuations in the numbers will not affect foreign investors&#39; optimism towards China&#39;s development. The atmosphere for the further expansion of FDI to China has not changed,” said Zhu Bing, director of Mofcom&#39;s Department of Foreign Investment Administration, when the figures were released last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Only the wearer knows where the shoe pinches&#39;: tough times for China&#39;s exporters&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While Zhu described the drop in FDI to China as “a small-scale dip”, this would raise further questions on how confident foreign investors remain in investing in the world&#39;s second-largest economy in the near future, when Beijing&#39;s post-Covid economy has yet to show a strong sign of recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet, foreign companies&#39; investment priorities and concerns have shifted in the past few years, as China closed off its borders during the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When you&#39;re trying to attract FDI, it is a multiple-year process … You need a signal from [company&#39;s] leadership that &#39;we need to invest more&#39;. You can only get that through visits,” said Michael Hart, president of the American Chamber of Commerce in China (AmCham).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hart said the process of executives visiting China after three years of absence “is still at the beginning”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese officials – from the top to bottom of the apparatus responsible for driving foreign investments – have been attempting to engage their counterparts on a charm offensive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past week, China&#39;s embassies around the world – from Cairo to Washington – have organised “roadshows” for local business leaders to brief them on a new event – the China International Supply Chain Expo that will take place in Beijing on November 28.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exhibition promises opportunities for foreign investors in smart cars, green agriculture, clean energy, digital technology and healthy living, according to official statements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These moves come with Washington and its Group of Seven (G7) allies having said they do not want “decoupling” but “de-risking” in their supply chains that they see as being overreliant on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The commerce ministry has been reaching out to foreign investors in recent months. Its chief, Wang Wentao, has met high-level foreign executives from multinational companies more than 20 times, and officials have held exchanges or “roundtables” with foreign business chambers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will new action plan give backbone of China&#39;s economy the wings to fly higher?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;During the latest roundtable discussion on Friday, Beijing tried to ease concerns of foreign investors on cross-border data flow, export controls and implementation of an anti-espionage law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite Beijing&#39;s rhetoric and moves, its latest economic numbers from the second quarter of the year were also a deterring factor for more investments to be made, as China&#39;s gross domestic product (GDP) rose by 6.3 per cent – up 0.8 per cent compared to the first three months of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This points to a continually uneven post-pandemic recovery, with faltering private confidence, record-high youth unemployment, and overhanging risks in the property market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jens Eskelund, president of the EU Chamber of Commerce in China, said after the second-quarter economic data was released that he was “almost certain” that the confidence levels among European companies operating in China had dropped further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a survey published last month, the European chamber said one in 10 firms had already moved, or planned to move, their Asia headquarters away from the mainland, with Singapore and Malaysia being the top two choices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European Commission&#39;s economic-security strategy and Germany&#39;s long-awaited China strategy – both released in the past month – also emphasised “diversifying” supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eskelund also noted that Beijing&#39;s broadening of the counter-espionage law, and the introduction of the law on foreign relations, both of which took effect from July 1, have further clouded investment prospects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chambers have been calling for clarity on these laws, and he said their members would need to do further dual diligence regarding these changes, as they are unclear on how to comply with the broad spectrum of law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There has been a lot of ambiguity in regulations … And I think, in many ways, security seems to be more important than growing the economy,” Eskelund said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eskelund added that these changes will require that more dual diligence be done, and therefore the costs and risks will have a bigger impact on small and medium-sized investors than on multinational corporations.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China vows private firms, like state firms, will be &#39;bigger, better, stronger&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An AmCham survey published in March has also expressed similar sentiments. A majority of 55 per cent of surveyed members no longer regarded China as a top-three investment priority amid growing concerns about the country&#39;s policy uncertainties and bleak bilateral ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese economists admit that it will continue to be a top challenge for China to boost that number under the current conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the economic numbers released from the first half of the year, Guan Tao, global chief economist at Bank of China International, said China would continue to face the challenge of “reshaping” the global supply chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Geopolitical factors have had big impacts on China, as they have brought along many uncertainties,” said Guan, a former director at the State Administration of Foreign Exchange. “We will be seeing more impacts on [our economy] from the changes in the global supply chain.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Wen, a researcher at the Academy of Macroeconomic Research, said: “Attracting foreign investment is, of course, very important to the Chinese economy, especially in terms of job creation and technology advancement.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, who works at the research centre under the National Development and Reform Commission, said that instead of sweeping policy changes, it is likely that the government will make “amendments on smaller aspects to improve the practical implementation of policies”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[On both the South China Sea and drug war probe, Philippines should stick to right side of international law]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228704/both-south-china-sea-and-drug-war-probe-philippines-should-stick-right-side-international-law?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/24/99c75a0f-91f8-4a95-904f-8ae8bc167ddf_22112e81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;There&#39;s an idiom in the English language that says “you can&#39;t have your cake and eat it, too” – in other words, you can&#39;t have it both ways. But the Philippine government under President Ferdinand Marcos Jnr is in danger of trying to do just that. On one hand it seeks protection under international law, while on the other it is simultaneously abnegating those aspects it disagrees with.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The International Criminal Court&#39;s (ICC) latest ruling dismissing the Philippines&#39; attempt to block the ICC&#39;s probe into the country&#39;s rampaging war on drugs comes at an inconvenient time for the Marcos administration as it seeks to garner international support against China&#39;s increasingly assertive territorial claims in the West Philippine Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Philippine senators are urging the government to bring the matter before the United Nations General Assembly in a bid to raise awareness, seemingly oblivious to the fact they could be accused of double standards. Still, the Philippines is a major player in the high-stakes territorial disputes in the South China Sea that are at the heart of simmering Sino-US tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But by cherry-picking compliance with international law, Marcos is not only in danger of damaging the country&#39;s reputation, he is hardly in a position to hold China to international obligations under the 2016 UN Convention on the Law of the Sea arbitral award which upheld Philippine sovereign rights in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The glaring dichotomy also places the United States in something of a bind as it ratchets up assistance to Manila under recently expanded defence cooperation agreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Biden administration&#39;s support for the ICC as a mechanism to pursue Russian President Vladimir Putin suggests the long arm of international law might yet reach former Philippine president Rodrigo Duterte, the chief architect of the drug war. The ICC issued an arrest warrant against Putin in March, a move US President Joe Biden supported and said, “I think it&#39;s justified.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ICC&#39;s recent decision is a warning that momentum in the case is building and the drug war&#39;s two main figures – Duterte and Ronald dela Rosa, a former Philippine National Police chief turned senator – could see arrest warrants issued against them, a development that might not sit well with Washington. Justice Secretary Jesus Crispin Remulla has reportedly advised Duterte and Dela Rosa to be cautious with their travel plans. After all, allegations of crimes against humanity are a global concern.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Marcos, who has vowed not to cooperate with the ICC, the decision is a litmus test of his government&#39;s commitment to international law and a stress test of the political alliance between the Marcoses and the Dutertes. The legacy of Duterte&#39;s vicious anti-drug campaign is rapidly becoming a shackle for Marcos, who has thrown his weight behind a dramatic policy shift in favour of Washington, in stark contrast to his predecessor&#39;s pro-China stance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The juxtaposition of the recent choreographed images of Duterte&#39;s audience with President Xi Jinping against Marcos&#39; statements welcoming US backing in the South China Sea suggests all is not well when it comes to Manila&#39;s foreign policy. As pressure mounts, Marcos will need to find a solution that pacifies the domestic support for Duterte while ensuring his own political survival.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Duterte says &#39;kill me, jail me, I will never apologise&#39; for drug war deaths&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Although Marcos might be trying to distance himself from the actions of his predecessor, all the signs are that it is business as usual. In June, Human Rights Watch marked the president&#39;s first year in office with a critical assessment. “Marcos has done little to address the pending human rights issues. Police and their agents continue their &#39;drug war&#39; killings, though at a lower rate than during the Duterte administration,” it noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marcos has preached the rule of law in his high-profile trips abroad, but the reality is that the rhetoric is not supported by facts on the ground. Much-needed foreign investment is also under threat as investors will weigh their environmental, social and governance (ESG) obligations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Closer to home, the Philippines&#39; vacillation over its commitments under international law is also an issue for the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean). To tamp down regional tensions, there has been speculation that a South China Sea code of conduct between China and Asean could answer the territorial concerns of the various claimants. That is all well and good, but the Philippines&#39; exception and revival of its claims under UNCLOS could see China scupper such a deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is an argument that ICC proceedings take years, but that misses the point. International perception that impunity, corruption and a loose relationship with international law are thriving in the Philippines will deny the progress the country and its hard-working citizens so richly deserve.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However tempted Marcos might be by the analogy of the cake, being on the right side of international law will serve him and the Philippines well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>