<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Titan sub search: experts raised safety concerns about missing deep-sea vessel in 2018]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224957/titan-sub-search-experts-raised-safety-concerns-about-missing-deep-sea-vessel-2018?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 11:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/f9d1340a-fea3-455e-baca-cb7b1cd5608b_3f47feba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;专家们在 2018 年对自周日以来失踪的潜水船提出了安全担忧， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;飞行员和四名乘客在船上，船上的可用氧气预计将在美国东部时间星期四早上耗尽（香港时间星期四晚上）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Titan 潜水器是一艘 6.7 米长的船只，由总部位于华盛顿埃弗里特的 OceanGate Expeditions 运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它首先下潜到 4,000 米据该公司网站称，该公司于 2018 年 12 月下潜至 13,100 米（13,100 英尺），并于 2021 年首次潜入泰坦尼克号遗址——大西洋下方约 3,800 米处。该公司计划今年进行 18 次此类潜水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但一些行业专家和一名举报员工担心它的安全性，并表示担心 OceanGate 选择不通过美国航运局（领先的潜水器分级机构）或欧洲集团 DNV 等第三方对泰坦进行认证，一家独立的质量保证和风险管理公司，为水下航行器的设计安全制定标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同行评审小组海洋技术协会 (MTS) 载人潜水器委员会主席 Will Kohnen 在一封信中致辞日期为 2018 年 3 月 27 日，致 OceanGate 创始人兼首席执行官 Stockton Rush，他正在驾驶失踪的车辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着时间和空气的短缺，丢失的泰坦尼克号潜艇的可能结果&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在在信中，Kohnen 表达了他所说的对 Titan 的普遍担忧，Kohnen 说他后来与 Rush 讨论了这封信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们进行了坦率的谈话。这是一次成人谈话。我们同意不同意，”Kohnen 周三在谈及他与 Rush 的电话时告诉路透社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题不是任何单一的设计缺陷，而是 OceanGate 选择不追求潜水器的行业公认认证程序设计、制造和测试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们担心 OceanGate 目前采用的实验方法可能会导致负面结果（从轻微到灾难性的），这将对行业中的每个人造成严重后果，”阅读&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kohnen 说，这封信是在许多潜水专家在为期三天的年度研讨会上表达了对 Titan 的担忧之后发出的。他说他要求 MTS 董事会代表整个社会发送这封信，但董事会拒绝了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我支持这封信以及我们成员的所有担忧情绪，”Kohnen 说. “说‘天啊，我们希望这不会发生’是没有意思的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate、ABS 和 DNV 没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Kohnen 将 Titan 的实验性质通知乘客归功于 OceanGate。 11 月，CBS 新闻播出了一名记者的报道，该记者阅读了他在登上 Titan 之前必须签署的弃权书，该弃权书将其确定为“未经任何监管机构批准或认证的实验性潜水船，可能会导致人身伤害，情感创伤或死亡”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《纽约时报》报道，与船只和其他船只不同，潜水器在很大程度上不受监管，尤其是在国际水域作业时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1 月 18 日, 2018 年，根据 Lochridge 和 OceanGate 当年相互提起的诉讼，OceanGate 员工 David Lochridge 向公司领导转发了一份他撰写的工程报告，该报告对 OceanGate 的 Titan 研发过程提出了批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Lochridge 尤其担心船体使用的材料，以及缺乏对船体进行的测试以衡量其承受深水巨大压力的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;失踪的泰坦尼克号潜艇的老板曾被召唤根据诉讼，他的行业“非常安全”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;公司第二天召开会议讨论 Lochridge 的担忧。在会议结束时，Lochridge 表示他不能接受 OceanGate 的设计决定，并且不会在没有进一步测试的情况下授权任何载人航行。然后他被解雇了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate 于 2018 年 6 月和 7 月对 Lochridge 提起诉讼，指控他与至少另外两人讨论过机密信息。 Lochridge 于 2018 年 8 月提出反诉，否认并声称 OceanGate 的诉讼是为了阻止“举报者提出威胁无辜乘客安全的质量控制问题和安全问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate 做到了不回应置评请求。洛克里奇通过他的律师表示，他不予置评。 Kohnen 说他的信不是基于 Lochridge 的抱怨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate 的创始人 Rush 说安全是“纯粹的浪费”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的意思是如果你只是想成为安全，不要起床，不要上车，什么都不要做，”拉什在 2022 年与 CBS 记者大卫·波格 (David Pogue) 的播客中说。 “在某些时候，你会冒一些风险，这确实是一个风险回报问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bloomberg 的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:50:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China restaurant gas tank blast kills 31, leaves 7 injured]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224962/china-restaurant-gas-tank-blast-kills-31-leaves-7-injured?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 11:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/7508eadf-8a6d-4fee-b784-b919714fcc07_98a199e3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三晚上，中国一家烧烤店发生煤气爆炸，已造成 31 人死亡据国家通讯社新华社报道，宁夏西北部地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消防队员救出了另外 7 名在爆炸中受伤的人，爆炸发生在晚上 8 点 40 分，发生在宁夏首府银川，当时一罐液化石油气发生爆炸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平呼吁“全力”救治伤员。他还敦促调查人员查明事故原因，严惩责任人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据银川市政府官方微信公众号称，爆炸发生时，厨师正在更换煤气罐上的阀门，在工作人员报告闻到泄漏后大约一个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方网站称，应急管理部已派出一个工作组到现场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地党报《宁夏日报》称当地政府已成立一个小组调查爆炸事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自 2019 年 3 月以来中国最致命的一次爆炸，当时江苏省东部的一家化工厂发生爆炸，造成 78 人死亡。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;更多内容……&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Intelligence service warns China is recruiting Canadians on LinkedIn to spy for Beijing unwittingly]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224922/intelligence-service-warns-china-recruiting-canadians-linkedin-spy-beijing-unwittingly?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/0419fd76-2770-4b30-a256-18577091a61e_edcdc51e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“高价值”加拿大人被中国情报人员无意中招募到网上从事间谍活动加拿大国家间谍机构在社交媒体上罕见地发出警告称，针对北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大安全情报局 (CSIS) 提出最新指控之际，该国仍在努力应对大量有关中国干涉的报道。其国内事务——北京一再坚决否认的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部没有回应《南华早报》的询问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Twitter 上发布的帖子中周二晚上，CSIS 详细说明了中国情报人员如何在国内外瞄准加拿大人以获取“机密、特权”信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们识别出正在战略部门积极寻找工作的人或拥有高价值证书的人，”CSIS 说。 “小心你在 LinkedIn 和所有其他在线平台上与谁联系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过伪装成人力资源工作者或招聘人员的中国情报“代理人”网络，加拿大人首先在社交媒体平台上接触，例如CSIS 说，例如 LinkedIn，然后对话转移到第三方平台，如微信或 WhatsApp。然后要求为“顾问”及其“客户”（他们都是中国情报人员）撰写可能包含敏感信息的报告，以换取报酬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“情报人员可能会也可能不会透露他们的真实信息该机构说：“为了保持目标的似是而非的推诿，”该机构表示。 ” 正在进行对涉嫌外国干涉的调查，尽管他没有说有多少与中国有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，一系列泄露的情报报告详述了北京如何据称干预前两个事件，加拿大对此感到震惊。有利于执政的自由党的联邦选举，以及自关闭以来在全国各地运作的“中国秘密警察局”的其他报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京坚称在提出指控时尊重加拿大的内政“出于政治动机”，是“抹黑中国”运动的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加拿大当局指责驻多伦多的中国外交官赵伟帮助中国情报机构恐吓保守党议员 Michael Chong 及其家人。随后，在加拿大驻上海总领事馆工作的 Jennifer Lynn Lalonde 被中国驱逐。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;加拿大前保守党领袖说，中国策划了针对我的运动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;加拿大总理部长贾斯汀·特鲁多 (Justin Trudeau) 继续面临来自反对派立法者和公众的越来越大的压力，要求他处理这些指控。本月早些时候，特鲁多任命的负责调查指控的特别报告员宣布因党派偏见指控而辞职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2018 年加拿大应要求逮捕华为首席财务官孟晚舟以来，中加关系一直紧张美国因欺诈指控而被捕，北京随后以间谍罪名拘留了两名加拿大人——迈克尔·斯帕沃尔 (Michael Spavor) 和迈克尔·康明凯 (Michael Kovrig)。三者均于 2021 年发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好的&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Titanic sub search: as time and air run short, possible outcomes for lost Titan vessel and its 5 passengers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224952/titanic-sub-search-time-runs-short-possible-outcomes-lost-titan-vessel-and-its-5-passengers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 10:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/6f2d019b-3289-4556-a9fc-5552a796fdae_01b8d333.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;寻找失去联系的失踪潜水器的时间很快就用完了周日，母船降落到泰坦尼克号的残骸处，船上有五人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着国际侦察船和飞机舰队在持续的搜救工作中奋勇前进，每一秒的过去都使它不太可能发生泰坦号上的乘客将被发现还活着，因为他们的氧气供应预计将在美国东部时间星期四早上（香港时间星期四晚上）耗尽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使泰坦号位于北大西洋，它如果它卡在泰坦尼克号残骸附近大约 3,800 米（12,500 英尺）的海底，几乎不可能到达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;船上的五人是飞行员 Stockton Rush，他是 OceanGate 的首席执行官，领导探险的公司；英国冒险家哈米什·哈丁； Shahzada 和 Suleman Dawood，一对来自巴基斯坦名门望族的父子；以及法国海底探险家和泰坦尼克号专家 Paul-Henry Nargeolet。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;泰坦号拥有内置安全系统，可在紧急情况下帮助它浮出水面，包括沙袋和铅管可以释放的，还有一个充气气球。该系统被设计为即使船上每个人都失去知觉也能正常工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福特汉姆大学学院教授劳伦斯布伦南说，这将是最好的情况，但即使那样也不一定会有任何幸存者&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰坦的舱门无法从内部解锁，“所以他们必须从外面打开舱门和螺栓，营救里面的人。这是最好的情况，我不确定这是否可能，”曾参与调查和起诉涉及潜艇救援船的案件的退休美国海军上校布伦南说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;据专家称，如果泰坦号被困在海底，船员们最终会耗尽氧气并因极度寒冷而体温过低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nargeolet 已经前往泰坦尼克号残骸 30 多次，在 2019 年的一次采访中向泰坦尼克号海峡解释了被困在另一艘名为鹦鹉螺号的深海潜水器中可能存在的危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那里的氧气足够四五天，但这无济于事，因为他说，届时不太可能提供帮助。海底最大的问题是接近冰点的水温。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一种可能性是被绳索、绳索或网卡住。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一个曾在类似潜水器上工作过的加利福尼亚海洋科学家 Greg Stone 说，海洋中有很多旧渔绳，存在被泰坦尼克号的绳索或电缆缠绕的危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; ，如果它们连接在两端，可以在水中形成一个你甚至都没有意识到的大弧度，”他说。 “我自己也经历过这些，结果被抓住时并不知道它在那里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那种情况下，母船应该有一个遥控潜水器，带有切割器，可以下降并切割线，斯通说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任务飞行员拉什意识到纠缠的危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我最担心的是会阻止我到达水面的东西——悬垂物、鱼网，纠缠危险，”他在去年接受哥伦比亚广播公司新闻采访时说，并补充说，一名优秀的飞行员可以避免这些危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一架加拿大军用侦察机在泰坦尼克号沉船区域，这可能表明至少有人在泰坦上还活着并试图发出求救信号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须保持希望，这是我们作为人类社区正在做的事情的一部分加拿大渔业、海洋和加拿大海岸警卫队部长乔伊斯·默里 (Joyce Murray) 星期三说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国海岸警卫队表示，他们无法说明是什么原因造成了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些声音令人鼓舞，因为无法与水面通信的潜艇船员被教导要敲打船体，以便声纳探测到它们。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“它发出一个信息，表明你可能正在使用军事技术来找到我，我就是这么说的，”潜艇搜救专家弗兰克欧文说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;名誉教授 Jeff Karson 说，这种情况是找到另一艘可以潜到足够深的船只进行救援。锡拉丘兹大学地球与环境科学系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果泰坦号的船体在深处破裂，将意味着在深海的巨大压力下立即死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;泰坦尼克号沉船地点地表以下 3,800 米处的水压大约为 400 个大气压或 6,000 PSI。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，如果发生压力故障，速度会非常快，而且会继续斯通说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚广播公司新闻记者大卫·波格说，泰坦号周日沉没后约 1 小时 45 分钟，该船的两个通信系统停止工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“只有两件事可能意味着。要么他们失去了所有动力，要么船体发生了船体破裂并立即内爆。 Pogue 周二对加拿大 CBC 网络说，“这两种情况都非常绝望。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;定位潜水器的一个问题可能是泰坦尼克号的碎片散布在整个 a 上，有些可能与潜水器本身一样大，Karson 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，潜水器本质上是“那里的另一个肿块”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果它在底部，需要什么才能取回它？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那些东西Brennan 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;用于深海石油钻探的设备可以工作，但该设备可能不在搜索地点附近。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore tenant jailed for trying to strangle landlord over slow Wi-fi]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224953/singapore-tenant-jailed-trying-strangle-landlord-over-slow-wi-fi?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 10:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/18d0822f-1316-4fd0-b5ee-2b644b7a2af3_de39533c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;酒后玩手游时对网速慢很生气六罐啤酒，李信与他的新加坡房东对峙。在不断升级的分歧中，他向这名 61 岁的妇女拔刀，威胁要杀死她的全家，然后试图勒死她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 30 岁的中国公民周三认罪被控一项意图致人死亡的刑事恐吓罪和一项掐住房东脖子致人受伤的罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时在酒店担任管家的李某被判处五个月徒刑&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在量刑时考虑了其他两项类似指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;狭窄、发霉、发臭：一名外籍人士在新加坡寻找一间价值 1,500 美元的房间&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;副检察官（DPP）Ashley Poh在法庭上说，今年5月16日晚上，李某一直在喝酒玩手机，而他的房东林素华则在她的房间里，关着门。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;李在比赛中让林离开她的房间告诉她Wi-Fi速度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在随后的分歧中，他从短裤后面拿出来一把刀刃尺寸为 14 厘米的刀，将 Lin 拉进他的房间，然后将她重重地摔在床上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他们在房间里时，他把刀放回短裤后面。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Lin 安抚了 Li，然后他离开去和另一个房客苏菊说话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此时，Lin 的第三个房客季兆良打电话给 Li，说他已经在楼下等了他两个小时.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lin随即大声质问Ji为什么下班后不回家，让他快点回来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡关押中国男子用手掌上的胶水偷赌场筹码&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李挂断电话后，他回答林关于季延误的询问说：“因为我告诉他我会杀了你所有的家人和你们所有人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种死亡威胁DPP Poh 说，因为 Lin 知道刀在 Li 的短裤后面，导致 Lin 担心自己的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当 Ji 回到家时，Lin 告诉他她与 Li 的分歧。她还向纪暗示李带了一把刀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李对此很激动，将林推到床上并试图勒死她，直到纪介入阻止了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回到房间反锁后，李某仍继续敲门喊她出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到苏某的雇主赶到并报了警，事件才告一段落。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡对“骗”购买250万美元房产的中国男子处以罚款&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;没有律师代理的李先生因一直处于焦虑状态，要求地区法官刘秋雨从宽处理在还押期间，他担心自己会受到惩罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，李在新加坡工作了 10 多年，如果他知道这个城市国家的法律，他会没有冲动行事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因勒死造成伤害，李可能被判处最高三年监禁或罚款 5,000 新元（合 3,730 美元），或两者兼施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任何人犯有导致死亡的刑事恐吓最高可被判入狱 10 年或罚款，或两者兼施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首发于 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will Cambodia’s concerns of ‘rocking China boat’ affect Asean unity over naval drills?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3224917/will-cambodias-concerns-rocking-china-boat-affect-asean-unity-over-naval-drills?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/30585c54-1ec8-4e54-8d09-4a3912e11580_ea46054f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于柬埔寨犹豫不决是否参加有史以来第一次威胁东南亚统一区域范围内的联合海军演习，分析人士表示，即使没有一个或多个国家的参与，演习仍应继续进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚军事总司令尤多·马戈诺最近在巴厘岛举行的东盟国防部长会议后表示，10 -成员地区机构将在南海举行首次联合军事演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演习将以海上安全和救援行动为重点，不涉及作战行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于周二，印度尼西亚军方表示，东南亚国家联盟（东盟）成员已就将于 9 月 18 日至 25 日举行的联合演习举行初步规划会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，此后不久最初宣布后，柬埔寨皇家武装部队总司令 Vong Pisen 将军发布了一份声明，称柬埔寨尚未同意演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，虽然印度尼西亚提出了这个想法，但欧盟轮值主席国柬埔寨和“其他几个国家”（未具名）均未作出回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马尼拉国际发展与安全合作智囊团常驻研究员约书亚·伯纳德·埃斯佩尼亚 (Joshua Bernard Espeña)，他说，柬埔寨对演习犹豫不决，因为它在地缘政治和经济上依赖中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，如果东盟成员国的目标是定期举行海军演习，可以邀请非参与国家的军事代表，因为&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[这是]保持东盟团结一致的信息，”Espeña 说，并指出虽然缅甸同样依赖中国，但由于内部冲突，它不会参加 9 月的会议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼军方已证实内比都拒绝参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2021 年 2 月政变夺权以来，缅甸军政府一直卷入抵抗武装战争&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柬埔寨在援助、贸易和投资方面严重依赖中国，在 1994 年至 2021 年期间，北京占这个东南亚小国外国直接投资总额的 44%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;新加坡 ISEAS-Yusof Ishak 研究所东盟研究中心协调员 Joanne Lin Weiling 表示，柬埔寨对将在南中国海举行的海军演习地点持谨慎态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果林说，他们没有在那里进行“这对柬埔寨来说可能更容易接受”，并指出金边参加了其他东盟演习，例如上个月在菲律宾苏比克湾水域举行的 2023 年东盟多边海军演习。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;雅加达最初表示，9 月份的联合演习将在印度尼西亚纳土纳群岛东北部海域（即北纳土纳海）进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳土纳群岛位于印度尼西亚的专属经济区内，但也属于北京宣称拥有主权的南中国海海域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，雅加达周二表示，目前正计划在南纳土纳海域进行演习，该海域就在北京宣布的九段线之外&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林表示，柬埔寨支持东盟合作，加强东南亚的海上安全，应对共同挑战。林补充说：“只要不激怒其他各方或加剧区域水域的紧张局势，”他指出，对于那些对印度尼西亚的倡议“感到满意”的国家，联合演习应该继续进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提到东盟海岸警卫队论坛由印度尼西亚于 11 月发起，旨在加强海上安全，林说只有八个东盟国家参加，柬埔寨和缅甸没有参与。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其成员国，务实很重要，”林说，并补充说，无法获得所有 10 个东盟成员国支持的倡议可能仍会与最直接参与的成员国一起推进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其他成员国可能”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然东盟的中心地位和团结对于该组织的有效性很重要，但该区域集团只是一个促进合作的政府间组织，Lin 补充道。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“东盟成员国当然不需要与外交或安全政策保持一致，也不需要在涉及该地区大国竞争的其他问题上保持一致，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;亚利桑那州立大学雷鸟全球管理学院副教授 Sophal Ear 表示，柬埔寨的不确定性反映出它不想“与铁定的朋友中国搅局”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何参与的人都是冒犯中国。任何不参与的人都与中国站在一起，”厄尔说，并补充说，如果柬埔寨不参与，东盟的团结和中心地位——“显然不是那么坚如磐石”——将受到破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是Ear 指出，演习应该继续进行，因为参加的国家将改善其海军行动和联合能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;9 月的演习将是自该机构成立以来的首次东盟联合演习成立于 1967 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西苏门答腊安达拉斯大学国际关系讲师 Rifki Dermawan 表示，虽然其他国家也可能出于担心惹恼中国而决定不参加演习，但与他们一起前进将发出一个强烈的信号，表明东盟正在集体保护该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国不是该地区的唯一威胁，”Rifki 说，并指出像 Aukus（澳大利亚、英国和美国）和四方（澳大利亚、美国、日本和印度）已经加剧了紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这迫使东盟计划演习以确保其在该地区的中心地位和相关性Rifki 补充说，这是大国竞争的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Espeña 表示，演习向美国和中国发出了信息，即华盛顿“不能指望东盟联合起来对抗中国”，北京也无法劝阻地区国家放弃&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iseas 的 Lin 指出，大国争端正在加剧，美国和中国都在该地区进行了更多的军事演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括美国与多个东盟国家的“超级鹰之盾”和“金色眼镜蛇”演习、中国与泰国的“猎鹰打击”空军联合训练以及中国与老挝的“友谊之盾”演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安缦友谊-2023（中国、柬埔寨、老挝、马来西亚、泰国和越南之间的和平与友谊 (Peace and Friendship-2023) 演习也计划在今年晚些时候举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自己的平台来促进区域合作，”Lin 说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Dead noisy: sounds of mourning make life hell for China residents who live next door to mortuary]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224615/dead-noisy-sounds-mourning-make-life-hell-china-residents-who-live-next-door-mortuary?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/4745782c-fa45-4f74-84ca-44dcdbc34063_c7f78af4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国太平间兼作灵堂的邻居说他们是被迫的忍受不断的哭泣和哭泣的他们制作了一段他们的困境的视频，以在大陆社交媒体上获得支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在热门视频中，一位来自中国北部河北省石家庄市的焦姓居民为她发声太平间距离她的公寓只有 50 米，这让她感到沮丧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据焦女士说，持续不断的哀号声和哭声使邻居无法打开窗户或无法入睡，造成严重的心理困扰。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“凌晨 4 点，我们被哭声吵醒。然后他们从早上 5 点到上午 11 点播放悲伤的音乐。中午有短暂的停顿，但随后又恢复到下午 5 点，”她告诉《海峡都市邮报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当前的周期已经连续三天进行。但是，一个家庭的葬礼一结束，几天后另一个家庭的葬礼就开始了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;争议延伸到太平间的建设和其他邻居（包括焦）居住的住宅楼。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;焦说她是2008年买的，2019年太平间还没建。不过，太平间发言人称住宅楼是太平间后建的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经通知住户了关于太平间的位置。发言人说，当时应该有购买公寓的补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;噪音已经迫使一些居民搬迁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工作人员表示他们会降低噪音水平&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频在大陆社交媒体上引起强烈反响和讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位网友评论说：“不应该太平间建在火葬场还是医院？为什么要建在路边？抛开迷信不谈，持续不断的噪音非常令人不安！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一人补充说：“如果只是暂时的，也许我能理解。但如果他们建立一个永久性太平间，那必须拆除。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三个人说：“如果一个人在家，他们会被吓死！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据根据中国生态环境部发布的年度报告，在 2021 年收到的 45 万起环境投诉中，噪音干扰占 45%，仅次于空气污染投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为解决这一问题，中国修订了2022 年 6 月颁布的《噪声污染防治法》对居民区附近的噪音扰民处以最高 20 万元人民币（2.8 万美元）的罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，中国中部的一家医院被罚款 5.6 万元人民币屋顶空调噪音过大。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How safe are Hong Kong taxis? Recent incidents raise concerns over quality of drivers, but industry leaders say new measures needed to lure younger workers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224938/how-safe-are-hong-kong-taxis-recent-incidents-raise-concerns-over-quality-drivers-industry-leaders?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/d45058bd-ea10-4460-b33b-c756955c18c6_ce34ca75.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Alex Li can still vividly recall the moment his taxi driver fell asleep and the vehicle almost crashed into a barrier on a Hong Kong road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We were on a highway, but the cabby fell asleep and lost control of the vehicle, which cut across two lanes on its own,” the 36-year-old technician said. “It was really risky.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When they arrived at the destination, luckily unharmed, Lee tipped the driver HK$500 (US$63) and urged him to end his shift immediately and get some rest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a young business executive, who did not want to be identified, the cab dashboards lined with mobile phones providing constant updates on pickup requests is worrying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Sometimes the cabbies start to drive off when the passengers are still getting out of the vehicles, and many drivers have a number of devices on their dashboards,” the 30-year-old woman said. “It looks really dangerous.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concerns over the safety of taxi passengers have increased after two cabbies lost control of their vehicles and drove off the side of the road down a slope last week. The two unrelated incidents occurred on Magazine Gap Road on Tuesday and on Shing Mun Lane on June 14&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this week, a 55-year-old cabby was charged with false imprisonment after he allegedly dropped off a tourist at a Tsim Sha Tsui hotel and drove off with the man&#39;s wife. He allegedly took her to a construction site in Kwun Tong and kept her there for about 30 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, at least three people were injured after a taxi was suspected to have lost control and ploughed into pedestrians at a crossing while driving downhill in Fortress Hill. The 84-year-old driver was arrested on a charge of dangerous driving causing grievous bodily harm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city recorded 3,989 traffic accidents involving 6,600 vehicles in the first quarter of the year, according to the Transport Department. Private cars accounted for 37 per cent of the incidents, followed by taxis at 17 per cent, the most by any form of public transport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Put another way, at least 12 taxis, out of roughly 18,000 in total, get into an accident daily.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tougher health checks on Hong Kong drivers &#39;could spark minibus manpower woes&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Quentin Cheng Hin-kei, a spokesman for commuter concern group the Public Transport Research Team, said he believed the recent cases were isolated incidents, but the city lacked a mechanism to spot drivers who were no longer fit to get behind the wheel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It would be better if each cabby has to come under review regularly for their service quality and would be sent for training or get their licence suspended if they have committed misconduct,” he said. “But the industry has no motivation to do so because of the manpower crunch and the self-employed nature of taxi drivers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow Kwok-keung, chairman of the Hong Kong Taxi and Public Light Bus Association, noted that almost half of taxi drivers were in their sixties, and said age could play a role in the number of accidents. The government has previously pledged to tighten health requirements for drivers over 65.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“An eight-hour shift could be very challenging for senior drivers, but that&#39;s what it takes to earn a living for them,” he said, adding that some drivers worked 10 hours a day. “That&#39;s why we always ask the government to ease the licensing requirement and increase taxi fares, to attract more new blood.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong cabbies want to slam brakes on annual health checks for drivers over 65&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Cabbies earn about HK$20,000 a month on average, and must sit a 45-minute written exam to obtain a licence, correctly answering at least 77 out of 90 questions to pass.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow said the exam was quite difficult for some prospective drivers with less education than other workers, and were not used to sitting tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many multiple-choice questions are quite impractical, like asking the location of certain buildings even though everyone uses GPS to navigate,” he said. “But one has to get 85 per cent of the answers correct to get a licence. That&#39;s definitely not easy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead of going through the exam, younger people with a driving licence would instead join car-hailing services, which offered more flexibility in terms of hours and decent pay for a side job, Chow added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Ryan Wong Cheuk-pong, chairman of the Hong Kong Taxi Council, said the round-the-clock presence of so many cabs on the road was likely a factor in their 17 per cent share of traffic accidents, but stressed passengers were not at greater risk simply because a driver was older.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the statistics, we see most drivers that get into an accident are old, but we should not forget that most taxi drivers in Hong Kong are not young in the first place,” he said. “A simulation experiment we did with Polytechnic University found that senior drivers were indeed safer when driving, compared with the young ones because they knew their physical limits and would properly manage their risks.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said the industry was working to make better use of technology to reduce the risk of accidents, including systems that warned drivers if they strayed out of their lane or were at risk of collisions, as well as devices that alerted drivers if they dozed off.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Already, the government&#39;s Smart Traffic Fund has allowed for some of the devices to be installed in about 1,000 vehicles, but Wong called for more funding to help expand the coverage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also agreed the current exam regime should be relaxed to attract younger drivers, a move that could allow them to screen out those with poor records.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport Department noted all taxi licence applicants had been required to take a course aimed at enhancing driving safety awareness since October 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To attract more new blood, the department has also relaxed the requirements for commercial vehicle driving licences, and adjusted the written exam questions to suit practical needs, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong developers offer huge discounts, cut prices to 2018 levels for new project launches to boost sales]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3224926/hong-kong-developers-offer-huge-discounts-cut-prices-2018-levels-new-project-launches-boost-sales?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/61287feb-a7e5-4a80-baa3-14978737bf7c_40eca4b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Buyers waiting to enter Hong Kong&#39;s property market could be spoiled for choice as some developers release homes at price levels last seen five years ago, looking to lock in sales before further anticipated increases in interest rates and supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Developers are even offering sweeteners like mortgage discounts, dining and travel vouchers to exotic destinations like the Maldives to drum up sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many developers “are rushing to launch at prices close to or even lower than the market price”, said Louis Chan, the Asia-Pacific vice-chairman at Centaline Property Agency. “Ultimately, buyers will benefit.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Chan expects the competitive pricing to attract buyers to the new homes market, “second-hand owners have no choice but to take a beating”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henderson Land Development on Wednesday said it would offer the first batch of 148 flats in the 740-unit Henley Park in Kai Tak at an average of HK$21,088 (US$2,694) per square foot after discounts. The company, however, has yet to announce a launch date for the sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The price is 15 per cent cheaper than leftover stock of new homes in the same district including Henderson&#39;s The Henley, according to Chan.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s weekend home sale sags amid looming supply&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last week after the Hong Kong Monetary Authority hit pause on rate hikes after several rounds of increases since March 2022, CEO Eddie Yue Wai-man warned that the cycle of rising interest rates was far from over.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bank of East Asia on Tuesday said it expected lenders to raise the prime rate by 25 basis points next month due to rising Hibor, which rose to 5.1 per cent on Tuesday, the highest level since 2007, and a tight aggregate balance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the aggregate balance, or liquidity in the banking system falls, it results in higher funding costs for banks to borrow from other lenders, which they then pass on to their customers. The aggregate balance, meanwhile, has fallen to the lowest since 2008, according to Bloomberg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The high interest rate is one of the points we have to address at this moment,” said Thomas Lam, general manager of sales at Henderson, adding that now is the time for buyers to enter the market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the economy picks up in the second half, so will the demand, pushing prices higher, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grand Ming Group on Wednesday priced 30 flats at the 76-unit The Grands in To Kwa Wan at an average discounted price of HK$18,526 per square foot, of which 24 flats are under HK$5 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The starting price of HK$3.79 million for a 231 sq ft unit is the lowest for a new project in Kowloon this year and over 10 per cent cheaper than new launches nearby last year, according to Chan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The developer was concerned about the high interest rates and wanted to offer a competitive price to the buyers, said Shuooky Fung, general manager of sales and marketing, adding that the company “intended to increase the price of the next batch”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;With Hong Kong&#39;s property market reeling, higher rates will dampen mood further&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hip Shing Hong (Holdings) on Tuesday priced the initial batch of 50 units at the 156-unit Oria in Shau Kei Wan at an average of HK$23,042 per square foot after discounts. The price is the lowest for a new project on Hong Kong Island since 2018, according to Centaline&#39;s Chan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prices start at HK$4.79 million after discounts for a 221 sq ft unit. Hip Shing Hong said it set the initial prices low to attract buyers and the price of the next batch would be adjusted accordingly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Oria&#39;s average price, however, is higher than some lived-in projects completed in the district in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, developers and agencies are going all out to offload leftover stock.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Swire Properties on Wednesday said it would offer an extra 5 per cent discount for three flats at Eight Star Street in Wan Chai. The discount, however, is only valid from June 25 to July 31.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mortgage brokers are offering high rebates for Hibor-linked mortgages with a high loan-to-value ratio for the 105-unit Aruna by Chuang&#39;s China Investments in Ap Lei Chau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Centaline said it would give the first 10 buyers of the project in the medical profession and their families travel vouchers totalling HK$1.28 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Midland Realty and Henderson are doling out dining vouchers worth a total of HK$120,000 for the first six buyers of four projects, including The Holborn in Sai Wan Ho.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Property Services said it would give five buyers of The Knightsbridge in Kai Tak travel vouchers for the Maldives totalling some HK$680,000. The project is being developed by a consortium that includes China Overseas and Henderson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The developers&#39; marketing offensive comes after new home sales in May sank 38 per cent to a three-month low of 942, according to Ricacorp Properties. The agency, however, expected transactions to rebound to above 1,000 this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After home prices fell 15 per cent in 2022, developers continue to cut prices, Centaline&#39;s Chan said, adding it would take time for the economy to recover.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US House approves Taiwan trade deal, demands future oversight]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3224948/us-house-passes-first-agreement-taiwan-trade-deal-demands-future-oversight?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 07:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/22/6c27e0fe-02a3-465c-9bb4-0fdb0c2eba23_d9e7cc2d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The US House of Representatives on Wednesday voted to approve the first agreement signed under the US-Taiwan Initiative on 21st Century Trade and to require congressional consultation for future negotiations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement, signed on June 1 under a framework for bilateral talks launched last year, covers streamlining customs procedures, combating corruption and helping small businesses navigate regulatory procedures in both markets. It broadly aims to strengthen the US-Taiwan trade and economic relationship, but does not include any market access provisions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers say the bill, which passed by voice vote and now moves to the Senate, is as much about asserting congressional authority over trade policy as it is about showing support for enhanced economic engagement with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the administration has the authority to negotiate such agreements if they don&#39;t require a change to US law, the political balance between executive decision-making and congressional oversight “is out of whack”, said Clete Willems, a partner at the Washington-based law firm Akin Gump Strauss Hauer &amp; Feld.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Willems said Wednesday&#39;s bill helped fill a void left by the expiration of trade promotion authority laws that guided the administration in negotiating deals. The Biden administration has not asked Congress for such authority, which is required to negotiate trade agreements with market access components.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The legislation was announced earlier this month by bipartisan leaders in the Senate Finance Committee and the House Ways and Means Committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representative Jason Smith, the sponsor of the House bill and chairman of the Ways and Means Committee, said Wednesday: “The relationship between the United States and Taiwan is vital to US interest in the Indo-Pacific.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This initial trade agreement negotiated by the Biden administration is a good step...it shows the world the Chinese Communist Party will not intimidate the United States from deepening our relationship with Taiwan,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Congress is sending a bipartisan message to President [Joe] Biden today that we will not sit idly by as the administration ignores our constitutional role in developing US trade policy,” added Smith, a Republican from Missouri.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US-Taiwan trade initiative signals a shift in approach, analysts say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The bill requires the Office of the US Trade Representative to show any future negotiating texts under the initiative to Congress before sharing with Taiwan or any parties outside the executive branch; provide daily briefings to Congress during negotiating rounds; and share any texts drafted by Taiwan within three days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also requires that future agreements not take effect unless the US president makes the text publicly available 60 days before entering into the deal and a bill approving it is enacted into law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rupert Hammond-Chambers, president of the US-Taiwan Business Council, said the agreement showed that there was “incremental ambition” for greater trade engagement with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It creates some momentum, it creates more ambition,” he said, noting the difference between the Biden administration and the “hostility” to trade agreements with Taiwan displayed under president Donald Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But as ambition continues to expand and more voices enter the fray, Hammond-Chambers said it would become harder for the two sides to conduct engagement through executive action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the absence of a broader consensus on trade and the hostility to free trade agreements in many quarters of the United States, navigating a robust aspirational trade policy toward Taiwan will become more complex,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the desire for a comprehensive free trade agreement may be mixed, Congress has increasingly signalled its desire for the US to step up economic engagement with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both chambers are currently considering a bill authorising the administration to negotiate a tax agreement with Taipei that would offer residents in the US and Taiwan relief from double taxation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s economic hub urged to show ‘dragon’s head’ in investor push as Shanghai seeks global partners]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224907/chinas-economic-hub-urged-show-dragons-head-investor-push-shanghai-seeks-global-partners?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/59ab0266-1930-4e37-847a-16bdaa2fa5f0_f0676946.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Shanghai could be positioned to exert its influence as the “dragon&#39;s head” of China&#39;s economy, amid the city&#39;s new charm offensive to lure global investors, with both the economic hub and nation as a whole struggling to attract multinational companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seen as being at the forefront of China&#39;s bid to regain the confidence of foreign investors since its economic reopening, Shanghai is inviting overseas businesses to invest in high-quality projects through an enhanced “global investment partner” scheme, according to an official readout of a government meeting that took place on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But its allure as a regional hub is decreasing among European companies, with a report by the European Union Chamber of Commerce in China on Wednesday showing that firms with Asia-Pacific headquarters in Shanghai dropped from 40 per cent last year to 33 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The idea of a global investment partner scheme was, in fact, brought up several years ago, but progress has been slow in the past couple of years because of the pandemic and heightened relations between China and the US,” said Shi Lei, a professor of economics from Fudan University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai&#39;s latest move is a further push for the introduction of high-end industries from overseas, as traditional domestic businesses continue to struggle amid a sluggish economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And while China has witnessed regionally unbalanced development in the past few years, Shanghai must exert its influence as the economy&#39;s “dragon&#39;s head”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city needs to expand foreign investment, especially by diversifying its partners, as China is faced with increasing containment efforts from the West, Shi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, via partnerships with the Middle East, Central Asia, and Central and South America, we may gradually shake off the dependence on Europe and North America,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China kicked off a nationwide campaign to lure foreign businesses in March and has rolled out the red carpet for foreign executives, including Tesla CEO Elon Musk, who visited the carmaker&#39;s manufacturing plant in Shanghai at the start of June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an apparent effort to reinforce its position as an international magnet for foreign investment, Shanghai is selecting a series of foreign companies that feature “strong capability, various channels, and standardised practices” to become its global partners, Mayor Gong Zheng said, according to the Shanghai Observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is hoped that this will lead the way for high-quality growth, a notion that China&#39;s top leadership has emphasised in recent years, Gong added, according to the city&#39;s official digital media platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Foreign investors bailed on Chinese bonds to the tune of US$7.2 billion in May&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Officials at the meeting earlier this week also agreed on a three-year action plan through 2025 to build Shanghai into a global hub for exhibitions to introduce a series of industry leaders and cultivate industrial clusters, the platform said without adding further details for both plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The moves follow an exodus of talent and businesses since Shanghai&#39;s two-month lockdown in 2022, while the interest in locating regional headquarters to the city among those who have stayed is falling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Less than 10 per cent of EU chamber&#39;s members who do not currently have their regional headquarters in Shanghai are considering relocating, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Retaining existing multinationals and inviting new investors have been moved high up Beijing&#39;s agenda as it strives to attain a 5 per cent overall economic growth target for China this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China urged to fix &#39;challenging human-to-human aspect&#39; amid talent hunt&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Actual use of foreign direct investment in China in the first five months of the year fell 5.6 per cent in US dollar terms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai will host more than 100 events by the end of the year to attract capital from overseas, the Shanghai Municipal Commission of Commerce said in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is home to 902 multinational corporation regional headquarters and 536 foreign-funded research and development centres, according to the commission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 11 multinational corporation regional headquarters and five foreign-funded research and development centres have been set up this year, the commission added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>