<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China pledges support for peaceful resolution of Palestinian issue amid Abbas visit and ‘profound changes’ in Mideast]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224032/china-pledges-support-peaceful-resolution-palestinian-issue-amid-abbas-visit-and-profound-changes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 14:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/7c9fdada-3e96-4d66-9894-d76c9cb8d8ef_ec68479a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国外交部长秦刚重申中国支持和平解决巴勒斯坦问题他的巴勒斯坦民族权力机构主席马哈茂德·阿巴斯访问了北京，并正值“中东发生深刻变化”之际。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦民族权力机构主席阿巴斯及其代表团周二抵达北京后，秦始皇与巴勒斯坦外交部长里亚德·马利基会面在为期四天的访问开始之际，这是他自 2017 年以来首次访华。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中东局势正在发生深刻变化，加强战略自主、加强团结合作是共同愿望和大势所趋，”秦说，根据中国外交部的宣读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国高度重视巴勒斯坦问题，始终坚定支持巴勒斯坦人民恢复合法民族的正义事业权利。中方将继续支持和谈的正确方向，为解决巴勒斯坦问题贡献中国智慧和中国力量。”沙特阿拉伯和伊朗在中国于 3 月斡旋下达成和平协议七年之后，以及沙特阿拉伯和叙利亚在近十年后恢复外交关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秦说，阿巴斯是沙特阿拉伯接待的第一位阿拉伯领导人今年的中国，他说这是两国政府特殊友谊的标志，也是北京对巴勒斯坦正义事业的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计阿巴斯将在访问期间会见中国国家主席习近平和总理李强。秦表示，他相信习近平和阿巴斯将制定“顶层”计划，并明确推动双边关系迈上新台阶的战略方向。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“微妙的时机”：为什么布林肯的沙特访问是一个&#39;给中国的信息&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据中国外交部的声明，马利基表示巴勒斯坦赞赏中国多年来在巴勒斯坦问题上提出的和平倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还说承诺巴勒斯坦支持中国的“核心利益”，包括“一个中国”政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国是值得信赖和可靠的朋友。巴方高度赞赏习近平主席就巴勒斯坦问题提出的一系列倡议，感谢中方始终坚定支持巴勒斯坦正义事业，在政治和发展领域为巴提供重要支持。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计阿巴斯将寻求中国对巴勒斯坦经济及其在联合国的正式会员资格的支持。据巴勒斯坦媒体报道，在他的访问期间，他还可能寻求中国调解巴勒斯坦与以色列的冲突，该冲突因西岸非法定居点和以色列极端主义官员访问圣地而愈演愈烈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;据巴勒斯坦驻华大使法里兹·迈赫达维 (Fariz Mehdawi) 称，预计两国政府将签署一系列致力于巴勒斯坦发展的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;沙特阿拉伯和中国无视西方的愤怒，承诺建立更密切的关系&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;随着中国在中东和乌克兰加强促和努力，中国在以巴问题上的声音越来越大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秦在不同的电话中重申了中国对以色列和巴勒斯坦的调解提议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在习近平任内就该问题提出了倡议并组织了和谈，但这些努力未能取得实质性成果。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Popular versions of ‘Glory to Hong Kong’ protest song no longer showing on Apple Music]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224034/popular-versions-hong-kong-protest-song-no-longer-showing-apple-music?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/5bbba5de-479a-4b61-ae3d-530fb4d75cbb_5071863c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一首广为流传的抗议歌曲版本在 Apple 音乐流媒体服务上不再显示邮报发现，香港政府寻求法院禁令禁止这首曲子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查结果于周三公布，同一天政府公布了传票和其他文件，呼吁任何人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律政司司长林定国上周一向高等法院申请禁制令，禁止宣传“光荣归香港”，广泛传播被视为由现已搁置的引渡法案引发的 2019 年反政府抗议活动的非官方国歌。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“荣耀属于香港”抗议歌曲将被禁止？政府向法院提交禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;申请消息（法院将于 7 月 21 日审理）使这首曲子重新流行起来。上周，它的各种版本在流媒体服务 Apple Music 上的播放次数最多的歌曲列表中名列前茅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但周三在该平台上搜索这首歌的中文名称时，只显示了该曲调的闽南语录音台湾摇滚乐队 The Chairman，根据 Post 检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将 IP 地址切换到香港以外的位置也产生了相同的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创作者页面下没有显示曲调“ThomasDGX &amp; HongKongers”，之前曾发行过不同版本的歌曲，包括广为流传的粤语版本和器乐版本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创作者对这首歌的各种版本目前仍可通过流媒体播放给香港用户服务 Spotify 和 KKBox，分别位于瑞典和台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮报已联系 Apple 和“ThomasDGX &amp; HongKongers”征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拟议的法院命令针对任何人意图煽动他人分裂香港、煽动煽动或侮辱中国国歌《义勇军进行曲》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该令状要求法院制止那些怀有犯罪意图的人“广播” 、表演、印刷、出版、销售、要约销售、分发、传播、展示或复制”歌曲“以任何方式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府的律师在周一的听证会上告​​诉法庭，禁令不会针对“整个世界”，而只会针对那些“现在正在进行被禁止的行为并打算进行此类行为”的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这首歌在“香港国歌”的谷歌搜索结果中名列前茅，导致在一些国际体育赛事中出现了一系列混淆，在这些赛事中播放的是它而不是“义勇军进行曲”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Google 被阻止了吗？香港互联网提供商对抗议歌曲禁令表示担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法律专家质疑谷歌和其他美国科技巨头遵守未决命令的能力和意愿，而一个代表互联网服务提供商的协会香港互联网服务供应商协会主席 Lento Yip Yuk-fai 早些时候表示，供应商可能不得不阻止城市用户访问某些或&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府周三表示，任何反对申请临时禁制令的人士，可于之前到湾仔分部报案室索取相关文件6月21日，七日内以书面形式提出异议。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Golf Club welcomes offer of land use for coming events but says course must be kept intact to avoid ‘hiccups’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3224033/hong-kong-golf-club-welcomes-offer-land-use-coming-events-says-course-must-be-kept-intact-avoid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/5bb1b744-1052-4070-a0cc-568bbab49e4b_b0cf90f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;独家香港高尔夫球会，必须归还部分城市最古老的球场公共住房政府欢迎该市领导人提出使用该场地举办比赛的提议，但再次对房屋建设计划提出反对意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俱​​乐部队长郭永梁周三表示必须保持球场的质量，以确保赛事组织者不会对香港举办高尔夫赛事的能力失去信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前一天，行政长官李家超曾表示香港仍有能力即使在 32 公顷的粉岭球场被收回后，当局仍“准备好并愿意”在任何施工开始前借出场地举办国际比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们感谢酋长行政人员支持该市继续举办国际锦标赛和大型活动，”郭在城市规划委员会会议上就政府对该场地的提议表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但最重要的是如何保持高质量的场地球场……所以不会出现问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要确保沙特阿美车队系列赛和香港公开赛的组织者相信香港举办比赛的能力保持不变……[所以]国际比赛不会移交给其他城市。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;有争议的在香港高尔夫球场建造房屋的计划下一步会怎样？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港预计将举办沙特阿拉伯支持的沙特阿美石油公司10 月的团队系列赛 (ATS) 活动。但周一 ATS 锦标赛总监警告说，如果设施发生重大变化，它可能会搬到另一个城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港公开赛是男子亚巡赛的一部分，定于 11 月举行。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;该俱乐部在粉岭租用了 172 公顷的土地，表示将与政府和主办方合作，使比赛能够如期举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管政府将收回 32 9 公顷，李在周二指出，俱乐部仍将拥有两个完整的 18 洞球场和第三个球场的 10 洞，这足以举办大型比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但郭重申他反对房屋提案，称土地有多种替代品，而高尔夫球场对香港作为国际体育中心的软实力至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据政府的重建计划，九公顷的土地被指定用于公共住房，其余保留用于保护和娱乐用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如果住房计划继续进行，香港“有可能失去阿美公司系列高尔夫赛事”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;副财政司司长 Michael Wong Wai-伦周三在电台节目中表示，康乐及文化事务署计划将余下的区域用作“被动式公园”，重点是提供开放空间，而不是游乐场和运动场等设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他补充说，国际赛事组织者可以使用该空间作为停车位和帐篷，但没有透露高尔夫球场部分是否会保持原样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名规划官员周一表示，康乐及文化事务署有经验&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但会谘询不同机构，如有需要考虑聘请专业团队维护，强调收回场地不会受损。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Woman in China bans daughter from attending ex-husband’s funeral but demands part of US$133,000 death payout from ex-in-laws]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3223799/woman-china-bans-daughter-attending-ex-husbands-funeral-demands-part-us133000-death-payout-ex-laws?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/0bf7f46d-3d71-4b2e-82f2-17dced763b7a_26705d52.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名妇女禁止女儿参加前夫的葬礼，然后利用女孩向前公婆索要金钱面临社交媒体的强烈反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在拒绝让女儿参加葬礼后，这名姓张的女子出现在前公婆家得知儿子的死亡，他们收到了 943,000 元人民币（133,000 美元）的保险赔付后回家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自中国中部河南省的张女士和她的前夫王姓，几年前离婚，女儿抚养权给了张某，张某后来再婚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年8月，王某因车祸去世，父母悲痛欲绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他们要求张让他们的孙女参加她父亲的葬礼，她拒绝了，并声称正在上小学的女孩因功课太多无法参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她的学习更重要，”据报道，张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在让儿子安息后，王的父母要求对造成儿子死亡的事故负责的司机赔偿。他们与司机和他的保险公司进行了庭外谈判，并同意接受 94.3 万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当张某带着孙女出现在他们家门口，要求三分之一的死亡赔偿金时，他们感到震惊，大约273,000 元（38,000 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇拒绝支付张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纠纷在当地法院结束，法院命令王的父母从赔款中拿出 20 万元给张和让她代孙女留下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该故事在中国网上引发热议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“前妻很恶毒。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;另一个人补充说：“她一定想出了花这笔钱的计划。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她不应该得到那么多钱，”一个人说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:20:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon excludes Chinese e-commerce app Temu from competitive price checks amid allegations of counterfeit goods]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224019/amazon-excludes-chinese-e-commerce-app-temu-competitive-price-checks-amid-allegations-counterfeit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/d152904d-3f15-4727-9ca8-63839a75cc26_346701d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亚马逊将其新竞争对手 Temu 排除在其检查产品是否售出的价格搜索算法之外在其平台上与竞争对手竞争，称该网站不符合其标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据亚马逊的说法，9 月推出的电子商务市场 Temu 不符合其对亚马逊的严格资格要求公平的定价政策。这意味着 PDD Holdings 旗下的 Temu 上的一些低价普通商品可能会超过亚马逊市场卖家提供的价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;定价算法使用自动和手动跟踪方法，检查在和关闭亚马逊，以确保其市场上的商家收取的费用不会明显高于亚马逊竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拼多多和 Temu 的所有者在对中国应用程序进行审查的情况下开设都柏林办事处&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;亚马逊对参与与它认为信誉不佳的竞争对手进行价格战。该公司表示，其资格标准确保其不会将价格与来自可疑市场的商品进行比较或匹配，包括可能是假冒的商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Temu 上销售的大部分商品来自供应商和供应商设在中国。在广告和社交媒体平台上，Temu 宣传从中国运出的家居用品、电子产品和服装的低价，包括 5 美元的连衣裙和 2 美元的化妆刷套装，希望与亚马逊竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Temu 及其驻美国律师 Mandell Menkes 均未回复多条寻求评论的消息。该公司在其网站上声明，它“有严格的政策禁止发布或销售侵犯第三方商标、版权或专利权的产品”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Temu“没有积极参与声明说，“卖家物品的上市和销售”，并且供应商有责任为其商店获得必要的许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚马逊决定无视 Temu 的价格——而不是与他们竞争——凸显了亚马逊的困境亚马逊面临着在保持价格竞争力的同时确保其平台上的产品安全和真实的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可以肯定的是，亚马逊在过去几年中一直在与自己的假冒问题作斗争。这家零售商表示，它已经加大了向执法部门报告假货的力度，并采取了其他措施来追踪和打击假冒产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Temu 的一般商品价值或已售商品总价值已从 2018 年的 1.415 亿美元增加到根据 YipitData 的数据，1 月至 5 月的销售额为 6.348 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有价格具有竞争力的商品的亚马逊商家将面临亚马逊移除其购买按钮（一个使购物者能够轻松购买产品的按钮）的问题，直到亚马逊商家匹配价格他们的竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚马逊通过暂停销售或将其从其市场中移除来惩罚那些被认为价格过高的屡犯者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们看到商店报价的定价做法​​损害客户信任，亚马逊可以删除特色优惠、删除优惠、暂停发货选项，或者在严重或重复的情况下暂停或终止销售特权，”根据亚马逊网站上的市场公平定价政策部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;TikTok 圣诞节想要的只是美国购物者，因为中国应用程序正在挑战亚马逊&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;亚马逊表示，它“每天都在努力为客户提供低价”。然而，如果该公司将价格与特木进行比较，可能会导致大量卖家受到处罚或被迫将价格降至无利可图的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国麦博科技首席执行官王飞翔公司，在接受路透社采访时告诉路透社，他在 Temu 上发现了据称其公司价值 25.99 美元、贴有 FitBeast 标签的健身器材的副本，售价不到 5 美元。当他看到这些产品时，他担心自己会根据亚马逊的公平定价政策受到处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang 在 5 月起诉了 Temu，在美国伊利诺伊州北区地方法院指控 Temu 及其供应商侵犯了他的版权并对其销售造成损害。他的投诉称，在“看到 FitBeast 运动器材的成功”之后，Temu 及其供应商复制并销售产品以窃取其“商业成功”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳康明诚科技，其 Hicober 品牌售价 29.99 美元亚马逊上的超细纤维头巾也在 4 月份提起的诉讼中指控 Temu 侵权。其诉讼称，Temu 有一款类似的头巾，售价为 5.88 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据法庭文件，这些未决的美国诉讼是亚马逊卖家与 Temu 之间的第一批法律纠纷。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:20:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Acclaimed Malaysian filmmaker Amanda Nell Eu talks Tiger Stripes, growing up in UK and ‘feminine monstrosity’ in film]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224025/malaysian-filmmaker-amanda-nell-eu-talks-tiger-stripes-growing-uk-and-feminine-monstrosity-her-films?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 14:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/1687a147-9935-45ad-82e3-4c0147f70e5a_fac8c050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;有一天，他们是欢乐的小束缚，下一个情绪波动的怪物叫做青少年斑点、身份危机和愤怒的海洋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在第一部在戛纳电影节上获得最高奖项的马来西亚电影《虎纹》中，这些青少年怪物不仅长粉刺，而且开始变形和咆哮，长出胡须和利爪，然后逃进丛林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导演阿曼达·内尔·尤坚持认为，这是青春期更真实的一面，她是“女性怪兽”的热情倡导者，她用它来提供一种非常新鲜的形象&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这并不全是美丽的——她是一个怪物，她是野性的，她是暴力和可怕的，但她也是她自己，我们应该庆祝这一点，”Eu 谈到电影中毛茸茸的女主人公时说。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;37 岁的 Eu 想挑战笼罩在青春期的沉默和恐惧，她回忆起自己在马来西亚和英国长大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我觉得很多女孩一旦到了决定性的时刻进入青春期后，他们开始了解羞耻感和不安全感，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我突然对自己的身体非常敏感，我意识到其他人也对它非常敏感，这让我感到非常不舒服。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Tiger Stripes 中，她在一所女子学校跟随三个朋友，以及其中一个来月经时的动态变化，揭露并爆发了这种不适。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;戛纳电影节的第一位马来西亚女导演是如何讲述的朋克赋予女性权力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当她开始出更多汗、闻起来不一样并且需要胸罩时，其他人看她的眼神就好像她很脏，一些女孩模仿社会习俗称她为“妓女”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;但随后影片转向了未知领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女孩掀开她的面纱，露出一个凶猛的怪物，吓坏了她周围的人，但也提供了一种新的解放叙事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我喜欢它的模糊性。她变成了一个生物而不是一个女人，这只会让每个人都更加开放。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eu 的第一部故事片的灵感来自她在马来西亚民间传说中读到的女性怪物 – 以及她的经历在一所女子寄宿学校学习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她有一位英国祖母，11 岁时移居英国，就读于海威科姆的一所学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它可以是最美丽的支持的地方，同时也是最可怕、最孤独的地方，”Eu 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在伦敦的中央圣马丁学习平面设计，但发现她真正的职业是电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她想拍电影，但在英国感觉格格不入，于是搬回了吉隆坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道自己是谁，而且……我找不到我想讲的故事&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，这种局外人的感觉只随着她回到马来西亚，在那里她说话不同，也没有分享同龄人的文化参考。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但简而言之电影激发了她的热情和探索“女性怪兽”的途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;养牛更容易（2017 年）讲述了一个生活在丛林中的青少年吸血鬼的故事，而醋浴（2018 年）的主角是一名堕胎护士，她大吃大喝&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;影片中的主题听起来很恐怖，而另一位女导演朱莉娅·杜库诺 (Julia Ducournau) 在戛纳电影节上大获全胜，而《虎纹》则被誉为模仿法国大片 Raw 的“身体恐怖片” 2021 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在直面复杂问题的同时，活泼的 Eu 并没有把自己或她的电影看得太严肃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望人们轻笑并感到不舒服很奇怪，但也觉得很有趣……我觉得你可以对这些严肃的事情和情绪发笑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新的马来西亚 romcom 展示了一个意想不到的地方的美丽&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Eu 引用 Mean Girls ( 2004 年），好莱坞最下流的青少年电影之一，可以说是 Lindsay Lohan 最精彩的时刻，也是她最喜欢的电影之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Tiger Stripes 中，成年人通常是嘲笑的来源。从远处拍摄，她们反应迟缓，当剧情来袭时毫无头绪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，女孩们经常拍摄强烈的特写镜头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了更深入地了解她们世界，Eu 还结合了女孩们用手机拍摄的镜头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“吸引她们的目光真的很重要，”Eu 在谈到这些女孩在学校厕所里喧闹跳舞、试穿胸罩的镜头时说，还有群体欺凌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕竟，青春期是要打破一切，但也要构建新事物，虽然 Eu 的女主人公逃进了丛林，但这并不是故事的结局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你想为自由而战，那不是你余生的彩虹和蓝天，你需要找到你的社区。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:20:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Putin ponders: should Russia try to take Ukraine’s capital Kyiv again?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224021/putin-ponders-should-russia-try-take-ukraines-capital-kyiv-again?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 13:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/77c29005-00a6-4be7-b519-a4c7297c5e37_d8c0a285.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;总统弗拉基米尔普京表示，任何进一步的动员都将取决于俄罗斯希望在乌克兰战争，并补充说，他面临着一个只有他能回答的问题——俄罗斯是否应该再次夺取基辅？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自普京派兵进入乌克兰 15 个多月以来，俄罗斯和乌克兰军队仍在与尽管距离首都基辅很远，但大炮、坦克和无人机沿着 1,000 公里（600 英里）的前线部署。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京多次使用“战争”一词，向西方发出一连串警告，暗示俄罗斯可能不得不在乌克兰设立“隔离区”以防止其攻击俄罗斯，并表示莫斯科正在考虑放弃黑海谷物交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，俄罗斯不需要全国戒严令并将继续应对违反其红线的行为。普京说，美国许多人不希望发生第三次世界大战，尽管华盛顿给人的印象是它不怕升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他最令人费解的言论是关于基辅的，俄罗斯军队曾尝试过但失败了– 去年 2 月 24 日普京下令军队进入乌克兰几小时后就占领了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们应该返回那里吗？为什么我要问这样一个反问？”周二，普京在克里姆林宫对 18 名俄罗斯战地记者和博主说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰声称在反攻初期取得新进展&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“只有我自己才能回答这个问题，”普京说。俄罗斯国家电视台播放了他在回答问题的几个小时内对基辅发表的评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军队从基辅被击退，最终撤退到普京宣布的乌克兰东部和南部的一片土地上现在是俄罗斯的一部分。乌克兰表示，在所有俄罗斯士兵都被逐出其领土之前，它永远不会罢休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 9 月，普京宣布他所谓的“部分动员”30 万预备役军人，引发至少同样多的俄罗斯人外逃他试图通过前往前苏联各共和国来躲避征兵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及国家电视台战地记者亚历山大·斯拉德科夫的另一次征召时，普京说：“今天没有这样的需要”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;不过，俄罗斯的最高领导人在这个话题上并不明确，他说这取决于莫斯科想要实现的目标，并指出一些公众人物认为俄罗斯需要 100 万甚至 200 万名额外的军人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这取决于我们想要什么，”普京说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然俄罗斯现在控制着乌克兰大约 18% 的领土，但这场战争凸显了曾经强大的俄罗斯的断层线武装部队以及在城市战斗中付出的巨大人力成本，例如在基辅面积二十分之一的东部小城市巴赫穆特。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京表示，这场冲突表明俄罗斯缺乏高精度弹药和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，俄罗斯已经控制了“几乎所有”他称之为“Novorossiya”（新俄罗斯）的地区，这是沙皇时代的帝国术语，指的是现在乌克兰南部的一片地区俄罗斯民族主义者使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰广播公司暂停记者在乌克兰的“亲克里姆林宫垃圾”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;有时使用俄罗斯俚语，普京说俄罗斯不会改变在乌克兰的路线.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯在乌克兰的未来计划，他说，将在他所说的 6 月 4 日开始的乌克兰反攻结束后决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰的攻势在任何地区，普京说，并补​​充说乌克兰的人员伤亡是俄罗斯的 10 倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，乌克兰已经损失了超过 160 辆坦克和 25-30% 的来自国外的车辆，而俄罗斯损失了 54 辆坦克。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二早些时候，普京的国防部发布了一段视频，显示据称是从乌克兰军队缴获的一辆豹 2 坦克和一辆布拉德利战车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该部是俄罗斯士兵在扎波罗热激战后拍摄的视频。目前无法立即核实视频的真实性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰方面表示，它在反攻中取得了进展。最近几天，基辅声称已经夺回了其东部顿涅茨克地区的一系列村庄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;交战双方的声明无法得到独立核实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京进一步表示，乌克兰已经6 月 6 日，他故意用美国提供的 HIMARS 火箭弹袭击 Kakhovka 水电站大坝，他说此举也阻碍了基辅的反攻努力。乌克以乌克兰为榜样宣布戒严。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有理由在该国引入某种特殊制度或戒严。今天不需要这样的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社和美联社补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft’s Activision acquisition temporarily blocked by US judge as FTC challenge awaits hearing in court]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224012/microsofts-activision-acquisition-temporarily-blocked-us-judge-ftc-challenge-awaits-hearing-court?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 12:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/25cd9809-6446-4f50-bf2d-d4a388ab2761_915e7c6e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名美国法官周二晚些时候批准了联邦贸易委员会 (FTC) 的临时请求阻止微软公司收购视频游戏制造商动视暴雪，并安排下周举行听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国地区法官爱德华·达维拉 (Edward Davila) 计划于 6 月 22 日至 23 日就 FTC 的初步禁令请求举行为期两天的证据听证会旧金山。如果没有法院命令，微软最早可能在周五完成这笔价值 690 亿美元的交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责执行反垄断法的美国联邦贸易委员会 (FTC) 在 12 月初要求一名行政法官阻止该交易。行政程序中的证据听证会定于 8 月 2 日开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国不顾美国和英国的反对，批准了微软与动视暴雪的交易&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据 6 月下旬的听证会，联邦法院将决定是否有必要发出初步禁令——该禁令将在案件的行政审查期间持续有效。美国联邦贸易委员会周一寻求临时禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达维拉表示，周二发布的临时限制令“对于在申诉悬而未决期间维持现状是必要的，(并)保持本法院下令有效救济的能力如果它确定初步禁令是必要的，并保留 FTC 在其未决行政诉讼中胜诉的情况下获得有效永久补救措施的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Microsoft 和 Activision 必须提交反对初步禁令的法律论据6 月 16 日前发出禁令； FTC 必须在 6 月 20 日做出答复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Activision 周一表示，FTC 寻求联邦法院命令的决定是“一个受欢迎的更新，它加快了法律程序”，周二拒绝发表评论。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;微软周二表示，“加速美国的法律程序最终将为游戏市场带来更多选择和竞争。在我们收到法院的裁决之前，临时限制令是有意义的，法院正在迅速采取行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国联邦贸易委员会拒绝置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Davila 表示关闭的限制将保持不变in place until at least five days after the court rules on the preliminary injunction request.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The FTC has argued the transaction would give Microsoft&#39;s video game console Xbox exclusive access to Activision games, leaving Nintendo consoles and Sony Group Corp&#39;s PlayStation out in the cold.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Microsoft&#39;s bid to acquire the Call of Duty video game maker was approved by the EU in May, but British competition authorities blocked the takeover in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Microsoft has said the deal would benefit gamers and gaming companies alike, and has offered to sign a legally binding consent decree with the FTC to provide Call of Duty games to rivals including Sony for a decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case reflects the muscular approach to antitrust enforcement taken by the administration of US President Joe Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Qin Gang calls for US to ‘show respect’, stop undermining China’s interests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224016/qin-gang-calls-us-show-respect-stop-undermining-chinas-interests?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 12:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/36d4b616-99af-40fd-a2dc-27daa3a50a2d_87f701dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The United States should “show respect” and stop trying to undermine China&#39;s sovereignty, security and development interests, Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qin made the remarks in a phone call with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Wednesday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I hope that the US side will take practical actions to implement the important consensus of the meeting between the two heads of state in Bali, move in the same direction as the Chinese side, effectively manage differences, promote exchanges and cooperation, and promote the stabilisation of China-US relations,” Qin said, according to a Chinese foreign ministry readout of the phone call.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the latest high-level engagement between Beijing and Washington in recent weeks, following US calls to improve ties that further deteriorated after an alleged Chinese spy balloon was shot down over US airspace in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two sides had said bilateral relations should be improved during a Bali summit between Chinese leader Xi Jinping and US President Joe Biden in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken was reportedly expected to travel to China for talks this Sunday but it is not clear if the trip will go ahead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow …&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s rise as ‘world’s back office’ in spotlight as service sector booms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3224005/indias-rise-worlds-back-office-spotlight-service-sector-booms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 13:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/b1856d47-3818-48bf-8b9b-2a4c9b9b840a_f5e9fd68.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;On the eastern side of Bangalore, the city that&#39;s sometimes called the Silicon Valley of India and is officially known as Bengaluru, sits a campus housing three cube-like glass buildings. Each is 10 storeys high, with facades glistening in the strong South Asian sun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These are the offices of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., home to about 8,000 workers, the bank&#39;s largest venue outside New York. When Goldman set up in the city in 2004, it had roughly 300 people mainly providing IT and other support. Now, its workers are quantitative analysts and software engineers, building systems for everything from making trades to managing risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Across India, the offices set up by multinationals to provide cheap operational support are taking on more sophisticated roles. While the shift has been under way for years, recent economic data highlight a rapid service-sector expansion that many attribute to the offices known as global capability centres.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These GCCs now account for more than 1 per cent of India&#39;s gross domestic product. But the boom also creates challenges, both for the companies and the cities that host them. Finding qualified employees is becoming more difficult, pushing salaries up, while offshoring may become politically sensitive again in the US presidential race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Over the last 30 years, while China specialised in becoming the world&#39;s factory, India specialised in becoming the world&#39;s back office,” said Duvvuri Subbarao, a former governor of the Reserve Bank of India. “Over the years, India moved up the value chain,” he said. But it can&#39;t “take its comparative advantage for granted.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India has roughly 1,600 of the centres, more than 40 per cent of the number worldwide, according to Nasscom, a trade body for the country&#39;s technology industry. Dotted around Bangalore are the offices of luxury retailer Saks Fifth Avenue Inc., aircraft-engine maker Rolls-Royce Holdings Plc, US bank Wells Fargo &amp; Co. and Japanese e-commerce firm Rakuten Group Inc. Some 66 global companies set up their first GCC in India last year. Even the lingerie brand Victoria&#39;s Secret &amp; Co. has a Bangalore GCC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offices generated about US$46 billion in combined revenue in the financial year ended March, more than the output of Nepal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The qualities that turned India into the world&#39;s back office starting decades ago are propelling GCCs&#39; metamorphosis: a vast pool of young people, an education system that emphasises science and technology, and the lower staffing costs that made India attractive in the first place. Add an unforeseen catalyst: the pandemic, which convinced decision-makers jobs can be done anywhere, including far-flung shores.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Far from dying, a new globalisation is emerging – driven by China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“India&#39;s story starts with its demographics and its talent,” said Gunjan Samtani, the country head of Goldman Sachs Services Pvt, the entity that operates the bank&#39;s GCCs in India. A software engineer by trade, he still codes from time to time. “What brought us here even two decades back was our ability to get access to technology and talent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, a mysterious surge appeared in the country&#39;s economic data. Services exports rose to a record for December, leading economists to speculate why. The trend continued. They climbed to about US$323 billion in the financial year ended March, up 27 per cent from the year before. Analysts reached the same conclusion: it was the GCCs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global capability centres have been driving the exuberance in services exports, Pranjul Bhandari, HSBC Holdings Plc&#39;s chief economist for India and Indonesia, and colleagues wrote in a report in March, calling it a “meaningful” shift in India&#39;s economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its significance went beyond the boost in output. The increase helped narrow the country&#39;s current account deficit, which in turn could support a rupee that&#39;s been depreciating for years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was an important moment for a business that&#39;s been in the making for decades. Global capability centres trace their roots to the 1980s, when Texas Instruments Inc. established a facility in Bangalore. India took off as an outsourcing hub in the 1990s, when airlines, technology companies and firms including American Express Co. and General Electric Co. set up centres in the country. The facilities took over business processes including accounting, payroll and customer support, with lower labour expenses allowing companies to cut costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The multinationals soon saw they could use their India offices for more than back-office functions. Today, they often handle core operations, such as inventory management or purchasing, while also using AI and other advanced technologies to improve how businesses run.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Retailer Target Corp. is working on new systems for order collection and shipping. At Goldman, engineers have helped develop a trading system called Atlas for quant clients with latency in microseconds. They&#39;ve also expanded a commodities platform called Janus, which provides data analytics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The conversation has changed completely,” said Sindhu Gangadharan, senior vice-president and managing director of SAP Labs India Pvt. Cost is “a beautiful advantage that we have, but that&#39;s not the conversation starter like it was 20 years back.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SAP Labs India is now responsible for almost 40 per cent of software firm SAP SE&#39;s global research and development and a quarter of its patents annually, Gangadharan said. Goldman&#39;s GCCs carry out more than 120 global functions across engineering and business operations. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. employs more than 50,000 people at GCCs in five locations across India, in areas including quant research, data science and cloud computing. GCCs “are now following a very different path,” said Lalit Ahuja, the founder and chief executive officer of ANSR Inc., a consultancy that has helped clients establish more than 100 of the centres in India. He says he sets up two every month and has never been busier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pandemic changed everything by making remote work more acceptable, Ahuja said. The industry came of age in the last few years, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of India&#39;s biggest attractions is its supply of workers. In April, it overtook China as the world&#39;s most populous country. It&#39;s now home to almost one-fifth of humanity, and more than half its population is under 30, with a median age of 28. That compares to 38 in both the US and China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a nation obsessed with education, many parents want their children to take subjects that will help them get good jobs and careers. Some 34 per cent of students study science, technology, engineering or mathematics at university, the highest among major economies, according to Unesco Institute for Statistics data.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indian startups had US$1 billion in the collapsed Silicon Valley Bank&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;And these days, India&#39;s thriving start-up scene is also a boon for companies setting up GCCs and seeking people to hire. India has about 90,000 start-ups, the third-biggest number of any country in the world. But the surge in GCCs is making it harder to find employees and creating a need to pay them more. Companies are forming ties with academia to develop hiring pipelines. SAP Labs India has a partnership with engineering school Birla Institute Of Technology and Science, Pilani. Goldman runs an annual contest called GS Quantify for students to find solutions to real-world financial problems. Samtani says the bank gets job applications from more than 1,100 campuses in 20 states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The war for talent definitely exists,” SAP Labs India&#39;s Gangadharan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even before competition for staff intensified, companies needed to spend much time training new hires, according to Dileep Mangsuli, executive director and head of the development centre at Siemens Healthineers AG, a medical-technology company involved in imaging and diagnostics, which now does half its software and digital-services R&amp;D in India. Good jobs exist in the country, but the booming education industry often doesn&#39;t adequately prepare people to do them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The employability of new graduates “is still a challenge,” he said. “Till they&#39;re trained and retrained and many times trained, they don&#39;t become employable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As GCCs use more advanced technologies, they&#39;re also finding it harder to find staff. An example is artificial intelligence. India has about 416,000 AI workers, far short of the more than 1 million it will need by 2026, according to Nasscom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Making the most of India&#39;s demographic advantages “will require significant investments and government attention,” said Partha Iyengar, the country leader for research at Gartner Inc. in India. Only 30 to 40 per cent of graduates in India are employable, he estimates. “Not enough attention is being given to this, given the massive scale of intervention required,” he said. “If that is not done on a war footing, the demographic dividend can very easily and quickly turn into a demographic disaster.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The boom is also adding to challenges for India&#39;s cities, especially Bangalore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Home to about 30 per cent of the country&#39;s GCCs, India&#39;s tech capital is constantly congested. As work continues on expanding the metro system, large stretches of the city are dug up, resulting in long traffic jams. Last year, torrential rain caused floods across key roads, forcing chief executive officers to ride to work on tractors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;India: an economic miracle still waiting to happen&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Multinationals are setting up in other places. Hyderabad, a city of more than 10 million people about 570km north of Bangalore, is emerging as a popular location. Goldman opened its second India GCC there in 2021 with a focus on consumer-banking services and business analytics. Pune, about 150km southeast of Mumbai, is another favoured destination, as are some areas near New Delhi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another risk is that Donald Trump will revive his campaign against offshoring of jobs as he runs for president again in 2024. Data sovereignty – another argument for keeping jobs at home – could also become an issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, Nasscom estimates India will have at least 1,900 GCCs by 2025, and annual revenue from the industry will increase to as much as US$60 billion. “India can overcome the geopolitical challenges because such a large talent pool is not available elsewhere,” said KS Viswanathan, the trade body&#39;s vice-president of industry initiatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Goldman, Samtani shares the optimism. He points out the bank had one managing director in the city in 2004. Today, in Bangalore and Hyderabad, 58 people have reached the coveted rank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If India is not part of the talent story for any firm globally, they&#39;re missing something,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong confident about attracting 6,300 mainland Chinese workers for airport but long commute could be a ‘challenge’, official admits]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3224013/hong-kong-confident-about-attracting-6300-outside-workers-airport-long-commute-could-be-challenge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 13:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/b6238ef4-193b-4816-9123-5e91111d5ebb_598dcbc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Plans to bring in 6,300 workers from mainland China to fill vacancies at Hong Kong airport have yet to be tested by reality amid a commuting “challenge” and competition from other cities, a government minister has acknowledged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government on Tuesday unveiled special schemes to bring in up to 20,000 non-local workers for the construction, transport and aviation sectors through expedited processes that bypass vetting by union leaders and other members of the Labour Advisory Board.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Airport firms can hire up to 6,300 outside workers and most are expected to make daily commutes from the mainland using the Hong Kong-Zhuhai-Macau Bridge, unlike imported construction staff who will live in quarters provided by employers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will importing 20,000 workers fix Hong Kong&#39;s labour woes?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Non-local workers will be allowed to fill 10 types of roles at the airport, including customer service agents, ramp operators, maintenance technicians and cabin cleaners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy Financial Secretary Michael Wong Wai-lun told a radio show on Wednesday that while requiring workers to make long commutes across the bridge “would be a challenge”, he said previous schemes had proved the city&#39;s offers were attractive to mainland jobseekers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is certainly confidence as the pay in Hong Kong is higher than similar roles on the mainland, but we can find out only in reality how much interest mainlanders have to work in Hong Kong,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong also ruled out housing airport workers at former quarantine facilities in Sunny Bay on Lantau due to “contractual term restrictions” with the adjacent Disneyland resort that he did not elaborate on.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong set to bring in 20,000 workers to help ease labour crunch&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Employers will be required to pay imported workers no less than the median wage of their equivalent local counterparts under the special schemes. Wong said the monthly salaries of the jobs covered by the scheme could reach about HK$20,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said it was important to fill the manpower gap as foreign airlines looking to resume services had been turned away or even chose to fly to nearby airports as staff shortages were restricting capacity locally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said the quota of 20,000 workers was only equivalent to about half of the manpower gap reported across the sectors covered by the schemes, as the government still hoped locals would fill the remaining vacancies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Labour and Welfare Chris Sun Yuk-han also told a radio show that although the city would be competing with Macau for mainland workers based in Zhuhai, which borders the casino hub, he was confident Hong Kong would get sufficient workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The overall size of the mainland&#39;s workforce is so large that I believe the extra demand from Hong Kong can be met,” Sun said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government said applications for importing labour under the schemes would be accepted from July and that it expected to grant approval within two months.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>