<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Latest China satellite Ludi Tance to survey one-third of Earth in high-orbit breakthrough]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3231313/latest-china-satellite-survey-3rd-earth-high-orbit-breakthrough?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 19:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/bf46f6d8-540a-466b-a9f4-4fbb626b262f_39a30e4c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国将拥有近三分之一地球表面的永久视野，世界首颗地球同步轨道合成孔径雷达卫星发射升空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京时间1时26分，民用鲁地坦斯4-01号搭载长征三号乙运载火箭离开西昌发射中心。据其开发商中国航天科技集团公司 (CASC) 称，周日，这颗卫星预计将爬升至约 36,000 公里（22,370 英里）的极高轨道，在那里它将持续监测亚洲- 太平洋地区的分辨率约为 20 米（65 英尺）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CASC 表示，Ludi Tance（翻译为土地勘探）卫星将提供“对中国及周边地区的全天、全天候观测” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该卫星还将用于满足海洋、气象、农业、林业等行业的应用需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该卫星还将用于满足海洋、气象、农业、林业等领域的应用需求。 p>;&lt;h3>;中国的ASO-S卫星升空，近距离观察太阳喷发&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与在可见光和近红外波段工作的光学遥感卫星不同，SAR卫星使用微波信号来创建图像通过向地球发送能量脉冲并测量它们返回所需的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于 SAR 卫星可以穿透云层、雾气和黑暗来日夜收集图像，因此许多国家在低地球轨道上使用 SAR 卫星各国监测地震、洪水、森林砍伐、石油泄漏以及军事监视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年初，中国向约 600 公里的轨道发射了两颗鲁地坦斯 1-01 卫星 - 嗯在 2,000 公里的低地球轨道范围内 - 监测山体滑坡、地震和其他地质现象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每个重约 3.2 吨，配备先进的 SAR 有效载荷，天线总面积为 33 平方米（355平方英尺），工作在L波段，信号波长约为23厘米（9英寸）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新卫星的发射符合中国2015-25中和民用航天基础设施中长期发展规划，其中列出了鲁迪坦斯系列卫星和高轨SAR技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该规划，中国还将建设高中分辨率光学和SAR星座用于陆地、海洋和大气监测。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为了与埃隆·马斯克的星链竞争，中国在太空测试新的太阳能翼技术&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国航天科技集团表示，Ludi Tance 4-01 – 第一个高-同类轨道卫星已进入实施阶段 - 也在 L 波段工作，在森林地区提供更大的穿透力，以便雷达信号与大树枝和树干之间有更多的相互作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stephen Hobbs，英国克兰菲尔德大学空间系统和传感器教授表示，该卫星的 20 米（65 英尺）空间分辨率“对于地球同步雷达来说实际上相当不错”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它应该能够观测到细微的变化、山体滑坡和地震引起的毫米级地面运动，这是一种强大的测量能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据霍布斯的说法，如此高的轨道的一个缺点是信号会因距离而减弱移动，使得很难解析超过几十米的特征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地球同步轨道的主要优势是在大陆尺度上永久观察地球——大约占地球表面的30% – 这样就可以用一颗卫星快速重复观察特定区域。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开发地球同步SAR卫星的一个主要挑战是长距离，这会导致信号微弱。霍布斯说，需要高发射器功率、大型天线和相对较长的信号积分时间来弥补这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有这些都是技术挑战，可能会使这些任务更加昂贵或效率较低。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然有关卫星配置的细节很少被公布，但霍布斯表示，该设备可能有一个 20 米宽的圆形可展开天线，比 Ludi Tance 1-01A 和 1- 上使用的天线大得多。 01B.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京填补卫星空白，密切关注有争议的南中国海&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;霍布斯表示，Ludi Tance 4-01 还可能配备 10-20 平方米的太阳能电池板，以产生几千瓦的电力，因为雷达卫星通常需要高电力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍布斯与北京理工大学的科学家合作开发了地球同步雷达的概念，他说一些早期研究是在美国，但自 2005 年以来，在该技术方面几乎没有发表任何工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他正在领导一个欧洲科学家团队设计一项名为 Hydroterra 的任务，该任务将使用地球同步 SAR 卫星来产生欧洲和非洲天气和地表快速变化的第一张连续图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hydroterra 概念将被提议作为欧洲航天局第 12 次地球探索任务的候选方案，以了解地球的系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;它将与大约 20 项其他任务竞争，如果成功，可能会在 2030 年代进入轨道——根据霍布斯的说法，至少在中国任务十年后。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div >;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese cryptocurrency mining firm charged with running pyramid scheme, as Beijing maintains tight grip on virtual assets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3231289/chinese-cryptocurrency-mining-firm-charged-running-pyramid-scheme-beijing-maintains-tight-grip?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/8906d199-8c83-4fda-9818-8576dadc51ba_839e7c47.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着香港加大力度成为虚拟资产中心，中国大陆仍然是坚决打击加密货币相关活动，地方当局最近起诉了该国最大的 Filecoin 矿工之一，罪名是传销。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广西南部自治区屏南县的检察官给予了严厉打击Filecoin 挖矿公司深圳时空云科技的四名高管被指控组织和领导传销，涉及金额超过 6 亿元人民币（8300 万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时空云“夸大”了经济模式和投资潜力据当地检察官在平南法院最近审理此案后发表的一篇博客文章中称，该公司在其 Filecoin 项目中采用了分布式存储技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，从 2 月份开始，该公司在其平台上注册了近 10 万名会员。从2021年到去年5月，时空云骗取了6.069亿元人民币和近3200万个与美元1:1挂钩的稳定币Tether（USDT）代币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官指控时空云要求成员购买或租赁其采矿设备。这些成员还通过为该公司的计划开发新参与者而获得回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司通过以高额回报引诱人们诈骗钱财，检察官将其描述为扰乱社会经济秩序的严重刑事犯罪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对四位时空云高管的指控突显了自 2018 年中国禁止比特币和其他数字代币的金融交易以来，中国大陆对加密货币的持续监管敌意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的起诉是在几年后发生的中国政府内阁国务院于 2021 年 5 月宣布打击加密货币挖矿。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的打击行动迫使加密货币矿工逃往新加坡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Filecoin 是一种在去中心化平台上运行的加密货币用代币奖励存储提供商的存储网络。它由去中心化文件共享网络星际文件系统 (IPFS) 的创建者 Protocol Labs 于 2017 年推出，这是一种在中国大陆拥有活跃追随者的 Web3 技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国的一些人也使用IPFS 共享禁书等非法文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时空云并不是第一个在北京对加密货币相关活动进行严格审查的情况下与中国当局发生冲突的 Filecoin 矿工&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 12 月，据报道，Filecoin 挖矿和存储服务提供商 RRMine 的高管在四川省省会成都被警方带走接受调查。去年 9 月，该公司表示，由于“大陆对加密货币使用的严格限制”，已将总部迁至新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国加密犯罪的范围暴露了资本管制漏洞&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;中国当局也对与加密货币相关的犯罪保持警惕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山西省北部警方上个月逮捕了 21 人，罪名是使用美元稳定币洗钱 3.8 亿元人民币。去年 9 月，中国北部内蒙古地区警方逮捕了 63 人，罪名是通过 USDT 洗钱 120 亿元人民币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些案件突显出，尽管北京方面禁止，但加密货币的使用仍在该国持续存在。倒闭的交易所 FTX 的破产申请显示，其 8% 的客户来自中国。在区块链研究公司 Chainaanalysis 的 2022 年全球加密货币采用指数中，中国大陆也排名第 10 位，高于 2021 年的第 13 位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民银行与其他九个政府部门和监管机构于 2021 年 9 月联合发布宣布该国所有加密货币交易都是非法的。他们声称这种贸易扰乱了经济和金融秩序，是犯罪活动的滋生地。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法院首次裁定加密货币是香港的财产&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京，已批准香港当局将香港发展成为加密货币中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 10 月大力推动虚拟资产行业发展后，香港随后制定了零售交易规则&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，本地加密货币公司 HashKey Group 和 OSL 获得监管机构的批准，可以为散户投资者运营香港首家持牌加密货币交易所。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hungry Ghost Festival: Hong Kong brings back largest annual event after 3-year hiatus, introduces AI-chatbot to draw younger crowd]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231315/hungry-ghost-festival-hong-kong-brings-back-largest-annual-event-after-3-year-hiatus-introduces-ai?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 20:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/9d200b39-6d7c-4073-a09f-a676030318d1_aa0cafef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港最大规模的中元节庆祝活动时隔三年回归并包括人工智能（AI）聊天机器人和角色扮演游戏等创新活动，以吸引年轻游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港潮人社团总会周三表示，该活动将举行九月初在维多利亚公园举行，希望城市的年轻一代能够参加，以更多地了解这个节日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望盂兰文化节活动能够将当下的元素与我们的传统习俗结合起来“通过利用创新科技和流行文化，将能够吸引年轻人了解我们的文化。”该组织副总监胡炎忠表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中元节兰节发生在农历七月，庆祝活动在这段时间达到高峰。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;避免“借用”雨伞以及其他中元节注意事项&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;这个节日的基石是通过仪式来祭祀祖先，并在街上烧祭以安抚游荡的灵魂，因为这个时期传统上被视为灵魂在现实世界中漫游的短暂窗口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个节日也受到当地潮州社区的高度重视，潮州社区的根源可以追溯到中国大陆广东省。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该联合会于 2015 年推出的年度活动自 2019 年以来一直没有举办，原因是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴周三表示，组织者决定今年引入更多创新元素，并承认念经和潮剧表演等传统活动可能对一些参与者没有吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;新活动包括由人工智能生成软件 ChatGPT 3.5 提供支持的节日聊天机器人和真人角色扮演游戏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该软件被称为“玉兰机器人 ChatGPT”，是经过修改的人工智能组织者表示，他们希望该工具能够帮助参与者更深入地了解这一活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴不顾对此类软件可靠性的担忧，并表示聊天机器人的主要目的是引发有关节日的讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望人们体验聊天机器人给出的答案。之后，我们会进行一些互动，人们会问‘这些答案正确吗？’”他说。 “他们会问我们并试图了解更多，所以我们正在努力创造这样的环境。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港中元节该做什么、不该做什么，以及哪里出了问题&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;吴还承诺为参加活动角色扮演游戏的人提供身临其境的体验，该游戏将采用增强现实元素，以及供玩家使用的脚本和待解决的谜题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A他补充说，较长版本的剧本将提供给那些预订了游戏时段的人，而未预约的玩家则可以玩较短的剧本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴表示，这些游戏旨在培养诸如给予和接受的行为以及业力概念等价值观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去活动的亮点也将回归，包括广受欢迎的幽灵格斗比赛，参与者相互竞争，以赢得胜利。他说，用手持式漏斗形工具捕获尽可能多的“祭品”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific to offer 100,000 discounted tickets, reveals nearly HK$293 million in dividends paid to government]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3231306/hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-offer-100000-discounted-tickets-reveals-nearly-hk293-million-dividends?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 18:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/83b477c3-6004-40a6-8ee9-91952d7c94f3_55561f47.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国泰航空将于 2019 年 12 月起提供 100,000 张飞往世界各地城市的经济舱折扣机票周四，这家香港旗舰航空公司表示，同时还透露，它已向政府支付近 2.93 亿港元（3745 万美元）的股息，用于在大流行期间购买的优先股。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;折扣机票将涵盖该航空公司表示，明年 1 月至 6 月期间将开通 34 个目的地，包括台湾高雄、东京、首尔、伦敦、悉尼和芝加哥。服务时间为周四下午 2 点至 8 月 30 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司周三还透露，已于周一向政府支付了 195 亿港元优先股所欠股息 2.925 亿港元，这是继该公司第二次支付股息后6 月底支付的 15 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府收购了优先股（投票权受限的股权），作为 2020 年商定的 390 亿港元资本重组计划的一部分，当时该航空公司正努力维持下去在全球旅游市场崩溃的情况下，国泰航空仍能维持生计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空上周公布 2023 年上半年净利润为 42.6 亿港元，此前连续三年亏损总计 337 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该公司还承诺将在今年年底前回购一半向政府发行的优先股。其表示，其余部分将在 2024 年 7 月底前收购，具体取决于拟议的资本削减完成情况和当时的业务状况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了其廉价航空香港快运之外，国泰集团还拥有更多其补充称，自2020年初疫情爆发以来，单月旅客吞吐量首次突破200万人次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“7月份是传统的夏季旅客出行高峰的开始，我们非常国泰航空首席客户兼商务官 Lavinia Lau Hoi-zee 表示：“很高兴看到需求强劲。” “随着七月中旬学校假期的开始，对亚洲各地热门短途目的地的需求大幅增加。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;招聘计划可以帮助香港国泰航空“竞争中国大陆旅行” &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该航空公司上个月载客量为 174 万人次，与去年同期的 219,746 人次相比，增长了近 700%。最新的载客率（衡量航空公司填补可用座位的情况的指标）为 89%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau 表示，两家航空公司“现在接近”大流行前客运航班的 60%能力水平。该集团的目标是在今年年底前将这一数字提高到 70%，并在 2024 年底前完全恢复水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空预计强劲的需求将持续到本月剩余时间，并且已她表示，增加了飞往北美、欧洲、日本和东南亚航线的运力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在货运方面，Lau 表示，预计夏季剩余时间货运量将保持平稳，但从第三季度末，传统的高峰期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国泰航空改进“亚洲万里通”计划，部分机票价格上涨近 30%&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为资本重组计划的一部分，国泰同意每六个月向政府支付股息，利率逐渐提高，直至赎回所有优先股。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前三年股息利率为3%，以后为5%。今年8月，12个月后将升至7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中文大学亚太商学院名誉研究员、经济学家李少波表示，优先股有累进股息&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“逆风方面，随着越来越多的航班恢复，机票价格将会下降，收益率也会下降。运营成本也在增加。”Lee 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;航空公司指出，机场工作人员的缺乏是恢复正常业务花了这么长时间的部分原因。业界领袖表示，首批近2,900名外劳预计最快12月开始在机场服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共批准2,841份申请，约占6,300名配额的45%分配到航空部门的输入工人。其中一半以上是乘客服务人员、停机坪服务代理和飞机机械师或技术人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwanese investing more in South Asia, Asean than mainland China amid global supply chains reshuffle]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3231287/taiwanese-investing-more-south-asia-asean-mainland-china-amid-global-supply-chains-reshuffle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/bb4682c0-7e58-4ebe-a6d9-ecdf43b74e96_def339c6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾在南亚和东盟的投资超过了中国大陆的投资台北表示，在两岸关系持续紧张和经济困境给中国商业前景带来压力的情况下，2023 年上半年台湾将在孟加拉国、不丹、印度、巴基斯坦、斯里兰卡和其他国家进行投资。经济事务副部长陈振其周二在一个论坛上表示，今年前六个月，东南亚国家联盟 (ASEAN) 10 个国家以及澳大利亚和新西兰的投资总额达到 21.26 亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该副部长补充道，同期来自全球第 21 大经济体台湾的资本流入中国大陆达 19 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在全球供应链重组下，东南亚陈在台北举行的台湾-东盟-印度战略投资伙伴论坛上表示：“台湾主张“加强与东南亚的经济关系，以减少对东南亚的依赖”。他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去 40 年来，投资者大多青睐中国大陆，因为它靠近自治岛屿、有共同语言以及相对廉价的劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;自 1991 年以来，部门数据显示台湾人在中国大陆投资了 2052 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，多年来成本上升、近期房地产市场下跌以及新冠疫情后经济复苏不平衡，导致这个世界第二大经济体的经济复苏不平衡。商业状况恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本、菲律宾、韩国最容易受到任何台湾战争的“巨大破坏”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;冠状病毒大流行期间中国大陆的生产和物流中断，引发了寻求资产的地域多元化，而中美紧张局势加剧则促使一些投资者转向与西方结盟的供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来台湾海峡的紧张局势也引发了人们对风险风险的更多担忧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2016年以来，台湾推出新南向政策，旨在扩大与南亚、东南亚和澳大利亚的投资、贸易、旅游和教育渠道，以减少对中国大陆的依赖。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该政策覆盖的国家包括上半年吸引台商投资超过中国大陆的18个国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度和东南亚部分地区拥有更便宜的土地和丰富的劳动力分析人士表示，“台湾在某种程度上不情愿，但最终还是接受了巨大的地缘政治问题”，Natixis 首席亚太经济学家艾丽西亚·加西亚-埃雷罗 (Alicia Garcia-Herrero) 表示。香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从中国的数据可以看出，情况进展不顺利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国周二发布的 7 月份经济指标普遍令人失望，房地产进一步萎缩投资以及工业产出和零售销售增长停滞。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;没有任何转机，失业率停止：中国 7 月经济数据的 7 个要点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;消费下降将降低中国大陆的吸引力台北附近的淡江大学外交与国际关系助理教授陈一凡表示，这些投资者向 14 亿人的国内市场出售工厂产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;担心两岸关系出现危险的衰退这位教授补充道，中美关系也会促使投资者选择其他目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但最大的问题仍然是中美之间的脱钩问题，投资者正在将工厂迁往东南亚以避免这种情况。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在东南亚，越南在今年前六个月处于领先地位，台湾投资额达 3.524 亿美元，高于 2022 年上半年的 1.434 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;电子巨头富士康总部位于台北郊区，在中国大陆设立了工厂，与台湾数千家制造服装、家具和机械的工厂一起运营着一条越南装配线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“过去十年来，这对台湾投资者具有很大的吸引力，”河内 Mekong Economics 首席经济学家 Adam McCarty 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不再像过去那样聚集在几家主要制造商周围他补充说：“台湾人现在正在扩张，他们在这里有一个很大的社区，这很重要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“创新就是一切”：快速发展的越南正在向中国学习什么&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;台湾在印度尼西亚的投资（包括丰富的矿产和工厂场地）从 2022 年同期的 1.187 亿美元跃升至 2023 年上半年的 1.437 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在的外国工厂运营商亚洲中心研究所顾问委员会驻雅加达成员 Nukila Evanty 表示，印尼最近修订了《创造就业综合法》，因此对印度尼西亚有利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律于 2020 年首次颁布，简化了法规和许可程序，反映了雅加达通过吸引离岸投资来推动创造就业机会的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Evanty 补充道，许多外资工厂将印度尼西亚的自然资源（例如鱼和橡胶）加工成新产品。&lt;/p>; >;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong man praised deadly shopping centre stabbings in online posts, called for ‘random and bloody violence’ against residents]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231308/hong-kong-man-praised-deadly-shopping-centre-stabbings-online-posts-called-random-and-bloody?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 19:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/cb918d73-0548-4443-a41e-28a6999e785a_5f96376c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名香港男子承认赞扬今年早些时候在购物中心发生的持刀致命事件今年，一系列社交媒体帖子敦促随机袭击居民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;34岁的李志伟周三在西九龙法院承认两项煽动伤人罪名，罪名是他在社交媒体上发布挑衅性信息。今年5月30日至6月3日期间在Facebook上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭获悉，被告在八个多月前就开始在社交媒体上写下自己受到社会压迫的妄想以及对“战争和种族灭绝”的渴望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方加强网上监控，打击类似三天前九龙东部两名购物者遇袭事件的煽动暴力行为，警方于 6 月 5 日逮捕了李某。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 39 岁的失业男子司徒成光 (Szeto Sing-kwong) 被控在钻石山荷里活广场商场谋杀两名妇女。他被还押在精神病院等待警方进一步调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袭击事件发生第二天，李在 Facebook 上写道，感谢袭击者，并表示社会需要更多像他这样的“烈士”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方发现李在5月30日发表了另一篇帖子，其中展示了台湾杀人犯郑杰的照片，并附有鼓励对香港人“随机和血腥暴力”的声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港男子因发帖呼吁缺席被监禁涉嫌谋杀首席裁判官&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;后来，警方在李的手机上发现了更多在社交媒体平台Telegram和Twitter上发布的攻击性信息，这些信息现已更名为X，最早可以追溯到去年9月30日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“暴力是解决问题的唯一途径，因此[我们]需要战争和种族灭绝，”Telegram 上的一篇帖子称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李还在 6 月 1 日的一条推文中声称，那是他的童年梦想用暴力为那些受到社会侮辱和压迫的人报仇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被告谨慎地承认自己发出了挑衅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只是因为我处于一个心情不好，感觉有人想伤害我。”他告诉警察。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法官因袭击兄弟而判处男子在精神病院服刑 1 年&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在随后的警方采访中在李的父母在场的情况下，被告证实他患有妄想症（一种无法区分真实与想象的心理健康状况），并希望通过表达自己的想法来获得保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;裁判官施祖尧表示，他倾向于接受政府精神科医生提出的为期四个月的住院令的建议，但批准检方休庭的要求，以等待对被告精神状况的最新评估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李先生将留在屯门小榄精神病治疗中心直至8月30日宣判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据《侵害人身罪条例》，煽动伤人最高可被判入狱三年，但法庭可如果被告确信其精神状况导致犯罪，则命令将其送往精神病院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商场杀人案的被告亦被监禁于屯门精神病院。预计他将于十月初重返法庭。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Russia resumes attacks on grain facilities with drones, stranded Hong Kong-flagged ship sets sail from port]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3231310/ukraine-war-russia-resumes-attacks-grain-facilities-drones-stranded-hong-kong-flagged-ship-sets-sail?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 19:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/9aff512f-cde0-4f9c-b2c6-2c97b5b849c4_015483a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当地官员表示，俄罗斯恢复了对乌克兰南部敖德萨地区粮食基础设施的攻击周三，在莫斯科破坏了一项通过黑海的重要战时出口协议后，使用无人机对多瑙河沿岸的储存设施和港口进行夜间袭击，基辅越来越多地利用这些设施和港口向欧洲运输粮食。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时当时，一艘自17个多月前俄罗斯全面入侵以来滞留在敖德萨港的满载集装箱船起航，正沿着乌克兰为商船建立的临时走廊穿越黑海前往博斯普鲁斯海峡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰经济因战争而严重依赖农业。与俄罗斯一样，中国的农产品出口对于发展中国家所依赖的小麦、大麦、葵花籽油和其他粮食的全球供应也至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫一个月前撕毁了一项去年达成的协议。夏季，为了确保乌克兰通过黑海的粮食安全出口，基辅已寻求通过多瑙河以及公路和铁路连接将运输转移到欧洲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这种方式的运输成本要高得多，一些欧洲国家对当地粮食价格造成的后果犹豫不决，多瑙河港口无法处理与海港相同的吞吐量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;敖德萨州长奥莱·基佩尔表示，俄罗斯夜间无人机轰炸的主要目标是港口码头和粮食筒仓，包括多瑙河三角洲的港口。据 Kiper 称，防空系统成功拦截了 13 架无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是数周空袭中的最新一次袭击，俄罗斯的目标是多瑙河三角洲港口，这些港口距离港口仅约 15 公里（10 英里）。罗马尼亚边境。多瑙河是欧洲第二长的河流，也是重要的运输路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，乌克兰副总理亚历山大·库布拉科夫表示，这艘从敖德萨出发的集装箱船是自 7 月 16 日起首艘起航的船只。自 2022 年 2 月以来，该船一直滞留在敖德萨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悬挂香港国旗的约瑟夫·舒尔特号 (Joseph Schulte) 正沿着乌克兰要求国际海事组织批准的临时走廊行驶。 The United States has warned that the Russian military is preparing for possible attacks on civilian shipping vessels in the Black Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sea mines also make the voyage risky, and ship insurance costs are likely to be high for operators. Ukraine told the IMO it would “provide guarantees of compensation for damage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last Sunday, a Russian warship fired warning shots at a Palau-flagged cargo ship in the south Black Sea. According to Russia&#39;s Defence Ministry, the Sukru Okan was heading northwards to the Ukrainian Danube River port of Izmail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ship-tracking data analysed by Associated Press confirmed that the Joseph Schulte was steaming south.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Joseph Schulte is carrying more than 30,000 tons of cargo, with 2,114 containers, including food products, according to Kubrakov.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the corridor will be primarily used to evacuate ships stuck in the Ukrainian ports of Chornomorsk, Odesa and Pivdennyi since the outbreak of war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the war&#39;s front line, Ukrainian officials claimed another milestone in Kyiv&#39;s grinding counteroffensive, with Deputy Defence Minister Hanna Maliar saying troops have retaken a village in the eastern Donetsk region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The village of Urozhaine is near Staromaiorske, a hamlet that Ukraine also claimed to have recaptured recently. The claims could not be independently verified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine appears to be trying to drive a wedge between Russian forces in the south, but it is up against strong defensive queues and is advancing without air support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also on Wednesday, the Russian military said it shot down three drones over the Kaluga region southwest of Moscow and blamed the attack on Ukraine. No damage or casualties were reported.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore’s PM Lee Hsien Loong says reserves adequate for ‘most circumstances’, warns against unnecessary drawdowns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231301/singapores-pm-lee-hsien-loong-says-reserves-adequate-most-circumstances-warns-against-unnecessary?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 18:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/e9d31703-badb-400d-bef8-db26d84da045_5c3a7691.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s financial reserves are enough to weather most circumstances but the republic must resist “frittering it away” as the scale of savings and investment returns of the past is unlikely to be replicated, Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an interview with the national broadcaster CNA, Lee suggested the biggest public “misconception” about the reserves was that there was “such a thing as enough” given that the scale of future crises is unknown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However much there is, I keep on having this attitude that I would like to build it up a little bit more when I can, so that the next generation will be in a more secure position than I am today,” Lee said in the interview released on YouTube and to be aired on television later on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee&#39;s remarks are some of the most extensive by a public official about the republic&#39;s much-vaunted reserves, built up since the days when his late father Lee Kuan Yew served as prime minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore warns against foreign interference ahead of presidential poll&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The total size of the reserves is deliberately undisclosed to guard against speculative attacks on the Singapore dollar, but observers have said the sum is likely to be well over US$1 trillion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Current policy dictates that a sitting government can tap up to 50 per cent of the long-term expected returns of the reserves, known as the net investment returns contribution (NIRC), for the annual budget.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee&#39;s interview with CNA also comes weeks ahead of the country&#39;s September 1 presidential poll. While a largely ceremonial position, one of the president&#39;s main roles is acting as a so-called “second key” to greenlight the government&#39;s request to drawdown on the reserves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ruling People&#39;s Action Party (PAP) government has twice tapped lump sums from the principal reserves: in the aftermath of the 2008 global financial crisis, and again during the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said in the interview that he was proud of Singapore&#39;s efforts to build up its reserves, but was “anxious that we keep it like this for as long as we can”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Because it&#39;s one of those things: once it&#39;s gone, it will never come back. It&#39;s finished, you cannot build it up again,” Lee said. He noted that Singapore was able to put aside substantial savings in earlier years when annual growth ranged from 8 to 12 per cent and budget surpluses ranged from 5 to 10 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today we&#39;re not as poor as we were before. Our incomes are higher, standard of living is higher,” said Lee, adding that Singapore&#39;s expectations and needs have also risen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prime minister said the ruling party&#39;s fourth-generation or “4G” team set to succeed him and his peers are “very conscious” that the returns from the reserves are unlikely to grow sharply while spending needs rise – especially as Singapore becomes a “super-aged society” by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singaporeans need to understand that the reserves were a “valuable asset” that is to be used “when you need to, but don&#39;t fritter it away”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prime minister also noted how the S$40 billion drawn down during the Covid-19 pandemic allowed the government to preserve jobs while not having to borrow funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among other things, the reserve drawdown was used to fund substantial wage subsidies even as the economy suffered from the pandemic-driven tailspin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said the financial firepower afforded by the reserves also allowed Singapore to be among the first to secure Covid-19 vaccines as it was ready to pay a premium if needed, as opposed to countries that had to take a “haggling and bargaining approach” to secure their supply of the jabs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the interview, Lee detailed the extent of the NIRC&#39;s contribution to the annual budget. He spelled out that at present the NIRC amounted to a fifth of government revenue, or 3.5 per cent of annual gross domestic product (GDP).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Corporate income tax is the biggest contributor to government revenue, amounting to 3.6 per cent of GDP. Other major income streams include personal income tax and the goods and services tax.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Extreme&#39; US-China rivalry could be economically &#39;disastrous&#39;: Singapore&#39;s Wong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The NIRC was “equal to [funding] more than one ministry for free”, Lee said, adding that in its absence other taxes would have to be substantially hiked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So when people say &#39;why don&#39;t we use the reserves to benefit the current generation?&#39; The answer is, we are, to a very big degree but you may not realise it because we have gotten used to it,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PAP has frequently contended with calls from fiscal doves for the current 50 per cent threshold long-term returns from the reserves to be increased.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Piyush Gupta, the chief executive officer of Singapore&#39;s biggest bank DBS, suggested in a conference this week that the city state should consider using its reserves to “address the underbelly of society” and to scale up in emerging sectors.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Intel ends deal to buy Tower Semiconductor after failure to gain Chinese regulatory approval]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3231304/intel-ends-deal-buy-tower-semiconductor-after-failure-gain-chinese-regulatory-approval?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 18:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/f8cbac4c-8b76-48d4-9633-804664c88a07_cb989e1b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Intel has cancelled its plans to buy Israeli foundry Tower Semiconductor after the deal failed to get approval from Chinese regulators ahead of a final deadline amid souring Sino-US relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The American tech giant on Wednesday terminated its deal to acquire Tower for US$5.4 billion “due to the inability to obtain in a timely manner the regulatory approvals required under the merger agreement”, the company said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing requires mergers involving companies with a major business presence in China to be approved by the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR), the antitrust regulator.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is one of Intel&#39;s largest markets. The company also houses several factories there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Intel&#39;s aborted acquisition was largely expected following several delays over the past year because of SAMR&#39;s opposition. Nasdaq-traded shares of Tower have declined by about 22 per cent year-to-date, closing at US$33.78 on Tuesday – compared with Intel&#39;s offer of US$53 per share.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Intel announced the intended purchase in February 2022, it predicted that the process would take about 12 months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on the terms of their agreement, Intel said it would now pay a walkaway fee of US$353 million to Tower.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Intel&#39;s failure to obtain Chinese approval for its deal underscores the pressure faced by US semiconductor companies amid worsening geopolitical tensions. China&#39;s review authority over global mergers and acquisitions is one tool that Beijing could use to retaliate against Washington&#39;s export restrictions on advanced chip technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Updates to US export controls last October effectively ban the shipments to China of any sufficiently advanced chips or chip-making equipment without explicit approval. The US Chips and Science Act, signed into law last year, banned American companies receiving chip funding to build leading-edge chip factories in China for 10 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, mainland Chinese regulators approved US chip maker MaxLinear&#39;s multibillion-dollar purchase of Taiwanese semiconductor firm Silicon Motion. However, the approval came with additional conditions, including a requirement for MaxLinear and Silicon Motion to continue supply of NAND flash memory chips to China in a “fair, reasonable and non-discriminatory manner”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MaxLinear ultimately chose to terminate its purchase of Silicon Motion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Intel has been walking a fine line trying to balance business interests on both sides of the Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, Intel CEO Patrick Gelsinger visited China, where he met commerce minister Wang Wentao and spoke at several industry events, highlighting the country&#39;s importance to the global semiconductor market. In an earnings call soon after, Gelsinger said he had been working during that trip to complete the Tower acquisition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gelsinger visited China again in July as his company pushed its latest processor for artificial intelligence deep-learning applications, the Gaudi2. The device is not subject to US export controls and can therefore be shipped to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Intel saw the Tower deal as part of its efforts to break into the chip contract-manufacturing market and provide a US-based alternative to Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), the world&#39;s largest semiconductor foundry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Western governments have signalled intention over the past year to invest in chip supply chains outside Taiwan. TSMC is building a US$40 billion factory in the southwestern US state of Arizona.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Tower is a fraction of the size of TSMC, the smaller company serves growing markets like electric vehicles. Intel had said Tower could provide the US giant with expertise and customers that it lacked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Intel on Monday announced a strategic partnership with American electronic design automation company Synopsys to develop a portfolio of various intellectual property offerings for its foundry services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the second quarter, Intel&#39;s foundry business reported a surge in revenue to US$232 million, up from US$57 million in the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-Philippines relations: outspoken Teodoro Locsin appointed as Manila’s ‘special envoy’ to Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3231305/china-philippines-relations-outspoken-teodoro-locsin-appointed-manilas-special-envoy-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 18:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/3cbcb64b-8268-4def-9ee5-47300ffa0f8a_349b4b6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former Philippine foreign minister Teodoro Locsin has been appointed the president&#39;s special envoy to Beijing, the government said on Wednesday, despite the outspoken diplomat&#39;s profanity-laced criticism of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Locsin, currently the ambassador to Britain and Ireland, often used strong language while serving as foreign secretary under former president Rodrigo Duterte and once swore at China online over the presence of its vessels in the disputed South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China, my friend, how politely can I put it? Let me see … O … GET THE F--- OUT,” Locsin posted on Twitter in May 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Locsin also likened China to “an ugly oaf forcing your attentions on a handsome guy who wants to be a friend”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His expletive-laden demand prompted a rebuke from Beijing and Locsin later apologised to his Chinese counterpart.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippine foreign affairs department declined to comment on Locsin&#39;s surprise appointment, which was announced by the Presidential Communications Office on its official Facebook page.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said in a brief statement Locsin had been appointed “Special Envoy of the President to the People&#39;s Republic of China for Special Concerns”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Philippines says &#39;promise&#39; to remove warship &#39;a figment of China&#39;s imagination&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;No other details were provided.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Presidential communications chief Cheloy Garafil told reporters Locsin would serve in a “concurrent capacity”, suggesting he would remain as ambassador.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Locsin is a prolific poster on the platform X, formerly known as Twitter, on topics ranging from Holocaust victims to his late pet cat but has not commented publicly on his appointment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision comes at a delicate time for relations between the Philippines and China, which are embroiled in another diplomatic spat over the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Philippines halts Manila Bay reclamation work amid US concern over Chinese firm&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing claims almost all of the waterway, through which trillions of dollars in trade passes annually, and has ignored a 2016 international court ruling that its assertion has no legal basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tensions flared this month when the Philippines accused Chinese Coast Guard vessels of blocking and firing water cannon at boats on a resupply mission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manila summoned Beijing&#39;s envoy over the incident, which resulted in one of the boats carrying supplies failing to reach a Philippine Navy vessel grounded on Second Thomas Shoal in the Spratly Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The handful of Filipino marines stationed on the crumbling ship to assert the Philippines&#39; territorial claims depend upon resupply missions to survive their remote posting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has defended its actions as “professional”, and accused Manila of “illegal delivery of construction materials” to the grounded ship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines has insisted that Second Thomas Shoal is within its exclusive economic zone and its efforts to resupply troops and repair the BRP Sierra Madre are legitimate.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[SF Airlines launches weekly cargo route to the United Arab Emirates from central China’s Hubei province]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3231293/sf-airlines-launches-weekly-cargo-route-united-arab-emirates-central-chinas-hubei-province?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 17:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/56ed9775-e909-4986-9ca2-a8e4d3423d78_348cd961.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A new air cargo route was launched on Wednesday linking Ezhou city in central China&#39;s Hubei province, with Abu Dhabi, capital of the United Arab Emirates (UAE), announced SF Airlines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early Wednesday morning, a Boeing 747-400 freighter took off from Ezhou Huahu Airport, China&#39;s first cargo-focused airport. This marked the launch of the first cargo route connecting the airport with the Middle East, said SF Airlines, China&#39;s largest air cargo carrier in fleet size.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A weekly round-trip air cargo service is scheduled for this route, with a total of around 200 tonnes of air express capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new route will mainly handle general cargo, e-commerce goods, and express shipments, providing efficient and reliable air logistics between China and the UAE, according to the cargo airline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prior to this route, SF Airlines and the UAE&#39;s Etihad Airways had jointly launched the Wuhan-Abu Dhabi air cargo route, a move to boost air logistics between the capital of central China&#39;s Hubei Province and the capital of the UAE and nearby markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ezhou Huahu Airport was put into operation in July 2022. It is positioned as a cargo-focused hub airport with extensive cargo traffic and some passenger traffic. It opened the first international cargo route in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Headquartered in Shenzhen, SF Airlines is the aviation branch of China&#39;s leading courier enterprise SF Express. It operates a fleet of 84 freighters, connecting more than 90 destinations at home and globally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To date, the cargo airline has launched multiple international cargo routes connecting the Ezhou Huahu Airport with Belgium, India, the United States, Germany and the UAE. It has carried a total sum of around 14,000 tonnes of international air cargo to and from this airport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is making efforts to expand the international air-route network from the Chinese cargo-focused airport, said the cargo airline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SF Airlines will continuously push forward its operations at the Ezhou Huahu Airport and support the airport in creating a world-class air cargo hub, the company added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 18:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>