<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Global climate change policy still failing women despite 50 years of meetings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222434/global-climate-change-policy-still-failing-women-despite-50-years-meetings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/70d392f3-3398-4334-b4bc-928928b35ee4_96c1f3b3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;6 月 5 日是联合国发起的世界环境日 50 周年1972 年 6 月在斯德哥尔摩人类环境会议上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使经过 50 年的努力来保护环境，气候变化的影响对女性的影响尤为严重。自 1970 年代以来，热暴露导致的女性死亡率显着增加。从 1970 年代到 2000 年代，自然灾害造成的性别死亡率的不平等现象不断加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，1991 年高尔基飓风袭击孟加拉国时，女性死亡人数是男性的 14 倍。在 2004 年的印度在海洋海啸中，女性占所有死亡人数的 70%，在受灾最严重的地区，这一数字上升到 80%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女性不成比例地面临气候变化的负面后果的原因有很多。例如，她们特别脆弱，因为她们经常需要为家庭提供食物、水和燃料等资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国估计，全球约有 3.83 亿妇女和女童生活在极端贫困中去年年底。尽管 63% 的 25 至 54 岁女性在全球工作，但据估计她们与男性相比仍面临 23% 的工资差距。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，缺乏经济和社会赋权限制了女性参与关于适应和减缓的气候变化决策。据估计，妇女和五岁以下儿童承担着 88% 的气候变化引起的疾病负担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要应对气候变化，必须承认性别因素并将其纳入政策框架。女性必须站在开发可持续技术的前沿，才能适应不断变化的气候。发展基础设施需要考虑性别平等的更多投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对气候变化采取针对特定性别的方法将有助于提升妇女权利问题并促进性别平等。在农业受到气候变化威胁的时候，它还可以帮助提高产量。根据联合国的一份报告，让女性与男性一样获得农业资源可以将发展中国家女性农场的产量提高 20% 到 30%，从而使农场总产量提高多达 4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢旺达是一个因其致力于促进性别平等而脱颖而出的国家，包括努力适应和减缓气候变化。其国家环境和气候变化政策强调了将性别观点纳入行动的重要性，多个网络作为女性交流知识、分享经验和倡导解决性别问题的气候政策的途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时妇女被认为容易受到气候变化的影响，但她们也是适应和缓解措施的拥护者。在智利，女性正在利用她们在工程、研究和项目管理方面的技能参与可再生能源项目，包括太阳能和风能的开发。他们在倡导家庭和社区的能源效率和节能实践方面发挥着至关重要的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当成员国在 2017 年德国波恩联合国气候变化会议上通过性别行动计划时，他们寻求改善气候政策对性别相关问题的回应。联合国气候机构强调了确保国家适应计划响应妇女需求的必要性，这些机构还加强了提高妇女平等参与气候宣传和行动的举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在性别日2021 年在苏格兰格拉斯哥举行的联合国气候变化会议上，女性走上了全球舞台，要求增加代表权。尽管有一天专门讨论性别问题，并且多个国家做出了财政承诺，但会议并没有让很多女性参与决策层，特别是土著妇女和来自弱势国家的妇女。这种代表性不足令人担忧，因为去年在埃及沙姆沙伊赫参加联合国峰会的国家谈判团队中女性不到三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;性别差异的另一个明显例子在合影中很明显去年峰会上的世界领导人，出席的 110 位领导人中只有 7 位是女性。据妇女环境与发展组织称，这是最近联合国气候会议上女性人数最少的会议之一，性别失衡超出了领导人的范围，因为一些国家的代表团由超过 90% 的男性组成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;11 月 30 日至 12 月 12 日在迪拜举行的下一届联合国气候变化会议的一项可能措施是更加优先考虑性别行动计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这将涉及鼓励各国创造气候考虑性别平等和增加妇女在各级决策角色中的代表性的政策。优先研究气候变化如何影响女性，以帮助制定更合适的政策响应，这一点至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果世界上最大的气候会议关注气候变化对女性的影响，并承诺为了确保他们有意义的参与，这将对全球决策产生重大影响，同时有助于为所有人创造一个公正和可持续的未来。五十年应该足以让世界实施对性别问题敏感的气候议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 03:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Senior US diplomat Daniel Kritenbrink to visit China amid tense ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222873/senior-us-diplomat-daniel-kritenbrink-visit-china-amid-tense-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 03:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/7b644a28-6c90-4583-9c6e-976cd34bb752_fdbe4a35.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位美国高级外交官将于下周访问北京，国务院周六表示，这是华盛顿试图缓和与其“战略竞争对手”的紧张关系并防止关系进一步恶化的一系列会议中的最新一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔克里滕布林克将前往中国和美国国务院在一份声明中表示，新西兰将于 6 月 4 日至 10 日“讨论双边关系中的关键问题”，但没有提供更多细节。国家安全委员会负责中国和台湾事务的高级主任莎拉·贝兰 (Sarah Beran) 将陪同他访问中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里滕布林克的访问是在中央情报局局长威廉·伯恩斯上个月秘密访问中国的报道以及与克里滕布林克之间的会谈之后进行的。美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文 (Jake Sullivan) 和中国中央外事委员会主任王毅也在 5 月访问了奥地利，作为加强沟通努力的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，中国商务部部长王文涛在前往密歇根州与美国贸易代表凯瑟琳·戴伊在亚太经合组织贸易会议期间会面之前，他在华盛顿会见了美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这些加强接触的早期迹象已经没有扩展到军队。北京继续拒绝美国改善防务关系的努力，美国国防部长劳埃德奥斯汀周六在新加坡香格里拉对话会上批评了这一立场，此前据报道中国国防部长李尚福将军拒绝在场边会见他。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;奥斯汀在周日闭幕的亚洲顶级安全峰会上表示，北京方面不愿谈判破坏了两个竞争对手正在增加军事火力的地区维持和平的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于负责任的国防领导人来说，任何时候都是合适的对话时机，”奥斯汀说，并补充说华盛顿不会容忍中国对其伙伴和盟友进行“胁迫和欺凌”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡的中国官员反驳道奥斯汀等美方官员歪曲事实，蓄意包围中国，通过对台军售、加强交流等方式破坏一个中国原则。双方都警告称，围绕这个自治岛屿发生军事冲突的风险越来越大。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香格里拉对话：美国和中国在台湾、南中国海问题上站稳脚跟&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其他世界上最大的两个经济体之间的紧张关系包括贸易、技术和投资政策、中国的人权记录和在南中国海的岛屿建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里滕布林克预计将于 6 月 4 日星期日抵达中国建交 34 周年纪念日镇压天安门广场的亲民主抗议者。周六，国务卿安东尼·布林肯在另一份声明中指出，美国将纪念这一周年纪念日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“受害者的勇敢不会被遗忘，并将继续激励全世界这些原则的倡导者，”布林肯说，并补充说：“美国将继续在中国和世界各地倡导人民的人权和基本自由。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月，中国国家主席习近平和美国总统乔·拜登制定了路线图通过高级金融、贸易和外交官员访问的“阶梯”改善关系，可能导致习近平 11 月前往旧金山参加 Apec 峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中关系继续解冻贸易官员在底特律举行会议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，在中国监视气球于 1 月底和 2 月初飞越北美之后，这些建立信任的努力戛然而止。华盛顿取消了布林肯原定于 2 月访问中国的行程，北京谴责气球坠落事件，指责华盛顿反应过度。几条沟通渠道因此被切断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上个月在日本举行的七国集团会议上，拜登预测华盛顿和北京之间的关系将很快解冻。白宫已表示正在努力安排布林肯、雷蒙多和财政部长珍妮特耶伦的访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里滕布林克此行的一个主要重点很可能是拜登可能访问中国，但克里滕布林克也将乘坐飞机前往奥克兰参加美新战略对话，然后返回华盛顿。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 03:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden signs debt ceiling bill that pulls US back from brink of unprecedented default]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222871/joe-biden-signs-debt-ceiling-bill-pulls-us-back-brink-unprecedented-default?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 02:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/79042b5d-84a8-4446-a5ae-750c9b253d40_071a5fc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登周六签署立法，解除国家的债务上限，避免了联邦政府债务史无前例的违约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫在一份电子邮件声明中宣布了在白宫私下签署的协议，拜登在声明中感谢国会领导人的合作.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政部警告说，该国周一将开始出现现金短缺以支付所有账单，这将对美国和全球经济造成冲击波。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;除非民主党同意削减开支，否则共和党拒绝提高该国的借贷上限，导致僵局直到白宫与众议院议长凯文麦卡锡之间数周的激烈谈判后才得到解决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终周三众议院和周四参议院通过的协议暂停债务上限至 2025 年——在下届总统大选之后——并限制政府支出。它为立法者提供了未来两年的预算目标，希望在政治季节升温时确保财政稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提高国家的债务上限（目前为 31.4 万亿美元）将确保政府能够举债支付已经产生的债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过这项预算协议至关重要。赌注不可能更高，”拜登周五晚上在椭圆形办公室说。他说：“没有什么比国家债务违约更灾难性的了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;和共识”。 “我们避免了经济危机和经济崩溃。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着美国债务交易在国会获得通过，避免了违约，拜登欢呼“大胜利”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拜登借此机会逐条列举了他竞选连任的第一个任期，包括支持高科技制造、基础设施投资和应对气候变化的财政激励措施。他还强调了他如何削弱共和党为推翻他的议程和实现更深层次的削减所做的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在削减开支，同时降低赤字，”拜登说。 “我们正在保护重要的优先事项，从社会保障到医疗保险再到医疗补助再到退伍军人，再到我们对基础设施和清洁能源的转型投资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使他承诺继续与共和党人合作，拜登也与反对党，特别是在增加对富人的税收方面，这是民主党总统一直在寻求的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他建议这可能需要等到第二个任期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我我会回来的，”他说。 “有你的帮助，我会赢。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登的这番话是这位民主党总统对他和他的幕僚谈判达成的妥协做出的最详细的评论。在高风险会谈期间，他基本上在公开场合保持沉默，这一决定令他所在政党的一些成员感到沮丧，但他的目的是为双方达成协议提供空间，并让立法者将其投票到他的办公桌上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;拜登称赞麦卡锡和他的谈判代表真诚行事，并称赞所有国会领导人确保立法迅速通过。 “他们采取了负责任的行动，将国家的利益置于政治之上，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总的来说，这份长达 99 页的法案限制了未来两年的支出，并改变了一些政策，包括实施新的工作年长的美国人接受食品援助和批准许多民主党人反对的阿巴拉契亚天然气管道的要求。修改了一些环境规则，以帮助简化基础设施和能源项目的审批——这是国会温和派长期以来寻求的举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国会预算办公室估计，它实际上可以扩大联邦食品援助的总资格，取消退伍军人、无家可归者和离开寄养的年轻人的工作要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;据报道，美国间谍头子威廉·伯恩斯秘密访问中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该立法还增加了国防和退伍军人，削减了国税局（IRS）的一些新资金，并拒绝了拜登关于取消特朗普时代对企业和富人的税收减免以帮助弥补国家赤字的呼吁。但白宫表示，美国国税局加强对高收入者和企业执行税法的计划将继续进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果国会未能通过该协议，则该协议将自动整体削减 1% 的支出计划批准其年度支出法案——一项旨在向两党立法者施压，要求其在 9 月份财政年度结束前达成共识的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在两院中，支持该立法的民主党人多于共和党人，但两党都对其通过至关重要。在参议院，票数为 63-36，其中包括 46 名民主党人和独立人士以及 17 名共和党人，31 名共和党人以及四名民主党人和一名与民主党人反对的独立人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院的投票结果为 314 -117.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Lebanon ministry to send team to Paris after envoy accused of rape and intentional violence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222870/lebanon-ministry-send-team-paris-after-envoy-accused-rape-and-intentional-violence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 01:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/896194ae-01ef-4791-8770-2ec6a049c7b2_0238b490.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;黎巴嫩外交部周六表示，将派遣一个调查组前往巴黎，此前有报道称贝鲁特驻法国大使拉米·阿德万 (Rami Adwan) 被指控犯有强奸罪和蓄意暴力罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国对阿德万的调查是在两名前大使馆雇员的投诉之后进行的，接近调查的消息人士告诉法新社，这证实了早前媒体报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国政府已敦促黎巴嫩当局取消阿德万的外交豁免权，允许他接受审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黎巴嫩外交部已决定“紧急派遣一个由该部秘书长领导的调查委员会……前往巴黎大使馆询问有关大使并听取大使馆工作人员的陈述”，它在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会将与法国当局会面“以澄清声明补充说，这是媒体报道的，但没有通过外交渠道传达给黎巴嫩外交部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一位 31 岁的前雇员于 2022 年 6 月提出强奸申诉据接近调查的消息人士证实了 Mediapart 的报道，她说她于 2020 年 5 月在大使的私人公寓里犯了罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据投诉，她与大使有关系，大使进行了“心理治疗”以及每天遭受羞辱的身体暴力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;黎巴嫩驻法国特使被控强奸 2 名前大使馆工作人员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第二名 28 岁的妇女去年 2 月提出申诉在她拒绝发生性关系后，她遭受了一系列身体攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她声称，在去年诺曼底世界和平论坛期间发生争执后，阿德万试图用他的车撞她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “鉴于上述事实的严重性，我们认为黎巴嫩当局有必要取消黎巴嫩驻巴黎大使的豁免权，以便利法国司法当局的工作，”法国外交部告诉法新社——周五晚些时候发布消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adwan 的律师 Karim Beylouni 表示，他的当事人“反驳所有形式或形式的侵略指控：口头、道德、性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说 Adwan在 2018 年至 2022 年期间与这两名女性发生了“浪漫关系”，“不时有争吵和分手”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 01:50:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Recep Tayyip Erdogan promises a stronger, more inclusive Turkey at inauguration]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222869/recep-tayyip-erdogan-promises-stronger-more-inclusive-turkey-inauguration?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 00:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/ee71f60c-468d-4db2-8eeb-ad231ffba1c7_46ec5759.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;土耳其总统雷杰普·塔伊普·埃尔多安承诺加强土耳其在全球的外交影响力，同时在在周六的就职演说中，他承诺在国内制定新的包容性宪法并改善经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们承诺将竭尽全力保护土耳其共和国的荣耀，提升其在世界，”埃尔多安在他位于安卡拉的总统府举行的仪式上说，来自近 80 个国家的代表和北约秘书长延斯·斯托尔滕贝格出席了仪式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔多安在 5 月 28 日的总统决选中赢得了另一场总统选举任期五年，周六早些时候宣誓就职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在执政 20 年后再次当选，正值二十年来最严重的生活成本危机，区域挑战和 2 月的毁灭性地震。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“选举进程现已结束；土耳其已经进入了一条新的道路，”他说。 “土耳其的世纪已经开始，”埃尔多安重复他的竞选口号说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他称自己的连任是“土耳其政治史上最关键的选举之一”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;埃尔多安还敦促土耳其反对派尊重国家意志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六早些时候——尽管有规定——以示抗议，反对派立法者拒绝在埃尔多安在议会宣誓时起立，宣誓强调遵守世俗的共和价值观、权利和法治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对派批评这位 69 岁的总统有他们所谓的“专制”倾向和不公平的竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔多安在他的就职演说中驳斥了诸如“诽谤”之类的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地广播公司称，在管弦乐音乐会和伊斯兰祈祷之后，埃尔多安举办了​​国宴，约有 5,000 人参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;宗教领袖，包括君士坦丁堡普世牧首巴塞洛缪一世，以及包括前德国国家足球运动员梅苏特厄齐尔在内的体育名人，都在埃尔多安的演讲中登台。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;埃尔多安看到了中国与西方之间的“平衡”北约早些时候表示，预计斯托尔滕贝格将在第三任期内与埃尔多安举行单独会谈。他的访问正值北约向成员国土耳其施加压力，要求其停止反对瑞典加入该联盟之际。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六晚些时候，预计埃尔多安将宣布他的内阁成员名单。当地媒体推测，埃尔多安将在他的新内阁中包括前经济沙皇穆罕默德·西姆塞克等前助手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔多安和他的民族主义、伊斯兰主义盟友组成了拥有 600 个席位的议会中最大的集团，议会召开会议在 5 月 14 日的选举之后，这是周五的第一次。然而，他们缺乏进行重要法律改革所需的多数席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，自 2018 年以来，根据他作为执行总统的权力，总统仍然可以通过法令通过一些立法改革。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine: counteroffensive on track despite Russian missile barrages – ‘we’ll win this war’, defence official confirms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222868/ukraine-counteroffensive-track-despite-russian-missile-barrages-well-win-war-defence-official?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 00:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/6edf21ac-94c9-419c-af7d-d30789313e19_d114eb2b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌克兰反攻俄罗斯占领的计划仍在进行中，副国防部长说周六，继乌克兰总统沃洛德米尔·泽伦斯基 (Volodymyr Zelensky) 早些时候宣布之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管最近几周全国各地发生了“前所未有”的导弹和无人机袭击浪潮，但还是得到了确认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Volodymyr V . 哈夫雷洛夫说，除了巡航导弹袭击外，乌克兰在 5 月还面临弹道导弹的多次齐射，尤其是在首都基辅等城市中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的主要目标是阻止我们的反攻和目标决定-建立中心，”他在亚洲顶级安全会议新加坡香格里拉对话的间隙说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰战争：瓦格纳老板说，俄罗斯军队试图炸毁我的手下&lt;/h3>; p>;Havrylov 称俄罗斯在 5 月份大量使用弹道导弹是“最后的战略手段”，并指出他的国家的防空系统对袭击的“效率超过 90%”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于俄罗斯“发现 [他们的弹道导弹] 对现代防空系统的有效性几乎为零，这是一个巨大的惊喜，我们从合作伙伴那里得到的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国和德国向乌克兰提供今年先进的爱国者导弹电池。乌克兰已经从西方合作伙伴那里获得了先进的短程系统，例如 NASAMS 和 IRIS-T。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰总统沃洛德米尔·泽伦斯基周六早些时候表示，他的国家已准备好发起期待已久的反攻。哈夫雷洛夫说，导弹弹幕并未影响时机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有什么能阻止我们的努力、我们的愿望以及我们对赢得这场战争的信心，”他说。他补充说，乌克兰将“开始反攻，目标是在今年解放我们的领土”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科将 2022 年 2 月开始的入侵称为“特殊行动”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Havrylov 拒绝就最近的无人机袭击和边境入侵俄罗斯领土发表评论，包括到达莫斯科附近的一些袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们 [俄罗斯] 有很多内部事件当然与此有关战争”，他说。 “我们俄罗斯境内有很多支持乌克兰的人”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国指责对方通过空袭在各自首都散播恐怖。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰战争：平民俄罗斯别尔哥罗德附近数百人丧生，逃离地区&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Havrylov 与来自世界各地的国防和军事官员一起参加了新加坡会议，他表示，乌克兰希望北约盟国在国防协定会议上提供详细的加入路线图下个月在立陶宛维尔纽斯举行首脑会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望看到双方都采取一系列明确的步骤”，他说。 “这不仅仅是大门敞开的迹象。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，乌克兰还希望在该国处于加入成员国的“过渡期”期间提供安全保证。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他驳回了印度尼西亚国防部长在新加坡会议上提出的建立非军事区以停止乌克兰战斗的提议，他说：“我们不会谈判任何与失去我们的领土有关的协议，包括克里米亚。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈夫雷洛夫赞扬了英国最近提供的风暴影子巡航导弹，英国国防部长本华莱士周五表示，这些导弹没有错过乌克兰袭击过的任何目标。 Havrylov 说，F-16 等现代战斗机的加入将提高该国的防空能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，他无法评论地面发射的小直径炸弹是否是另一种远程打击武器西方盟友今年已提供，但已用于战斗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈夫里洛夫说，乌克兰在香格里拉对话会上与包括亚洲国家在内的许多国家进行了良好的会谈和讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们希望与所有人互动，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shangri-La Dialogue: Australia-China defence ministers meet as bilateral tensions show signs of easing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3222863/shangri-la-dialogue-australia-china-defence-ministers-meet-bilateral-tensions-show-signs-easing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 22:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/ce025200-466c-47f1-957a-916f572038c0_30919f3f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚国防部长理查德马勒斯会见中国国防部长李尚福将军李今年的任命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六晚些时候，两人在新加坡举行的香格里拉对话防务峰会期间会面，讨论了恢复部长级会谈作为稳定双边关系努力的一部分的重要性。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;自 2020 年以来，在澳大利亚总理斯科特·莫里森领导下的上届政府呼吁对冠状病毒的来源进行独立调查后，这两个国家一直处于争执状态，这激起了中国对被指责为大流行源头的愤怒。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次会议是自去年 5 月新奥尔巴尼政府上台以来两国高级部长之间不断增加的互动清单之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，澳大利亚贸易部长 Don法雷尔访问了北京，会见了商务部长王文涛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与法雷尔和王文涛一样，马勒斯和李也讨论了中国取消对澳大利亚出口限制的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚称 Aukus 与中国的军事扩张不同&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 2020 年和 2021 年对来自澳大利亚的七种产品实施非正式禁令并对澳大利亚葡萄酒和大麦征收反倾销税后，中国最近取消了对木材的限制&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京也在世界贸易组织争端解决机制之外审查大麦反倾销问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更有希望的迹象是，Marles 和 Li 讨论了继最近于 3 月在堪培拉恢复的国防协调对话之后，又恢复了国防战略对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marles 还向李谈到澳大利亚致力于支持印度洋的和平、稳定与安全。太平洋并重申了该地区海空安全互动的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还重申了堪培拉对《不扩散核武器条约》的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早些时候，在另一次采访中，Marles 试图将 Aukus 安全联盟描绘成一个透明的倡议，有助于该地区的稳定，但指责中国不公开其核和军事扩张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外之后，马勒斯向李提出了澳大利亚公民持续被拘留的问题，以及人权问题。记者程磊和作家杨恒均是在中国被拘留的澳大利亚人之一。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the US-China chip war is dismantling Taiwan’s silicon shield]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222471/how-us-china-chip-war-dismantling-taiwans-silicon-shield?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/7cff87ba-59fa-4817-b3d3-a3264b929e16_24d2029e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾半导体公司的地缘经济作用越来越受到学术界和公众的关注。一些分析师将台湾半导体制造公司 (TSMC) 等公司视为全球生产网络中的关键参与者，甚至是超级掠夺者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这种台湾半导体公司代理的观点存在严重缺陷，因为它不&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 年芯片短缺期间出现了台湾芯片制造商超大机构的神话，预计当年全球汽车行业将损失 2100 亿美元的收入，此外还会阻碍许多国家的经济复苏。台湾半导体代工企业有望成为经济救星，因为它们占全球代工芯片制造的 60% 以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国、日本和韩国与台湾当局接洽，要求他们敦促该岛的半导体代工厂增加汽车芯片供应。美国总统乔·拜登邀请台湾企业家参加虚拟会议，商讨微处理器短缺相关问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾企业在回应政客要求时模棱两可，拒绝优先考虑汽车制造商的订单而牺牲了其他客户及其股东。当时，国家行为者似乎无法指挥大型科技公司；然而随后几年发生的事情对台湾芯片行业来说并不是好兆头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事后看来，2021 年的芯片短缺确实是国家技术关系转型的关键时刻——直到那时，伟大的大国充分意识到半导体可能成为世界经济的咽喉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;短缺导致国家机器试图管理该行业。美国开始制定旨在从根本上挖空东亚高科技基地的半导体战略，以加强其国内实体并保护其芯片供应免受地缘政治风险的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 6 月 8 日，华盛顿发布了其100-day supply chain review report, blaming the lagging competitiveness of American manufacturers in part on “unfair trade practices by competitor nations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report affirmed that semiconductor foundries&#39; geographical concentration in East Asia posed a threat to US economic independence and technological supremacy. It also provided a rationale for the Biden administration to impose long-arm jurisdiction over hi-tech activities overseas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The measures included asking Taiwanese chip makers to hand over confidential information to the US Department of Commerce and banning US entities from exporting advanced chips, the equipment used to make them and the related intellectual property to China. Contentiously, the policy effectively forced some companies to transplant their production lines to the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The American plan was to replicate a Taiwan-style semiconductor complex in Phoenix, Arizona, where TSMC undertook the building of 4-nanometre and 3-nanometre fabrication plants expected to be commissioned in 2024 and 2026 respectively. As construction started from scratch in a desert, accompanying TSMC across the Pacific were 2,000 engineers and 26 suppliers specialising in fields ranging from upstream epitaxy (growing a crystal film) to downstream assembly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US$40 billion construction spending, one of the largest foreign investments in American history, means it will cost more to produce chips in Arizona – twice more than in Taiwan, despite the federal government&#39;s pledge to subsidise 25 per cent of the expenditure under the Chips and Science Act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Arizona project appears to be a honey trap. Fabrication plants in Phoenix weaken Taiwan&#39;s geostrategic significance because the US could continue to procure cutting-edge microchips even if mainland China takes control of the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the US eventually showed its true colours by announcing last March that under the Chips Act&#39;s guardrail provisions US-sponsored foreign chip makers would be required to share any excess profit with the federal government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US is not the only great power tightening its grip on Taiwanese semiconductor corporations. Back in 2015, China&#39;s State Council announced the Made in China 2025 initiative, proclaiming that 70 per cent of national chip demand should be met domestically by the date. One crucial measure was to seek investment from Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this context, United Microelectronics Corporation, Taiwan&#39;s second-largest chip maker, the Xiamen municipal government and Fujian Electronics and Information Group established the Lianxin joint venture, a fabrication plant in Xiamen which later was made capable of using 28-nanometre technology. Under the agreement, UMC, which initially had around a 30 per cent stake, has the right to acquire shares from the local government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the Sino-American tech war intensified, UMC became concerned about Lianxin&#39;s “China-funded entity” label and reportedly tried to acquire the remaining shares last year, but was blocked by the local government. The botched acquisition shows that mainland China is also prepared to play hardball with Taiwanese companies in pursuit of greater semiconductor self-reliance.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why US efforts to control chips industry will put Taiwan at risk&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A new order of technopolitics has resulted from the parochialism, interventionism and hegemonism of both the US and China, ratcheting up the pressure on the mobility, competency and leeway of third-party actors such as Taiwan&#39;s hi-tech corporations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Associated with the diminishing autonomy of Taiwanese companies is the shrinking geostrategic importance and bargaining power of the island. The Taiwan miracle was made possible when Taiwanese enterprises forged a connection between mainland China and the West – such an advantage no longer exists with geoeconomic decoupling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Companies in Taiwan, together with those in Singapore, Israel, the Netherlands and South Korea will continue to face the predicament of picking a side between the two major powers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shangri-La Dialogue: US and China in the same room but worlds apart on Taiwan, South China Sea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222854/shangri-la-dialogue-us-and-china-same-room-worlds-apart-taiwan-south-china-sea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/5c205df3-fcb1-4960-856f-9d2f458ca446_6881640b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Top Chinese and US defence officials may have shaken hands but they were soon back bristling over Taiwan and the South China Sea at a major security conference in Singapore on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing and Washington seemed as far apart as ever as US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin renewed his country&#39;s commitment to defend the Taiwan Strait against “bullying and coercion” while a senior Chinese official accused Austin of making “false accusations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The terse exchanges at the Shangri-La Dialogue all but eliminated any hopes of a meeting between Austin and his Chinese counterpart, Li Shangfu, who had bilateral talks with his counterparts from Malaysia, Germany, Britain, Australia, Japan and South Korea on the sidelines of the forum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Austin&#39;s speech to the conference covered the biggest frictions in the military relationship between the two countries, and stressed US determination to work with Asian allies to deter aggression and prevent conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So we&#39;re stepping up planning and coordination, and training with our friends, from the East China Sea to the South China Sea to the Indian Ocean,” Austin said. “That includes staunch allies such as Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, the Philippines and Thailand.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said the US network of friendly countries in Asia would defend against coercion, especially in the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The comments prompted Lieutenant General Jing Jianfeng, vice chief of the Central Military Commission&#39;s Joint Staff Department, to accuse the US of “hollowing out the one-China principle” by strengthening exchanges between US and Taiwanese officials, condoning Taiwanese separatist activities and selling lethal weapons to Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s only one China in the world, and Taiwan is a sacred and inalienable part of Chinese territory,” Jing said, stressing the one-China principle “represents the consensus of the international community”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, other countries have their own Taiwan policies, which do not entirely align with Beijing&#39;s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most countries, including the United States, do not recognise Taiwan as an independent state. Washington, however, opposes any attempt to take the island by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the conference gathered pace on Saturday, the guided-missile destroyer USS Chung-Hoon and the Canadian frigate HMCS Montreal sailed through the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US Seventh Fleet said the transit showed the commitment of the US and its partners to a free and open Indo-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jing said the frequent passages by US warships through the Taiwan Strait and Washington&#39;s attempts to draw more countries in to “interfere” in the Taiwan issue had further encouraged the self-ruled island&#39;s independence-leaning forces, forcing the People&#39;s Liberation Army to step up its military exercises in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The PLA&#39;s retaliatory military operations … targeting the Taiwan separatist activities and the interference of external forces … are completely justified, lawful and beyond reproach,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The PLA has been fully prepared and ready to firmly defend China&#39;s sovereignty, reunification and territorial integrity at any time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another member of the Chinese delegation, Senior Colonel Zhao Xiaozhuo, from the PLA Academy of Military Sciences, also took aim at US military aid to Taiwan, saying it was “a plot” to “legalise” Washington&#39;s intervention in the Taiwan issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US doesn&#39;t want to see a stable Taiwan Strait because it wouldn&#39;t fulfil the US&#39; Indo-Pacific strategy to let it send more troops and deploy more weapon systems to the region, while Taiwan would need to buy more US weapons,” Zhao said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Shangri-La Dialogue puts focus on shifting US-China military balance&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jing, from the Central Military Commission, also objected to Austin&#39;s accusation that a PLA aircraft engaged in “risky intercepts” in the South China Sea, a disputed waterway through which a large share of the world&#39;s trade passes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days before the conference, the Pentagon released footage of an “unprofessional interception” by a PLA J-16 fighter jet of an American RC-135 reconnaissance plane in the South China Sea, claiming the “provocative and dangerous actions are the root cause of maritime security issues”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jing said the Shandong aircraft carrier was conducting drills in the area and the US plane&#39;s close-in reconnaissance warranted the expulsion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The PLA&#39;s reaction was a necessary response to the provocation of certain countries, and was legal, justified, safe and professional,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jing said the risk of a greater crisis would only grow as the US increased its deployment of weapons and troops to the region, and as it pressured external parties to “meddle in the regional issues”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing claims almost the entire South China Sea as its territory, claims that are contested by the Philippines, Vietnam, Brunei, Malaysia – and Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US is not a claimant but it conducts frequent freedom of navigation patrols in the waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lieutenant General He Lei, another member of the PLA delegation, said China preferred to negotiate on a bilateral basis with rival claimants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US&#39; move to join with its allies, especially the Five Eyes alliance and other European countries, to meddle in the regional issue … will only complicate the issue,” He said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You Americans live thousands of miles away from the South China Sea. Why are you coming here to provoke other countries to confront China?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former Chinese ambassador to the US Cui Tiankai said Europe had “mismanaged” its security, as exemplified by its response to the Ukraine war, and should look to the Asia-Pacific for its approach to peace and stability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should also learn something, a very important something, from [Europe&#39;s] lack of success. I don&#39;t want to use the word &#39;failure&#39;, but lack of success.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese delegation said that overall Austin&#39;s speech was less “hostile” than the one he gave last year, but Beijing decided against resuming high-level military-to-military communication because of the US push to enlist allies in and outside the region to “meddle in regional issues”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jing said that 32 years after the Cold War, US-led alliances had divided the world into ideologically driven camps and provoked confrontation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US pursues its selfish interest, regardless of other countries&#39; aspirations for stability and uses them as pawns through trickery and coercion,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Victoria Park full of food and booths instead of candlelight as carnival takes over venue of annual June 4 vigil]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3222857/hong-kongs-victoria-park-full-food-and-booths-instead-candlelight-carnival-takes-over-venue-annual?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 20:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/d815e245-8afb-40e5-88a2-05a4a7c3cc91_c04cf9bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Folk music, food tasters and a heavy police presence filled Hong Kong&#39;s Victoria Park ahead of the Tiananmen Square crackdown anniversary as spaces that once hosted the annual June 4 candlelight vigils were taken over by a carnival organised by pro-Beijing groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was a noticeable police presence at the park on Saturday, with officers in bulletproof vests patrolling and a Chinese-made Sabertooth armoured vehicle stationed outside the entrance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The absence of an organised vigil did not silence everyone. A petition signed by 360 pastors and other Christian figures in the city will be published in the Christian Times on Sunday, among the signatories is Reverend Chu Yiu-ming, one of the co-founders of the Occupy Central campaign.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Lord! We must admit that distortions in politics, imbalances in society and the diaspora phenomenon will bring us fear … May the Lord give us greater confidence and courage, so that we will be fearless and not be scared by changes,” the prayer read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three-day carnival, co-organised by 26 compatriot groups to mark the 26th anniversary of Hong Kong&#39;s return to Chinese rule on July 1, opened on Saturday morning with 200 booths offering Chinese food and folk art performances, including concerts and dance shows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the opening ceremony, Chief Secretary Eric Chan Kwok-ki said the event would showcase the features of various parts of the nation and help stimulate local consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A steady stream of visitors filled the carnival ground on Saturday morning despite the sweltering heat – the mercury soared above 32 degrees Celsius according to the Hong Kong Observatory, which issued a special hot weather alert at 1:30pm.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong security chief warns troublemakers ahead of June 4 anniversary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Today&#39;s vibe is excellent with a lot of people. It&#39;s only that we are all sweating profusely,” said veteran entertainer Natalis Chan Pak-cheung, who was offering a free tasting of canned abalones and mooncakes sold under his brand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He urged Hongkongers to get used to the absence of June 4 vigils and move on: “The mainland has not held vigils, and it&#39;s been the same for them. Under &#39;one country, two systems&#39;, we&#39;re integrating into the nation and putting the economy first.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Out of the six soccer pitches at Victoria Park, the carnival would occupy four from Saturday to Monday, while two others were fenced off for maintenance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The entire lawn was also off-limits to regular park users as part of it was under maintenance, while the rest was occupied by game booths and several inflatable bouncers set up by the carnival organisers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thousands of police officers to patrol Hong Kong on Tiananmen Square anniversary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For decades on June 4, these open spaces at Victoria Park had been used by thousands of Hongkongers to remember those killed in the crackdown in Beijing at vigils organised by the Hong Kong Alliance in Support of Patriotic Democratic Movements of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The alliance&#39;s attempts to hold the vigils in 2020 and 2021 were blocked by authorities citing public health risks amid the Covid-19 pandemic. There were no attempts to organise an event in 2022 or this year after the organisation disbanded in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A carnival visitor in his thirties, who identified himself only by the surname Chan, said his memory of attending a vigil a few years ago felt remote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To be frank, even if there was no such [carnival], the application for a June 4 [vigil] would not have been accepted,” said the worker in the manufacturing sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to the numerous police officers on patrol, visitors, who had to pay HK$5 (63 US cents) for admission, were also subject to a bag check by security guards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My family and I were surprised to see so many cops,” said Ng Hoi-chun, a 29-year-old interior fit-out worker, who was leaving the fair after finding the offerings “so-so”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having taken part in the vigils with his family from a young age, he last joined in 2018. This year he planned to take an evening walk with friends to mark the date. “I believe some spontaneous activities will take place. They won&#39;t all be gone,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong cinema cancels private screening on &#39;sensitive&#39; June 4, group says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Another vigil attendee who was taking a stroll in the park with family, Wilson Leung, said he would look to his friends on whether to do something on June 4.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve been talking less about politics because of the national security law. I wouldn&#39;t go out on purpose if there were not so many friends going together,” he said, referring to the sweeping legislation imposed by Beijing three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s security chief Chris Tang Ping-keung had last month warned “resolute action” would be taken against anyone taking advantage of the “special occasion” to threaten national security, though city officials have avoided giving specifics of actions that would face enforcement actions.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s former US envoy Cui Tiankai slams Europe for ‘mismanaging’ own security situation, points to Asian wisdom]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222856/chinas-former-us-envoy-cui-tiankai-slams-europe-mismanaging-own-security-situation-points-asian?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 20:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/2c4e7f05-3efe-4250-80fb-219c2e469d10_d742e0c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Europe had “mismanaged” its own security and should look to the Asia-Pacific for guidance, a former Chinese ambassador to Washington told Asia&#39;s top annual defence conference on Saturday, as he rejected a call for China to speak to Russia as an “older brother”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think you are managing effectively and constructively your security situation,” Cui Tiankai said during a panel discussion at the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A better word for it will be &#39;mismanaging&#39; it. You see the outcome: it&#39;s hurting everybody.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The panel on managing security in the Euro-Atlantic and Asia-Pacific regions was also attended by Ukrainian Defence Minister Oleksii Reznikov, his Dutch counterpart Kajsa Ollongren, and the governor of the National Resilience Institute of Indonesia, Andi Widjajanto.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has published a 12-point position paper that says peace talks are the only way to end the Ukraine war. The West has been sceptical of the proposals, saying close ties with Russia made China unsuitable as a peacemaker.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EU move to link Chinese relations to Ukraine war unfair, envoy says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Cui, who was China&#39;s ambassador to the United States from 2013 to 2021, said the regional approach to peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific had worked for decades, despite a few hotspots here and there, unlike the approach taken by Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We used to look to Europe for their experience in regional integration, but nowadays, people in Europe and the Atlantic, can look to us,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should also learn something, a very important something, from your lack of success. I don&#39;t want to use the word &#39;failure&#39;, but lack of success.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asian way to peace was based on consultation, communication and economic cooperation, in addition to a “recognition of diversity and respect for diversity”, that allowed countries to follow their own policies, with none having the right to impose its will on others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ollongren disagreed with Cui, saying Europe&#39;s security was not mismanaged but hampered by Russia&#39;s disregard for how the continent&#39;s security was supposed to be managed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s Reznikov, who sat next to Cui on the panel, made it clear that Kyiv would not negotiate until the war against Russia was won.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We don&#39;t need a facilitator right now. Our country is still conducting war,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s special envoy for Eurasian affairs, Li Hui, upon returning to Beijing after a 12-day tour of Ukraine, Russia and four other European countries to find common ground on a way to end the Russian invasion, said it was “rather difficult” to get all parties to the negotiation table.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reznikov said world leaders willing to negotiate in the war had formed a “queue”, but Ukraine needed “the tools for us to finish this war”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has been more than 450 days since Russian military forces invaded eastern Ukraine in February last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his closing remarks, the Ukrainian minister floated the idea that China could perhaps convince Russia to end the war as Moscow&#39;s “older brother”, alluding to relations between the Soviet Union and the erstwhile Communist bloc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are not imposing our ideas on Russia, as if we are the older brother,” Cui responded. “This is not our tradition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reznikov also brushed off his Indonesian counterpart Prabowo Subianto&#39;s peace plan pitched at the Shangri-La Dialogue earlier on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan suggests an immediate ceasefire and cessation of hostilities, followed by a withdrawal of 15km (9.3 miles) each from their forward positions to form a demilitarised zone. The United Nations should form a monitoring and observance force to be deployed along the zone, and organise an eventual referendum in the disputed areas, the plan says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I will try to be polite,” Reznikov said, before starting his response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It sounds like [a] Russian plan, not [an] Indonesian plan,” he added, before branding the proposal a “strange plan” that had not been discussed with him.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>