<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[South Korean babies found dead in freezer amid search for 2,236 ‘missing’ infants]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3225051/south-korean-babies-found-dead-freezer-amid-search-2236-missing-infants?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/efbd268c-ec1b-4642-bfe1-0d7a632cae12_e0f2aff7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国警方正在寻求对一名被指控勒死两人的女子发出逮捕令观察人士称，这一案例突显了该国一些母亲缺乏支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在政府审计发现差异后，当局怀疑可能还会有许多其他此类案例报告的在医院出生的婴儿数量与出生后一个月必须进行当地登记的婴儿数量之间的差距，以便父母获得公共卫生和儿童保育服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员发现，从 2015 年初到 2022 年底， ，有超过2000名婴儿没有因此被登记。这八年期间登记的出生总数为 263 万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据差异促使官员调查数百起可能存在杀婴事件的失踪婴儿案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两起事件审计监察委员会 (BAI) 表示，审计人员随机挑选了 23 个病例（约占 2,236 名在医院出生但后来未登记的婴儿中的 1%），并要求当地官员确定他们是否安全，结果发现了死亡婴儿。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“这起严重的谋杀案是在仅仅 1% 的盲样抽样下发现的。韩联社援引 BAI 官员的话说，“因此，我们正在考虑调查所有”这 2,236 名婴儿，以了解他们发生了什么事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，当地政府官员出现在位于水原市距首尔30公里。当一名住在那里的三十多岁的妇女（她还有另外三个孩子，年龄分别为 12 岁、10 岁和 8 岁）不允许警察进入时，他们向她的公寓申请了搜查令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这会据韩联社报道，她后来告诉警方：“我们很难抚养他们，因为我们经济困难，而且我无力承担堕胎费用，所以我在生完孩子后立即杀死了他们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么母亲要杀人？在印度尼西亚，孩子的死亡促使寻找答案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方称，这名妇女涉嫌于 2018 年 11 月和 2019 年 11 月在医院生下孩子后不久勒死婴儿，并将尸体存放在冰箱中。据报道，她告诉丈夫她已经堕胎了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，韩国裁定将堕胎定为刑事犯罪违宪，为 2021 年起合法堕胎铺平了道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该程序是允许的怀孕期间最长 14 周，如果发生强奸或经济困难，则最长 28 周。堕胎费用通常为 100,000-200,000 韩元（77-154 美元），具体取决于怀孕的持续时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;堕胎药也可以在柜台上轻松获得，而女性则需要处方紧急避孕药。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在接受检查的另外 21 名婴儿中，一名在出生后约 70 天死于营养不良，另一名被留在孤儿院，还有三分之一据称被身份不明的养父母收养。 BAI 表示，警方还将最后一起案件作为涉嫌谋杀进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;婴儿死亡事件的发现正值韩国面临人口危机之际。其生育率（女性在育龄期平均生育孩子的数量）目前为 0.78，是世界上最低的国家之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国网络大学警察管理学教授李润浩 (Lee Yoon-ho) ” 说，当夫妇在经济上或精神上没有做好生孩子的准备时，杀婴事件往往会发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有必要在学校系统地教授有关怀孕婴儿和成为父母的信息和责任的课程。”未来，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国之前曾发生过杀婴事件，涉及在冰箱中发现尸体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017 年，一名 34 岁的妇女在监狱中被捕。南部城市釜山的两名婴儿在 2014 年和 2016 年出生后因忽视而死亡。她将他们的尸体保存在她与男友同住的家里的冰箱里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我把婴儿藏起来了。”据报道，金姓女子告诉警方，“我之所以把尸体藏起来，是因为我不确定孩子的父亲是谁，而且我担心如果我的同居男友知道了，他会和我分手。”她后来被判处两年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2006年，一名居住在首尔的37岁法国妇女被发现杀害了她在2002年和2003年生下的两个孩子。他们的尸体她返回法国度假时，被丈夫在冰箱里发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2006年，她在当地被警方逮捕，后被法国法院判处八年监禁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australian PM Albanese says Russian diplomat squatting on blocked embassy site not a threat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3225081/australian-pm-albanese-says-russian-diplomat-squatting-blocked-embassy-site-not-threat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 10:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/ffcb6fbf-17c0-477d-9bfb-8e4ecd9b6927_85333914.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯周五表示，拟议中的俄罗斯大使馆有争议的地点是在政府决定取消租约后，一名俄罗斯外交官擅自占地，这让情况变得安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，澳大利亚通过了一项法律，阻止俄罗斯将其大使馆从堪培拉郊区迁至黄金地段。该地点靠近议会和中国大使馆，理由是国家安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚报纸周四报道称，一名俄罗斯外交官在警察的监视下蹲在这片土地上，但警方无法逮捕他，因为他外交豁免权。它补充说，他一直在向该地点订购食品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚以安全威胁为由封锁议会附近的新俄罗斯大使馆&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“澳大利亚将捍卫我们的价值观，我们将捍卫我们的价值观。” “我们的国家安全，一个站在堪培拉寒冷的草地上的人不会对我们的国家安全构成威胁，”阿尔巴尼斯在周五的新闻发布会上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该网站是安全的，我们对我们的立场感到满意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯驻堪培拉大使馆没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫发言人德米特里·佩斯科夫上周表示，澳大利亚正在从事“恐俄”活动国营塔斯社报道称，取消租约是“歇斯底里”的行为，并补充说莫斯科可能会采取相应行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔巴内塞周五表示，政府预计“俄罗斯不会对我们的回应感到满意”正在对堪培拉网站进行“正式占有”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“俄罗斯最近在法律方面并不擅长，”Albanese 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科周三禁止了禁止 48 名澳大利亚人进入俄罗斯，据称这是对澳大利亚自身对该国长期制裁制度的报复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[James Cameron compares sub tragedy to Titanic disaster: ‘warnings went unheeded’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225088/james-cameron-compares-sub-tragedy-titanic-disaster-warnings-went-unheeded?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 11:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/73235ead-5cba-40e7-a109-80155d57a4dd_a31352b3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;泰坦尼克号导演詹姆斯·卡梅隆将海洋之门潜水器内爆与最初的泰坦尼克号灾难进行了比较。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;68 岁的卡梅伦指出了这两起案件中涉及的傲慢态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对泰坦尼克号灾难本身的相似性感到震惊，船长多次被警告有关他的船前面有冰的情况，但他在无月之夜全速驶入冰原，导致许多人死亡，”他告诉美国广播公司新闻。 “这是一场非常相似的悲剧，但警告却被忽视。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡梅伦本人已探索泰坦尼克号残骸约 33 次，他的 1997 年奥斯卡获奖影片将沉船重新带回了公众的聚光灯下。卡梅隆还执导过水下灾难电影《深渊》和多部深海纪录片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在拍摄票房巨作之余，卡梅隆还喜欢深海探索。 2012 年，他参观了海洋最深点马里亚纳海沟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“社区中的许多人都非常担心（OceanGate）潜艇，”卡梅伦告诉美国广播公司新闻。 “深潜工程领域的一些顶尖参与者甚至给该公司写信，称他们所做的事情过于实验性，无法载客，需要获得认证。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;专家提出2018 年泰坦尼克号潜艇失踪引发的安全担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据报道，有问题的 OceanGate 潜水器泰坦号也是 2018 年诉讼的对象。该公司时任海事运营总监戴维·洛奇里奇 (David Lochridge) 声称，在他指出车辆的安全问题后，公司解雇了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“潜水器前部的视口仅按照经过认证的压力建造洛奇里奇在投诉中写道：“尽管 OceanGate 打算将乘客带到 4,000 米深处，但它的深度却达到了 1,300 米。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰坦尼克号残骸位于海平面以下约 3,800 米的深度。当局认为泰坦潜水器内爆是由深海的巨大外部压力引起的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，《华尔街日报》报道称，美国海军秘密海洋声音探测系统在泰坦失去作用后不久就记录到了泰坦内爆。在它沉入大西洋水域约一小时零 45 分钟后发生接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在内爆中丧生的五人之一是法国探险家 Paul-Henri “PH” Nargeolet，卡梅伦将他描述为一位朋友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个非常小的社区，”他告诉美国广播公司新闻。 “我认识希盟25年了，他以这种方式惨死，我几乎无法接受。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific expects to deliver profit for first half of 2023, helped by ‘strong rebound’, one-off gain from reducing Air China stake]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3225093/hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-expects-deliver-profit-first-half-2023-helped-strong-rebound-one-gain?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 11:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/ba303f50-9f1b-47c7-b7a7-380cf6029ddc_8131e5ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港国泰航空预计今年上半年实现盈利这是自 2019 年以来的第一次，得益于资产处置的一次性收益，该集团在经历了多年的严格的 Covid-19 大流行规则后，规划了一条复苏之路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国泰集团已经看到了强劲的表现我们航空公司的业绩出现反弹。我们的现金流持续改善。”首席客户兼商务官 Lavinia Lau Hoi-zee 在该公司周五发布的最新流量报告中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该集团将录得一次性收益，预计为上半年，国航股份从 18.13% 减至 16.26%，实现 19 亿港元（合 2.43 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计该集团将在 2019 年实现综合利润刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继 2021 年和 2020 年出现赤字之后，该集团去年录得年度亏损 65 亿港元，原因是该航空公司努力应对严格的疫情限制，导致其大部分业务都受到影响。机队停飞并裁员数千人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着旅行限制的取消以及机票价格飙升，需求回升，该航空公司在 2022 年和今年都实现了现金产出。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国泰航空太平洋航空​​预计货运业务将在下半年起飞&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该集团（包括国泰航空及其廉价航空香港快运航空）已设定目标，到 2020 年达到疫情前的 70%国泰航空表示，上个月载客量为 1,417,906 人次，为 2019 年同月的 48%。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;上个月的载客率（衡量航空公司填补可用座位情况的指标）为 85%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“5 月对于我们的旅游业务来说又是一个好月份。我们继续逐步增加客运航班运力，并增加飞往美国、南亚和日本热门目的地的班次。”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过香港枢纽的过境交通量也令人鼓舞，有相当大的增幅。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;招聘计划可以帮助香港国泰航空“争夺中国大陆旅游市场”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该航空公司将于 8 月恢复飞往约翰内斯堡的航班，2019 年恢复飞往芝加哥的航班。 10月，以及12月至明年2月的新西兰基督城。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，5月份货运业务市场量基本持平，预计到9月底需求才会回升。&lt;/p>;&lt;刘说：“由于整体货运需求落后于供应，我们预计竞争将更加激烈。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，国泰航空表示将在年底向政府支付 15 亿港元的递延股息。那个月表现不佳。该公司欠政府作为 390 亿港元救助计划的一部分而收购的 195 亿港元优先股。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong declared free of Sars, after more than 100 days of fears and tears - from the SCMP archive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3224201/hong-kong-declared-free-sars-after-more-100-days-fears-and-tears-scmp-archive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/442b13f7-3b37-4f42-8627-3835b7b0e480_9b5af939.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;作者：Jimmy Cheung、Chow Chung-yan 和 Benjamin Wong&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;继昨天世界卫生组织正式宣布香港摆脱非典之后，香港已准备好花费 10 亿美元来重建其受损的形象，并吸引游客和企业回归。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员们表示，这一宣布是触发旨在宣传香港作为亚洲最适合游客和经商的地方的活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些计划包括在未来九个月内斥资 4 亿美元推动旅游业。免费机票、酒店优惠和餐厅折扣等你来拿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界卫生组织传染病执行主任戴维·海曼 (David Heymann) 在下午 3 点的一份声明中表示：“这是非常重大的成就。香港人口稠密，与中国的边界流动性大，是疫情最难控制的地区之一。这一成功意味着世界现在可以感到更加安全，免受非典威胁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界卫生组织表示，自最后一个病例被隔离以来已经过去了 20 天，感染链被认为已被打破。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它赞扬政府官员提供有关非典的诚实信息和开创性的控制措施。报告称：“令人欣慰的是，这些措施现已使香港取得了战胜病毒的胜利，尽管继续保持警惕仍然至关重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京，官员们已向世界卫生组织申请旅行警告取消。已连续 12 天没有新增病例，目前患者人数已低于 50 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港以非官方庆祝活动结束了为期三个月的抗疫斗争。世界卫生组织宣布倒计时后，学生们在学校排队将外科口罩扔进垃圾袋。尖沙咀和铜锣湾的商场因传统的舞狮表演而热闹非凡。但官员们表示，这是一个纪念和感恩节，而不是庆祝的日子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;非典的教训帮助香港淘大花园平静地面对Covid-19&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;行政长官董建华标志着&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每次想到那些因非典而去世或牺牲的人们，我和大家一样感到非常悲伤。也许庆祝这个词不太合适。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董先生敦促公众保持警惕，并表示政府将为未来的袭击做好准备。他说：“我们的名字已从名单中删除，但从其他地方的经验来看，我们必须提醒自己，这种情况可能会再次发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他承认政府最初对疫情的反应很被动.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们很被动，因为我们对病毒了解不多。我们那个阶段还很无知。但我们变被动为主动， ”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董建华回避了官员是否应该承担责任的问题，并表示将启动审查以做出改进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;驻香港的中国人民解放军表示已致函董先生，赞扬香港的成功，这是罕见的声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅游发展局主席周梁淑怡表示，入境人数需要一年时间才能达到达到非典前的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望8月和9月每月入境人数能达到100万，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“恢复需要时间我们正面临来自其他地区的激烈竞争，这些地区也迫切希望赢得旅客回来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作者：Ella Lee&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非典是香港的一个词。这一代人永远不会忘记。这是一个将被铭记的事件，就像我们的长辈被中日战争所困扰一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一场造成 296 人死亡、几乎使这座城市与世界隔绝的灾难。但这给了我们大家更多思考和关心的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昨天下午3点钟声敲响时，日内瓦世界卫生组织宣布香港已脱离非典，将香港从受影响地区名单中删除.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一宣布标志着香港“黑暗时代”的结束——这场危机始于65岁的广东医生刘建伦将病毒带入边境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港孔已经经历了三个多月的恐惧和泪水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于与家人隔离的非典患者和医护人员来说，他们感受到了分离的痛苦，也感受到了团聚的喜悦。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;在淘大花园，疫情导致 42 名居民死亡，现在社区意识比以往任何时候都更加强烈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数十名因病毒失去父母的孤儿知道他们面临着不确定的未来，但在至少他们知道香港人是关心香港人的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有在抗击非典的战斗中牺牲的八名医护人员，让我们看到了真正的英雄是什么样的——没有光环，只有一颗奉献的心。他们的名字和故事将被永远铭记。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年轻医生谢婉雯是第一位死于非典的公立医院医生，她为香港留下了一句座右铭：“风雨过后，会有彩虹” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然昨天人们摘下口罩，在兰桂坊欢呼喝香槟，但他们也需要提醒自己现实——非典仍然是一个巨大的威胁，随时可能再次袭来。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们有充分理由保持警惕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医学专家警告说，非典可能会在冬季卷土重来，但香港应对另一场疫情的能力仍存疑问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一些人问，如果公共卫生保健系统反应更迅速，非典危机是否本来就可以避免。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于王子是否应该采取行动，一直存在争论。威尔士医院应该早点关闭，以阻止病毒传播到社区。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;我们卫生官员的警觉性也受到质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在疫情爆发的早期阶段三月，卫生福利及食品局局长杨永强否认社区爆发疫情，但这一说法很快被证明是错误的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悉尼中文大学医学院院长当非典患者陆续入院时，钟尚志很快反驳了他的观点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港非典幸存者讲述应对 Covid-19 的惨痛教训&lt;/h3>;&lt;事实证明，公立医院对传染病过于开放。需要的地方没有足够的隔离设施或防护设备，使医务人员面临不必要的危险。在1,755名非典受害者中，有386名是医务人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些护士正在考虑对医院管理局恶劣的工作条件采取法律行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港与内地卫生当局之间的沟通不足非典期间也被曝光。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11月广东报告内地首例非典型肺炎后，广州市民开始抢购。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那部剧，对一些香港人来说，这更像是一场喜剧，未能引起卫生官员的注意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近有消息称，香港卫生部门负责人对内地当局一月份编写的一份报告一无所知，该报告概述了他们的症状和治疗该疾病的经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及为何香港无法获得该报告时，一名高级卫生官员表示：“我们不知道我们不知道什么；我们知道我们所知道的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港为这场致命的疫情爆发付出了巨大代价，但仍需汲取教训。就在一周前，卫生署副署长梁伯贤承认，他只是从传媒报道得知广东爆发乙型脑炎疫情，该病已造成18人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家组将开始对非典疫情处理情况进行调查。但由杨医生担任主席的该小组因其组成而受到批评，一些观察家质疑其公正性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨医生昨天写信给公立医院医务人员，表示：“团结和信念，医疗保健部门已经应对了近期非典的挑战，但传染病的威胁永远不会消失。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[TikTok COO Pappas, who defended firm against China fears, quits after 5 years at ByteDance-owned firm]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225083/tiktok-coo-pappas-who-defended-firm-against-china-fears-quits-after-5-years-bytedance-owned-firm?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 10:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/9fdef45b-c25e-4c21-a222-c8107bcb1808_46f7bd3f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;TikTok 的首席运营官 V Pappas 即将离开这个流行的社交媒体平台。在公司工作五年了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四早上发给员工并随后在 Twitter 上分享的一份说明中，使用“她/她”和“他们/他们”代词的帕帕斯表示，现在公司已经取得了很多成就成功后，她觉得现在是继续前进并专注于“创业热情”的最佳时机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok 首席执行官周受子在发给员工的一份说明中表示，Pappas 是公司最公开的面孔之一，将继续担任战略顾问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想借此机会感谢 V 多年来所做的许多贡献，”Chew 写道。 “在 TikTok 工作期间，他们在发展业务、为公司宣传、提升我们的产品供应和营销活动以及培育积极的创作者和用户社区方面发挥了重要作用。他们产生了重大而持久的影响，我们衷心感谢他们的不懈努力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pappas 于 2018 年加入 TikTok，担任总经理，并于 2020 年时任首席执行官凯文·梅耶尔 (Kevin Mayer) 离开后晋升为临时负责人。在该公司任职三个月后。这位前 YouTube 官员于次年担任首席运营官，并在国会山作证并接受媒体采访，为该公司提供了全力辩护，该公司一直受到担心其中国起源的立法者的审查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年来，TikTok 一直在否认其中国母公司字节跳动将与中国政府分享其流行视频共享应用程序的用户数据，或代表其传播宣传和错误信息的说法。该公司目前正在与拜登政府就其数据隐私计划进行谈判，今年早些时候，拜登政府威胁称，如果其中国所有者不出售其股份，将在全国范围内禁止该公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok 坚称，从未被要求这样做。中国政府要求共享美国用户数据，但如果要求的话，中国政府不会这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在给员工的电子邮件中，Chew 还宣布了公司的组织重组。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Zenia Mucha 曾在迪士尼担任传播主管近二十年，他将加入 TikTok，担任首席品牌和传播官，负责监督该公司的营销和公共关系部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chew 表示，TikTok 的幕僚长 Adam Presser 将加入 TikTok。成为公司运营主管。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[This time for Africa: Chinese lured by untapped potential say it’s ‘not optimal market’, but one ‘where we could survive’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3225014/time-africa-chinese-lured-untapped-potential-say-its-not-optimal-market-one-where-we-could-survive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/5a3fd25f-5cf9-4c5c-9267-888dce0f834b_9f2884cc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是有关旅游业当前状况的两部分系列中的第二个故事以及中国与非洲之间的业务。 5月，《华盛顿邮报》参加了坦桑尼亚驻华大使馆安排的为期两周的坦桑尼亚宣传之旅。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一月初重新开放边界后，旅程就开始了。就像一群迁徙的角马一样，成千上万的中国制造商出发前往国外参​​加展览会和贸易展览会，热衷于争取新客户，同时三年来首次与老客户见面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些制造商直奔拉斯维加斯消费电子展 (CES) 等活动，但由 30 名成员组成的代表团有不同的目的地 - 非洲的工业园区和贸易区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团队于 5 月从美国出发广东省佛山市商务局组织的一次考察活动，旨在帮助佛山产业走向世界并保持竞争力。他们的想法是，与许多其他目的地相比，非洲提供了未开发的机会，成本更低，贸易壁垒也更少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;代表团成员冯建平利用这一优势，获得了向非洲大陆各国的非洲家庭销售充电风扇的合同。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“非洲市场爆发期尚未到来，”小家电出口商表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“东南亚市场实际上已经饱和。它有[近7亿]人口，中国投资者太多，而非洲有14亿多人口，市场还有很多未满足的需求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲已经成功提升了自己的地位&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着国内生产成本的提高，这种供应链转移变得越来越普遍。上升，竞争加剧，运往美国的货物受到关税和非贸易壁垒的阻碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多中国生产商表示，他们担心被从美国供应链中剔除，并被东南亚或其他国家的同行取代。印度，由于世界最大的两个经济体之间的竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国企业现在必须硬着头皮——先是我们被美国打压，很快我们就会成为欧洲的目标，”冯并补充说，不祥之兆已经迫使他们下手了。 “我们要等到成为目标之后再制定计划吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲因素在哪里？她补充道，“虽然这不是最优市场，但却是我们能够生存的市场”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未来几天，湖南省省会长沙将启动第三届中国-非洲经贸博览会，预计6月29日至7月2日将有至少50个非洲国家和8个国际组织参加，进一步深化中国与非洲大陆的贸易联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“投资非洲是位于东非国家坦桑尼亚达累斯萨拉姆郊区的西诺坦工业园董事长 Janson Huang 表示：“这是一项更长期的商业战略。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;30 亿美元的贸易增长湖南申办中非枢纽&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;园区去年破土动工。未来五到八年建成后，面积将接近四平方英里，其宏伟目标是吸引超过200家企业入驻，创造50万个就业岗位，带来约30亿美元的直接投资，年收益率60亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈到产业链转移，黄说东南亚是未来五年值得关注的地区，非洲未来十年潜力巨大， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚有其优势，比如靠近中国，基础设施和产业链更加成熟，但“现在在东南亚建设工业园区已经被认为是晚了，黄证实道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们参观了那里的一些工业园区，”他解释道。 “这里的土地价格约为每平方米 150 美元至 200 美元，而达尔地区的土地价格为每平方米 15 美元”——至少便宜 10 倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多种因素导致非洲大陆的房价上涨无论是作为新兴市场还是作为搬迁目的地，都更具吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲人口相对年轻且增长迅速，因此提供了一个潜力巨大的广阔消费市场 - 到 2050 年，每四个人中就有一个生活在非洲根据联合国的预测，地球预计属于非洲。目前，每6.5人中就有1人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相对较低的劳动力成本和丰富的自然资源，包括矿产和能源储备，也带来了利润丰厚的投资机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着贸易随着中非关系不断加强，中国投资者正在利用这些有利因素建立互利关系，抓住非洲的巨大潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早在2009年，中国就超过美国成为全球第二大经济体非洲最大的双边贸易伙伴。根据中国官方数据，去年双边贸易额增至创纪录的 2820 亿美元，是 2000 年总额的 26 倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至 2020 年底，中国对非洲直接投资的份额为中国商务部的数据显示，这一数字为473.5亿美元。但中非贸易理事会2021年的报告预计，由于部分企业未注册、部分投资未计算在内，中国企业在非洲的实际投资不应低于560亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该委员会的报告指出，在中国投资中，70%以上来自私营部门。这些资金大部分投入了工业园区和工厂，这有助于促进东道国的工业化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“非洲张开双臂欢迎中国投资，”非洲外交使团团长马丁·姆帕纳 (Martin Mpana) 表示。 China and the Cameroonian ambassador to China, in April, adding that the African side eagerly anticipates more Chinese enterprises visiting the continent to explore opportunities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aside from the private sector, the most notable Chinese investment in Africa has come via Beijing&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative – a decade-long government effort to link economies into a China-centred trading network, including many African nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Washington has repeatedly levelled accusations that Chinese investment activities in Africa have burdened countries with loans they cannot repay. Beijing has rejected this notion.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China denies creating &#39;debt trap&#39; for African countries&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, some private Chinese businesses have expressed concerns about security and policy matters on the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;High-profile attacks on Chinese citizens working in restive regions have made headlines and fuelled such concerns. For example, a gunman killed nine Chinese workers at a gold mine site in March. This came after a Chinese citizen was gunned down in Ethiopia in January, prompting Beijing&#39;s embassy in Addis Ababa to order its citizens to evacuate from high-risk areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dai Jufeng, a new-materials manufacturer in Foshan who joined the delegation to Africa in May, said that security concerns and policy matters are the most crucial considerations when it comes to exploring the African market. And if he does decide to do business on the continent, he would prefer to collaborate with a Chinese-funded industrial park.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are not familiar with the local environment,” Dai said. “And the industrial parks, having been there for a long time, must have more resources and channels. If we venture out there and want to make headway, we must use their resources and connections to expand our business.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The investor said he has also been hesitant to make such a move because his factory is largely automated, and it mainly serves Chinese construction contractors and interior-design firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It might make more sense for clothing and shoe manufacturers” to invest in Africa, he said. “It is also unrealistic to move the whole industrial chain all the way over. The procurement of raw materials, as well as the replacement and storage of equipment parts, would be a huge challenge.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nonetheless, Dai said he has felt compelled to consider overseas options, particularly as his business was severely impacted by the property and economic downturn in recent years. But while acknowledging that Africa seems like a promising market, he is more interested in mature markets such as Vietnam or Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Electricity would be a big issue – the power went out three, four times a day in the hotel we stayed at in South Africa, indicating serious electricity shortages,” he said. “Also, the [electricity] expenses go up 20 per cent every year – that would be demanding for a high-energy-consumption enterprise like us.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s a tricky time&#39;: firms adjust to new reality as China pull-out intensifies&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Over the past two decades, Chinese investments in such industrial parks in Africa have increased significantly, and special economic zones have long been promoted as opportune instruments to emulate the development trajectory seen in China, noted Tim Zajontz, a research fellow with the Centre for International and Comparative Politics at Stellenbosch University in South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing actively promotes Chinese investments in industrial parks and special economic zones as part of wider efforts to &#39;export&#39; its own development experience to Africa,” Zajontz said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many African governments have incentivised investments in such zones in the hope that they would kick-start economic diversification, create jobs [and have] spillover effects in other sectors of the economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, the results have been mixed across the continent. Some zones have added production capacity – for instance in Ethiopia&#39;s leather-processing industry – while other zones were criticised for underperforming in terms of boosting manufacturing and creating jobs, although tax holidays and regulatory exemptions were granted to investors.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many African governments have offered Chinese investors loose regulations, tax incentives and public land, or have set up necessary facilities inside such zones and built transport infrastructure linking them with other parts of the country or neighbouring and overseas markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Zajontz suspects that “future policy support will likely depend on the success of existing industrial parks and special economic zones”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China-Tanzania ties sealed with 15 agreements during presidential visit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Among the notable Chinese-funded industrial parks in Africa, several stand out for their size and significance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Lekki Free Trade Zone in Nigeria, backed by substantial Chinese investment, is making significant strides in promoting industrialisation and attracting foreign businesses. This expansive industrial park covers an area of 155 sq km and is strategically positioned near Lagos, Nigeria&#39;s economic hub. Its integrated infrastructure and favourable investment environment have enticed a wide range of industries, including manufacturing, logistics, and energy, contributing to Nigeria&#39;s economic diversification and job creation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Eastern Industrial Zone in Ethiopia has also facilitated the transfer of technology, skills and employment opportunities to the local population, with a focus on sectors such as textile and garment manufacturing. The park has played a pivotal role in enhancing Ethiopia&#39;s manufacturing capabilities and positioning the country as a regional manufacturing hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Chinese-funded industrial parks will bring much-needed FDI, as opposed to &#39;hot money&#39;,” said XN Iraki, an economics and management professor at the University of Nairobi. “They will also bring competition, which could improve the quality of goods and services, as well as lower prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a win-win situation. The Chinese make money and we get jobs. The government welcomes Chinese investors, as they will bring technology, new skills, competition and link Africa to the bigger Chinese market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alongside the growing number of Chinese industrial parks in Africa, businesses from other countries are also building industrial parks on the continent. India, Turkey, Germany, Japan and South Korea, for example, have shown a rising presence in Africa via their own industrial parks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Chinese investors are very well networked, which allows them to set up new supply or value chains rapidly,” Zajontz said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have also proven to be highly adaptive to local political and economic context factors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“African governments, for their part, hope to see further Chinese investments in sectors that are deemed essential for Africa&#39;s industrialisation. Expectations are obviously high that Chinese industrial parks create jobs in the so-called formal economy and boost manufacturing and processing in Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Yet, their actual impact on local economic development very much depends on how well such investments are integrated with local businesses and suppliers. Industrial parks and investment zones aren&#39;t magic bullets. They require comprehensive industrial policies that focus on maximising local value-added [industries] and creating spillover effects beyond certain investment enclaves.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong rolls out first AI curriculum for junior secondary students, including on ChatGPT, with ‘lives definitely affected by artificial intelligence’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3224954/hong-kong-rolls-out-first-ai-curriculum-junior-secondary-students-including-chatgpt-lives-definitely?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 10:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/22/2c6a298b-6c97-4020-b018-808a8c2c54ed_d712ae93.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has rolled out the first curriculum in the city on artificial intelligence for junior secondary students, including on the use of ChatGPT as well as ethics and social impacts of the technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a memo distributed by the Education Bureau to more than 450 public secondary schools, teachers are asked to incorporate a total of 10 to 14 hours of AI education into the information and communication technology (ICT) subject for Form One to Three students from September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students are expected to learn basic concepts of AI, computer vision, computer speech and language, robotic reasoning, AI ethical issues, and the resulting social impact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Contents of the curriculum are adopted from deliverables of “AI for the Future Project”, an AI education project for secondary students launched in 2017 by Chinese University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nearly 50 per cent of the curriculum focuses on ethics and social impacts of AI,” said Yam Yeung, a research professor at the university.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is important for students to know powerful tools like AI could be both good and bad for society. I hope students can have a good understanding of how to use AI well,” added Yam, who headed the “AI for the Future Project”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong Baptist University begins ChatGPT trial for teachers, but concerns remain&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Generative artificial intelligence, which is the latest development of AI and represented by ChatGPT by OpenAI, is also included in the curriculum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students will be taught to generate pictures and write letters with mirror sites of ChatGPT, which is currently not directly available in Hong Kong, as well as to evaluate the quality of the tool&#39;s deliverables.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students are also expected to work on group projects, in which they first identify existing problems and solve them with AI knowledge taught in class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Students may not take up jobs in innovation and technology in the future, but their lives will definitely be affected by AI, no matter positively or negatively,” said Henry Lin Ting-kit, the bureau&#39;s chief curriculum development officer for technology education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So we believe it is necessary for them to have some knowledge about AI and cultivate a correct attitude towards the technology.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;University of Hong Kong allows staff to use ChatGPT but students still banned&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to Lin, about 70 per cent of public secondary schools have included AI elements in their curriculums, but he wishes to revamp those with the bureau&#39;s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I hope schools will incorporate our AI curriculum into their course design for the coming academic year starting this September,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lin added that the bureau would also offer workshops on AI teaching to more than 1,000 public secondary school ICT teachers from September.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;No plans to let Hong Kong officials use ChatGPT, minister says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Alongside the AI curriculum for junior secondary students, the bureau will also introduce an enriched curriculum on coding for Primary Four to Six pupils in the coming academic year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government introduced coding education to Primary Four to Six students back in 2017, and nearly all public primary schools had included coding in their curriculum, Lin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The enriched curriculum “covers basic computational thinking concepts, namely abstraction, algorithm and automation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Booklets for the curriculum show that students will learn coding with Scratch, a programming language designed for schoolchildren, to complete tasks including content visualisation and game design.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indian carriers’ record plane deals could pose ‘serious threat’ to Middle East aviation hubs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3225078/indian-carriers-record-plane-deals-could-pose-serious-threat-middle-east-aviation-hubs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 10:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/23/7679804e-bd51-41a2-8583-a694b82872d0_f828ec17.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s IndiGo ordered a massive 500-aircraft from Airbus this week, overtaking rival Air India&#39;s record order of 470 planes from Boeing and Airbus earlier this year, setting the stage for one of the world&#39;s most ambitious aviation expansion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the two historic orders have injected fresh life into a moribund sector that is recovering from the aftermath of Covid-19, the size of the deal has sown doubts about whether the market will be able to support such a large expansion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts say there is unlikely to be a dearth of customers in the nation that recently became the world&#39;s most populous, with the only hurdle being whether the deal will help remove red tape that has for years hobbled the country&#39;s potential as an aviation hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India is a different animal from what it used to be. The airlines would not be making these orders if they were not confident of the infrastructure development,” said Mayur Patel, Asia head at global travel data provider OAG Aviation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Air India faces difficult comeback despite &#39;eye-popping&#39; aircraft order&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The fleet expansion comes at a time when India is preparing to open Asia&#39;s largest airport next year in the city of Jewar in the northern Indian state of Uttar Pradesh. The Indian government plans to spend 980 billion rupees (US$11.9 billion) by 2025 on constructing and modernising airports within the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2017, at least 73 airports have been operationalised under India&#39;s regional connectivity scheme – a plan to link smaller towns and cities to the domestic air travel network.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India is embarking on a hub strategy. It takes three to tango to make it work – the government, airlines and airports,” Patel said. “The geographical location of India is such that it can rival places like Doha and Dubai.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IndiGo commands a 60 per cent share of India&#39;s aviation market, which is the world&#39;s fastest growing. With the latest order, Patel said the airline would be able to consolidate its position in the domestic market and launch new routes to the Middle East, Southeast Asia and further destinations such as Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Indian airlines expansion would be a serious threat to Middle East hubs. It will also have an impact on Southeast Asia as IndiGo is planning direct flights,” Patel said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IndiGo did not provide a breakdown of the aircraft configuration it was planning, but industry executives said it was likely to opt for a mix of A320, A321 and A321 XLR (Extra Long Range) that would be decided closer to delivery dates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Air India&#39;s order earlier this year is also set to more than double its fleet from its present 228 planes. It also has options to buy another 370 jets. The state-run airline was acquired by India&#39;s Tata group last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two Indian carriers appear to be preparing to grow their presence in domestic and international markets over the course of a decade, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Both airlines will dramatically expand their fleet capabilities and their global networks, but this will take time to implement,” said Gary Bowerman, director of Check-In Asia, a travel consulting and consumer research firm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Air India uses the phrase &#39;transformation journey&#39; while IndiGo refers to &#39;defining its long-term future&#39;, so both airlines are in the early stages of long-term plays,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s finally started&#39;: hope for aviation&#39;s recovery at Singapore Airshow&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s domestic air traffic hit a record high with 456,082 passengers flying on a single day on April 30 – spurred by a post-pandemic recovery. More than 400,000 passengers took flights daily in May, breaching the mark of 13 million in a month for the first time since December 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The fleet expansion by IndiGo and Air India is likely to cramp market space for smaller Indian carriers such as Spicejet and Akasa Air. But even regional carriers should be prepared to face the heat, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a clear statement of intent, particularly as competition intensifies from airlines in the Middle East, Turkey, Singapore and China,” Bowerman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are going to see highly intensified competition between the major carriers, and business models and customer engagement strategies will evolve and transform.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, the Indian government denied an application by United Airlines to code-share with Emirates on the routes between the United Arab Emirates and India, saying the proposal fell outside the existing UAE-India bilateral air services agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Emirates is the largest operator in the country with flights to nine Indian cities. Last September, United Airlines and Emirates announced a commercial agreement that resulted in United starting scheduled services between Newark and Dubai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patel said denying the application signalled the Indian government&#39;s intention to level “the playing field” as the proposal would have resulted in more competition for Air India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the years, Air India has ceded ground to rivals on lucrative routes such as those serving the Middle East, which are used by thousands of migrant workers and where it once had an edge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The success of the two Indian carriers in the coming months would depend on their ability to not just fill up planes but the kind of yields they were able to generate, said Shukor Yusof, founder and analyst at Malaysia-based Endau Analytics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This will be the sole critical determinant for both IndiGo and Air India,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indian airlines have been affected by high aviation turbine fuel (ATF) prices, which have been exacerbated by a depreciation of the Indian rupee against the US dollar. Fuel costs determine about a third of an airline&#39;s expenses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a report by rating agency ICRA, ATF prices stood at 121,013 rupees per kilolitre in the financial year 2023 and 90,431 rupees in June, compared to 64,715 rupees three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The Indian] government is doing much but not enough. India is in a sweet spot today so [Indian Prime Minister Narendra] Modi has to exploit it,” Yusof said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How China’s top electronics recycling platform ATRenew is giving used gadgets a new life]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3225048/how-chinas-top-electronics-recycling-platform-atrenew-giving-used-gadgets-new-life?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/22/045b33d0-2926-43c0-be54-2c9498b8d320_a0b0f9d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;ATRenew, the operator of China&#39;s largest trading platform for pre-owned electronics, hopes to cash in on the growing resale market as people cut down on spending amid a slowing economy and give a boost to the circular economy, an executive said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the pre-owned market still has much room to grow given the increasing consumer awareness in China, ATRenew is looking to expand AHS Recycle – better known in China as AiHuiShou – to other segments like clothing and luxury goods, and even sell products made from recycled waste, said Jeremy Ji, director of corporate development and investor relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Consumers have slowed down their spending, especially this year,” said Ji. “Under the current economic conditions, people will have stronger motivation to reuse or [go for] trade-ins. ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company also saw growing demand from consumers in trading more categories of pre-owned products, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shanghai-based company saw trade-ins of consumer electronics jump over 60 per cent year on year on its platform, and double on JD.com, the Chinese e-commerce giant that owns a 33 per cent stake, during the recently concluded midyear 618 shopping festival.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese government has been actively promoting a circular economy to support the country&#39;s sustainability goals and achieve net-zero emissions by 2060. The National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), China&#39;s top economic planner, made the circular economy a priority in 2021 with the release of a five-year plan, calling on society to recycle and reuse materials to conserve water and energy as well as reduce greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s domestic second-hand consumer market exceeded 1 trillion yuan in 2020 and is expected to cross 3 trillion yuan by 2025, according to a report by Tencent-backed second-hand e-commerce platform Zhuanzhuan and consultancy Frost &amp; Sullivan in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Buying a used smartphone can reduce carbon emissions by at least 25 kilograms, compared with buying a new phone, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, ATRenew posted first-quarter revenue of 2.87 billion yuan (US$399.8 million), a 30 per cent increase year on year. Net profit rose to a record 44.4 million yuan, a third consecutive quarterly profit since its debut on the New York Stock Exchange in June 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We believe consumers&#39; willingness and demand for purchasing pre-owned products will remain strong in the long term,” said Ji.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under a slowing economy and with youth unemployment hitting a record 20.8 per cent last month, consumer attitudes are shifting. E-commerce firms such as Taobao, owned by Alibaba Group Holding, and JD.com experienced a relatively quiet 618 shopping festival. The companies did not release gross merchandise value numbers due to weak consumer spending this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Price remains a dominant factor when Chinese consumers make purchase decisions,” said Ji, adding that second-hand trading platforms allow consumers to make purchases at a much lower price and trade-in programmes help society to put idle goods to better use.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ATRenew wants to utilise its 1,935 stores and 2,015 self-service recycling facilities in 269 cities across China and its AiHuiShou platform to provide consumers with a one stop for trade-ins and services for pre-owned electronic products, such as quality check, data migration, personal data erasing and cashbacks, to populate the concept of a circular economy, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, ATRenew expanded its product recycling categories to include pre-owned cameras, luxury bags, watches, gold as well as high-end liquor, shoes and clothing in its stores. It also partnered with companies such as Nestle and Chinese sportswear maker Li Ning to produce coffee mugs, T-shirts and bags made from recycled waste such as coffee residue and plastic bottles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Compared to mature pre-owned markets like in the US and Japan, China&#39;s circular economy still has much to develop,” said Ji, pointing to sales of pre-owned smartphones, which account for about 5 per cent of the total for the segment on JD.com.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the upgrading of technology and acceleration of product iteration, there is a lot of room for development in China&#39;s pre-owned trading market, Liu Rui, director of the Institute of Ecology and Environment under the Yangtze River Delta Region Institute of Tsinghua University, said at the Two Sessions meeting this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial rewards could encourage more people to take in the second-hand goods market, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singaporeans gobble up dirt cheap Malaysian durians as prices crash amid plentiful harvest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225075/singaporeans-gobble-dirt-cheap-malaysian-durians-prices-crash-amid-plentiful-harvest?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.23 09:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/23/837f492c-dc37-4b6e-87ce-4e895ca1c80c_11270e03.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Singaporeans love durians. And this year, the spiky and pungent fruit is in such abundance that it can be found in claw machines, giving enthusiasts a chance to catch one for just a dollar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A surplus in major producer Malaysia has pushed prices in the city state down to levels never seen before. Even with demand staying high, premium varieties like Musang King were selling for as cheap as S$3 (US$2.24) a kilogram earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the lowest price I&#39;ve ever seen,” said Sam Tan, executive director of MAPC Sdn. Bhd., a major durian supplier. “Typically, a Musang King will go at S$12 to S$13 per kilogram,” said Tan, who&#39;s also president of the Malaysia Durian Exporters Association and has been in the industry for 12 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farmers in Malaysia, which supplies more than 85 per cent of Singapore&#39;s durians, have been diversifying into the fruit since 2016 as prices jumped, instead of growing traditional crops like palm oil and rubber. Durian trees take at least five to seven years to start producing, contributing to the bountiful harvest this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore police investigate after woman loses life savings in durian scam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A record-breaking heatwave earlier this year has also affected the quality of the fruit, helping to push prices lower. That&#39;s all good news for durian enthusiasts in Singapore, which imports more than 100,000 kilograms of the fruit a day from Malaysia in peak season.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It isn&#39;t just Malaysia ramping up output, however. Farmers in Thailand and Vietnam have also switched to durians from crops such as rubber and coffee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their main target customer is China, where the durian is rapidly becoming the most popular imported fruit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The surge in investment in Malaysia was driven by booming Chinese demand, according to Lim Chin Khee, a durian consultant based in Pahang who has spent more than two decades in the industry. He blames quality issues for the drop in prices this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hot and dry weather has resulted in 50 per cent to 60 per cent of the durians developing burnt seeds and having less “meat,” MAPC&#39;s Tan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With their creamy, custard-like texture, musky flavour and an aroma so strong they&#39;re banned on public transport in many Southeast Asian countries, durians have something of a cultlike following.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singaporean durian fan Melissa Yap, 55, said she and her husband have been eating the fruit up to three times a week due to the cheap prices. “We are really happy that durians are more affordable now and will certainly be eating more in the coming weeks.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>