<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Dreamed about my dad last night’: Chinese girl, 7, filmed at grave of father reading him stories moves mainland social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226067/dreamed-about-my-dad-last-night-chinese-girl-7-filmed-grave-father-reading-him-stories-moves?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/bdf9955c-c374-4966-925d-07bb52536fe1_e4732196.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国社交媒体被一段七岁儿童的情感视频所吸引女孩在父亲的坟前读故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自中国中部河南省的女孩林丽去年在一次溺水事故中失去了父亲，当时他一直在中国东部钓鱼。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频拍摄当天，即6月23日，林告诉姑姑：“我昨晚梦见了我爸爸”，并恳求去附近扫墓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;林的阿姨说，父亲每次从1000公里外回来，都会给林看书、讲故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从林去世后，林主要和奶奶住在一起，没有父亲的工资，她的姨妈补充道，他们一直在艰难度日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的母亲患有长期的临床抑郁症，在林还是婴儿的时候就离开了，从那以后他们就再没有见过面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;小女孩的阿姨说，由于林的母亲还活着，她没有资格获得向孤儿发放的儿童福利证书，该证书每月提供 800 元（110 美元）的经济援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无奈之下，林阿姨向当地一家慈善机构寻求帮助，视频当天，该慈善机构的志愿者正在探访，回应她的求助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频中林对父亲的浓浓依恋感动了很多人。大陆社交媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看到一个小孩子如此体贴，真是令人心碎”，一位网友表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“别人最害怕的‘鬼’是某人另一位网友表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国社交媒体经常被有关孩子们在失去父母一方或双亲后承受悲伤的故事所吸引。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三月份，一个为期三年的-来自中国东部的老女孩的母亲去年因癌症去世，她被拍到亲吻逝去亲人的放大照片后，在网上走红。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What is your perfect death? Hong Kong to give terminally ill patients more say over how and where they die]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226286/what-your-perfect-death-hong-kong-give-terminally-ill-patients-more-say-over-how-and-where-they-die?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/ad975943-5376-4225-b218-277e8e4ca180_4fa2b5c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当97岁的曹冠培想到死亡时，他很确定关于一件事，他希望能在自己已经住了六年的养老院里去世，周围都是他认识的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最好是在一个熟悉的地方，环境优美的地方平静地离开。” ，”这位前交易员说，他有五个孩子、八个孙子和三个曾孙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到了时机成熟时，他不想被送往医院并面临复苏或强制喂食以保住自己的生命。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“延迟死亡，让我多受几天苦有什么意义？如果是我的时间，我应该去。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，如果他的健康状况恶化，蓝田的疗养院会先把他转移到临终关怀室，住24-小时的医疗护理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，根据香港现行法律，一旦死亡临近，他就必须被送往医院。运送他的救护人员将进行复苏，即使他早些时候表示不希望这样做。而且他的死亡必须在医院得到证明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，所有养老院的死亡都必须报告，并需要警方和法医病理学家采取后续行动，必要时进行尸检。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;香港政府正计划修改香港法律，以改善临终关怀，并赋予人们更多法律权力来决定身患绝症时接受的医疗治疗，以及更多死亡地点的选择。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;经过2019年的公众咨询，上个月对该法律提出了多项修正案。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港绝症患者可能在医疗和死亡方面拥有更多发言权&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;《死因裁判官条例》的修订旨在排除在安老院和残疾人士院舍内自然死亡的情况，只要该人被诊断出患有末期疾病、在过去 14 天内接受过医生治疗，并且医生确认死亡没有可疑之处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对《消防条例》的拟议修改将允许护理人员尊重患者不接受复苏的意愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这必须在预先指示，由精神健全的成年人签署的一份法律文件，表明他们在临终时不希望接受的治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然目前没有立法规定该文件的法律地位，这导致了不确定性在患者中，政府计划根据拟议的变更赋予指令法定权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“请勿尝试心肺复苏”命令，目前针对精神上无行为能力或未成年且依赖的人发布也将在法定规定的表格上确定他们在身患绝症时最好不要接受心肺复苏的时间。遵守这些命令的急救人员将免除法律责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“理所当然”：为什么香港家庭选择亲人在家中去世&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;医生和疗养院经营者接受《华盛顿邮报》采访的人士对这些变化表示欢迎，称其是改善该市临终关怀的一大进步，但呼吁采取更多措施来提高公众和医疗保健专业人员的认识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;香港姑息医学会的陈慧灿医生表示，垂死的病人应该对自己在家中或疗养院的生活有更多的掌控权，让他们在生命的最后几天有更多的时间与亲人在一起。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“在熟悉的环境中，患者会感到不那么焦虑，更舒服，”拥有 20 多年绝症治疗经验的专家陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家庭成员也可以全天候陪伴临终者，不像医院有固定探视时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“医院环境比较吵闹，充满了各种机器的声音，而且周围还有其他病人，隐私性也较差。 ，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她对心肺复苏方面的变化表示欢迎，并表示这种复苏的弊大于利，对于那些垂死的人来说，可能会导致肋骨骨折和内脏出血。&lt;/p>;&lt; “现阶段心肺复苏的成功率非常低，接近于零，”她说。 “治疗没有效果，反而会带来很多不适和并发症。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“全家人都来送别”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;61岁退休人士杨子湘回忆道3月初，他和家人在青衣疗养院的母亲最后24小时内，与母亲正式告别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他86岁的母亲已经在疗养院待了更长时间。一年多后，她被转移到那里的临终关怀室。近20名家人设法见到她最后一面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们可以一一去她的房间告别，”杨回忆道。 “我告诉她，‘妈妈，我很抱歉小时候调皮，惹你生气了。’”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港立法会议员呼吁建立患者临终指导数据库&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;虽然母亲已经昏迷不醒，但家人可以在身体上安慰她，抱着她，抚摸她的脸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果她住院了，全家人都不可能说再见，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的母亲在被转移到医院之前就去世了，所以必须报告死亡情况。这意味着警方必须跟进，尸体必须送往公共太平间检查，涉及疗养院额外的文书工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨说这些额外的程序似乎很麻烦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;由于香港现行法律，大多数死亡发生在医院。从2012年到2021年，每年有43,000至51,000人死亡，其中五分之四以上发生在公立和私立医院。其余的大部分发生在特定的有执照的疗养院，然后才能将个人送往医院或在家中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 DoctorNow 称，Covid-19 大流行引发了在家死亡的新需求，一家为人们家中提供医疗服务的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其首席运营官David Wong Chuk-hin表示：“在疫情期间，人们不想住院，因为不允许访客入院。他们还担心医院环境恶劣，容易被感染。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在家中去世，只要被诊断为绝症，或者在医院内接受过医生检查，就不必报告。死亡前14天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司成立于2015年，2019年开始提供在家临终服务，次年处理的家庭死亡人数不超过20例。此后，这一数字不断上升，已处理了超过 400 起家庭死亡事件，其中大多数发生在公共屋村或政府资助的单位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去十年，香港也有越来越多的人签署预先医疗指示。 2012 年至 2021 年间，公立医院患者签署拒绝心肺复苏术的医疗文件数量从 150 份增加到 1,742 份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然在家中临终在香港相对较新，但黄说，在家中的安排姑息治疗和死亡在台湾和日本等地已经进行了数十年。台湾多达五分之二的死亡发生在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡还计划到 2027 年将医院死亡比例从目前的 61% 降低到 51%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;“为什么要为死人叫救护车？”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港老年学学会会长梁文福博士希望，拟议的法例修改不仅意味着更好的终结-对临终者的生命关怀，也减轻了医院的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们可以顺利完成生命旅程，而不影响医院急诊室的服务。这样不是更好吗，不浪费社会资源了？”他问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人已经死了，为什么还要叫救护车、去医院急诊室挂号、开死亡证明、送尸体去太平间？”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;梁振英希望安老院也能为晚期疾病的院友提供更多临终关怀，避免重复送院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，每100名护理人员中，约有10至20人每年都有家庭居民死亡，估计一半的死亡与他们已知的疾病有关，如器官衰竭、癌症或晚期痴呆症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在生命的最后六个月到一年内，即使在死亡不可避免的情况下，其中一些居民也会被反复送往医院，他形容这是“一种折磨”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们可能会接受大量的检查和治疗并出院，只是为了再次被录取，”他说。 “这对他们的家人来说也是一种痛苦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在长沙湾经营一家安老院的Rebecca Chau Tsang已经准备了一间临终关怀室，尽管她的住户不能还没用过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她希望一旦法律允许对养老院的死亡进行证明，就能使用它。它将需要电热毯和医疗床等设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“立法通过后，它就可以随时投入使用，”她说。 “我们希望老人能顺利离开。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周说，希望到时候政府能就如何处理养老院的自然死亡问题给出明确的指导方针。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;护理人员必须遵守预先指示，他们也希望在困难情况下得到明确的指示和保护，例如当家庭成员对某人的治疗意见不一时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪氏协会主席张春杰 (Jang Chun-kit)香港消防处救护员工会说：“大儿子可能会出示父亲的预先指示，说不需要复苏，但另一个儿子可能会说他们的父亲希望活下去。如果我们进行复苏，应该有豁免条款。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“初级保健医生可以提高意识”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;医学专家表示，法律的修改是重要的第一步，但需要更多的教育来提高公众对临终护理选择的认识，护理院行业也需要受到关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老年学协会的 Leung 预计，随着立法的变化，疗养院对姑息服务的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要为疗养院的高级、中级和一线人员提供更多培训。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;姑息医学专家陈说，初级保健水平的医生可以帮助促进患者的临终教育，并研究预先护理计划。 “当人们来进行健康检查或患有小病时，医生可以提供一些教育，在更理想的环境中讨论预先护理计划和预先指示。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;临终者可以告诉我们什么如何生活：姑息治疗的教训&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中文大学公共卫生教授、前卫生部长杨永强在 2017 年完成了一项政府委托的研究，研究了该市的临终关怀，他说初级保健医生还可以为希望在社区死亡的患者提供实际支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地区卫生中心可以协调其初级保健医生网络，为在家中垂死的患者提供姑息治疗，包括疼痛控制，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨还认为，立法改革可能会促使更多人考虑他们最后几天的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一旦我们谈论这个问题，人们就需要理解你所做的决定。当你没有足够的心理承受能力的时候，就去做吧。每个人的时机都不同，但至少你开始了，你有一个工具，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Young China science journal The Innovation joins international rankings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226280/young-china-science-journal-innovation-joins-international-rankings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/c67fc3d0-d2c0-46e6-8624-d8bc5291e7bf_7fd7315a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由一群年轻的中国科学家推出三年后，经过同行评审开放获取的在线期刊已成为世界顶级的多学科出版物之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新——主要依靠个人储蓄运行，没有官方支持——首次被收录在科睿唯安最新的年度期刊中周三发布的引文报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这本英文期刊的“影响因子”(IF) 为 32.1，位居第三位，仅次于全球两本被引用最多和最受尊敬的出版物。类别——《自然》，IF 为 64.8，《科学》，IF 为 56.9。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新超越了一些著名的国际出版物——包括《美国国家科学院院刊》(PNAS)、《美国国家科学院院刊》，其得分为 11.2，击败了所有期刊IF报告由英美分析公司科睿唯安（Clarivate）自1975年起每年编制，被认为是主要学术期刊的权威指标期刊在各自领域的表现和影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据科睿唯安称，期刊的 IF 大致是通过将过去一年的引用次数除以前两年发表的文章总数来计算的。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;IF排名是研究人员决定向何处提交稿件时的主要参考。一些大学和研究机构在评估其研究人员的学术表现时也会使用这些报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新报告对来自 112 个国家的 21,000 多种学科和多学科期刊进行了评估，《The Innovation》的总体排名为第 79 位.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国排名最高的学科期刊是《Cell Research》，IF 为 44.1，由上海生命科学研究院与英国自然出版集团合作出版，涵盖细胞和分子生物学。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《创新》杂志社长兼创始人之一陈公爵表示，中国对科学研究的巨大贡献是这本北京期刊迅速崛起的一个因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国已经世界上近 30% 的学术论文由他们撰写，但所拥有的期刊数量却不足 2%。这种巨大的科学产出是我们在短时间内快速增长的主要原因。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着美国份额的下降，中国贡献了世界一半的储能研究&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;该杂志的成功证明了陈和他在中国科学院的同事们的正确性，他们在 2016 年发现需要本土版本的《科学》和《自然》来配合中国作为科学强国的崛起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;当他们的支持请求被国家资助机构拒绝时，年轻的科学家们决定继续前进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;100 多名创始成员每人自掏腰包数千美元来购买这本期刊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈辞去了癌症研究员的工作，领导编辑部，而其他人则贡献了大量时间来运营该期刊。在线会议在深夜或周末举行，讨论从内容到艺术和营销的所有内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的年轻科学家从头开始建立学术期刊&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“并不是每个人都坚持到了陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;留下来的人之一是来自深圳先进技术研究院的神经科学家戴吉。自 2019 年以来，他一直积极参与该期刊的运营，尤其是稿件的预筛选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我花了大约 20% 的时间为 The Innovation 工作。它的影响因子告诉我们，我们的工作已经得到了回报。”Dai 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dai 目前正在管理 The Innovation Medicine，这是上周推出的四份姊妹期刊之一。他说，筹备工作在一年前就开始了，与 2020 年的同样经历相比，第一期的整理“要容易得多”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;顶级数学家表示，中国必须让科学家进行宏观和长期的思考&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;其他标题涵盖生命科学、材料科学和地球科学。戴表示，此次扩张对于 The Innovation 的长期可持续性非常重要，出版费用的增加有助于缓解其资金短缺问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举还将更好地利用不断增长的提交数量和陈说，扩大期刊的影响力。作为两名全职员工之一，他每天工作长达 16 个小时，每月处理 100 到 150 份手稿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的期刊越来越为研究界所熟知，我们正在陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新研究发现，中国在顶尖科学论文方面领先世界&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该团队还在建立自己的平台，在香港注册了一家名为The Innovation Press的出版公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一旦我们拥有了自己的出版平台，我们就可以节省大量资金，并且在出版过程中拥有更大的灵活性，”陈说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;虽然构建平台在技术上具有挑战性，但陈和戴表示，真正的挑战是打造品牌并提升其国际影响力，超越排名。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;当科学家们面对面时中国的龙人首次&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“老实说，中国科学家每天都在产出高质量的论文，但没有多少人会决定在《The Innovation》这样的期刊上发表它们，”戴说，并补充道这在一定程度上是由于现有的评估体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每个研究人员都知道，如果他们在《科学》或《自然》杂志上发表论文，他们用同一篇论文赢得研究基金或奖励的机会就会高得多，”他说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈认为，改变的发生需要时间。 “我们需要二十年或更长时间才能真正拥有像《科学》或《自然》这样的品牌。虽然路很长，但我们会到达那里。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Top chip design tool makers see China’s auto industry going places and look to leave export restrictions in the dust]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3226305/top-chip-design-tool-makers-see-chinas-auto-industry-going-places-and-look-leave-export-restrictions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/6b7d5925-2edc-4efe-8af5-0d5502f029a1_26adaebf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;芯片设计软件公司将希望寄托在中国不断发展的汽车工业及其日益增长的需求上对于集成电路，高管们上周在中国国际半导体展上表示，而全球顶级企业正在努力应对对世界第二大经济体的出口限制的收紧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘卫平，中国顶级芯片设计公司的创始人兼董事长工具提供商九天科技周五在上海举行的芯片会议上表示，该公司正在加倍努力构建中国汽车电子电子设计自动化（EDA）解决方案，以抓住智能汽车市场快速增长的机遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“汽车尤其是新能源汽车中的电子元件越来越多，需要芯片、显示器、激光雷达等大量零部件。”刘说。 “所有这些组件的设计都需要EDA软件的支持。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;智能汽车的蓬勃发展如何推动了黑芝麻等中国汽车芯片制造商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;成立于2009年的九大科技并于 2022 年 7 月在深圳上市，被视为中国 EDA 行业实现自给自足的最佳希望之一。该行业目前仅由四家美国公司主导：Cadence、Synopsys、Ansys 和西门子 EDA（在 2017 年被西门子收购之前称为 Mentor Graphics），占据了约 90% 的市场份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; EDA 是一类软件工具，用于设计先进的集成电路或包含数十亿个晶体管的芯片，这些集成电路是为从现代电器、智能手机和个人电脑到复杂的医疗设备、汽车和飞机等一切设备提供动力的“大脑”。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;西门子 EDA 环太平洋地区高级副总裁 Danny Perng 也指出汽车行业对芯片设计的重要性日益增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“汽车电子的生态系统一直在发生变化，”他说彭在周五的会议上发表另一场主题演讲。 “像比亚迪这样的一线[汽车]公司有志于完全整合芯片设计和制造，并建立自己的工厂。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perng称赞中国电动汽车制造商在全球市场的“领先地位”，他表示，这为汽车电子和半导体的发展创造了绝佳的机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perng表示，西门子EDA为汽车制造商开发了一套从汽车芯片到系统智能的“全面解决方案”，可以帮助企业利用人类更有效地利用资源、提高产品质量、控制成本并缩短新产品的上市时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汽车市场一直是中国芯片制造商特别关注的焦点，因为汽车通常使用成熟节点芯片，不受美国出口规则的约束。该市场也在快速增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据世界半导体贸易统计数据，汽车行业是去年半导体最终用途行业中增长最快的行业，占全球半导体销售额的 14.1%。组织。报告称，亚太地区预计将成为汽车芯片增长最快的市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿不断升级的限制措施导致中国芯片行业陷入低迷，供应链中断也导致了中国芯片行业的下滑。地缘政治紧张局势也加剧了这种情况。根据 Gartner 4 月份的预测，全球半导体行业 2023 年收入预计将同比下降 11.2%，至 5320 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去几年中，中国一直在加速发展据AskCI Consulting的报告，其汽车芯片产量预计今年将达到172亿美元。这将比 2018 年跃升 55%，这一增长是由智能汽车在全球最大汽车市场日益普及所推动的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;电动汽车投资者表示，中国需要在先进芯片方面迎头赶上&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;九大的刘表示，公司开发了一套专门用于汽车芯片设计的工具，与其他集成电路相比，其标准更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汽车用芯片需要较长的寿命他说，周期至少为 30 年，并且能够在包括高温在内的恶劣环境下工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘补充道，总部位于北京的九大天地的目标是最终赶上四位 EDA 领导者。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望向‘老大哥’学习，与他们并肩站在[全球EDA行业]的最前沿”，他的发言赢得了与会者的热烈掌声。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Modi’s much-hyped US visit has shifted no sand in the Indo-Pacific alliance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226081/modis-much-hyped-us-visit-has-shifted-no-sand-indo-pacific-alliance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/02/47d9847a-6e22-4b68-be59-eaeb0affacb2_a7bbf366.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;许多人认为印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪对美国的访问在全球经济中具有重要意义和地缘政治阻力。莫迪曾因人权问题被美国拒绝发放签证，现在被华盛顿视为重要合作伙伴，而印度则被视为对抗中国在印太地区日益自信的力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这次访问中，印度和美国美国结束了对从国防和新兴技术到太空探索合作等广泛问题的讨论。这些协议承认印度作为美国重要合作伙伴的作用，并支持加强印度在印太地区的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管华盛顿长期以来将印度视为抵消中国地区野心的战略伙伴，但新德里却从来没有完全放心过这个标签。然而，如果没有印度的全面参与，美国的印太政策、四边安全对话或任何其他希望制衡中国的国家集团都将只不过是一个话题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于胁迫是不可能的随着中国推行南海非军事化，美国加强了对西太平洋和印度洋两个关键海域航行自由的维护。这表明美国将印度视为真正的战略伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国长期以来一直敦促印度承担起印度洋海洋和海军中心的责任。但除了美国和中国之外，俄罗斯也已成为印度-太平洋地区一个值得注意但谨慎的贡献者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了在太平洋地区建立军事存在，俄罗斯将自己定位为武器提供者以及向印度-太平洋地区的小国提供能源，包括越南、印度尼西亚和菲律宾。这些国家担心卷入中美竞争，寻求替代方案。俄罗斯也是印度的主要武器供应国，这意味着印度武装部队的军事装备备件依赖莫斯科。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对印度来说，俄罗斯是既定的战略伙伴。难怪今年担任G20主席国的印度今年，在承认乌克兰周边地缘政治紧张局势的同时，恳请各国避免让分裂性话题阻碍就争议较小的问题达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度是俄罗斯武器装备的全球最大买家，约占俄罗斯武器装备的 20%订单簿。 2018年至2022年，俄罗斯是印度最大的武器来源国，占印度武器进口的45%。法国是第二大供应商，占 29%，美国排名第三，仅占 11%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，即使五角大楼寻求减少印度对俄罗斯武器的依赖，这种情况也不会随时发生。很快就会影响印度在乌克兰战争等问题上的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济方面也存在同样的不对称。根据中国海关数据，去年印中贸易额达到1359.8亿美元，创下历史新高。然而，印度商务部表示，从4月1日开始的财政年度，美国是印度2022-2023年最大的贸易伙伴，贸易额达1285.5亿美元，中国位居第二。但无论这个数字如何，与中美贸易额相比都显得相形见绌，中美贸易额去年增长了 2.5%，达到创纪录的 6906 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;换句话说，印太地区的地缘政治正在变得越来越重要。尽管受到美国制裁、贸易战和中国去风险化战略的影响，但其前景却被潜在的地缘经济所掩盖，并且没有任何变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪访问期间，几位众议院民主党人决定抵制他的演讲向国会表达他们对印度政府在人权方面的不良记录的反对，特别是在印度穆斯林少数民族方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四名议员发表声明，称莫迪在国会联席会议上发表讲话是“可耻”的表现，认为允许这样做，“国会削弱了其成为世界各地宗教少数群体和记者权利的可信倡导者的能力”。想象一下，如果对习近平主席给予同样的待遇，中国会作何反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度长期以来一直保持战略自主权，做出最符合其国家利益的判断，甚至可能会坚持这一蓝图随着印度与美国建立又一个“准联盟”——双方都对莫迪此行结束时建立的美印全面全球战略伙伴关系表示欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;保持自主权将让印度展现其作为世界大国的资格。亚洲的替代大国，避免被定性为美国的副警长，并追求成为独立的亚洲大国的愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于中国的发展、俄罗斯的战略趋同，印度仍处于安全困境中美概念上模糊的印太地缘政治立场。在解决这一困境的过程中，印度从不结盟走向了战略自主，但这也引发了对其战略轨迹的质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度如何在美国阵营中占据应有的地位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这些问题围绕着印度是否会与美国建立正式联盟、维持与中国的接触、维持与俄罗斯的长期关系，还是加强实施“向东行动”政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从怀疑到antagonism, past complaints to future prospects, it has taken the US and India three-quarters of a century just to establish an economic-strategic relationship. Modi&#39;s trip to the US was little more than an engagement aimed at devising strategies to counter an assertive China and expanding the US-India partnership&#39;s role in promoting stability in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting, held with the professed intention of cooperation, connectivity and a strategic partnership, appeared to offer little more than Washington&#39;s desire to protect its Indo-Pacific interests by building deeper connections with New Delhi. For all the hype and hope over Modi&#39;s visit, no sand has shifted for the much touted Indo-Pacific alliance, nor will it any time soon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ex-arms dealer, freed in prisoner swap for US basketball star, to enter Russian politics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3226322/ex-arms-dealer-freed-prisoner-swap-us-basketball-star-enter-russian-politics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 07:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/9e1bde21-c66b-4fd6-9bd4-d49a4ccc50e7_c127b0be.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Russian arms dealer freed last December in a prisoner swap for US basketball star Brittney Griner has been chosen as the candidate of a far-right party for a seat in a Russian regional legislature, state news agency RIA reported on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Viktor Bout, once dubbed “the merchant of death” by the United States, served 10 years of a 25-year sentence in US prisons on arms dealing charges until his release in the prisoner exchange with Griner, an Olympic gold medallist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;RIA cited an official in Russia&#39;s ultranationalist Liberal Democratic Party (LDPR)&#39;s local organisation as saying that Bout had been nominated as a candidate for the legislative assembly of the Ulyanovsk region in central Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bout was arrested by US agents during a sting in Thailand in 2008. The US Department of Justice described him as one of the world&#39;s most prolific arms dealers who had sold weapons across the globe to terrorists and America&#39;s enemies for decades. Bout always denied the charges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Griner was sentenced in 2022 to nine years in a penal colony for possessing vape cartridges containing cannabis oil – which is banned in Russia – after a judicial process labelled a sham by Washington. Griner has since resumed her sports career.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bout publicly joined the LDPR following his return to Russia. Despite its name, the LDPR holds far-right, ultranationalist views and strongly supports President Vladimir Putin&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The LDPR has previously provided a home to Andrei Lugovoi, who is wanted in Britain for the 2006 murder of ex-KGB officer and Putin critic Alexander Litvinenko. Lugovoi has served as an LDPR member of Russia&#39;s national parliament since 2007.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong scams using AI? Police issue warning as fake clip of bank CEO tricks victim, man flags blackmail attempt with doctored sex video]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3226304/hong-kong-scams-using-ai-police-issue-warning-fake-clip-bank-ceo-tricks-victim-man-flags-blackmail?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/02/9263ba99-602d-477a-a126-754a98255ee7_19a668f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong police have received two reports of scammers using artificial intelligence (AI) to trick their victims, creating videos featuring cloned voices and doctored images.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Japanese man reported losing HK$1,700 (US$217) worth of computer game credits in May after being fooled by a fake video interview apparently with the chief executive of a bank in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 25-year-old Hong Kong man made a police report even though he did not fall for a scammer&#39;s demand to buy HK$10,000 worth of game credits after being threatened in March with a video in which his face was superimposed on the naked body of a stranger engaged in sex acts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong businesses vow to combat scammers by not collecting client data by text&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The force said people should be on the alert for scammers using new ways to trick victims, while an expert who warned of a possible emerging trend said a single photo or mere seconds of recording of a victim&#39;s voice would be enough to generate fake material using AI technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Superintendent Chan Shun-ching, from the force&#39;s cybersecurity and technology crime bureau, said police had yet to see scams using deepfakes, which include high-quality videos that could place real people in fake videos showing them speaking or moving about in real time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he said technology was already being used to cause confusion, as scammers could put real people into fake video calls and recordings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Japanese man told police in his country that he was tricked after coming across an Instagram profile apparently of a Hong Kong retail bank chief executive, with a video of the CEO promoting an investment plan in an interview with an international broadcaster.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man followed the account and began to chat with the scammer, who he thought was the bank CEO, and eventually bought HK$1,700 worth of in-game credits at the scammer&#39;s request.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was only after he bought the credits that he called the bank&#39;s headquarters in Hong Kong to verify the authenticity of the CEO&#39;s Instagram account, and realised he had been scammed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bank also contacted Hong Kong police over the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said scammers were able to collect face and voice data for their fake videos from genuine content available on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said AI software tools also enabled tricksters to “swap faces” and appear to be someone else convincingly in real-time videocalls, confusing their victims, but there had been no such case reported in the city yet.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong, mainland police arrest 17 in connection with 149 online fraud cases&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 25-year-old man who reported a scam attempt in March said it happened after he and the swindler had a video call on a sex live-streaming app from an unclear source.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was threatened with a video showing him engaging in sex acts, but knew right away that it was fake.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He ignored the scammer&#39;s demand to buy HK$10,000 worth of game credits and deleted the app and all their conversation records, before reporting to the force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police did not investigate as the man had suffered no loss, but officers believe the scammer grabbed his image and voice during the video call to use in the fake sex clip.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior Inspector Tyler Chan Chi-wing, from the cybersecurity and technology crime bureau, said there were telltale signs in deepfakes used in video calls and people should look out for unnatural eye and mouth movements.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong ex-district councillor remanded in custody over alleged phone scam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;To test the authenticity, he said, the caller should be asked to move a finger across their face.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the programme needed to adjust to the sudden movement, the imitated face would become blurred as the finger moved. In an authentic video, there would be no blurring as the same movement occurred.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Francis Fong Po-kiu, honorary president of the Hong Kong Information Technology Federation, expected the use of AI by fraudsters to become a trend because it was so easy and inexpensive to get the tools to make convincing deepfakes.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong rolls out first AI curriculum for junior secondary students&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A single photo and a voice recording of just a few sentences were enough to make a fake product, and video calls were fertile ground for scammers to obtain the data needed for their sinister creations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It can take 30 seconds or a minute as the scammer records your face and voice to impersonate you,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He listed more than 20 face-swap and voice-cloning AI tools available from sites charging less than US$100 per month in subscription fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He advised people to ignore all video call requests from unknown sources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The police also urged tech-savvy teenagers to remind older family members about the dangers of such technology.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wagner boss has ‘gone off the rails’ over money, Russian TV presenter says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3226321/wagner-boss-has-gone-rails-over-money-says-russian-tv-presenter?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 07:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/600b1933-c692-4359-831f-a48a2ff41f48_1c641833.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A top Russian propagandist on Sunday accused the head of the Wagner mercenary group Wagner of going “off the rails” after receiving billions in public funds, as Moscow&#39;s new narrative takes shape after Wagner&#39;s brief mutiny.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last weekend Yevgeny Prigozhin led his Wagner forces in a short-lived rebellion against Russia&#39;s top military brass, in a huge embarrassment for the Kremlin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Prigozhin has gone off the rails because of big money,” Dmitry Kiselev, one of the main faces of the Russian propaganda machine, said on his weekly television show on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He thought that he can challenge the defence ministry, the state itself and the president personally.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kiselev said that Wagner&#39;s operations in Syria and Africa had given Prigozhin a feeling of impunity that was later reinforced by his rag-tag forces&#39; battlefield successes in eastern Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Without providing any evidence, Kiselev said Wagner had received more than 858 billion roubles (US$9.7 billion) in state funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a stunning admission earlier this week, Russian President Vladimir Putin said for the first time that Russian authorities “fully” financed the paramilitary outfit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between May 2022 and May 2023, Wagner received more than 86 billion roubles from the Russian state, Putin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private mercenary groups are banned under Russian law.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s Communist Party confident in military grip after Russian rebellion: experts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Wall Street Journal newspaper reported on Sunday that agents from the Federal Security Services have raided the headquarters of the Wagner Group in St Petersburg to find evidence against Prigozhin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The headquarters said on Saturday on Telegram that it was moving but would remain operational albeit under a “new format.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Targeted by sanctions from Washington and Brussels, Prigozhin had for years operated in the shadows but has catapulted into the limelight since Putin sent troops into Ukraine in February 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In profanity-laced diatribes, he accused the Russian military of attempting to “steal” victories from Wagner in eastern Ukraine and slammed Moscow&#39;s “monstrous bureaucracy” for slowing military gains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin was allowed to recruit fighters from prisons and in March, Russian lawmakers approved legislation introducing lengthy prison terms for those who criticise “volunteer groups” such as Wagner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month Prigozhin abandoned his advance on Moscow and struck a deal with the Kremlin under which he accepted exile in neighbouring Belarus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many political observers saw Prigozhin&#39;s attempt at insurrection as a sign that Putin&#39;s grip on power is weakening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moscow officials and propagandists insist, however, that Russians have rallied around Putin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Sunday, Vyacheslav Volodin, the speaker of Russia&#39;s lower house of parliament, wrote that Putin emerged out of “this very difficult situation” even stronger.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He did everything to prevent bloodshed,” Volodin wrote on messaging app Telegram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If there had been people like Putin at the helm of the state in 1917 and 1991, there would have been no revolution and no collapse of the USSR.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Kyiv came under attack from the air for the first time in almost two weeks, the Ukrainian air force reported on Sunday, as President Volodymyr Zelensky again vowed that his country would never tolerate occupation by Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s air defences were able to destroy all the incoming missiles, but one person was injured and houses in the region were damaged by falling debris.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other regions were also affected. A total of eight drones and three cruise missiles were downed by air defences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On a visit to the port city of Odesa, Zelensky said in a video message: “Together we will win. The Ukrainian coasts will never tolerate these occupiers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added: “The enemy will definitely not dictate conditions in the Black Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The occupiers will be worried about approaching our Ukrainian Crimea and our coast on the Sea of Azov.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Crimean peninsula was annexed by Russia in 2014 but is recognised internationally as Ukrainian, while cities on the Sea of Azov have been invaded by Russian troops over the course of the 16-month war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky visited military commanders in Odesa and injured soldiers in hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Saturday, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sánchez had visited Ukraine and pledged millions in fresh aid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He visited Kyiv on a symbolic date, the first day of Madrid&#39;s six-month European Union presidency. The goal of his trip, he said, was to convey Europe&#39;s continued backing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine is trying to win back territory lost in the full-scale war launched by Russia in February 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by dpa&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shot teenager’s grandmother pleads for an end to French riots]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226320/shot-teenagers-grandmother-pleads-end-french-riots?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 06:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/34f2f6b3-c369-43bf-946b-4bd58019736f_4169f3b4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The grandmother of the French teenager shot dead by police during a traffic stop pleaded on Sunday with rioters to stop as the nation faced a sixth straight night of unrest, while authorities expressed outrage by the targeting of a mayor&#39;s home with a burning car that injured family members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The grandmother of 17-year-old Nahel, identified only as Nadia, said in a telephone interview with French news broadcaster BFM TV, “Don&#39;t break windows, buses ... schools. We want to calm things down.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said she was angry at the officer who killed her grandson but not at the police in general and expressed faith in the justice system as France faces its worst social upheaval in years. Her grandson, identified by only his first name, was buried on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers had initially stated that the youth had wanted to run them over. Only when video images of the incident, verified by the media, went viral on social networks did they back down from this account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The policeman who fired the shot has been remanded in custody. A manslaughter investigation has been launched.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A call for donations for the officer who shot dead Nahel has reached more than €500,000 (US$545,000).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The aim of the donation drive is to support the family of the officer, “who was doing his job and has paid a high price,” the campaign said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The campaign was set up by Jean Messiha, a supporter of the French far-right politician Éric Zemmour.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China warns of France travel risks after protesters attack tourists&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The violence appeared to be lessening. But as a new night approached, the office of Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said 45,000 police officers would again be deployed in the streets to counter anger over discrimination against people who trace their roots to former French colonies and live in low-income neighbourhoods. Nahel is of Algerian descent and was shot in the Paris suburb of Nanterre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French President Emmanuel Macron was holding a special security meeting on Sunday night and it was not clear whether he would make public comments. Macron has delayed what would have been the first state visit to Germany by a French president in 23 years, starting on Sunday evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said they made another 719 arrests on Saturday night, bringing the total number of people detained to more than 3,000 following a mass security deployment. Hundreds of police and firefighters have been injured in the violence, although authorities have not said how many protesters have been hurt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French authorities were appalled on Sunday after a burning car struck the home of the mayor of the Paris suburb of L&#39;Hay-les-Roses. Several police stations and town halls have been targeted by fires or vandalism in recent days, but such a personal attack on a mayor&#39;s home is unusual.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mayor Vincent Jeanbrun said his wife and one of his children were injured in the attack while they slept and he was in the town hall monitoring the violence. Jeanbrun, of the conservative opposition Republicans party, said the attack represented a new stage of “horror and ignominy” in the unrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regional prosecutor Stephane Hardouin opened an investigation into attempted murder, telling French television that a preliminary investigation suggests the car was meant to ram the house and set it ablaze. He said a flame accelerant was found in a bottle in the car.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron has blamed social media for fuelling violence. France&#39;s justice minister has warned that young people who share calls for violence on Snapchat or other apps could face prosecution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mass police deployment has been welcomed by some frightened residents of targeted neighbourhoods, but it has further frustrated those who see police behaviour as the core of the crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On a public square in Nanterre, a young man of Senegalese descent said France would learn little from the latest unrest. Faiez Njai said of police: “They&#39;re playing on our fears, saying that &#39;If you don&#39;t listen to us,&#39;” - and then he pointed a finger at his temple and fired.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Attack on mayor&#39;s house, fires, looting: France faces fifth night of rioting&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Video of the killing showed two officers at the window of the car, one with his gun pointed at the driver. As the teenager pulled forward, the officer fired once through the windscreen. The officer accused of killing Nahel was given a preliminary charge of voluntary homicide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thirteen people who did not comply with traffic stops were fatally shot by French police last year, and three this year, prompting demands for more accountability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nahel M&#39;s death first reflects the rules and practices for how police officers use weapons during roadside checks and, more broadly, the flawed relations between the police and young people from working-class neighbourhoods,” the newspaper Le Monde said in an editorial on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid the unrest, a World War II monument in Nanterre commemorating Holocaust victims and members of the French resistance was vandalised on the sidelines of a silent march on Thursday to pay tribute to Nahel. The slogans included “Don&#39;t forgive or forget” and “Police, rapists, assassins.” The European Jewish Congress denounced the vandalism as a “shameful act of disrespect for the memory of the victims of the Holocaust.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Life in some parts of France went on as usual. In the capital, tourists thronged to the Eiffel Tower, where workers set up a nearby clock counting down to next year&#39;s Paris Olympics. A short walk from Nanterre, a shopping centre bustled on Sunday with customers from all walks of life. But in the empty square where Nahel was shot, someone had painted “The police kill” on a bench.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the foot of a bridge near the Eiffel Tower where generations of couples have attached padlocks to symbolise lasting love, a Senegalese man selling cheap locks and keys shook his head when asked if Nahel&#39;s killing and the ensuing violence would change anything.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I doubt it,” he said, giving only his first name, Demba, for fear of retaliation. “The discrimination is too profound.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by dpa&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will China’s central bank defend the falling yuan as its new Communist Party chief, Pan Gongsheng, takes the helm?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3226292/will-chinas-central-bank-defend-falling-yuan-its-new-communist-party-chief-takes-helm?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/02/bedea078-c393-4ee7-bf05-5ec63a6c868f_ed8ea6aa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The market is waiting to see whether China&#39;s monetary authorities will take action to defend the yuan as the Chinese currency hits a seven-month low against the US dollar and approaches a key psychological threshold.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speculation about a possible intervention surged as the People&#39;s Bank of China (PBOC) warned against big swings in the yuan exchange rate earlier this week, and Pan Gongsheng, chief of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, was appointed as Communist Party chief of the central bank on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fast depreciation of the yuan, partly driven by the country&#39;s weak post-Covid recovery, is one of the biggest challenges ahead for 59-year-old Pan, who has over two decades of financial industry experience and a track record of steering the forex regulator since 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ll take comprehensive measures to stabilise expectations and firmly prevent the big rise and fall of the exchange rate,” the PBOC said in a summary of its quarterly monetary policy meeting released on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s forex regulatory head named Communist Party chief for central bank&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Pan also attended the policy meeting, which took place on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The central bank has tried to assure the market that it is equipped with the necessary toolbox to maintain stability, and it emphasised the deepening of market-oriented reforms in the exchange rate system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The exchange rate of the Chinese yuan fluctuates in both directions, while remaining fundamentally stable at a reasonable and balanced level, serving as a stabilising force for the macroeconomy,” the meeting summary said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offshore yuan weakened to 7.28 against the US dollar on Friday, falling by 4.7 per cent since the start of the year to the lowest level since November. The PBOC has so far refrained from direct intervention in the foreign exchange market to steady the yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government set the yuan&#39;s daily reference rate at 7.2258 on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As chief of the country&#39;s forex regulator, Pan has been talking up the Chinese currency&#39;s role as a safe-haven asset to discourage fund outflows and promote the overseas use of the yuan. He also took part in reforms to China&#39;s exchange rate policy to promote a more market-driven mechanism for determining the yuan&#39;s value.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have accumulated considerable experience in dealing with external shocks over the years, and our macroprudential tools are more robust,” he told the Lujiazui financial forum in early June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have the confidence, conditions, and capabilities to safeguard the stable operation of China&#39;s foreign exchange market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Yuan to remain under pressure as central bank weighs moves to stem weakness&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A wider interest rate gap between China and the US is another factor weighing on the yuan exchange rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China slashed its policy rate by 10 basis points a week ago, although the Federal Reserve is approaching the end of its interest rate tightening cycle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese yuan is now nearing the key threshold of 7.3, a pivotal level that holds significant importance in market sentiment and expectations,” said Zhou Junzhi, chief macro analyst at Minsheng Securities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a possibility of new measures being introduced in the near term to manage the exchange rate, with foreign exchange liquidity adjustment tools being the preferred choice.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Zulu king treated for suspected poisoning following adviser’s sudden death]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3226319/zulu-king-treated-suspected-poisoning-following-advisers-sudden-death?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.03 04:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/03/11bc29b9-0eb9-43fd-b157-cee9317fdbe2_4ddd98d5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;South Africa&#39;s Zulu king, head of the country&#39;s most influential traditional monarchy, has undergone “thorough” medical examinations following the sudden death of a close adviser, a spokesman said on Sunday, amid suspicions he was poisoned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The king, who was visiting neighbouring Eswatini, “underwent precautionary and thorough medical exams in a context of Covid and after the sudden death of his close adviser,” Douglas Xaba, explained spokesman Prince Africa Zulu, contacted by telephone by Agence France-Presse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Misuzulu Zulu, 48, ascended the throne last year after the death of his father, Goodwill Zwelithini, amid a bitter feud over the royal succession.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overnight on Saturday, the influential Zulu prime minister, Prince Mangosuthu Buthelezi, said in a press release that the monarch had been hospitalised in Eswatini after falling ill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The king believes he was being poisoned, after the sudden and unexpected death of one of his close advisers on Saturday, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xaba “passed on quite suddenly and that there are suspicions that he was poisoned”, added Buthelezi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The royal spokesman on Sunday, however, assured that the Zulu king, also known as Misuzulu kaZwelithini, was “in perfect health and is not currently admitted to any hospital”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The spokesman criticised what he said was an “orchestrated agenda” to circulate “baseless claims of His Majesty&#39;s ill health”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Africa&#39;s Zulus to crown new king as succession row rages&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Several police sources in Eswatini confirmed to Agence France-Presse that there was heavy security deployed at a private hospital close to the country&#39;s royal residence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the title of king of the Zulu nation does not bestow executive power, the monarchs wield great moral influence over more than 11 million Zulus, who make up nearly a fifth of South Africa&#39;s population of 60 million people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;King Zwelithini, who died after more than 50 years in charge, left six wives and at least 28 children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Misuzulu is the first son of Zwelithini&#39;s third wife, who he designated as regent in his will.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The queen, however, died suddenly a month after Zwelithini, leaving a will naming Misuzulu as the next king – a development that did not go down well with other family members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The current king preferred treatment in Eswatini because “his parents had both received treatment in South Africa and subsequently died”, said Buthelezi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last September, another counsellor of the Zulu king was shot dead in mysterious circumstances on the sidelines of a traditional ceremony.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 03 Jul 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>