<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Catching insects instead of fish’: video of man fishing next to bed in flooded home after heavy rain goes viral delighting Chinese social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3225448/catching-insects-instead-fish-video-man-fishing-next-bed-flooded-home-after-heavy-rain-goes-viral?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/592741d3-0d4c-4a49-969c-a43853db354f_9f3b0b3b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一段中国男子回家后在床边钓鱼的视频近日，湖北省武汉市的一位不愿透露姓名的男子，在最近的大雨导致他的家被淹后，开始在床边钓鱼，但他没有钓到鱼，只钓到了昆虫据澎湃新闻报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子的妻子董某拍摄了这段视频，并在网上分享了细节，称本月早些时候发生倾盆大雨时，他们正在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“哎呀瞬间，我们家就被水淹没了。”董告诉澎湃新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山洪爆发后，董说她的丈夫想到了钓鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他是一名钓鱼人。” ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男子将一根鱼线扔进洪水里想看看发生了什么，但经过半个多小时的多次尝试，他没有钓到任何鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有看到任何鱼，但确实看到了很多昆虫。”董补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事逗乐了中国的网上观察者，他们称赞这对夫妇的积极态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人说：“有这样阳光态度的人，懂得如何生活。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人写道：“男人很可爱，他的妻子也很可爱。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan to get tactical boost with Nato’s Link 22 and US SeaGuardian drones: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225627/taiwan-get-tactical-boost-natos-link-22-and-us-seaguardian-drones-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/5b683d59-6c7a-4254-8845-d7646d57e54e_cf5fbe4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾获得北约 Link 22 战术通信系统将增强该岛的防御能力，特别是在军事专家表示，计划增加四架美国先进监视和侦察无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾一名高级国防官员上个月证实，美国将帮助这个自治岛屿获得先进的数据链&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三年前美国国务院批准了价值 6 亿美元的交易后，台湾还预计在 2025 年接收强大的 MQ-9B SeaGuardian 无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，在与大陆发生冲突时，Link 22 对于台湾来说将是一项非常有价值的国防通信资产，因为台湾没有自己的卫星系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾获得北约的 Link 22 将使其能够运营MQ-9B SeaGuardian 无人机将由美国提供，”台北军事评论员池乐毅表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[美国]向台湾出售四架 MQ-9B 并收购 Link 22鉴于台湾与大陆之间军事冲突的风险日益增加，寻求支持可以被视为美国综合威慑战略的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Link 22是超视距通信平台北约成员国在联合行动中使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SeaGuardian 无人机的航程可达 6,000 公里（3,730 英里），飞行时间为 40 小时，预计将推动反潜行动&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五角大楼的综合威慑战略强调综合运用外交、经济治国手段和军事力量来威慑敌军的侵略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周晨鸣，北京研究院研究员远望军事科技智库表示，Link 22将帮助台北提高对抗冲突中通信干扰的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Link 22用于安全的空中和海上数据传输，主要是用于冗余增强，以发送联合作战图像等更大的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾军方已经使用美国制造的 Link 16 系统来连接其美制武器系统，但它与其从法国购买的拉斐特级护卫舰和幻影 2000-5 战斗机等非美国武器系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但高雄台湾海军学院前教官卢立士表示台湾获得Link 22并不意味着北约会像一些台湾分析人士预期的那样自动允许台湾加入其通信系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据北约创始条约，集体防御原则将亚洲排除在外” ......作为核心成员的法国已表示反对将[联盟]扩展到亚洲，”陆说，并补充说，他认为法国和其他北约成员国不会与台湾分享他们的军事行动代码。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“美国希望台湾拥有Link 22，因为这是操作MQ-9B最方便、成本最低的措施，MQ-9B需要与卫星连接，而台湾没有自己的卫星系统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陆说，虽然台湾可以升级其 Link 16 系统以连接 SeaGuardian 无人机，但这将要求该岛与美国共享其军事操作代码 - 台北不愿意这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 上个月访问台湾时，曾于2017年至2020年担任太平洋地区海军陆战队司令的美国退役将军史蒂文·拉德表示，美国的最终目标是将台湾纳入其C4ISR系统，这是一种指挥机制，控制、通信、计算机、情报、监视和侦察。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader John Lee has hit nearly every goal for his first year in office, but what do residents think of his performance?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3225646/hong-kong-leader-john-lee-has-hit-nearly-every-goal-his-first-year-office-what-do-residents-think?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/1abbba0b-4369-4f8e-b06d-972b1936ce8b_a3cb5c1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港领导人已实现了他在任期内承诺的几乎全部 68 个目标《华盛顿邮报》发现，他上任第一年，但观察人士警告说，居民的生活可能仍不会因此而变得更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超在竞选时承诺一种能够接受公众监督的“以结果为导向”的治理方法。他在10月份的施政报告中提出了近200个关键绩效指标（KPI），涵盖土地和住房、经济、医疗保健、福利、青年发展和公务员制度改革。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在194个关键绩效指标中，68个是到年中实现 55 个目标，年底实现 55 个目标，其余的在 2 到 10 年内实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》的一项检查发现，李明博政府已经实现了所有 KPI 的三分之一，而实现了 68 项短期目标中的 66 项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他尚未向政府工作人员发布更新后的《公务员守则》以供咨询。他的政府提出了取消公务员遵守“政治中立”要求的想法，以防止该规则被用来逃避任务，并一度暗示将在今年第一季度公布征求意见稿。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;但公务员工会联合会主席梁朝廷表示，放弃这项规定可能会拖延咨询。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这非常敏感，涉及很多细节， “ 他说。 “如果有的话，我们还在等待咨询文件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有待实现的另一个目标是政府金融科技证明中超过 50% 的项目商业化2022-23 年概念补贴计划。政府在 6 月 5 日回复立法会时表示，已批准 166 个申请中的 56 个项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;出口持续低迷，香港李家超为东盟贸易之旅做好准备&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;但李在实现吸引人才和企业以及土地和住房供应相关目标方面特别成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 12 月以来，政府推出了顶尖人才通行证计划，降低了一些官方数据显示，各类人才计划已收到约84,000份申请，其中49,000份已获得批准，到五月底。李早些时候表示，该市正在顺利吸引每年目标 35,000 名工人的近两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据移民局的数据，通过人才计划发放的签证中，近 95% 发给了来自中国大陆的申请人。部门。这种现象引发了人们对该市吸引国际候选人能力的担忧。新来者是否会如政府希望的那样在香港停留一年也仍是未知数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在招商方面，政府设立了战略企业引进办公室，并拨款300亿港元（38亿美元） ）从未来基金设立“联合投资基金”——两项关键绩效指标被认为是吸引企业的基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该办公室告诉《华盛顿邮报》，它已经会见了超过 150 家从事尖端技术的顶尖企业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港李约翰上任第一年：取得了什么成就？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这些企业大多表现出了兴趣该办事处补充说，在香港设立业务方面。 2027年的一项关键绩效指标要求政府吸引至少100家具有高潜力的创新科技企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据商务及经济发展局的资料，已有186家内地及海外企业决定设立或扩大规模。自 1 月份以来，香港的业务已实现了近 20%，即 2023 年至 2025 年间吸引 1,130 家企业的目标的近 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但代表科技行业的立法会议员邓肯·赵 (Duncan Chiu) 怀疑许多公司是否会来到香港&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自去年 10 月以来，我们每个月都看到新政策出台，”他说。 “但如果没有政策的连续性，仅靠交付的关键绩效指标数字就无法促进发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然自李上任以来，几乎所有香港部长都访问过内地或海外城市，以宣传香港的优势。中国制造业协会会长施洛德在办公室表示，现在评估此类旅行的影响还为时过早。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“出去比呆在家里好，”施说。 “但我认为短期内不会有成果，还得看这样的活动能不能经常举办，而不是达到某个目标，然后就什么都没有了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甚至尽管土地和住房方面的大多数关键绩效指标都是中长期的，但李明博政府成功实现了所有九个短期指标。其中包括提出法案以缩短开发程序的时间，推出计划以加强与私人开发商合作建设资助公寓，以及设立专门办公室来协调政府旗舰项目北方都市的开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府还告诉公众，它已经获得了足够的土地，可以在未来十年建造 360,000 套公共住房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这幅美好图景中缺失的部分是，所有这些开发项目将如何融资，”立法者表示。立法会房屋事务委员会委员江玉芬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府行政会议最高顾问叶刘淑仪早些时候敦促政府优先考虑北方都会计划，而不是北都计划。明日大屿愿景，一个有争议的建造三座人工岛的项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于政府在粉岭高尔夫球场建造公共公寓的计划的争论——因香港高尔夫球会广泛游说阻止该计划而重新引发——也对李实现目标的能力表示怀疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孔补充说，解决住房问题不仅仅需要建造公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“还应该建设基础设施和配套设施设施，”她说。 “你会住在附近没有任何配套基础设施的公寓里吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学政治与公共行政学系名誉教授约翰·伯恩斯表示，人们关心的不仅仅是满足条件关键绩效指标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伯恩斯表示：“但现在评估与关键绩效指标相关的所有这些活动的结果可能还为时过早。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港公司开始在以下领域达成重大交易：李约翰访问后的中东&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这位政治学家还指出，由于人们对政府的信任度仍然很低，李约翰政府必须明白“结果是共同产生的”，需要人们的合作和尊重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“让公民参与是关键，而不是将他们边缘化，”他说。 “公众咨询可以建立信任和合法性，并为香港更稳定的国家与社会合作奠定基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府似乎认为自己没有时间这样做，这是危险的位置。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Natalie Wong 的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rocky US-China relationship could benefit from couples therapy strategies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225473/rocky-us-china-relationship-could-benefit-couples-therapy-strategies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/1af16e30-bc17-4a2b-86ab-7471b2d4c375_4732fe69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在任何长期关系中，冲突都是不可避免的。真正重要的是合作伙伴是否能够管理、解决和克服分歧，并随着时间的推移建立更健康的关系。这种见解既适用于国际外交，也适用于浪漫关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可以公平地说，二月份气球事件的后果并不是解决冲突的光辉典范。中美两国非但没有冷静有效地沟通，反而陷入相互指责的怪圈，导致两国关系跌至数十年来的最低谷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;值得庆幸的是，美国国务卿布林肯成功访华。北京为建立更具建设性和和谐的美中关系打开了机会之窗。双方都有责任抓住这个机会——作为世界上最重要的两个大国，两国的动态不仅影响各自国家，而且影响整个全球格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯此访是美国国务卿首次访华五年后，我们与外交部长秦刚、最高外交官王毅和国家主席习近平进行了建设性会晤，但最后一次会议绝无保证。这些积极的互动发出了一个强烈的信号，即在危险地接近边缘之后，双方都认识到不能冒完全决裂的风险，并致力于使两国关系建立在更稳定的基础上。中美两国应共同努力，为两国关系奠定坚实的基础，这样未来的事件就不会像过去几个月那样破坏两国关系。为了实现这一目标，关系治疗有四个原则可以用来帮助指导发展更强大、更稳定的美中关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，开放和定期的沟通是任何牢固伙伴关系的基石。中美必须重新就各自的意图、关切和期望进行频繁、透明的对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首要任务是加强高层互动，为习美会晤扫清道路。乔·拜登总统将于今年晚些时候出席 20 国集团或亚太经合组织峰会。希望布林肯此行之后，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦、商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多和拜登的气候特使约翰·克里也能到访。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下级政府之间的定期接触以及双边关系也应该恢复。特朗普执政期间的对话已经萎缩。总的来说，这些会议可以提供平台来探索合作途径，解决任何正在酝酿的问题，并在紧张局势滚雪球演变成更大的冲突之前化解紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次，任何关系都需要强有力的机制来管理和解决冲突（当冲突发生时） 。中美两国必须建立危机期间迅速有效的沟通渠道，以及预先制定的协议来管理此类事件，以帮助在局势变得难以控制之前缓和局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使是在最严重的时候冷战期间，美国和苏联保留了沟通和危机管理的渠道，包括华盛顿和莫斯科之间的热线电话。中美之间缺乏这样的机制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;冷战式的协议是否有助于防止中美紧张局势升级？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从长远来看，第三点是关系治疗师可能会强调的是需要培养相互尊重、同理心和共同利益。人们经常建议正在经历困难时期的夫妻尝试理解对方，并参与共同活动或共同爱好来加强他们的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，各国可以通过以下领域的文化交流来培养同理心：作为教育、研究和旅游，有助于增进相互了解并减少“我们与他们”的心态。近年来，由于政治和 Covid-19 大流行，中美之间的文化联系有所减弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国现已重新开放，但缺乏足够的往返美国的航班仍然是一个瓶颈。野村证券最近的一份报告显示，2019 年中美之间的航班只有不到 6% 已恢复，而且保留的航班价格昂贵。部分问题在于，对飞越俄罗斯领空的限制增加了这些航线的运营成本。双方要探讨如何增加航班数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更广泛地说，双方应努力促进双边社会交流。上学期，在华美国学生人数减少至仅350人左右。希望随着学生下学期的新申请，这个数字将开始上升。这也有利于促进学术交流，包括减少邀请外宾来华参加学术会议的繁文缛节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，富布赖特中国项目派出美国学者到中国进行了超过四次的访问。几十年来，他们的中国同行却走上了相反的道路。该计划于 2020 年被取消，但应该恢复，同年退出中国的和平队计划也应该恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，共同的目标和合作项目在帮助夫妻加深联系方面发挥着关键作用。同样，中美两国必须找到共同点并采取有利于两国的共同举措。这不应局限于解决眼前的问题和冲突，还应涵盖气候变化和全球金融稳定等更广泛、更具建设性的主题。在这些问题上的长期合作和逐步取得的成就可以帮助两国在共同的事业下团结起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像成功的夫妇一样，两国都必须投入时间和精力来培育他们的伙伴关系。布林肯访问后，中美两国有机会为两国关系打下更坚实的基础，这样下次意外到来时，两国关系就不会脱轨。与任何关系一样，道路上都会有坎坷，但这些可以通过仔细管理来克服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rivalry between Trump and DeSantis deepens with duelling New Hampshire campaign events]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225645/rivalry-between-trump-and-desantis-deepens-duelling-new-hampshire-campaign-events?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/b61555f2-9589-469d-ad17-2d920e4676fc_207ce332.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，佛罗里达州州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯和美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普之间的竞争进一步加剧两位主要的共和党白宫候选人在关键的提前投票州新罕布什尔州的决斗活动中互相嘲笑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯在霍利斯市政厅发表讲话时发誓要“真正”建造美墨边境墙特朗普作为总统曾尝试但未能完成这一任务。他还承诺以特朗普未能做到的方式摧毁华盛顿的传统权力中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来在康科德举行的共和党妇女午餐会上发表讲话时，特朗普反驳说，德桑蒂斯被迫在初选中屈居第二，并且指责州长支持削减社会保障、医疗保险和其他福利计划，以此作为控制联邦支出的一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了言辞之外，相互冲突的事件还显示了每位候选人不断变化的战略。德桑蒂斯回答了广泛的观众提问——这是新罕布什尔州政界的一个标志，他在上次访问该州时回避了这一问题，招致批评，认为他生硬且过于照本宣科。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，特朗普发表了一场随心所欲的演讲，以了解更多内容比小时。他没有在康科德接受提问，报道此次活动的记者被限制在一支笔中，在陪同下进入浴室，并被告知他们不能在会议中心宴会厅甚至走廊里与与会者交谈。但这位前总统在随后前往曼彻斯特的一站回答了问题，他在那里开设了新罕布什尔州竞选办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯询问了因特朗普承诺“排干沼泽”而两次投票支持特朗普的人的情况。在华盛顿，他用自己的回答与这位前总统形成了迄今为止最鲜明的对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他没有耗尽它。今天的情况比以往任何时候都更糟糕，”德桑蒂斯说。他补充说，这样的承诺还不够远，因为下一任总统“可以重新填补它。”德桑蒂斯说，“我想打破沼泽”，并承诺通过指示将权力从华盛顿手中夺走。内阁机构将那里的员工人数减半。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法院称特朗普必须面临纽约民事欺诈索赔；伊万卡案被驳回&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯试图通过质疑前总统对全国共和党的持续控制来赢得特朗普的支持。在市政厅，州长猛烈抨击了特朗普领导下的共和党的“失败文化”，并提到了共和党许多人所预测的“大规模红色浪潮”，但在去年的中期选举中从未在全国范围内实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我们在佛罗里达州掀起了一股红色浪潮，”德桑蒂斯说道，并指出他去年秋天轻松赢得了连任。 “但那是因为我们在佛罗里达州取得了成果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多共和党领袖仍然对特朗普非常忠诚，但有一些证据表明，对这位前总统的攻击正在引起共鸣。周二，众议院议长、加州共和党人凯文·麦卡锡在谈到特朗普时表示：“他能赢得选举吗？是的，他能赢得选举。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“问题是，他是最有能力赢得选举的吗？”麦卡锡在 CNBC 的 Squawk Box 节目中继续说道。 “我不知道这个答案。”当天晚些时候，他向保守派新闻媒体 Breitbart 澄清，特朗普“今天比 2016 年更强大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普在自己的讲话中指出，民意调查显示他在初选中大幅领先。他抓住德桑蒂斯的说法，虽然社会保障和其他项目需要为老年人提供保障，但对于年轻人来说，可能需要“以两党合作的方式来弄清楚如何加强这一点”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你可以打赌他稍后会这样做，”特朗普在谈到削减计划时说道。 “他会对你这么做。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普还发誓要“一劳永逸地排干沼泽”，但更多地用这个口号来批评美国总统乔·拜登，而不是佛罗里达州州长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “如果你是沼泽的一部分，你就无法排干沼泽，而乔·拜登和其他对手，其中许多人，都100%拥有、控制、购买和支付，”特朗普&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前总统在很大程度上也呼应了德桑蒂斯的观点，承诺“这次选举将是我们国家首都腐败政治阶层的世界末日。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国总统候选人妮基·黑莉寻求对华政策进行重大改变&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯还被问及 2021 年 1 月占领美国国会大厦的亲特朗普暴民的情况，她回答说：“如果是为了对发生两三年的事情重新提起诉讼，几年前，我们就会输。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那天发生的事情与我无关。显然，我不喜欢看到它，”德桑蒂斯说。 “但我们必须在这件事上继续前进。我们不能向后看。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也与特朗普发生了冲突，特朗普周二重申了毫无根据的说法，称他因选举舞弊而无法连任。许多联邦和地方官员、一长串法院、前竞选高级工作人员，甚至特朗普自己的司法部长都表示，没有证据表明他所指控的欺诈行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位候选人的同时访问凸显了这一作用新罕布什尔州是全国第一个共和党初选州，将在决定下一届共和党总统候选人的过程中发挥作用。早期初选的大部分焦点都集中在爱荷华州和南卡罗来纳州，那里福音派基督徒占主导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，在新罕布什尔州花时间让候选人在更多人面前测试他们的信息。倾向自由主义的选民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普在爱荷华州输给得克萨斯州参议员特德·克鲁兹后，在新罕布什尔州 2016 年共和党初选中获得第一名，帮助他获得了党内主导地位。但他的民主党竞争对手在 2016 年和 2020 年大选中赢得了该州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二发表讲话之前，特朗普宣布他的新罕布什尔州团队在该州 10 个县拥有 150 多名敬业的活动家和组织者。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;来自亨尼克镇的萨布丽娜·安特尔 (Sabrina Antle) 表示，她无力参加康科德午餐会。她和她九岁的女儿稍后试图在曼彻斯特会见这位前总统，但在他们到达之前，活动就已经满员了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我是特朗普支持者，但我不会因为罗恩·德桑蒂斯，因为我认为他会做单口喜剧，”安特尔说。 “我只是不知道他是否有特朗普那样的态度，只是自信。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普在新录音中听到讨论“高度机密”文件&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯的竞选活动激怒了一些人新罕布什尔州共和党妇女联合会的成员在特朗普在该组织的午餐会上发表讲话的同时安排了他的市政厅。它称德桑蒂斯的活动“试图从午餐中夺走焦点”，并指出其他总统候选人围绕它安排了活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这并没有阻止德桑蒂斯，他在市政厅谈论了新的移民政策提案他周一在得克萨斯州南部发布了这一言论，并押注这一问题能够激励共和党选民，甚至是那些位于美墨边境以北 2,000 英里的选​​民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们实际上要修建隔离墙，”德桑蒂斯谈到了特朗普未能兑现的承诺。 “很多政客都在叽叽喳喳地说。他们做出宏伟的承诺，却未能兑现实际成果。找借口的时间已经结束了。现在是取得成果并最终完成工作的时候了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但佛罗里达州州长还针对新罕布什尔州周二的信息进行了调整，指出更严格的边境安全最终将有助于限制阿片类药物成瘾的破坏，尽管全国各地吸毒过量导致的死亡人数不断攀升，但这些对国家的打击尤其严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他承诺对贩毒集团采取“任何政府都没有采取过的最果断”的政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们必须这样做，”德桑蒂斯说，“因为这将拯救生命。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Carbon Finance: How the launch of a new voluntary carbon markets claims code can help reclaim lost credibility]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3225626/carbon-finance-how-launch-new-voluntary-carbon-markets-claims-code-can-help-reclaim-lost-credibility?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/2f647e1d-3e59-4a0a-bbe7-a238dcddddd0_de5983ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自愿碳市场诚信倡议 (VCMI) 推出了一套全球指南，以使企业能够对其购买的碳信用额做出更可信的气候声明，以抵消温室气体排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个非营利性国际机构周三发布了其“声明实践准则”，这是一本针对企业的规则手册在提出气候效益声明时要遵循。遵守该准则是自愿的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“索赔准则填补了一个关键空白，为自愿碳市场的需求方带来了诚信，”它在一份声明中表示。该准则是约 70 家（主要是跨国公司）经过 12 个月多的道路测试、一系列公众咨询和多方利益相关者合作的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然自愿碳市场有潜力帮助填补这一空白。该组织在索赔代码文件中表示，缓解气候变化的资金缺口，特别是在发展中国家，只有在高度诚信的情况下才能实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着碳信用额必须通过以下方式产生：这些活动真正超越了一切照旧，有利于东道社区（供应方），并且它们的使用可以增加整体温室气体减排，而不是取代现有行动（需求方）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “如果这两方面没有明确的高度诚信的规则，自愿碳市场将继续受到怀疑，公司将害怕投资，他们的潜力将会丧失。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该准则，之前公司购买任何碳补偿时，除了公开承诺不迟于 2050 年实现净零排放外，还必须披露其年度温室气体排放量和近期减排目标，并经科学目标倡议验证。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他们还必须证明他们正在实现近期减排目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后，公司可以根据自己的残余排放量百分比，从三级声明中选择其中之一进行声明这将通过购买碳信用额来抵消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在发布 VCMI 索赔代码之前，公众对今年早些时候欧洲多家媒体报道指出的一个关键类别（预防毁林项目）信用额的可信度表示担忧.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“显然，[它们]是市场中非常重要的一部分，”VCMI 执行董事 Mark Kenber 在代码发布前接受采访时告诉《华盛顿邮报》。 “目前，森林保护所获得的资金还不到保护热带森林所需资金的 3%，因此我们需要找到答案。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI 于两年前在以下机构的支持下启动：资助者包括英国政府、对冲基金儿童投资基金管理公司的慈善部门、贝索斯地球基金和科技巨头谷歌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI 准则的推出将对香港产生影响，蓝筹公司正在香港寻求发展buy high quality voluntary carbon credits to offset carbon footprints they cannot reduce by their own efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has also indicated an ambition to become a regional market for carbon credits trading, bridging global demand for carbon offsets and China&#39;s potential credits supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voluntary credits are issued by carbon offset registries on climate mitigation projects, for each unit of emission reduction or removal that is verified. The robustness of the registries&#39; standards and methodologies are key to the quality of the credits issued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voluntary credits traded globally jumped nearly fourfold to US$2 billion in 2021 from 2020, according to data compiler Ecosystem Marketplace. The most popular categories include renewable energy and forestry projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI is considering providing compliance relief for some companies, Kenbar said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For companies that are just starting or are halfway on the net zero journey, how we incentivise them [to do more on decarbonisation] is part of the work we are doing in the next few months on introducing flexibility,” he said. “We hope to have a package by the end of the year that will be attractive both to multinationals and domestic mid-market companies.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese tourists in Thailand face jail, fine after touching ‘cute’ starfish, stepping on coral reefs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3225614/chinese-tourists-thailand-face-jail-fine-after-touching-cute-starfish-stepping-coral-reefs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/f9a312b7-0c8a-4c9e-a28c-d40118691476_7f5a1bef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Three Chinese tourists accused of touching a starfish and stepping on coral reefs during their diving expedition in Phuket could face two years in jail after they were charged for violating a marine protection law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident, which happened last week on the Thai island of Koh Racha, came to light following photos shared by a group that tracks environmental transgressions in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Environment minister Varawut Silpa-archa said in a Facebook post that two visitors admitted to the offence after turning themselves into police, while the third suspect was still at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Smog drives away Thailand&#39;s tourists as farmers next door slash and burn land&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Varawut added officials coordinated with the provincial tourism police, marine office and the company that organised the trip to track down the lawbreakers. He did not elaborate if the missing tourist was still being pursued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If found guilty, the visitors face two years in prison and a 200,000 baht (US$5,667) fine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two-month-old travel firm apologised for the tourists&#39; behaviour who were part of a diving group, saying it was the establishment&#39;s first junket and it “learned a lesson”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The operator also promised to raise awareness about not meddling with marine wildlife among its clients, especially Chinese who have previously been involved in similar incidents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some of them find the animals cute and want to have the pictures taken with them to show to their friends,” The Phuket News quoted a company executive as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On behalf of the company, we are very sorry that this has happened.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thai social media users directed their ire at “wild Chinese tour groups”, while others blamed the diving instructors for not sensitising the guests about the regulations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some lamented such incidents keep occurring despite law enforcement actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two Chinese tourists were arrested in 2020 for catching protected ornamental fish using a spear gun while snorkelling in central Thailand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, South Korean actress Lee Yeol-eum was charged with catching endangered giant clams in a Thai national marine park while taking part in a reality TV show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marine experts say more than three quarters of Thailand&#39;s coral reefs have been damaged by rising sea temperatures and unchecked tourism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tourism-dependent country&#39;s sandy beaches helped draw 6.15 million foreign visitors, including more than 700,000 Chinese, in the first quarter of the year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan says it has spotted two Russian warships off its east coast]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225644/taiwan-says-it-has-spotted-two-russian-warships-its-east-coast?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 06:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/683d7d0a-90e2-43f6-b24e-cfdbb62e47af_e2570a3a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan spotted two Russian warships off its eastern coast on Tuesday and sent its own aircraft and ships to keep watch, the island&#39;s defence ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement late on Tuesday, the ministry said the two frigates sailed in a northerly direction off Taiwan&#39;s east coast and then “departed from our response zone” in a southeasterly direction off the port city of Suao, which is home to a major Taiwanese naval base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s military sent aircraft and ships to keep watch and activated shore-based missile systems, it added, without providing further details.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Shoot them down&#39;: Taiwan vows to destroy &#39;risky&#39; mainland Chinese balloons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s Interfax news agency reported on Tuesday that a detachment of ships of the Russian Pacific Fleet had entered the southern parts of the Philippine Sea to perform tasks as part of a long-range sea passage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan has joined the United States and its allies in enacting wide-ranging sanctions against Russia following its invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Democratically governed Taiwan - which mainland China views as a breakaway territory that must be reunified, by force if necessary - has over the past three years regularly reported Chinese navy ships and air force aircraft operating around the island, as Beijing seeks to press its territorial claims.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong theft cases jump by nearly 40 per cent in first 4 months of the year, with police linking surge to return to normality]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3225615/hong-kong-theft-cases-jump-nearly-40-cent-first-4-months-year-police-linking-surge-return-normality?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/e743677b-8a4d-4f31-b34f-9f500787ebad_c4f649ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Theft cases in Hong Kong rose by nearly 40 per cent in the first four months of the year over the same period in 2022, with police attributing the surge to the city&#39;s return to normality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of the latest thefts took place in Mong Kok, which Chief Inspector Choi Wing-yuk of the crime prevention bureau said was not surprising “given the high foot traffic in the area”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force recorded 7,167 thefts between January and April, an increase of 39.4 per cent over the year before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As society returns to normal, we are seeing more people on the streets in general,” Choi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong dropped the last of its Covid-19 travel restrictions and social-distancing rules earlier this year after remaining largely closed off since 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the force, the city recorded 27,911 total crimes in the first four months of the year, up 44 per cent from the 19,379 recorded the year before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trend continued into May, taking overall crime for the first five months to 35,863, or 10,434 more than the number recorded over the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among them, 3,872 were considered violent crimes - 598 more than in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi also revealed that wallets or credit cards, cash and Octopus stored-value cards were among the most common items stolen by pickpockets, followed by mobile phones.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong man, 79, robbed of Rolex and ring after woman promises massage&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Parked bicycles were also in the top three items taken by thieves, with Choi pointing out that many were secured with flimsy locks that could be easily removed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She urged owners to choose thicker, higher quality locks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest numbers included 2,498 shoplifting cases, compared with 1,915 last year in the same four-month period, and 2,369 in 2019 before the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Supermarkets recorded the most cases, at 999, but Choi said this could be linked to them being the most common type of store in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police hunt thieves who used GPS tracker to find car and steal HK$260,000&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Store managers have been advised to designate staff members to watch over customers using increasingly common self-service checkouts, as a number of recent shoplifting cases involved people failing to scan all their items and hoping it goes unnoticed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force said it had resumed a regular security workshop with retailers, which aimed to educate them on how to prevent theft and burglary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The workshop was held roughly every six months before the pandemic but was halted for several years due to Covid measures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Steve Mok, who runs a vehicle repair shop in To Kwa Wan, was one of the 50 store owners who attended the most recent session this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest woman, 53, over theft of jade pieces worth HK$9.5 million&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The event was very useful, and we learned a lot,” he said. “We realised that, apart from well-known methods like installing basic security cameras and locking up your valuable products in special display boxes, there are newer, more technologically advanced tools, such as infrared surveillance systems and motion detectors that are available on the market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the force&#39;s Sai Kung division said it had carried out special operations with other departments such as the Government Flying Service, marine police and dog units to search and patrol areas where people entering the city tended to hide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said the operation was conducted “in view of the recent increase in the number of burglary cases in the district”, and urged residents to work with police and stay vigilant.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s cloud services subsidiary and Shanghai’s Fudan University establish new intelligent computing platform for AI initiatives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225619/alibabas-cloud-services-subsidiary-and-shanghais-fudan-university-establish-new-intelligent?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/f260826c-32fc-4f21-af5e-27b1afbc2ec5_c815a8f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Group Holding&#39;s cloud computing services subsidiary and Shanghai&#39;s Fudan University have jointly launched what they describe as the country&#39;s largest cloud-based scientific research and intelligent computing platform for universities, deepening the business unit&#39;s ties with major public institutions and boosting its support for new artificial intelligence (AI) initiatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new Computing for the Future at Fudan (CFFF) platform was designed to train large AI models, such as large language models (LLMs), for the purpose of scientific research, according to a statement published by Alibaba Cloud on Tuesday. Hangzhou-based parent Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In universities, professors may be able to afford cloud computing [services] with scientific research funds, but not every student can afford it,” said Alibaba Cloud founder Wang Jian at a ceremony held at the university&#39;s campus. “I hope that everyone can use cloud computing to realise their scientific research ideals.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China Telecom, the country&#39;s largest fixed-line network operator and a major domestic cloud services provider, was also behind the development of the new computing platform. Earlier this month, China Telecom unveiled a plan to set up a huge computing centre in Shanghai to support the city&#39;s AI industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CFFF project, which Wang depicted as a dream come true after 15 years, reflects China&#39;s big bet on generative AI as a strategic tool that would not only save a national economy saddled by debt and a sluggish post-coronavirus recovery, but also refuel the country&#39;s bid to beat the US in their heated tech rivalry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;LLMs are deep-learning AI algorithms that can recognise, summarise, translate, predict and generate content using very large data sets. These represent the technology used to train AI chatbots like Microsoft-backed OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fudan University president Jin Li said the academic institution hopes to build a number of world-class models using the CFFF, including models related to life sciences, material science and integrated circuits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Cloud – headed by Daniel Zhang Yong, who will step down as the parent group&#39;s chairman and chief executive in September – unveiled in April its answer to ChatGPT, called Tongyi Qianwen.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Generative AI, cloud computing and security top tech trends for 2023: Alibaba academy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Cloud computing services from Alibaba and other providers enable enterprises to buy, sell, lease or distribute a range of software and other digital resources as an on-demand service over the internet, just like electricity from a power grid. These resources are managed inside data centres.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Enterprises and universities should join hands in innovation and talent training,” Jin was quoted as saying in Fudan University&#39;s WeChat post on Tuesday about the “comprehensive strategic cooperation” with Alibaba Cloud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Echoing that statement, Alibaba Cloud&#39;s Wang said he expected the company and Fudan University would further “deepen the integration of production and education”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Alibaba Cloud and Fudan University did not elaborate on the details of their cooperation, the two sides are expected to help cultivate new local talent in AI.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Alibaba seeks growth from AI co-development programme, cloud price cuts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chinese state media recently drummed up support for generative AI, referring to the algorithms that power ChatGPT and similar services. A People&#39;s Daily op-ed piece published earlier this month extolled the technology&#39;s potential to help drive economic growth and become a useful daily tool.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba&#39;s Cloud Intelligence Group, meanwhile, is expected to become an independent entity in the next 12 months under the e-commerce giant&#39;s sweeping restructuring plan. That would eventually enable the firm to seek a separate public listing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Court says Donald Trump must face New York civil fraud claims, tosses case against Ivanka]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225643/court-says-donald-trump-must-face-new-york-civil-fraud-claims-tosses-case-against-ivanka?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 06:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/2563186d-1159-485c-8d7b-f5889483ef86_c5df5a1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A New York appeal court on Tuesday rejected Donald Trump&#39;s bid to end the state attorney general&#39;s lawsuit accusing the former US president and his family business of “staggering” fraud, but dismissed all claims against his daughter Ivanka Trump and said the remaining case may be limited further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Attorney General Letitia James&#39; civil case filed last September accused Trump of lying from 2011 to 2021 about asset values, including for his Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida and Trump Tower penthouse in Manhattan, as well as his own net worth, to obtain better terms from lenders and insurers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawsuit seeks at least US$250 million in damages from Trump, his adult sons Donald Jnr and Eric, the Trump Organisation and others, and to stop the Trumps from running businesses in New York.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Donald Trump, the Republican front-runner for the 2024 presidential election, has denied wrongdoing. He has also called James&#39; case and two unrelated criminal indictments, where he has pleaded not guilty, part of a Democratic “witch hunt.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a 5-0 decision, the Appellate Division in Manhattan said state law gave James power to police alleged “repeated or persistent fraud or illegality,” and conduct lengthy and complex investigations many years after suspected misconduct began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it said statutes of limitations prevented James, who had investigated Trump&#39;s business dealings for three years, from suing over claims that arose before July 13, 2014, or February 6, 2016, depending on the defendant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also said all claims against Ivanka Trump should be dismissed because they were filed too late, and because she was no longer with the Trump Organisation at the relevant time.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump heard discussing &#39;highly confidential&#39; documents in new recording&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The court returned the case to Justice Arthur Engoron of the state Supreme Court in Manhattan to determine which parts could proceed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An October 2 trial is scheduled. Trump was questioned under oath for the case in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a mountain of evidence that shows Mr Trump and the Trump Organisation falsely and fraudulently valued multiple assets and misrepresented those values to financial institutions for significant economic gain,” a spokeswoman for James said. “This decision allows us to hold him accountable for that fraud, and we intend to do so.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During oral arguments on June 6, a lawyer for James said Trump&#39;s transactions did not occur in a vacuum, and that letting him commit fraud hurts honest participants in banking, insurance and real estate markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Christopher Kise, a lawyer for Donald Trump and most of the other defendants, called the decision “the first step” towards ending a case that James should not have filed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The correct application of the law will now limit appropriately the previously unlimited reach of the attorney general,” he said. “We remain confident that once all the real facts are known, there will be no doubt President Trump has built an extraordinarily successful business empire.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ivanka Trump&#39;s lawyer did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the criminal cases, Trump faces a 34-count indictment obtained by Manhattan District Attorney Alvin Bragg over hush money payments to a porn star, and a 38-count US Justice Department indictment saying he mishandled classified documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The New York civil case is New York v Trump et al, New York State Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Department, No. 2023-00717.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>