<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[To improve UK-China relations, focus on the grey areas]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228239/improve-uk-china-relations-focus-grey-areas?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/5bd70949-8de8-4815-88c8-dc7a8898288d_6ef97351.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中英关系恶化之前，我的印象是英国完全向世界开放，没有太多警惕。但进入2020年以来，风云突变，国家对中国极度谨慎和怀疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对华正确态度是什么？由于英国媒体将国内政治置于外交政策之上，未能彻底解释中美之间的地缘政治竞争。许多英国人可能对唐宁街10号态度的巨大转变感到困惑。他们的日常生活严重依赖中国制造，无论他们喜欢与否。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我生活在中国时，我的心态受到中国官方媒体的影响，所以我相信中国政府正在做的事情是基于主权原则的合理性。在英国生活的19年里，我接触到了更高的人权和自由价值观，这与中国强调主权和社会责任是不一致的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从西方价值观来看，中国政府给人的印象是落后于西方的趋势。我感觉到我出生、接受教育和工作的中国很像19世纪的英国——一个经济强劲的国家，但社会不公平、不平等，饱受种族主义困扰。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;当我听到中国王毅在国际关系论坛上试图说服首尔和东京重启与北京的合作时，表达了这样的观点时，我惊讶地发现，即使是中国最高层的外交也没有取得多大进展：“当我们去美国时，他们分不清中国人、日本人和韩国人。我们在欧洲可能也会经历同样的情况。不管你把头发染得多金，鼻子做得多尖，你永远不会成为西方人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果我今天生活在中国，我会给王热烈的掌声因为大陆的心态是一种对西方帝国主义的愤怒，而西方帝国主义的基础是相信白人的优越性。只有少数英国人意识到前殖民地国家中持续存在的怨恨情绪。与此同时，中国人却没有意识到，许多英国人对帝国主义的黑暗时代感到羞耻，并正在尽最大努力与自己国家的种族主义作斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;儒家思想强调对家庭、统治者和公民的责任和义务。 2000多年来，国家对中国社会产生了深远的影响。西方启蒙运动的精神并没有触及中国大陆社会的大部分人。俄罗斯共产主义对中国来说是一个相对较新的事物。它的历史只能追溯到一百多年前。今天的中国政治是俄罗斯共产主义、儒家思想和中国共产党自己探索的混合体，与清朝时期的民主相差并不远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为第一代英国移民来自中国的我对中英关系的恶化感到非常沮丧。我最近在我的一篇专栏文章中采访了前英国财政部首席秘书、现任亚洲基础设施投资银行副行长丹尼·亚历山大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我原本以为会见到一位压力很大的英国人鉴于加拿大最近暂停了与该银行的关系，原因是该银行的全球通讯总监（加拿大人）辞职，称该银行“由共产党控制”。不过，亚历山大一脸轻松地表示，在当前环境下他并没有感受到任何压力，英国和中国一样，对亚投行的工作持积极态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我问他亚投行是否是他回答说，该银行是一个独立组织，只支持亚洲的优秀项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次采访不仅向我强调了一些说法我在英文媒体上看到的消息不实，也说明了西方与中国之间的误解程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们应该避免做出极端的判断。除了黑与白之外，还有很多灰色地带可供维护和平。无论西方对中国政府的人权记录有多大异议，它都需要保持耐心，学习如何与这个新兴大国和平合作，应对气候变化和俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea threatens nuclear response after US submarine deployment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3228410/north-korea-threatens-nuclear-response-after-us-submarine-deployment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 07:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/21/c1913d15-9dce-4b2c-b068-7d334ea490e6_fd7760f7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;朝鲜国防部长周四表示，美国核潜艇目前正在港口访问向韩国派遣潜艇可以满足平壤使用核武器的法律条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国关系正处于历史最低点之一，外交陷入僵局，朝鲜领导人金正恩呼吁加强武器研发，包括战术核武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，美国和韩国加大了军事实力的展示力度，一艘美国核潜艇本周访问了韩国港口自1981年以来首次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平壤国防部长康顺南表示，一艘美国俄亥俄级潜艇抵达釜山港“可能属于朝鲜指定的使用核武器的条件”朝鲜的官方名称是“核力量政策法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国潜艇抵达韩国后，朝鲜发射了两枚导弹&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;朝鲜去年采取了全面的制裁措施核法，规定了一系列可以使用核武器的情景，包括在受到威胁时进行先发制人的核打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;康表示，潜艇的存在是“对美国的公开和直接的核威胁”。朝鲜”，意思是“40多年后首次在朝鲜半岛部署战略核武器”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美军方应该认识到，其核资产已进入极其危险的水域” ”，他在朝鲜中央通讯社发表的一份声明中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈周三视察了俄亥俄级潜艇，并警告平壤如果对朝鲜使用核武器俄亥俄级潜艇最多可携带 20 枚三叉戟 II 弹道导弹。美国海军通常不会在潜艇出海前确认其是否携带核武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;盟国还在首尔举行了首次核磋商小组会议，以改善对任何核潜艇的联合反应。韩国国家统一研究所研究员洪敏表示，朝鲜的核攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看来，潜艇的部署让朝鲜感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“平壤发出的信息他说：“美国和韩国的行动方式正在促使朝鲜更接近考虑援引其核武器使用准则。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;朝鲜表示，在威胁美国侦察机后，它击退了一架美国间谍飞机。击落它们&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“尹在访问潜艇期间提到朝鲜政权终结的评论似乎让平壤感到非常不安，促使其做出更加积极的反应。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;朝鲜今年进行了一系列被禁止的武器试验，包括两次发射其最新的固体燃料Hwasong-18洲际弹道导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔和华盛顿已加强防务合作作为回应，举行联合军事演习拥有先进的隐形飞机和美国战略资产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿于四月份首次宣布将部署一艘能够向朝鲜半岛发射携带核弹头的弹道导弹的潜艇，当时尹正正在进行国事访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;朝鲜不愿在朝鲜半岛周围部署美国核资产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;康说，对于华盛顿和首尔来说，“对朝鲜使用军事力量将是他们最悲惨的选择”平壤发表声明之际，据信美国士兵特拉维斯·金 (Travis King) 在前往朝鲜旅游期间越过边境后被朝鲜拘留。周二，非军事区（DMZ）的联合安全区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平壤长期以来一直拘留美国人，并将他们用作双边关系中讨价还价的筹码。目前尚未对金发表任何评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国士兵笑着越过边境后被朝鲜拘留&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国领导的联合国司令部表示正在与朝鲜合作军事力量“解决这一事件”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但由于平壤和华盛顿之间的关系处于多年来的最低点之一，专家表示很难获得金的领事探访。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;此外，在朝鲜于 2020 年因 Covid-19 大流行关闭边境后，几乎所有驻平壤的外国大使馆都撤回了外国工作人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括负责处理美国在朝鲜首都的领事事务的瑞典.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US chip curbs are scaring venture capital firms from Chinese AI start-ups, but not us, says BlueRun Ventures China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3228372/us-chip-curbs-are-scaring-venture-capital-firms-chinese-ai-start-ups-not-us-says-bluerun-ventures?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/20/8f1e3339-b200-4c6b-b21a-a339874b9e78_5cd8012b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国芯片出口限制使一些中国风险投资者不再支持生成人工智能（总部位于硅谷的 BlueRun Ventures (BRV) 中国分公司的一位投资者表示，随着中国公司竞相创建类似于 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT 的服务，人工智能）初创企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的人工智能发展可能会BRV 中国执行合伙人 Jui Tan 周四在接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时表示，短期内将面临挑战，因为美国对先进图形处理单元 (GPU) 出口的限制“吓跑了一些人”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“你担心你投资应用场景、投​​资人才后，可能半途就意识到自己没有足够的计算能力，无法获得足够的 GPU，”Tan 说。 “我认为这给企业家和投资者带来了某种恐惧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 8 月，美国商务部禁止美国公司 Nvidia 和 Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) 销售其一些最先进的产品。芯片运往中国。这一决定导致中国人工智能行业争先恐后地争夺英伟达生产的有限 GPU 供应，英伟达几乎垄断了用于训练人工智能系统的处理器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当中国科技巨头争论中国在人工智能方面落后了多远时关键技术的缺乏阻碍了一些国内投资者加入生成式人工智能潮流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国亿万富翁投资者、电动汽车巨头比亚迪联合创始人夏作全上周告诉《华盛顿邮报》他对ChatGPT级别的产品很快会在中国诞生持怀疑态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，谭表示BRV致力于投资中国的人工智能领域。他表示，这家风险投资公司计划将去年 5 月筹集的 55 亿元人民币（8.17 亿美元）新基金中的 50% 以上分配给人工智能初创企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan 表示，他从长远看，“足够的资本和人才”将能够解决中国的算力困境。他表示，在不久的将来，中国的企业家可以擅长创建不需要密集计算能力的独特的生成式人工智能应用程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan 表示，BRV 中国还重点关注机器人和新能源等领域。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司是中国电动汽车制造商理想汽车的支持者，该公司于 2021 年 8 月在香港上市。Tan 表示，BRV China 也希望与香港的行业进行更密切的合作。这座城市是人才、数据和金融中心，可以帮助中国的人工智能初创企业走向全球。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BRV China 由 Tan 于 2005 年创立，是众多在中国投资的风险投资公司之一。应对日益复杂的地缘政治环境。中美紧张关系引发了人们对美国对中国技术的投资正在枯竭的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;源代码资本是一家总部位于北京的风险投资公司，从中国地方政府和全球有限合伙人那里筹集资金，该公司正在结束对中国技术的投资。中国媒体周二报道了种子融资计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国风险投资巨头红杉资本上个月宣布，将把其中国子公司分拆为一家名为红杉的独立公司，作为全球重组的一部分，该重组还创建了一个独立的公司该品牌专注于印度和东南亚的业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan 表示，对于 BRV 中国来说，地缘政治风险“不是什么问题”，因为该公司一直与美国兄弟公司分开运营，尽管它们在相同的品牌名称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谭补充说，BRV 中国的决策是独立做出的，不分享利润和后台服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，中国在美国的投资仍受到严格审查风险投资行业正在不断发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括纪源资本、金沙江创投、华登国际和高通创投在内的几家美国风险投资公司正因对芯片、人工智能和量子计算的资助而受到美国国会委员会的调查据《华尔街日报》周三报道，中国的公司。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s ‘self-aware’ DINK couples, with no kids, could prolong demographic crisis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228374/chinas-self-aware-dink-couples-no-kids-could-prolong-demographic-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/20/f3de067d-95f3-4bc1-8317-e6aadd903215_a8db55fc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是关于 2023 年上半年动荡的经济陷阱和逆风的第二篇文章当张成英第一次告诉她的父母她和她的丈夫不会生孩子时，当他们问张成英时，他们的反应是震惊她是否有什么问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没什么，这位 32 岁的女士解释道。他们只想成为一对丁克夫妇——双份收入，没有孩子。他们目前距离这个目标还差两倍的收入，但预计这种情况很快就会改变——他们正在享受开放的道路上的休息时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我母亲说她已经 60 多岁了，会被嘲笑的因为没有孙子，”张说。 “但我会改变自己的生活，只是为了避免她被别人嘲笑吗？没有。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张刚从山东省一所医科大学毕业，获得药学博士学位，她正在等待时机，等待今年晚些时候在一家医院空缺的科研职位。她的丈夫将在两周后开始在公共机构工作。目前，他们喜欢熬夜、睡懒觉，不用担心孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，这对夫妇出发了 5,499 公里（3,417 英里）的公路旅行 - 精心计划了 59 个小时三分钟——这将带他们穿越中国其他三个省份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我有一个孩子，我绝对不可能这么无忧无虑，”张说。 “由于父母的责任，我的一些朋友很少有时间出去和我见面。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管北京在12月结束了近三年的限制性零新冠措施，它们对人们的经济和精神福祉产生了持久的影响。对于许多人来说，由此产​​生的经济压力和焦虑使他们对未来的前景感到担忧，并且更倾向于拒绝为人父母的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种趋势在零之前的几年中逐渐兴起。 -新冠疫情期间，全国范围内的停工、停工和广泛的经济不确定性似乎加剧了疫情期间的流动性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的出生率去年创下历史新低，死亡人数首次超过出生人数六十多年来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为自己变得更加有自我意识，而我们的父母认为我们变得更加自私，”26 岁的深圳个体户杨晓彤说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;和张一样，杨也不愿意为了孩子而放弃自己的生命和自由。她和她的丈夫于四月结婚，他们说三年的流行病控制对他们的想法产生了很大的影响。除了厌恶生孩子之外，他们开始反思生命的真正意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[我意识到]我想看看整个世界，而不是被孩子限制在一个世界里。”深圳 80 平方米的公寓，”杨说，他的旅行野心与张和其他许多人的愿望一样。 “现在很多年轻人更加注重提高自己的生活质量，因为我们珍惜在这个星球上拥有的时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨说，自己创业的压力已经够大了。虽然她确实有一些有孩子的朋友，但她也有几个也满足于做丁克人，还有一些甚至不想结婚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任远，人口研究所教授复旦大学教授表示，这种情绪将对国家产生长期影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“考虑到结婚率下降和未婚人口比例上升，中国将非常未来几十年，中国的低生育率可能仍将保持在较低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据国家统计局的数据，2022年总人口比2021年减少85万人，这是61年来人口首次下降。年。首胎生育率也下降至0.5。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有研究发现，生育的经历本身就可以提升人们的生育意愿，所以现在中国最大的担忧就是生育率过低。”南开大学人口与发展研究所教授陈为民表示，“一胎家庭的生育率越来越高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，生育成本的上升，加上当前的生育成本上升，经济低迷，超过五分之一的年轻人失业——意味着更多的夫妇发现自己无力抚养孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“说实话，扣除房租、水电费和生活费后，没有多少钱可以养活孩子。”我每月 5000 元（700 美元）的工资还剩下钱，”山东省 24 岁的护士屈云说。她说，她不想要孩子的主要原因是缺钱和时间——她每天工作超过12个小时，连午饭时间都没有，更不用说要孩子了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此越来越多的地方政府和企业正在推行补贴作为生育激励措施，瞿先生的想法仍然没有被吓倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府最好加强对劳工权利的保护，比如规范加班和加班等。” “提高工资，而不是试图说服人们结婚生子。”曲说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使是拥有高级教育证书、可以找到相对较高薪工作的张，仍然担心能够充分供养孩子。她会关注亲戚们的支出，尤其是在辅导上的支出，以便让他们的孩子在如此有争议的经济中占据一席之地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“教育成本如此之高，我不希望我的孩子出生在这样的环境中。”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着人口危机的迫近，中国减少了农民工结婚的繁文缛节&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，心理健康问题正在上升，包括年轻人的心理健康问题。在大流行的孤立主义时代，让孩子融入其中的想法似乎令人畏惧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时应对抑郁症，当孩子变得淘气时，“让我们更难保持耐心”，杨南开大学陈教授表示，即使是与成年人的人际关系也变得更加难以处理。在社交媒体上，不可否认的是，中国必须让社会变得更有利于生育婴幼儿，以“建立儿童友好型社会”为目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“年轻人的生育欲望确实已经增强。” ” 陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在开始中国的公路旅行之前，张成英总结道：“我不能说我是否会改变我的生育习惯。等我40岁的时候才会介意，但现在我非常坚决不要孩子。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I’ll never forget’: Hong Kong health workers in Turkey quake rescue mission recall sleepless nights, freezing temperatures]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3228375/ill-never-forget-hong-kong-health-workers-turkey-quake-rescue-mission-recall-sleepless-nights?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/20/b2f51e32-1807-4c81-aeba-5d5d4f1d4b44_b24c1ba9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;魏永森和他的医疗同事曾经失眠超过48天今年早些时候，一支由 59 人组成的香港团队执行了为期 9 天的援助土耳其地震灾区的任务，期间她已经工作了 10 个小时，并且一个多星期没有洗澡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 40 岁的护士说，当中午气温升高时，由于缺乏干净的水，该小组不得不经常使用湿纸巾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我永远不会忘记这次经历，”Ngai说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回忆道当他们收到一袋五至十公升的水用于清洁目的时，他们感到很兴奋，他们用这些水在室外淋浴设施清洗头发和身体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倪与护士郭展凤一起今年 2 月，土耳其发生 7.8 级地震，造成数万人死亡，救援人员从该市派往土耳其，帮助寻找幸存者，卫生署医生刘健生和范婉雯医生也是其中之一。该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团队包括消防员和两只狗，救出了四人并找到了六具尸体。 59名成员因其在国家的工作而荣获首届行政长官模范表现奖。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;派往土耳其地震任务的香港团队荣获首届最高奖项&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据该部门55岁的家庭医学顾问范说，四名医务人员的任务是照顾团队的身心健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还在出发前为团队接种了疫苗，并进行监测范说，恢复尸体可能会对灾区的传染病、治疗疾病和处理紧急情况产生影响，并补充说，她和她的同事鼓励他们联系他们的家人或与救援犬玩耍以缓解压力。他们还获得了糖果来缓解情绪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，他们在执行任务期间遇到了许多障碍，包括语言障碍、道路受损、食物和水短缺、严寒以及全天候的密集工作。工作安排很紧凑，但当幸存者获救时，辛苦得到了回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们得知人们可以获救时，我们非常兴奋，忍不住哭了，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;刘，58岁，是该部门的高级医疗卫生官员，他说他和同事每天早上都会对救援队成员进行健康检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们只是尽力而为” &#39;：香港救援队回忆土耳其任务的挑战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;部分人员因天气寒冷而出现体温过低、血压升高，部分人员出现打喷嚏、咳嗽和皮肤问题等症状”，刘说，并补充说，他和他的同事为他们治疗了疾病，并教会了他们保暖的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们每个人都尽了最大努力，发挥了我们的专业知识。我们在充满余震和危机的环境中拯救了四人的生命。”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭是该部门的一名36岁护理人员，接受过灾难护理服务和心理健康急救方面的培训，称地震地区细菌、病原体猖獗，存在传染病风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港救援人员土耳其地震救援归来获赞&lt;/h3>;&lt;他说，四人设立了消毒区，救援人员返回后用洗手液和湿纸巾清洁自己，并用生理盐水清洁两只救援犬的眼睛和鼻子。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管困难重重，郭先生也回忆起一些温馨的时刻，比如用纸板为团队成员制作生日贺卡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望成员能够感受到困难之下有一点甜蜜。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese hacked emails of US ambassador to China, senior State Department envoy for Asia: reports]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228409/chinese-hacked-emails-us-ambassador-china-senior-state-department-envoy-asia-reports?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 06:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/21/b10dfa50-5df7-451e-b556-ef3f10e9e5a4_6c9f139a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;华盛顿驻北京大使和国务院东亚事务高级官员的电子邮件帐户据《华尔街日报》和 CNN 援引消息人士称，据报道，太平洋和太平洋地区遭到中国黑客入侵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次黑客攻击涉及美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯 (Nicholas Burns) 及其助理丹尼尔·克里滕布林克 (Daniel Kritenbrink) 的账户负责东亚和太平洋事务的国务卿的事件似乎与白宫上周披露的一起事件有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向美国政府提供 IT 服务的主要提供商微软表示，一家已知的中国组织称Storm-0558 成功使用 Microsoft 消费者签名密钥入侵了超过 25 个组织，其中包括各个政府机构和美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多 (Gina Raimondo) 的办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然据称没有机密电子邮件被泄露美国有线电视新闻网 (CNN) 援引内部人士的话说，黑客可能获取了有关美国高官近期多次访华的国内政策磋商和安排的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果得到证实，伯恩斯和克里滕布林克将是据《华尔街日报》报道，目前还没有证据表明国务卿安东尼·布林肯及其直接助手受到了影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院最高级别官员的电子邮件遭到黑客攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》联系了美国国务院和中国驻华盛顿大使馆请其置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于政府未能认识到威胁，中国针对英国机构&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国外交部发言人毛泽东宁周三回应了有关北京支持或资助黑客从美国获取信息的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毛声称中国本身就是网络攻击的受害者，并强烈反对任何此类活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发言人指责美国多年来“对其他国家进行不分青红皂白的大规模网络攻击”，并表示华盛顿“绝不能用毫无根据的言论抹黑其他国家，以服务其政治议程”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s ‘shameful’ parading of naked women in Manipur condemned by Modi, promises tough action]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228400/indias-shameful-parading-naked-women-manipur-condemned-modi-promises-tough-action?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/20/792e7048-7451-48a9-ae69-a81f7c4c1430_80788a52.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;总理纳伦德拉·莫迪谴责曼尼普尔邦对妇女的性侵犯指控“这是他对偏远东北地区的种族冲突发表的首次评论，这场冲突已造成至少 125 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一段显示袭击事件的视频引发了巨大的愤怒，并于周三晚些时候在社交媒体上广泛传播尽管互联网基本上被封锁，记者也被锁在这个偏远的州。它显示两名裸体妇女被数十名年轻男子包围，这些年轻男子摸索她们的生殖器并将她们拖到田野里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有罪者将不会幸免。发生在曼尼普尔邦女儿身上的事情永远不能被原谅，”莫迪在周四晚上的议会会议前对记者表示，这是他首次就曼尼普尔邦冲突发表公开评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有提及暴力事件。莫迪直接敦促各国政府首脑确保妇女的安全，并表示这一事件“对任何文明国家来说都是可耻的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的心里充满了痛苦和愤怒，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;发生致命冲突后，印度教的梅蒂斯和基督教的库基斯下一步该怎么办？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;视频中描绘的种族暴力是曼尼普尔邦近乎内战的象征，暴徒们在村庄里横冲直撞，并纵火焚烧自 5 月份以来，已造成 130 多人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场冲突是由一场平权行动争议引发的，其中克里斯蒂安·库基斯 (Christian Kukis) 抗议以印度教徒为主的梅泰人 (Meiteis) 提出的特殊地位要求，允许他们在印度购买土地。库基人和其他部落群体居住的山地，并获得一份政府工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管军队驻扎在曼尼普尔邦，但冲突仍然持续。曼尼普尔邦位于印度与缅甸边境的山区，拥有 370 万人口现在分为两个民族地区。交战各方还组建了武装民兵，偏僻的村庄仍然枪林弹雨。超过 60,000 人已逃往挤满人的救援营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，对两名妇女的袭击发生在 5 月 4 日，即该州发生暴力事件的第二天。根据警方 5 月 18 日提交的起诉书，这两名妇女所在的一个家庭遭到暴徒袭击，并杀死了两名男性成员。投诉指控“身份不明的恶棍”强奸和谋杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;是什么导致印度曼尼普尔邦爆发种族暴力？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;就在莫迪结束声明时，曼尼普尔邦首席部长比伦·辛格发推文该州警方已对该案进行了首次逮捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前正在进行彻底调查，我们将确保对所有肇事者采取严厉行动，包括考虑死刑的可能性，”说辛格被人权组织和一些印度人民党议员指责未能解决暴力问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曼尼普尔邦警方表示，他们已经立案侦查轮奸案并逮捕了一名男子，并补充说其他人将警方称，初步调查显示，这两名妇女的袭击发生在 5 月 4 日，但她们被武装歹徒拖拽、摸索和赤身裸体游街示众的视频在周三疯传。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;印度最高法院表示对这些图像深感不安，并要求政府告诉法院为逮捕肇事者并确保此类事件不再重演而采取的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度首席大法官 DY Chandrachud 表示：“在宪政民主国家，这是不可接受的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度妇女和儿童发展部长斯姆里蒂·伊拉尼 (Smriti Israeli) 称这一事件“应受谴责且完全不人道”。 She said investigations were under way and that “no effort will be spared to bring perpetrators to justice”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s main opposition Congress party president Mallikarjun Kharge, however, accused the ruling Hindu-nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party of “turning democracy and the rule of law into mobocracy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kharge said Modi should speak about Manipur in Parliament, a demand that has been made by other opposition parties and rights activists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India will never forgive your silence,” he wrote on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will China’s private firms fly higher, freer under new action plan as Beijing calls for ‘fresh troops’?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228379/will-chinas-private-firms-fly-higher-freer-under-new-action-plan-beijing-calls-fresh-troops?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/a3f4bdc4-431e-4ab5-9972-9b0729f534ef_6d9eaae8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China issued a comprehensive action plan on Wednesday to support its private businesses amid a weakening economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the end of Beijing&#39;s strict zero-Covid policy, business confidence has remained low and many firms are on the edge of closure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having served as the backbone for the economy as the biggest contributor to employment and innovation, the private sector has been a topic of heated debate over the past decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has also previously received multiple rounds of policy support.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The new plan, which includes 31 measures, for the first time called private companies “fresh troops in pushing forward China&#39;s modernisation”, emphasising their strategic importance in China&#39;s future growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vowing to make them “bigger, better and stronger”, the plan rolled out a series of measures that responded directly to the major concerns shared by business owners, including difficulty in obtaining payments from governments and state-owned companies (SOEs).&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s economic backbone, private firms decry lack of parity in policy support&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The most comprehensive policy package issued since President Xi Jinping started his third presidential term in March, the plan also called for a more tolerant environment for private firms and more social respect for entrepreneurship and innovation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There should be an atmosphere of “encouraging innovation and tolerating failure”, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While business leaders, including Tencent&#39;s Pony Ma and Xiaomi&#39;s Lei Jun, welcomed the plan, others expressed concern whether all the measures could be implemented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an article published by state television on Wednesday, Ma said the measures were clear and “highly targeted”, and that they “have stabilised expectations for realising high-quality development”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But smaller industry players are worried the plan is just paying lip service, as despite plenty of government pledges to boost the private economy over the years, issues such as unfair competition from SOEs, less access to funding, excessive government supervision and a lack of legal protection, have continued to trouble private companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aside from impact from the coronavirus pandemic, many private firms, including platform companies, property developers and private tutoring services, have also suffered from Beijing&#39;s regulatory crackdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While promising tolerance and urging social understanding for the private sector, Beijing has been tightening its grip on businesses, with phrases related to the Communist Party appearing 11 times in the plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It vowed to “actively and prudently” develop party members among private companies, strengthen education about socialist values and “explore new ways” to build the party.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As growth falters, China&#39;s private sector struggles, and jobs take a hit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Having emerged as a global power, largely due to the freeing up of private businesses over four decades ago, China allowed entrepreneurs to become party members in 2001 to recognise their stronger role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And any private company with more than three party members is obliged to set up a party cell, according to the Communist Party Charter.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It has been argued that China&#39;s SOEs are advancing, while the private sector has been retreating since the 2000s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private firms&#39; anxiety about their fate reached a peak in 2018 when a viral post online urged them to “leave the stage” as their “task of assisting the state-owned economy in achieving its rapid development” had been fulfilled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite denials from the authorities in the following years, private companies are yet to enjoy a level playing field, encounter stricter market entry and are regarded as being riskier when trying to obtain bank loans.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese authorities approve new guidelines for private firms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the post-Covid climate, state giants are faring better than their private counterparts. In the first half of the year, fixed-asset investment by private firms fell 0.2 per cent from the previous year, in sharp contrast with the rise of 8.1 per cent among their state-owned rivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Profits for private industrial enterprises with an annual revenue of at least 20 million yuan (US$2.8 million) fell by 21.3 per cent in the first five months of the year, compared with a drop of 17.7 per cent by SOEs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;Weak private sector is holding back China&#39;s economic recovery, adviser warns&lt;/h3>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 05:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Divide grows in Washington over US-China trade, as hawkish bipartisanship starts to crack]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228408/divide-grows-washington-over-us-china-trade-hawkish-bipartisanship-starts-crack?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/2af9bb74-f8a9-42d7-9cd5-f2bac6893c08_064aa1ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US lawmakers&#39; debate over how best to handle the US-China economic relationship was on full view at a congressional hearing on Thursday, with many Republicans arguing for a complete decoupling while some Democrats contended such a move would weaken American companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representative Blaine Luetkemeyer, a Missouri Republican, took aim at Thea Rozman Kendler, assistant secretary of commerce for export administration, during her testimony before the House select committee on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luetkemeyer suggested that approvals for exports to Chinese companies including Huawei Technologies, along with the long-running US trade deficit with China, helped Beijing “build detention camps against their own people, subsidise their industries against ours and build up their military”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve got to stop everything going to China,” Luetkemeyer said. “If we don&#39;t, they use everything against us, and your willingness to continue to play games with them and be a partner with them endangers us down the road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When they overtake us [economically], we&#39;re done,” he added, citing a Goldman Sachs estimate that China “will finally be able to overtake the United States within the next 10 years”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They will be able to dictate all sorts of things to all their economic partners around the world.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kendler contended that the Commerce Department had taken “a litany of steps … to make sure that the Chinese government” did not gain “technology that they can use to threaten US national security interests”. She cited the restrictions on the export of “dual-use civilian technologies by the military”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rhetorical battle over US trade and investment with China underscored a growing divide on Washington&#39;s approach to Beijing, one of the few fronts on which the two parties have increasingly converged in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republicans have seized on a recent resumption of dialogue between high-ranking officials in US President Joe Biden&#39;s administration – including Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen – and their counterparts in Beijing, characterising these efforts as appeasement.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US-China economic rivalry not &#39;winner-take-all&#39;, Yellen says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As Kendler did on Thursday, the Biden administration often touts restrictions it placed last year on exports of the most advanced semiconductors and their production equipment to China. But Republicans have cited statistics showing high rates of approval for US exporters seeking permits to sell such items to the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security Alan Estevez told the House Foreign Affairs Committee that the department and other government agencies approved about 70 per cent of export licence applications involving China in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representative Jake Auchincloss, a Massachusetts Democrat, sketched the administration&#39;s position on trade and investment with China by leading Kendler through a series of questions, all of which she answered positively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Could trade with China “give America incorporated scale economies, especially for high fixed costs, low marginal cost industries like biopharmaceuticals or semiconductors or telecoms, so that we can invest more in R&amp;D here”?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Could such trade allow the US industry “have standard-setting and other soft-power prerogatives”?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Might it help “prevent Chinese dominance of large internal markets in a way that would give them that standard setting and soft power”?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet not all Democrats completely disagreed with the hawkish assessments by Luetkemeyer and other Republicans that trade with China undermines American interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representative Ro Khanna of California, whose Bay Area district includes Silicon Valley, called the offshoring of manufacturing to China and the resulting growth in US bilateral trade deficits “a bipartisan mistake for 40 years”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Khanna said, addressing the problem should start with efforts to bring steel, aluminium and other “critical industries” back to the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We said we&#39;re going to do all the invention and we&#39;ll do all this stuff in Silicon Valley,” he said. “You go to places like Lordstown, Ohio, and they&#39;re hollowed out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I was there, I&#39;d be terribly upset at failed American leadership for 40 years while we just watched as steel left, as aluminium left.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;American chip companies need access to China: semiconductor trade group&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The hearing Thursday was the committee&#39;s third public event in a week that included economic disengagement from China as a focal point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, it hosted a debate with four experts on whether the US should revoke China&#39;s permanent normal trade relations (PNTR) status.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PNTR, a US legal designation for most-favoured nation status, was granted to China by then-president Bill Clinton in 2000, letting the two sides align their bilateral trade relationship with the rules of the World Trade Organization, which China acceded to the following year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Republicans argued for ending PNTR to eliminate incentives for companies to source from China, Democrats contended that revoking the status would raise taxes on American consumers and lead to retaliatory measures from China without bringing manufacturing jobs back.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In light of the debate, committee members appeared to be considering relatively moderate changes to the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;5 things to know about a possible new US ban on investment in China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One “middle path”, as Auchincloss called it, included reauthorising the generalised system of preferences, a trade programme that provides duty-free treatment for certain US imports from developing countries. Auchincloss said it could help reduce the US trade deficit with China.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 05:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Dingo pack leader killed after attacking jogger on a popular Australian tourist island]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3228392/dingo-pack-leader-killed-after-attacking-jogger-popular-australian-tourist-island?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/51d97ae7-62cd-4f4b-9f70-cc75379b4849_319721ff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Wildlife authorities have killed the leader of a pack of dingoes that mauled a jogger on a popular Australian tourist island in a ferocious attack that a rescuer said could have been fatal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sarah Peet, 23, was attacked by three or four Australian native dogs on Monday as she jogged along a beach at Queensland state&#39;s K&#39;gari, the world&#39;s largest sand island formerly known as Fraser Island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Brisbane resident was flown by helicopter to a mainland hospital in a stable condition. The health department refused to provide an update on her condition on Thursday, citing patient confidentiality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wildlife rangers captured and humanely euthanised the leader of the pack on Wednesday, the Queensland Parks and Wildlife Service said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Euthanising a high-risk dingo is always a last resort and the tough decision by the Queensland Parks and Wildlife Service was supported by the island&#39;s traditional owners, the Butchulla people,” a service statement said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dingo was the second on the island in recent weeks to be killed for biting and threatening behaviour. Authorities blame dingoes&#39; increasing fearlessness on tourists who ignore rules by feeding them or encouraging them to approach to post social media images.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wary young dingoes avoided humans when pandemic travel restrictions were first eased in late 2021. But their dangerous human interactions are increasing with tourists&#39; encouragement as visitor numbers rise.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;She was sunbathing on a beach in Australia. Then a wild dingo appeared&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Peet did not deliberately encourage dingoes to approach her. But visitors to the World Heritage-listed Great Sandy National Park are warned against running or jogging outside fenced areas because of the risk that dingoes will chase them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dingoes forced Peet into the surf, deploying the same hunting strategy that rangers say they use against large prey such as kangaroos and wallabies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tourists Shane and Sarah Moffat were driving along the beach in their SUV when they saw Peet being attacked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve seen two dingoes hanging off the side of her”, Shane Moffat told Nine News television. “她举起手朝我走来，大喊‘救命，救命’，”他说。 “I could see fear in her face, that she wasn&#39;t in a good way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moffat said he ran to Peet, forcing himself between her and the pack leader. Moffat bloodied his fingers on the dingo&#39;s fangs as he punched it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moffat said Peet&#39;s injuries included a chunk of flesh missing from her right upper-arm and bite marks to her legs. He doubted she would have survived if he had arrived at the scene any later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wildlife rangers agreed that Peet would have died without the Moffats&#39; help. “We believe the people who intervened saved her life that day,” principal ranger Danielle Mansfield said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pack leader was one of three dingoes on the island fitted with tracking collars because of their high-risk behaviour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he was collared in April, he was around two years old and weighed 17 kilos, which was heavy for a dingo and indicated he had been fed by humans, authorities said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dingo killed by authorities in June after separate attacks on a 7-year-old boy a 42-year-old French woman was the first to be destroyed on the island since 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rangers said that dingo was the offspring of a collared mother that had taught her pups their dangerous ways.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Baby dragged from bed by wild dingo on Australian island&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;K&#39;gari is home to some of Australia&#39;s purest dingoes because domestic dogs have long been banned. Dingoes are a protected species and authorities are considering how they can more safely coexist with humans on the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tourists who breach wildlife rules on K&#39;gari to take selfies with dingoes have been warned that the Queensland Parks and Wildlife Service monitors social media to impose fines that can be as high as 12,000 Australian dollars (US$8,191).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two tourists had recently been each fined AU$2,300 (US$1,569) for getting too close to dingoes to “get selfies and videos,” Environment Minister Leanne Linard said after visiting the island in response to the attack.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The women, aged 29 and 25, were only caught because they posted the images on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One woman had videoed three sleeping dingo pups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m sure they were very cute, but there would have been a mother nearby and any mother will defend their child and their babies really voraciously,” Linard told Australian Broadcasting Corp.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 05:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[McDonald’s must pay US$800,000 to US girl burned by hot Chicken McNugget]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228407/mcdonalds-must-pay-us800000-us-girl-burned-hot-chicken-mcnugget?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 04:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/53a657f5-0f7a-462c-94ef-b8788ce82628_2ff4adb2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A South Florida jury awarded US$800,000 in damages to a little girl who received second-degree burns when a hot Chicken McNugget fell on her leg as her mother pulled away from the drive-through of a McDonald&#39;s restaurant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawyers for the family of Olivia Caraballo, who was four when she was burned in 2019, were seeking US$15 million in damages. Jurors reached their verdict after deliberating for less than two hours on Wednesday, the South Florida SunSentinel reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jury&#39;s verdict form allotted US$400,000 in damages for the past four years, and another US$400,000 for the future from the McDonald&#39;s USA and its franchise operator, Upchurch Foods. A separate jury decided in May that the company and franchise owner were liable for the injury, which occurred outside a McDonald&#39;s in Tamarac, near Fort Lauderdale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m actually just happy that they listened to Olivia&#39;s voice and the jury was able to decide a fair judgment,” Olivia&#39;s mother, Philana Holmes, told reporters outside the courtroom. “我对此很满意。 I honestly had no expectations, so this is more than fair for me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She testified on Tuesday that Olivia, now eight, calls the scar on her inner thigh her “nugget” and is fixated on having it removed, the newspaper reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawyers for McDonald&#39;s argued that the child&#39;s discomfort ended when the wound healed, which they said took about three weeks. They contended that the girl&#39;s mother is the one who has the problem with the scar, and told jurors that US$156,000 should cover damages, both past and future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She&#39;s still going to McDonald&#39;s, she still asks to go to McDonald&#39;s, she&#39;s still driving through the drive-through with her mom, getting chicken nuggets,” defence lawyer Jennifer Miller said in her closing argument Wednesday. “她并没有因为受伤而感到困扰。 This is all the mom.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence lawyers declined to speak after the verdict.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chicken nuggets order led police to Facebook video murderer&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Holmes testified that she had bought Happy Meals for her son and daughter, who was sitting in the back seat, and was driving away when the nugget fell on the child&#39;s leg. She said that the girl screamed in pain, and when she pulled over in a car park, she realised the nugget was lodged between Oliva&#39;s thigh and the seat belt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother testified that at no point did McDonald&#39;s warn her the food might be unusually hot. The company testified they follow food safety rules, which require McNuggets to be hot enough to avoid salmonella poisoning, and that what happens with the food once it leaves the drive-through window is beyond their control.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While both sides agreed during the trial in May that the nugget caused the burns, the family&#39;s lawyers argued the temperature was above 93 degrees Celsius (200 degrees Fahrenheit), while the defence said it was no more than 71 degrees Celsius (160 degrees Fahrenheit).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Photos the mother took of the burn and sound clips of the child&#39;s screams were played in court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case may stoke memories of the McDonald&#39;s coffee lawsuit of the 1990s, which became an urban legend of sorts about seemingly frivolous lawsuits, even though a jury and judge had found it anything but.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A New Mexico jury awarded Stella Liebeck, 81, US$2.7 million in punitive damages after she was scalded in 1992 by hot coffee from McDonald&#39;s that spilled onto her lap, burning her legs, groin and buttocks, as she tried to steady the cup with her legs while prying the lid off to add cream outside a drive-through.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She suffered third-degree burns and spent more than a week in hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She had initially asked McDonald&#39;s for US$20,000 to cover hospital expenses, but the company went to trial. A judge later reduced the US$2.7 million award to US$480,000, which he said was appropriate for the “wilful, wanton, reckless” and “callous” behaviour by McDonald&#39;s.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>