<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Don’t wait for me’: fugitive Chinese killer arrested after 30 years on the run urges wife to find new husband saying ‘I will not be leaving jail’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226814/dont-wait-me-fugitive-chinese-killer-arrested-after-30-years-run-urges-wife-find-new-husband-saying?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/73d9b81e-7b4b-47af-8572-e901d6d653ce_f5d7d043.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名逃亡三十年后在中国因谋杀被捕的逃犯正在大陆上流行他告诉妻子去找新丈夫的视频在社交媒体上流传开来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1993 年，自认杀人的周姓男子与另外三名男子在湖北省中部的北京刺死了一名男子。 《青年报》报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;案发后不久，他的同伙就被抓获，但周一直在逃，直到上个月底，湖北警方在他藏身的南方城市广州将他逮捕。报道称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一段疯传的视频显示，当警察把他带走登上返回湖北的火车时，周要求妻子与他离婚并再婚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当周的妻子拥抱时告别时，他哭着对嫂子说：“离婚协议书在这儿，让你姐姐签个字吧。你一定要劝她再婚，不要等我。我不会离开监狱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的妻子泪流满面地回答：“我想知道你是否不想要我……我不同意。我不同意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当周重复“别等我”时，他的妻子用手捂住他的嘴，摇头表示不同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来周告诉北京青年报，他对30年前犯下的罪行感到后悔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我很悔恨，”周说。 “这些年我没有见过父母，也没有尽孝心。我年轻的时候就做过错事。我不该打杀那个家伙。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;逃亡者和他妻子的视频在微博上的浏览量已达3000万次，并在网上引发了一场关于逃亡者与妻子的恩爱的讨论。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他的家人越幸福，他就越后悔。”一位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们非常相爱。或许这一刻是该男子对自己的罪行最后悔的时候。但时间永远不会倒转，”第二个人评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没必要同情他。被他杀害的人没有机会拥有幸福的家庭。”第三位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果他有良心的话，他几年前就应该向警方自首了。”另一位人士说道。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Boost for Hong Kong’s biomedical hub ambitions as Chinese University’s biobank gets international certification]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227054/boost-hong-kongs-biomedical-hub-ambitions-chinese-universitys-biobank-gets-international?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/cc79ce64-69b8-43ab-80ce-b4cb42567596_c06a9c64.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中文大学数据及人体组织样本生物库成为全港首个获得国际认证，该机构表示这将提升该市作为药物研发中心的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该大学表示，拥有国际认可的生物库意味着可以完成早期开发和临床试验阶段&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中大医学生物库于2019年在沙田威尔斯亲王医院成立，获得ISO认证20387：2018年四月认证。该认证由非营利性非政府机构美国实验室认证协会完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该设施拥有 21 个冰柜，目前储存了超过 150,000 瓶血液、尿液等样本和粪便。它可以容纳一百万瓶，并且有计划增加其容量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自卫生部长罗仲茂接受《香港报》采访以来，有关将香港发展成为生物医药中心的讨论一直备受关注。上个月发布消息称，香港正在考虑建立自己的药品监管机制，此举可能会吸引制药公司在香港进行研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港中文大学医学院院长陈家良教授”，上周在新闻发布会上表示，这项认证意味着香港可以在药物研究方面发挥主导作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港有能力和潜力获得国际认证，吸引海外制药公司来到香港陈说：“我们不应该再做追随者”：香港科学家支持药物监管计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;认证过程检查了该设施的各个方面，从样本采集到加工、储存和分发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生物库不仅仅是拥有数十台冰箱，”陈说。 “我们还需要严格的管理体系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生物样本库执行委员会联席主任马正云教授表示，该设施存储的数据和信息可以帮助发展医学、生物样本库等各个领域。例如改善遗传疾病的诊断、预测疾病风险以及发展精准医疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府在2020年发布的香港发展基因组医学的战略文件中，推动建立生物样本库网络是一项关键建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港拥有各种生物库，其中一个关于糖尿病的生物库自 2014 年以来一直在收集超过 20,000 名患者的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港有足够的人才来建立国家生物医学实验室：科学家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;马表示，研究人员能够利用这些数据做出与风险预测相关的发现，例如识别与中国人和东亚人患糖尿病的较高风险相关的基因。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他们还发现了一种可能导致中国糖尿病患者患终末期肾病风险更高的基因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，研究人员还需要做更多的工作，将基础研究成果转化为应用。直接使人们受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈说，从最早阶段开始的药物开发需要获得国际认可的生物库，涉及一期试验和海外融资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有国际认可的基础处理生物样本，没有人会考虑你，”他指的是大型制药公司和潜在投资者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港如何成为生物医学创新领域的亮点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他透露据了解，自获得认证以来已有多家国际制药公司与该大学接洽合作，但没有提供更多细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;展望未来，该大学希望与大家分享运营高标准生物样本库的经验。其他公立医院，首先是治疗罕见疾病患者的香港儿童医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院管理局表示，已邀请了香港中文大学和香港大学两所医学院的代表（香港大学） – 成立联合工作组，并开始讨论通过三方合作建立生物样本库的建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学临床试验中心董事总经理邱光智表示，生物样本库对于基因组医学的发展很有用，但对于临床试验则不太有用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;科学家正在研究 3D 打印生物医学设备，这可能会“开辟可能性”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然承认认证表明，如果设施符合某些标准，他说他认为临床试验与使用经认可的生物库之间“没有联系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我 20 多年的经验中，没有发生过临床试验被拒绝的事件因为缺乏经过认可的生物样本库，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，在临床试验中从患者身上采集的血液通常要么立即进行检测，要么在设施中储存很短一段时间，然后再送往海外进行检测。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他认为拥有一个经过认可的生物库可能有利于基因组医学，而基因组医学通常需要长期储存生物样本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，如果科学家将来识别出与生物样本相关的特定生物标记物，癌症，他们可以检索生物库中存储的癌症患者的血液样本进行分析，看看是否存在这样的指标。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese scientists hope Alzheimer’s gene discovery will pave way for new treatments]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227070/chinese-scientists-hope-alzheimers-gene-discovery-will-pave-way-new-treatments?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/4045a13d-e506-43d2-879f-9e395a64b301_25f5032f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国研究人员发现了一种可导致阿尔茨海默病的新基因突变，这一发现作者表示可以帮助开发新药来治疗这种疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔茨海默病是最常见的痴呆症，也是全世界的一个主要公共卫生问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全世界约有 4400 万人根据《柳叶刀神经病学》杂志 2019 年的一项研究，全球都患有阿尔茨海默氏症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科学家此前已发现三个基因的突变，这些突变会导致一种称为β淀粉样蛋白的蛋白质产生增加和异常积累，这种蛋白质是阿尔茨海默氏症的特征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，据首都医疗的研究人员称，这些遗传缺陷仅发生在大约 10% 至 20% 的家族病例中，这意味着导致该疾病的更多基因和机制仍不清楚。北京大学宣武医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的新研究于 6 月 26 日发表在同行评审期刊《BMC Medicine》上，发现另一个基因（名为 ZDHHC21）存在突变，该基因也可能导致阿尔茨海默病。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;该研究的通讯作者、宣武医院研究员贾建平表示，这一发现的影响将是巨大的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“之前的研究报告了三个已识别基因的突变……但我们的研究贾说：“发现了一个全新的基因，其中的一个突变导致了阿尔茨海默病。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，新基因突变和机制的发现可能会为药物开发带来新途径，带来新希望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管存在担忧，中国新的阿尔茨海默病药物仍向患者销售&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;贾表示，这项研究是10年研究的积累。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;贾和他的团队于2002年建立了中国家族性阿尔茨海默病网络，旨在研究中国阿尔茨海默病患者的遗传特征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该网络共招募了 404 名阿尔茨海默病或轻度认知障碍患者，共 1,330 名。遗传谱系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们发现 83% 的谱系不携带先前已知的三种突变，这表明可能涉及其他基因和机制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015 年，55 7岁女子因记忆力逐渐衰退而到医院神经内科就诊。她以及她的母亲和一个兄弟被诊断出患有阿尔茨海默病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团队对这位妇女及其家人进行了外显子组测序——一种仅对基因组蛋白质编码区域进行测序的技术成员并发现了一个可能导致这种疾病的基因中的新突变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外显子组只占人类基因组的不到 2%，但它包含已知的约 85% 的遗传变异。导致疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据这项研究，在她患有阿尔茨海默病的家庭成员中检测到了这种突变，但在未患有该病的人中未发现这种突变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员随后使用基因组编辑技术在小鼠中产生突变，并发现证据表明它会导致学习能力受损并降低记忆力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究称，该突变还增强了一种称为棕榈酰化的过程，该过程改变了记忆的方式蛋白质的行为会影响大脑和神经系统的功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国研究小组报告最年轻的人被诊断患有可能的阿尔茨海默氏症&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在这种情况下，它导致了淀粉样β蛋白的增加，导致阿尔茨海默病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的研究结果表明，特定底物的棕榈酰化修饰是阿尔茨海默病的另一种驱动机制，并表明棕榈酰化是药物治疗的一个有前途的靶标，”该研究得出结论。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Passing district council reforms brings down curtain on Hong Kong’s years of political drama]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227061/passing-district-council-reforms-brings-down-curtain-hong-kongs-years-political-drama?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/1c81daf5-f22d-4dd3-a26e-1f4ca7ede64d_4a51e309.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;《2023年区议会（修订）条例草案》定于7月10日刊宪，精心策划的政治制度改革落下帷幕，旨在使香港的选举制度符合北京“爱国者治港”的施政原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以应对导致香港陷入困境的社会动荡。 2019年停滞不前，北京从2020年6月开始采取行动。始于全国人大常委会通过香港国家安全法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不久之后，全国人大启动了香港国安法的修订。选举行政长官和选举立法会的选举规则。虽然没有提到改组区议会，但选举委员会和立法会都取消区议会席位，就表明这是故意的，区议会将受到政治排斥。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;区议员必须宣誓效忠政府，否则将被禁止，政府人士将政治动荡和社会动荡首当其冲地归咎于区议会。北京认为有必要介入并解决这一选举缺陷，因为它看到外国干涉和外部势力控制了地区一级的政治，并选举人们担任立法会和区议会的职位，公开挑战“一国”的合法性。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港区议会改革将如何改变邻里政治生活？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国务院港澳办对区议会一致通过的回应上周四的《2023（修订）条例草案》重申了这一立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法案称反华派系在2019年社会动荡期间，利用制度漏洞进入区议会，严重扰乱政府工作，挑战政府“一国两制”原则的底线，并威胁到国家安全和香港的稳定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京解决这一政治缺陷的愿景意味着区议会必须进行非政治化，首先是废除他们在具有真正政治影响力的机构中的地位。区议会议员并不凭借担任区级公职而拥有选择行政长官的发言权或制定法律的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;区议会的政治清洗已大大减少直选议席由95%增至19%，其余议席要么由行政长官任命，要么由三个区委员会的2,490名议员选出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所有候选人仍须通过如果以2021年改革后的立法会选举获得提名为指导的话，要实现国家安全审查制度并获得区级委员会的提名，这并不是一件容易的事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些将要任职的人区议会中将有一些由区官员（政府在区一级的最高代表）担任主席的议会的一部分，以确保它们是“行政领导的”，从而符合宪法。他们将受到行政指令的问责，该指令将于今年年底起草，其中将包括一份“负面”行为清单，用于衡量区议员的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们将根本没有实权，根据其宪法作用，它们仅发挥咨询职能。他们将不再被授权监督或批准地区项目的资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种政治解毒应该足以让当权者对新的选举制度感到更加安全。它有机制确保香港各级公职人员，无论他们是否拥有实权，都是合格的爱国者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港政府未能讲好新区议会的故事&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;区议会将如何运作以及选举将如何在选民投票率方面展开仍有待观察。无论出于何种意图和目的，它们都是一个完全不同的实体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我希望这意味着这座城市能够结束第三次也是最后一次政治和解行动，并最终开始从分裂的损害中恢复过来。社区和家庭。政府现在肩负着艰巨的责任，要引领香港继续前进，度过社会动荡的日子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= “https://feedx.best” style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea denounces US move to bring ballistic missile submarine to peninsula]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3227102/north-korea-denounces-us-move-bring-ballistic-missile-submarine-peninsula?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 06:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/83dbbdee-13ba-462e-8cc9-4b71accc0ec1_43b6cfa3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;朝鲜周一谴责美国所谓的引入朝鲜半岛附近海域的核动力弹道导弹潜艇，称这造成了一种使核冲突更接近现实的局面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜还声称美国侦察机最近侵犯了其东海岸附近的领空，在官方朝中社发表的一份声明中援引国防部一位未透露姓名的发言人的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不能保证美国空军战略侦察机被击落的令人震惊的事件一定会在上空发生。”发言人表示：“东海不会发生这种情况。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;朝鲜誓言在纪念战争周年的集会上对美国进行“报复”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国引进战略核资产的举动朝中社称，朝鲜半岛核攻击是对朝鲜和地区国家的公然核讹诈，对和平构成严重威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一艘美国核动力巡航导弹潜艇抵达韩国釜山港上个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月，韩国和美国领导人同意美国海军核弹道导弹潜艇将自20世纪80年代以来首次访问韩国，但没有给出时间表这样的访问。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s foreign relations law signals new red lines, but doesn’t say what crosses them]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226945/chinas-foreign-relations-law-signals-new-red-lines-doesnt-say-what-crosses-them?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/b3a9ebed-f944-41a1-a368-e3052e8d2c3c_5600276a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着宣布全面立法管理对外关系，中国似乎决心加大力度据观察人士称，这是一场针对制裁及其所认为的其他外国挑衅行为的法律斗争，同时寻求将国内法的影响范围扩大到境外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史无前例的《外交关系法》已生效7 月 1 日，这也表明中国越来越有决心缩小与美国在法律战场上的差距。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国官员和官方媒体称，新法律堵住了“外国法治的漏洞”。 ”，为北京对外“遏制、干涉、制裁、破坏”的“斗争”以及美国的“长臂”管辖提供了法律依据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;外交秘密渠道仍然有效吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与 2021 年颁布的《反外国制裁法》一样，新规则是北京对美国主导的制裁措施的回应的一部分，这些制裁措施已将超过 1,300 家中国公司和官员列入黑名单。据称存在不当行为 — — 北京一再否认 — — 包括侵犯人权以及与俄罗斯的可疑关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但共产党权力集中于外交、法律含糊不清以及缺乏明确性专家表示，国家安全的定义可能会给海外投资者和在中国的企业运营带来新的障碍和不确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律是中国自 2017 年开始全面将国家安全、军事和外交事务合法化的最新举措。加州大学黑斯廷斯法学院中国法专家基思·汉德 (Keith Hand) 表示，这一进程是在 2000 年代中期，并在中国国家主席习近平的领导下加速发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汉德是该大学东亚中心主任美中关系全国委员会成员法律研究表示，新立法具有“重要的象征意义和信号功能”，但其实际法律影响可能有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该法律的目的是提升中国的国际形象，表明中国决心利用国内法作为应对国际挑战的工具，并提供一个全面的立法框架，将中国过去六年颁布的一系列更具体的法律法规联系起来。或七年，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，总的来说，它是相当笼统和具有宣言性的。由于它太笼统，不太可能被引用为具体法律行动的主要依据。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律也是北京努力解决其利用国内立法能力不对称问题的又一步。应对外部挑战，作为其针对美国及其盟国的法律战略的一部分，北京将其视为冷战式对抗的加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管美国没有类似的法律来阐述其总体外交政策从原则上看，中国近年来制定的详细法律法规与美国用来向中国施压的一系列立法有明显的相似之处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿有能力通过法律手段对中国发动贸易、经济和技术战汉德表示，自前总统唐纳德·特朗普 2016 年上任以来，美国和中国领导人可以使用的国内法律工具的能力暴露出“严重不对称”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国外交下一步应将重点放在“对外”上风险”：外交部&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;多年来，美国的贸易战、技术封锁、针对中国电信巨头华为和中兴的打击、与新疆和香港有关的制裁，以及美国最近针对中国的许多法律行动投资和其他利益使双边关系跌至历史低点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京对 2018 年华为高管孟晚舟的高调拘留感到特别愤怒，这是在美国“长臂”管辖下的一个有争议的举动，中国谴责美国霸权和“帝国主义”的幌子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平此后多次呼吁加快建设“在中国管辖范围之外适用的法律体系”，以对抗美国的管辖范围，并“协调推动中国的司法管辖权”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着美国和其他大国对中国的崛起做出反应，外国挑衅行为给中国领导人带来了公众压力，要求他们采取强硬行动，否则就会面临公众的反对，”汉德说。 “通过制定和部署涉外国内法，中国领导人可以缩小与美国法律的差距，并向国内民众展示决心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悉尼大学中国法教授凌冰表示对外关系法源于习近平推动建立规范中国对外关系和对外交往的法律制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平明确将法律视为国际‘斗争’的一个重要方面，国内法是国际‘斗争’的重要组成部分。”法律。因此，制定了这项法律。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他将该立法描述为一项“框架”法，它不是“为外交政策或国家安全创建特定的工具包”，而是奠定了基础观察人士还指出，北京方面正在努力加强国内法的域外影响力，以授权中国领导人惩罚外国实体在其境外进行的敌对行为，例如&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柏林墨卡托中国研究中心 (Merics) 专家卡嘉·德林豪森 (Katja Drinhausen) 表示，中国已经通过了一系列法律，正式授权北京方面采取反制措施， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“外交关系法的范围和目标要广泛得多：它将中国的安全、发展利益和全球崛起置于其与外国交往的前沿和中心位置。”其他国家，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一系列具有域外效力的新法律反映了中国在捍卫中国利益方面采取更强硬路线的决心。他们为北京的行为增添了合法性的光彩，但并没有从根本上改变做法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但官方通讯社新华社表示，中国在涉外领域的法律法规的实施“与某些国家完全不同”相反，新华社表示，该法律旨在解决“一些缺陷”以及“维护国家主权、安全和发展的法律存在的空白” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据新华社报道，中国现行的297部法律中，涉及外交的有52部，另有150余部有涉外条款，其中包括《反外国制裁法》、《2020年出口管制法》等。控制法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位 Merics 分析师 Francesca Ghiretti 在 6 月发表的一项研究指出，自 2018 年以来，中国使用进口限制、签证和旅行禁令等单边制裁的情况大幅增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究显示，在 2012 年至 2023 年间北京实施的 39 项制裁中，自 2018 年以来，中国实施了 17 次签证和旅行禁令，四次采取进口限制，七次资产冻结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，吉雷蒂形容，中国的制裁方式“相对克制”，主要针对美国民众和高层人士，“信号效应较强”，成本相对较低，对中国经济影响有限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然这些措施表明中国实施单边制裁的信心和能力更强，但“对中国来说，制裁尤其成为针对美国的地缘政治斗争的工具”，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王香港城市大学法学院教授江宇表示，虽然域外管辖权本身在国际社会中很常见，但法律的有效性很大程度上取决于其执行情况，目前评估还为时过早。&lt;/p>;&lt;王说：“任何国家都不能指望通过法律来最大限度地减少或减少（外部）风险，因为外部环境的恶化远远超出了中国的控制范围。” “中国能做的不多，但在提供合法化或更高程度的合法性以及透明度方面，我认为法律可以做得很好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是来自大学的凌悉尼总理表示，将国际条约纳入中国宪法的条款引发了人们对中国是否遵守国际法和条约的质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法第三十条规定“国家缔结或者参加的条约、协定应当遵守”。不违反宪法”，第31条规定其实施“不得损害国家主权、国家安全和社会公共利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“法律口头上维护国际法，但其关于中国对国际法承诺的关键条款还有很多不足之处。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然此类条款“在其他法律体系中并不罕见”，但凌表示，国际法要求任何国家都不能利用其国内法，包括宪法，为其违反国际法的行为开脱——中国过去经常宣扬这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，新规定“存在问题且令人担忧”，因为它们有可能允许中国“以其一些不透明的宪法规范为借口”无视条约，而没有一个有效的中国宪法解释体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汉德回应了令的担忧，并补充说，新法律可能会给北京更大的回旋余地无视国际法和条约，以中国拒绝 2016 年南海仲裁案的裁决为由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为该法律不会对中国现有的国际法实践产生太大改变。如果中国倾向于忽视或推翻其国际承诺，即使没有外交关系法，它也会这样做。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牛津大学中国中心研究员乔治·马格努斯 (George Magnus)表示，新法律意义重大，因为“对于一个大国来说，事实上，国际法不适合其目的，而其本国法律将优先适用，这是独一无二的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在从大局来看，我认为我们可以将这部法律视为中国与国际法脱钩的一个例子，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了现有的立法，例如反制裁法和北京针对制裁的运动之外，马格努斯表示，新法律将使中国成为“一个越来越充满敌意和尴尬的经商之地”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律还可能对北京吸引外资的努力产生新的怀疑。新加坡管理大学法学教授高亨利表示，该立法的某些部分让他感到不安。他说，第五条强调了党对外交的“集中统一领导”，而第三十条则表示中国将“真诚地”履行其条约义务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可能意味着中国不会严格履行条约义务。”如果条约不被认为是善意签订的，则遵循条约的文字，例如[2020 年 1 月]与美国签订的第一阶段贸易协定。这将进一步增加商业的不确定性。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高指出，第六条明确要求中国所有机构、企业、社会组织和公民必须“维护国家主权、国家安全、尊严、荣誉和利益”。 during international exchanges and cooperation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The terms &#39;national security, honour and interests&#39; are very ambitious and create even wider obligations than those under the national security law and anti-sanctions law. They will not only make it harder for Chinese firms to operate overseas, but also make foreign businesses think twice before deciding to invest in China,” Gao said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gobor Holch, leadership consultant and author of a new book on expat managers in China, said creating “new barriers are the very rationale of such laws”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Regulations and sanctions do not puzzle executives if they are consistent. What hurts China&#39;s image is the ambiguity and unpredictability of new laws,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Noting the law was in line with Beijing&#39;s growing focus on security in an increasingly challenging geopolitical environment, the European Union Chamber of Commerce in China raised concerns about the ambiguity of the law and the Chinese concept of national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ambiguous rules and regulations is the number one business challenge that our members face,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Laws that are vaguely worded and broad in scope present compliance challenges, and can also result in discretionary implementation, which is not conducive to attracting foreign investment or rebuilding business confidence among the foreign business community in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This same principle applies to the broader concept of &#39;national security&#39;, as foreign businesses do not have clarity on what is officially considered a national secret.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Vanessa Cai and Hayley Wong&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 06:20:10 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Netanyahu: Israel to work to prevent collapse of Palestinian Authority]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3227100/netanyahu-israel-work-prevent-collapse-palestinian-authority?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 05:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/8b8fee3b-aeec-4f2c-bc32-07c4e82ee426_f662d528.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu&#39;s security cabinet on Sunday decided that Israel would work to prevent the collapse of the Western-backed Palestinian Authority (PA), but did not offer any concrete steps to do so.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel has been stepping up military operations against armed groups in the occupied West Bank, where the PA has limited autonomy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The volatility has laid bare the weakness of the PA in the face of hundreds of Palestinian militants and the expansion of Israeli settlements in the West Bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu&#39;s office said his security cabinet had decided to act to prevent the collapse of the PA, though it was not a unanimous decision. His coalition includes far-right parties that oppose Palestinian statehood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight members of the top-level forum voted in favour, with one voting against and one abstaining.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement said Netanyahu and his defence minister would bring forward “steps to stabilise the civil situation in the Palestinian arena,” but did not give any specifics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Set up 30 years ago as part of interim peace accords with Israel, the PA has seen its popularity shrivel amid allegations of corruption, incompetence and widely hated security cooperation arrangements with Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UN refuses to retract condemnation of Israel over Jenin military operation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There is also uncertainty over the position of 87-year-old Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Abbas has defied prophecies of an end to his two decades in power and refused mounting demands to go, even as prospects of a lasting peace with Israel look more distant than ever.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an interview with CNN broadcast earlier on Sunday, US President Joe Biden warned that the PA “has lost its credibility, not necessarily because of what Israel&#39;s done, just because it&#39;s just lost its credibility, number one, and, number two, created a vacuum for extremism.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s not all Israel now on the West Bank, all Israel&#39;s problem, but they are a part of the problem,” he said, referring to nationalist cabinet members bent on expanding Jewish settlements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Palestinians, Netanyahu&#39;s far-right government has made worse an already bleak outlook, with violence surging and Jewish settlements set to expand in the West Bank – among territories where Palestinians hope to build a future state.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In call with Turkey’s Erdogan, Biden expresses support for Sweden’s Nato bid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227099/call-turkeys-erdogan-biden-expresses-support-swedens-nato-bid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 04:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/e95cddce-c8d6-4bd2-8bc2-e6461464c2f9_a53a5c06.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden expressed a desire to see Sweden join Nato “as soon as possible” in a phone call with Turkish President Tayyip Erdogan in which they discussed Sweden&#39;s bid to become a member of the Western alliance, the White House said on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey, along with Hungary, has been a stumbling block to Sweden&#39;s bid, which requires unanimous approval by all Nato members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan told Biden that Stockholm has taken steps in the right direction for Ankara to ratify its bid, referring to an anti-terrorism law, but said these steps were not useful as Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) supporters continued to hold demonstrations in Sweden, the Turkish presidency&#39;s communications directorate said separately on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden “conveyed his desire to welcome Sweden into Nato as soon as possible,” the White House said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The leaders agreed to meet face-to-face in Vilnius, Lithuania, at a coming Nato summit and discuss bilateral relations and regional issues in detail, the Turkish presidency also said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Sweden failed to convince Turkey to lift its block on Stockholm&#39;s path to Nato membership in a foreign minister-level meeting, as Ankara requested more action in the fight against terrorism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nato Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg said he would convene a meeting between Erdogan and Swedish Prime Minister Ulf Kristersson in Vilnius on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Turkey&#39;s parliament ratifies Finland&#39;s Nato accession as Sweden kept waiting&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sweden and Finland applied for Nato membership last year, abandoning policies of military non-alignment that had lasted through the decades of the Cold War in response to Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Finland&#39;s Nato membership was green-lighted in April, Turkey and Hungary have yet to clear Sweden&#39;s bid. Stockholm has been working to join at next week&#39;s Nato summit in Vilnius.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During their call, Biden and Erdogan also discussed the delivery of F-16 fighter jets to Turkey, and Ukraine&#39;s aim to join Nato, according to the Turkish presidency&#39;s readout.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How protests in France are fuelling calls for a ban on TikTok and other social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227069/how-protests-france-are-fuelling-calls-ban-tiktok-and-other-social-media?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/09/c9258597-d96d-4ff2-904b-6a13e3fd0f62_8e5c5daa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The killing of Nahel M, a 17-year-old boy of Algerian and Moroccan origin, and the subsequent protests in France have led to thousands being arrested and reportedly cost more than €1 billion (US$1.1 billion) in lost business and property.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Large-scale protests are nothing new in France, with similar unrest breaking out across the country in 2005 in suburban neighbourhoods with low-cost housing known as banlieues. Many of the inhabitants of these neighbourhoods are people from immigrant backgrounds or a third- or fourth-generation descendants of the same.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;France has a long, complicated history with immigration given its colonial past. Previously, people from countries colonised by France – such as Algeria, Morocco and Tunisia – moved to France to fill labour shortages during the 20th century. These people were often looked down upon as the working class, a mindset that continues to this day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, many of these immigrants and their children were Muslim, potentially bringing them into conflict with the French constitutional principle of laïcité, or secularism. Terrorist attacks carried out by groups such as Islamic State were done by Muslims or people of North African descent, further contributing to an atmosphere of public distrust, which far-right politicians have tried to capitalise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All these factors have led to a rise in incidents in France of discrimination against Muslims and people of African origin, whether citizens and foreigners. Reports have pointed out a frequent pattern of racist behaviour by the French police, who often racially profile African or Muslim citizens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The excessive force used by police during their run-ins with these people has kept tensions with the public at a steady boil. Nahel&#39;s killing during a traffic stop – which was caught on video and even condemned by French President Emmanuel Macron – was the final straw for many, leading to widespread protests that have raged across the country for more than a week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the initial protests were largely focused on the injustices of the state, later gatherings have devolved into riots and looting. This has included attacks on symbols of the state, including 99 town halls, other government buildings and vehicles. These attacks on government buildings are reminiscent of the Yellow Vest protests of 2019, which began as protests against high gas taxes before turning violent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A prominent but underdiscussed aspect of the riots is the salience of social media as a means for protesters to grow and learn from each other. Social media has played a prominent role in protests across the world, with the demonstrations in Hong Kong and India during 2019 and 2020 being mobilised significantly on social media platforms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron and other politicians have laid some of the blame for the violence in France on social media platforms such as Telegram, TikTok and Snapchat. Reports suggest a surge in usage and new subscribers during the protests, with fears that users are inciting riots on TikTok. This has led to Macron hinting at “cutting off” social media, sparking outrage over government attempts at unlawful censorship.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Social media platforms the front line in narrative war&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One major target in this increased scrutiny of social media, both in France and elsewhere, is TikTok. The app – which is owned by ByteDance, a Chinese company – is one of the most popular in the world, claiming more than 3 billion downloads as of this year. It has been accused of shortening attention spans and encouraging mediocrity, and governments around the world are concerned about its security implications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s national intelligence law states that “all organisations and citizens shall support, assist and cooperate with national intelligence efforts in accordance with law”, suggesting that could include handing over data. This has generated fears of China subverting other governments and collecting sensitive information of users including those belonging to government backgrounds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result, countries and organisations from various countries have prohibited workers from using the app over security concerns and a lack of work-related benefits from its use. India took it one step further and banned TikTok and dozens of other Chinese apps from the entire country in 2020, citing similar reasons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;France now appears to be considering this step. The French Senate released a report last week that made a series of recommendations on how to deal with TikTok, including expanding prohibitions on the use of the app from government workers to include those in key sectors such as energy, finance, transport and water management. The report was originally commissioned in March and came after months of investigations and questioning TikTok officials in court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While it is unclear if France will go ahead with the expanded TikTok ban, it is not outlandish to think it will happen, given that other countries have carried out similar bans. Restrictions on Chinese technology and apps is a significant part of the US-China rivalry that is now spilling over into other nations around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the protests in France started out in the physical realm, it is important to keep an eye on their influence in the digital one, as well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[FDA asked to look into YouTuber Logan Paul’s energy drink over dangerous caffeine levels]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227098/fda-asked-look-youtuber-logan-pauls-energy-drink-over-dangerous-caffeine-levels?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 03:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/f32e683c-cf91-4e5e-982e-d2eb01060f61_c7f1fc11.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An influencer-backed energy drink that has earned viral popularity among children is facing scrutiny from lawmakers and health experts over its potentially dangerous levels of caffeine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Sunday, Senator Chuck Schumer called on the Food and Drug Administration to investigate PRIME, a soft drink brand founded by the YouTube stars Logan Paul and KSI that has become something of an obsession among the influencers&#39; legions of young followers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One of the summer&#39;s hottest status symbols for kids is not an outfit, or a toy – it&#39;s a drink,” said Schumer, a Democrat from New York. “But buyer and parents beware because it&#39;s a serious health concern for the kids it so feverishly targets.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Backed by two of YouTube&#39;s best known stars, PRIME was an immediate sensation when it launched last year, prompting long queues in shops and reports of schoolyard resale markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Advertising itself as zero sugar and vegan, the neon-coloured cans are among a growing number of energy drinks with elevated levels of caffeine; in PRIME&#39;s case, 200 milligrams per 12 ounces, equivalent to about half a dozen Coke cans or nearly two Red Bulls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That high caffeine content prompted bans from some schools in the United Kingdom and Australia where some paediatricians warned of possible health impacts on young children such as heart problems, anxiety and digestive issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Boozy YouTube shows make K-pop stars &#39;relatable&#39;, but critics voice concern&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Company representatives, meanwhile, have defended the product as clearly labelled “not recommended for children under 18.”他们出售一种单独的运动饮料，称为 PRIME Hydration，完全不含咖啡因。 Representatives for PRIME did not immediately return a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in his letter to the FDA, Schumer claimed there was little noticeable difference in the online marketing of the two drinks – leading many parents to believe they were purchasing a juice for their kids, only to wind up with a “cauldron of caffeine.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A simple search on social media for Prime will generate an eye-popping amount of sponsored content, which is advertising,” he wrote. “This content and the claims made should be investigated, along with the ingredients and the caffeine content in the Prime energy drink.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukrainian and Polish presidents remember WWII Volhynia massacres]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227097/ukrainian-and-polish-presidents-remember-wwii-volhynia-massacres?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 02:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/499acb60-b34c-484e-88b0-f52a43097071_9d1445e6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky and his Polish counterpart Andrzej Duda on Sunday commemorated the Volhynia massacres of World War II in an event in Lutsk, the north-western Ukrainian city where it took place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Together we honour the innocent victims of Volhynia! Memory unites us! Together we are stronger!” Zelensky said on Telegram. The event was not publicised in advance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the war, nationalists of the Ukrainian Insurgent Army (UPA) murdered around 100,000 Poles in Volhynia and Eastern Galicia between 1943 and 1945.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky published photos showing himself, Duda and clerics in the city which lies some 85km east of the Polish border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Paweł Szrot, secretary of state in Duda&#39;s office, termed the event “historic” in comments to broadcaster Polsat News. But he added that explaining the historical truth to Poland&#39;s Ukrainian friends would continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Szrot expressed optimism that Ukraine would lift a ban on exhuming the bodies of Polish victims by the end of Duda&#39;s second and last term in office in August 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UPA&#39;s campaign at the time was aimed at reinforcing Ukrainian claims to the region through an uprising against the occupying German forces and by removing the Polish civilian population.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russians could blow up nuclear plant to halt Ukraine&#39;s forces, Zelensky warns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The violence reached a peak in July 1943, with victims being herded into churches and burnt alive. Up to 20,000 Ukrainians died in the subsequent reprisals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clerics from Ukraine and Poland have called for the crimes to be investigated and for reconciliation to mark the 80th anniversary of the massacres.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>