<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Turned subway into private restaurant’: hungry man sets out 3-course meal on China metro train seats, then tucks in oblivious to fellow passengers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224734/turned-subway-private-restaurant-hungry-man-sets-out-3-course-meal-china-metro-train-seats-then?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/6341fbca-bbca-44da-b915-f1b1fce53739_4b9163b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一位老人将几个盘子放在地铁座位上的视频吃这些东西在大陆社交媒体上引发了一场关于公共交通上不文明和怪异行为的争论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子被拍到将三个装有不同菜肴的碗和一个盛有米饭的碗放在他旁边的座位上。据新闻网站梦马新闻报道，6 月 18 日，中国东部江苏省苏州地铁系统内的一列火车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;附近其他乘客的存在似乎并没有打扰该男子，因为他正在吃东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该市地铁运营商的一名工作人员表示，地铁列车上禁止饮食，但该男子所在的线路目前正在试运营，免费对乘客开放，因此工作人员不会在车厢内巡逻。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“如果您发现任何违法行为，可以拨打我们的客户服务热线。我们会派人提醒、劝说旅客停止这种行为。”该工作人员说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段视频在中国大陆社交媒体上引起了轩然大波。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抖音上，4百万人观看，评论2000条。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地铁上不准大声说话、吃东西、喝水，也不准放手机，这是常识。这是一个封闭的空间，你的行为显然会影响到别人。所以请考虑一下别人的感受。”一位网友评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位网友则表示：“他真的把地铁变成了自己的餐厅。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但也有人没想到，男子的行为有问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我以前没有坐过地铁。我不知道是否允许吃东西，但我认为吃东西是可以的，就像在火车上一样。”一位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你认为他做错了什么，请告诉他。我认为没有必要把他拍下来并上传到网上，以免受到各种公众言论的影响。”该人士补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位人士对这名男子表示同情，并表示：“也许他的心情很紧张。”日程安排，或者他可能已经很长时间没有吃饭了。虽然他的行为不文明，但我们社会应该多一些宽容。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地铁上乘客的不当行为在中国经常在网上流行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年底，一名女子中国东部的一名女子在满载乘客的地铁列车上像狗一样爬行，两名同伴走在她旁边，拍摄他们说是行为艺术的视频。地铁工作人员后来劝他们离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年，上海地铁上，一名小男孩缠着其他乘客拿着手环和他一起玩秋千游戏。站在附近的他母亲也这么做了。没有干预，而是微笑着鼓励男孩。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud founder Wang Jian says Paris Olympics 2024 presents great opportunities and challenges]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225162/alibaba-cloud-founder-wang-jian-says-paris-olympics-2024-presents-great-opportunities-and-challenges?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/87fb41e2-2291-424a-a9a8-55b55fb3b719_141d26c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;2024 年巴黎夏季奥运会将为阿里云带来巨大的机遇和挑战。创始人王健表示，是活动组织者选择的合作伙伴，提供下一代广播、物流规划和无传感器跟踪服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次活动为这家中国科技公司提供了一个独特的平台来展示其基于云的技术在中国与西方之间不断加剧的地缘政治紧张局势使中国科技公司面临更大压力和审查之际，阿里云赢得了成为国际奥委会 (IOC) 官方代表的独家协议。 2017 年击败亚马逊网络服务后，成为云服务合作伙伴。该交易包括提供基于云的广播、大数据分析、后勤支持以及对运动员在场上表现的无传感器跟踪，将持续到 2028 年洛杉矶夏季奥运会王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里云是阿里巴巴集团控股公司的子公司，该集团还拥有《南华早报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;阿里云创始人将香港登月项目指向天空吸引人才&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;王说，虽然这家中国公司已经为 2020 年东京奥运会和 2022 年北京冬奥会提供了基于云的支持，但明年在巴黎举行的活动将更加重要。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他说，基于云的广播将首次“全面”取代传统的卫星广播基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望这可能成为一个催化时刻，使云技术成为主流，就像尼古拉·特斯拉 (Nikola Tesla) 在 1893 年芝加哥世界博览会上为 [交流电] 电力所做的那样，”他指的是使用电力来照亮博览会，这预示着现代电力时代的到来。&lt;/王承认，西方和中国之间不断加剧的地缘政治竞争使局势进一步复杂化。法国媒体早些时候报道称，主办国国家信息系统安全局（ANSSI）表达了担忧，并试图阻止国际奥委会让阿里巴巴成为其全球合作伙伴的决定，担心这可能会让这家中国公司获得敏感数据。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王表示，通过与国际奥委会的密切合作，阿里云“肯定”将成为明年夏季奥运会的独家云服务提供商，并补充说2028年洛杉矶奥运会将带来更大的政治挑战。但王希望巴黎奥运会的成功将有助于消除任何数据安全担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所有获得 2024 年巴黎奥运会许可的转播商都将通过阿里巴巴和奥林匹克广播服务公司 (OBS) 构建的云基础设施独家接收现场录像。 ）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里云还将提供其他技术帮助主办城市优化物流规划、简化后台操作。例如，他们正在与国际奥委会合作建立一个基于云的模拟模型，可以帮助巴黎当局了解不同场馆的选择和交通安排如何影响当地社区和企业。主办城市将能够选择最具成本效益的方案并降低运营成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;阿里巴巴联合创始人蔡崇信接替张勇担任董事长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一个例子正在利用美国芯片巨头英特尔和阿里云联合开发的3DAT（3D运动员追踪）技术，通过人工智能驱动的摄像头收集运动员的生物力学数据。这将允许对赛场上的运动员进行无传感器跟踪，从而提高效率和成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这代表了重大的范式转变，”王说。 “这对我来说将是一个历史性的时刻。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王健林被广泛认为是为阿里巴巴成为电子商务巨头奠定了技术基础的人。 2008年，王从微软亚洲研究院加盟阿里巴巴时，云计算的概念还处于起步阶段。尽管内部屡屡质疑，他还是白手起家建立了集团的云业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在2016年出版的《在线》一书中，王详述了他在联合创始人马云的信任下发展云业务的经历。马云在该书的前言中写道，“当我第一次见到王博士时，我被他对互联网的理解所迷住，并讨厌自己不能早点见到他”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里云是根据研究公司 IDC 4 月份的一份报告，尽管其市场份额从上半年的 34.5% 下降到 2022 年下半年的 32.6%，但它目前是中国最大的云提供商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，完成明年巴黎奥运会的工作并不是一件容易的事，因为这需要国际奥委会和转播商进行重大的运营调整。他说，地缘政治紧张局势和当地法规带来了额外的困难，并补充说，合规性挑战包括完成安全测试和落实当地支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“解决[所有这一切]需要时间，”王说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴目前正在进行大规模重组，云部门将被剥离为独立业务。云是公司最重要的增长引擎之一，将于 12 个月后上市，阿里巴巴集团董事长兼首席执行官张勇将于 9 月份辞去这些职务，专注于他已经领导的云业务。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s transgender teens struggle with confusion and pain as specialised healthcare is for over-18s only]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3225277/hong-kongs-transgender-teens-struggle-confusion-and-pain-specialised-healthcare-over-18s-only?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/fcf19063-e650-42df-8db9-3977be035050_c224ca80.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港少年刘玉琪出生时是男性，但从小就感觉到作为一个男孩是不对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孩子害怕接近青春期，并讨厌随之而来的变化，例如声音变得低沉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种感觉变得更加强烈。 “我无法停止哭泣，我会撞头或割腕，”现年 18 岁的刘回忆道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法接受自己作为男性生活。每当我想到这样的未来时，我就感到痛苦。然后我意识到，认定自己是变性人对我来说是正确的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;15 岁时，刘觉得迫切需要帮助才能转变为女孩。但是，尽管香港提供性别肯定医疗保健，提供社会、心理、行为或其他医疗帮助，但 18 岁以下的人没有资格在公立医院接受此类治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管刘已经认为自己是跨性别者，她还没有准备好向父母出柜，而父母本可以同意并支付私营部门提供的治疗费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;饱受性别问题困扰的儿童和青少年几乎无法获得公共医疗服务，并且尽管私人执业医生的需求不断增长，但香港的社会支持仍然存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于像刘这样的青少年来说，缺乏专业帮助只会增加他们在家庭、学校和医疗环境中面临的障碍。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;两名跨性别男子的权利因身份证而受到侵犯，这是香港法院的最高规则&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;跨性别者会经历性别不一致，这意味着他们不认同出生时分配的性别。这可能会导致一些人也经历性别不安，即心理困扰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了解决他们面临的问题，他们可能会经历性别转变的各个方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社会转变意味着改变他们的名字、代词和表达方式。法律过渡将使他们在官方身份证明上更改姓名和性别。医学转型意味着接受激素治疗或性别重置手术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国，6 至 17 岁患者中新诊断的性别不安患者几乎增加了两倍，从 2017 年的 15,172 例增至 2021 年的 42,167 例。在英国，2021-22 年有超过 5,000 人转介到政府运营的性别认同发展服务，而十年前这一数字还不到 250 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，18 岁或以上的跨性别者可以前往威尔斯亲王医院设立性别认同诊所（GIC）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院管理局没有提供跨性别人士在 GIC 接受服务的数据，但服务人数从 2019 年的 950 人次上升至 2021 年的 1,131 人次。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;18岁以下的人可能只能在公立医院接受儿童和青少年精神科服务，但卫生当局无法提供该群体的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在私营部门，精神科医生可以开激素药物来治疗获得更男性化或女性化的外表，帮助减少性别焦虑，或将患者转介给更专业于激素治疗的内分泌科医生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法庭上身份证性别变更之战的跨性别活动人士出版了书籍&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;精神科医师黄俊斌医生在私营机构治疗性别焦虑症已有四年，他注意到患者中变性青少年的数量不断增加，并将其归因于人们意识的提高和信息获取的增加。&lt;/p>;&lt; “更多的人也可能会在社交媒体上出柜并分享他们的旅程，这可能会传达出柜和变性并不像其他人想象的那么可怕，”他说。 “还有更多关于如何以及在哪里寻求帮助的信息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，每年他新推荐的大约有十几名跨性别年轻人，最小的只有 12 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“他们可能只是冰山一角，因为许多人可能没有财力去看私人医生，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位私人诊所的精神科医生 Cheung Ngo 医生说，他看过 10 至每年有 20 名 18 岁以下的新患者出现性别问题，最小的年龄为 15 至 16 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“性别不一致可能从儿童时期就开始出现。跨性别者在成年之前寻求帮助是理想的选择。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但实际上，许多青少年并没有向父母透露自己的情况，而许多人可能无力承担费用。将孩子送往私营机构，那里的治疗费用每月可能为 1,500 至 2,000 港元。有些家长可能会拒绝让自己的孩子接受这样的治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;跨性别男性活动家兼医生 Zephyrus Tsang 是跨性别青少年同侪网络 Quarks 的联合创始人，他说他遇到了一些中学生。近年来被认定为跨性别者的在校学生中，最小的只有14岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数人因没有家人的支持而没有接受过任何医疗服务。他补充说，许多跨性别者可能会遇到心理健康问题或自杀念头。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在线购买激素药物很危险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;无法在公共部门获得与性别相关的医疗保健服务，Yuki Liu，她开始使用代词“她”和“她”，在网上购买激素药物，以显得更加女性化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“幸运的是，这些药物不是假货，”她说。 “我有一个朋友正在政府的性别认同诊所接受治疗，所以我只是按照她的处方服用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张警告说，如果没有医生的处方，患者可能会服用比他们需要的剂量更高的药物，并且这可能有风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于激素药物，当您服用最佳剂量时，体内产生的变化发生得非常缓慢。当人们没有看到他们想要的变化时，他们可能会不断提高剂量，这可能会损害他们的肝脏，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们也可能不知道正确的服药方法。有些药物建议放在舌下，以尽量减少对肝脏的影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;私人诊所的内分泌科医生Rose Ting Zhu-wei博士说，她已经为跨性别患者看诊了大约六年。她还给青少年服用青春期阻滞剂，让他们在开始激素治疗之前有时间探索自己的性别认同。她说，治疗费用昂贵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些跨性别女性患者在见她之前一直在服用避孕药，这可能会产生与激素药物类似的效果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丁说服用激素未经医生处方服用药物可能会导致静脉血栓风险增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法律推动香港变性男子安心使用公厕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;精神科医生黄说，变性青年面临着多重劣势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“年轻本身就意味着处于弱势群体。他们的资源和自主权有限，在经济上依赖他人。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“跨性别者是另一个弱势群体，面临歧视和耻辱。他们可能会担心父母不会接受他们，并将他们赶出家门，而且他们可能会在学校受到欺凌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，推迟性别肯定治疗可能会导致更多不可逆转的变化，可能会加剧这种情况。青少年的焦虑和不快乐，甚至影响他们在学校的表现和社交互动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;缺乏父母的支持&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuki Liu在父母发现后仍试图保守自己的身份2019 年，她穿着女性化的衣服和假发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在她母亲鼓励她敞开心扉之前的两年里，她表现出了情绪困扰的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cherry Liu，50 岁，在这家公司工作部门回忆道：“当我拥抱由纪时，我告诉她，‘无论你是女孩还是男孩，你仍然是我的宝贝。你的健康和幸福才是最重要的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然她很支持，但她说接受Yuki身份的过程对父母双方来说都是痛苦的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们有很多疑问。我们不知道为什么会发生这种情况，因为我们在她年轻时没有观察到任何迹象，”她说。 “但同时，我可以看到我的女儿变得更快乐了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港最高法院敦促授予跨性别者更换身份证的权利&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她还对 Yuki 的未来有很多担忧，包括手术可能产生的副作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只是希望她能找到一个爱她、珍惜她的人，”母亲说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuki 更多比 Adam 幸运，他在 18 岁时开始从女性转变为男性。他接受了激素治疗，使他的声音变得低沉，并进行了切除乳房组织并创造出更具男性魅力的胸部的手术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有父母的支持，他独自经历了这一切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我还没有成功地与我的父母就此事进行过深入交谈，”现年 21 岁的亚当说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“唯一一次当他们陪我去看心理医生时，我们谈到了我的身份，但后来他们反应很大，无法接受。他们假装什么都没发生，并避免谈论这件事。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾在银行业工作的Bobo*表示，当她14岁的女儿告诉她自己是男孩时，她感到很无助&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她能把孩子的幸福放在第一位，并接受随之而来的重大变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她的丈夫保守，无法接受这种情况，坚持称自己的孩子为“女儿”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我儿子甚至会用头撞墙，”50 多岁的波波回忆道。 “我丈夫坚持认为我们可以改变孩子的想法。然后我的儿子开始割腕，并做了噩梦，他被埋在粉红色的花朵中，穿着裙子毫无生气。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一开始，她不知道如何以及在哪里为她寻求治疗孩子，不知道什么可能会引发情绪困扰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我每天都非常害怕他会伤害自己，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;差不多十年后，Bobo 现在她认为自己是一名 23 岁跨性别男人的母亲。经过她坚定不移的努力，她的丈夫改变了态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我告诉他，你要么接受生个儿子，要么失去我们的孩子，”她说。 “如果我们作为家庭成员不接受他，那么没有人会接受他。无论是儿子还是女儿，我们都会一视同仁地爱他。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我本性是女孩，不是男孩”：改变人生的张国荣电影&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bobo说她希望在那里这将为父母提供更多支持，因为这对孩子的过渡至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在不知道如何对待孩子的情况下，有些人可能会选择忽视他们。家长的不接受以及外界的歧视可能会给孩子带来巨大的羞辱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倡导团体性别赋权的公共教育官员林樱表示，当家长发现自己的孩子是跨性别者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意识到这个问题后，该组织成立了跨性别儿童家长互助小组。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“家长的痛苦并不比他们的孩子少。孩子们，”林说。 “有些人可能担心孩子的未来。有些人可能会责怪自己，甚至认为自己在怀孕期间吃错了东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使父母支持，她补充说，其他家庭成员也可能不支持，这也可能很困难。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;在学校，“一切都很严峻”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuki Liu 记得中学时代是她生活中严峻的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她不被允许穿女生校服或留着长发，被一些同学和老师嘲笑和欺负，甚至社工也不太了解如何处理变性青少年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上课时我总是哭起来”，她回忆道。 “我的班主任会因为我的头发长度而责骂我，有时甚至对我不公平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在中三，一些同学会分发我的照片并嘲笑我。他们会说我很恶心，并告诉我不要靠近他们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法律胜利背后的香港跨性别男子猛烈抨击在更换身份证方面的不作为&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;幸运的是，在更高的形式中，她找到了一群支持我的朋友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们是学校严峻环境中的一束小光，”她说。 “青少年的周围要么是家庭，要么是学校。如果学校和家里的环境都很惨淡，再加上看自己的身体都觉得可怕，一切都会很严峻。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘妈妈说，在她向校长和老师申诉后，学校允许了她要求女儿使用残疾人厕所，但拒绝将“残疾人”标志改为“中性”或“男女皆宜”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的女儿不是残疾人，”她说。 “他们说，如果她愿意，可以在午餐时使用附近购物中心的厕所。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专门研究 LGBTQ 群体心理健康的教育大学咨询教授 Diana Kwok Kan 表示。学校缺乏如何处理对性别认同有疑问和性别不安的学生的指导方针。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，如果治疗跨性别青少年的医疗专业人员能够与学校社会工作者合作和工作，那将是理想的选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学校对跨性别学生的态度不同，她必须根据每所学校的宗教背景或性别问题立场来与老师沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她建议向台湾学习，台湾通过了2004年，法律要求所有学校提供性别教育，教师必须接受相关培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;展望未来，Yuki Liu表示，她希望在大学毕业前接受变性手术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望我能过简单的生活，永远不会因为性别问题而苦恼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;*应受访者要求，化名。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Preserving Fanling golf course or building public housing is not a binary choice]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224997/preserving-fanling-golf-course-or-building-public-housing-not-binary-choice?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/2e784220-f736-45e1-bfd8-ad3c03d50aa7_0580b788.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;我不打高尔夫球，甚至没有在练习场挥杆。我曾开过高尔夫笑话，说我不想花时间把小球打进很远的小洞，或者高尔夫评论员总是说话轻声，因为他们不想吵醒电视观众。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;然而，真正的知识是知道自己无知的程度。高尔夫必定是一项伟大的运动，因为有如此多的人喜爱它，并且是开展业务的好地方，在球场上达成了如此多的交易 - 更不用说仅高尔夫球杆的全球市场就达到 100 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;建筑师和设计师总是必须学习新事物，有时学习曲线非常陡峭，在短时间内从业余到半专家。当我在研究生院的第三年也是最后一年设计一个高尔夫球场时，这就是发生在我身上的事情。我了解了小鸟球和柏忌、球道和长草区以及球员的障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高尔夫球场设计是一门科学，尽管它可能看起来并非如此，可能是因为修剪整齐的草地和与自然的联系。 18洞球场需要提供多种挑战，包括每个洞的打球长度、地形、海拔以及周围的障碍物。失去任何一个洞，球场就会被毁掉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有适当遗产的真正伟大的球场因其提供的完整体验而具有其价值。这就是阿美团队系列赛、世界城市锦标赛或任何国际高尔夫锦标赛的吸引力所在。这是“你好香港”的召唤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港高尔夫球会理事会主席郭永良强调，保留粉岭的三个18洞球场对于举办有信誉的赛事和带来良好的声誉至关重要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然我们可能不知道沙特阿拉伯支持的LIV巡回赛对香港成为主办城市的要求，但我们确实知道确认这样的协议将大大推动经济和旅游业比行政长官李家超二月份中东之行期间签署的任何象征性谅解备忘录还要多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进入公共住房问题。建还是不建？当然是建设，但为什么一定是那块特定的土地呢？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一个贫富差距悬殊、意见两极分化的社会，涉及富人消遣和公共利益的问题- 人是敏感的，注定会令某些人感到不安，无论是区议员、环保人士、高尔夫球手、弱势群体还是其他人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有任何政策可以取悦每个利益相关者。然而，在一个开放的社会中，所有的声音都应该被听到和考虑，这样才能利用批判性思维和利益平衡来做出决定。这个过程需要辩论、谈判和妥协。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港需要更多而不是更少的公众参与项目规划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果发展局局长林汉豪只是谴责反对意见在城市规划委员会最近的公众咨询听证会上表示，她认为只有那些反对政府建议的人才会参加此类会议，为什么要举办听证会？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林恩还表示，“我们希望收到听证会期间提出很多反对意见。这并不奇怪，我们不应该因为有更多的反对意见而改变我们原来的想法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果Linn从2007年至2012年担任发展局局长的林郑月娥那里学到什么，她就会知道不倾听而采取坚定、坚定的立场并不会让她变得坚强和坚定。相反，利益相关者会认为她傲慢、固执和脱离现实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最好的领导者是那些善于倾听并在听到所有证据后做出决定的人。这些年我们有惨痛的教训，应该知道，如果不给自己退缩和反思的空间，我们就是在自取失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;撤回香港土地征用高尔夫俱乐部不会是一种让步，而是一个经过深思熟虑、富有同理心的举动。放弃前任政府的提议将表明我们如何发展并变得更加聪明和理性。自2018年提出在高尔夫球场建造公共住房的想法以来，时代已经发生了变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果Linn认为反对声音代表性过高或主要来自俱乐部成员，她可以考虑组建一个独立专家小组”免责声明是必要的。我支持公共住房、社会平等和社区组织协会，并且不是任何高尔夫俱乐部的成员。然而，支持公共住房并不意味着我们必须推倒城市精英建造的东西，就像支持完整保留高尔夫球场并不意味着我们要背弃需要公共住房的人们。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;如果政府无法找到足够的土地来建造所需的住房，同时保持具有巨大生态和经济价值的遗产高尔夫球场完好无损，这意味着我们还没有充分发挥我们解决问题的能力和创造性思维。这也许是一个独立专家小组可以为发展局和土木工程拓展署提供新想法的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港的新篇章中，没有必要惩罚任何人或任何私人俱乐部证明一点。住房和土地使用问题不一定是零和问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pilgrims perform final rituals in Mecca, Saudi Arabia before heading to Mina for haj]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3225281/pilgrims-perform-final-rituals-mecca-saudi-arabia-heading-mina-haj?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 06:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/d044f0d8-a8c0-4dba-81c0-217bc939236e_9f46563f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六，朝圣者涌入沙特阿拉伯麦加大清真寺，进行最后的仪式前往米纳，为朝觐做准备，朝觐是伊斯兰教的第五大支柱，也是世界上最大的宗教集会之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们穿过伊斯兰教圣地的白色大理石庭院，进行塔瓦夫（tawaf），即行走围绕着天房（Kaaba），这个立方体的结构覆盖着黑色的金色绣花布，他们热烈的朗诵声在空气中回响。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;沙特 7000 亿美元的财富基金是阿里巴巴的粉丝，Flat Glass Coupang &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于参与者人数众多，最靠近天房的一楼的人们都在洗牌。楼上的人能够走得更轻快，甚至跑步。朝圣者在进行塔瓦夫时举手祈求，自拍或视频，并给亲戚打电话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他们在两座山之间步行或跑步，重现夏甲为儿子寻找水源的情景，伊斯梅尔，一个在穆斯林、基督教和犹太教传统中以不同形式出现的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝圣者必须进入一种精神纯洁的状态，称为受戒，才能进行朝觐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男人穿着无缝白色长袍，这一规则旨在促进富人和穷人之间的团结。妇女遮盖自己的身体和头发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在仪式和每日五次祈祷之间，朝圣者们寻找阴凉处，涌向大酒店周围的许多商店和空调购物中心，这使该地区陷入了庄严的停滞状态。在接下来的艰难日子到来之前，让清真寺放松一下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯已经恢复了今年朝觐的全部朝觐能力，此前三年，由于冠状病毒大流行，朝觐人数大幅减少，预计将有超过 200 万穆斯林前往朝觐。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为今年的观众太多了”，来自孟加拉国的 42 岁软件工程师 Mahboub Morshed 说道，他指的是往年的出席人数较少。 “但政府和管理层（朝觐和副朝部）正在努力非常顺利地管理此事。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US, allies consult as security crisis unfolds rapidly in Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225282/us-allies-consult-security-crisis-unfolds-rapidly-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 07:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/71e17c9d-3a3a-470a-b4d0-1ff681240f66_87ad780c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登和高级政府官员与六个以上西方盟友进行协调on Saturday as developments in Russia that pitted President Vladimir Putin against a mercenary leader who had played a key role in the Kremlin&#39;s war against Ukraine unfolded at a bewildering pace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around the time of reports that Yevgeny Prigozhin, head of the private military outfit Wagner Group, had agreed to leave Russia as part of a deal that would spare him prosecution in Russia, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said in a call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba that Washington&#39;s support for Russia&#39;s neighbour “will not change”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The brief readout from the State Department also said that Washington “will stay in close coordination with Ukraine as the situation develops”. Blinken delivered roughly the same message in a separate call with Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin delivered a similar message in separate calls with his counterparts in Canada, France, Germany, Poland and Britain, according to a readout by Pentagon press secretary Pat Ryder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier in the day, Biden spoke with his counterparts in Germany, France and Britain, a call in which the four leaders “affirmed their unwavering support for Ukraine”, according to the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House said Biden, who departed Saturday afternoon for the presidential retreat Camp David, and Vice President Kamala Harris were briefed by his national security team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those officials included Blinken, Austin and National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan, who travelled to Camp David with the president, Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Mark Milley, Director of the Office of National Intelligence Avril Haines, CIA Director William Burns and US Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian mercenary boss Prigozhin to move to Belarus under Wagner deal, Kremlin says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The White House statement said Biden and Harris would receive briefings throughout the day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Biden administration officials had yet to offer any assessments of the situation in Russia, several members of the US Congress speculated on the fast-moving events, offered support or both.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Florida&#39;s Marco Rubio, a Republican member of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, suggested that Prigozhin&#39;s move to Belarus under a deal that the Kremlin said was brokered by Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko did not necessarily mean that Putin had prevailed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If in fact Wagner is standing down it is likely because [Army Chief of Staff Valery Gerasimov and Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu] are being replaced by officials loyal to Prigozhin,” Rubio said on Twitter. “That would make him the most powerful man in Russia now.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former US Ambassador to Nato Kurt Volker made a similar assessment in a CNN interview earlier on Saturday, before the Kremlin announced Prigozhin&#39;s move to Belarus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it&#39;s beginning to unravel there in Russia,” Volker said. “I think that this is really going to be a struggle of the state versus Prigozhin. I have to think the state is still going to pull it out, but I think it&#39;s the end for Putin.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Volker added that Nato should take the opportunity of the apparent rift between Putin and Prigozhin, whose forces had taken vast swathes of Ukrainian territory that Kyiv&#39;s forces have recently begun to claw back, to deliver significantly more weapons to Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We ought to help the Ukrainians with some types of equipment we have still not given them yet, like long range artillery and cluster munitions and aircraft, because now is the time for the Ukrainians to really press forward,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And then Nato really needs to make clear that it is going to bring Ukraine as a member for real this time,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;California Representative Ted Lieu, who sits on the House Foreign Affairs Committee, tweeted that the “escalating conflict between the Wagner Group and the Russian military would not be occurring if Russia&#39;s illegal invasion of Ukraine was going well. Clearly it is not.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk: MMA cage fight with Mark Zuckerberg ‘might actually happen’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225283/elon-musk-mma-cage-fight-mark-zuckerberg-might-actually-happen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 07:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/1864e514-a4ab-4d23-9153-868d571e84b8_419950f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Elon Musk said on Saturday he will start training if the mixed martial arts (MMA) cage fight he has provoked with fellow billionaire media mogul Mark Zuckerberg takes shape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter owner Musk tweeted on Tuesday he was up for a cage match in Las Vegas with Zuckerberg, chief executive of Facebook parent Meta, who has trained in jiu-jitsu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I haven&#39;t started training yet. So if this does happen, I will,” Musk said in a talk on Twitter with Ashlee Vance, the author of a book on Musk and the space race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The match “might actually happen” said Musk while attending a birthday party in Europe, adding it was possible that it could go badly if Zuckerberg takes the match seriously.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk also said SpaceX has made well over 1,000 changes to Starship following the vehicle&#39;s first test launch in April, which failed to reach orbit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Space Exploration Technologies Corporation has changed how the vehicle operates on its path to orbit and it now stands a much improved chance of success with its second attempt, according to its chief executive officer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So I think the probability of the next flight working – or getting to orbit – is much higher than the last one,” Musk said. “Maybe it&#39;s like 60 per cent; it depends on how well we do at stage separation,” he said on a Twitter Spaces on Saturday with Bloomberg senior reporter Ashlee Vance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investment in the Starship project is likely to approach US$3 billion this year, Musk said. Starship is SpaceX&#39;s next-generation rocket, designed to carry cargo – and eventually people – to deep space destinations such as the moon and Mars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk announced that SpaceX has “made a sort of late breaking change” to the way that Starship separates during launch, when the large Super Heavy booster breaks free from the Starship spacecraft mid-flight. He noted that SpaceX has decided to do hot staging, a process where the engines on the Starship vehicle ignite while the Super Heavy booster is still attached.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Meet the newest employee at Elon Musk&#39;s SpaceX. He&#39;s 14.&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“This is something that the Soviets and Russians have used in their space designs,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During Starship&#39;s first test flight, which launched from SpaceX&#39;s Starbase facility in Boca Chica, Texas, US the rocket successfully cleared its launch pad, but suffered multiple engine failures during the vehicle&#39;s climb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Starship was meant to separate from Super Heavy, the two vehicles remained attached as the entire rocket spun out of control. SpaceX was forced to activate the rocket&#39;s flight termination system, which blew up the rocket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk was pressed on whether his commitment to space exploration has wavered in light of his acquisition of Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re trying to get to Mars as fast as possible,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk declined to discuss several topics broached by Vance, including the status of his recently created artificial intelligence company that might rival OpenAI.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said it would be “illegal” to talk about plans for a possible initial public offering for Starlink, SpaceX&#39;s constellation of satellites that provide high-speed internet access in remote areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen sees support fall to 4-year low as #MeToo scandals rock ruling party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3225259/taiwanese-president-tsai-ing-wen-sees-support-fall-4-year-low-metoo-scandals-rock-ruling-party?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/24/61ec794f-50b0-46be-8df5-63bfe54d93bc_b805f650.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Public support for Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen has dropped to its lowest level in four years as her party becomes caught up in a wave of #MeToo allegations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Taiwanese Public Opinion Foundation put Tsai&#39;s approval rating at 42.3 per cent this month, down from 45.3 per cent in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her disapproval rating, meanwhile, rose to 48.2 per cent – from about 37 per cent in May. It was the worst showing since May 2019, when nearly 47 per cent of voters found her performance disappointing, according to the Taipei-based independent polling agency known for its impartial stance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are two main reasons for the drop in her popularity. The first is due to the impact of a host of sexual harassment cases on the ruling Democratic Progressive Party (DPP),” foundation head Michael You Ying-lung said as the latest survey results were released on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wave of sexual harassment and assault allegations, which began with a DPP whistle-blower on May 31, has also taken a toll on the governing party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its popularity dropped to 24.6 per cent, from 31.1 per cent in May, a June 14 survey by the foundation showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You said Tsai had to take the blame as all of the alleged incidents of sexual harassment occurred while she was the head of the party, and her close aide, senior presidential adviser Yen Chih-fa, was alleged to have been implicated in one of the cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, Tsai&#39;s office on June 4 said it had no right to start an investigation into the case as the alleged incident did not take place at the presidential office. The diktat was interpreted as an attempt to dodge the blame, according to You.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yen, 86, has been accused of sexually harassing a former employee of a campaign group, Friends of Tsai Ing-wen Association, when she worked there in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yen denied the allegation, but resigned two days later on June 6 and withdrew a libel suit against the complainant that he had filed only the day before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His departure was followed by a second apology from Tsai in the space of a week over the #MeToo allegations rocking her party, and a pledge to reform gender equality rules within the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second major factor for Tsai&#39;s loss of popularity might have been the controversy over her choice of four grand justices to fill vacancies on Taiwan&#39;s constitutional court, You said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The four nominees are seen as friendly to the independence-leaning DPP, sparking criticism that Tsai had turned the entire 15-seat council of grand justices into a pro-DPP organisation, with future rulings likely to favour the DPP&#39;s political positions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other likely factors were inflation and the high cost of living, shrinking exports and poor overall economic performance, according to You.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Tsai began her second and final four-year term in May 2020, her approval rating was as high as 71 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is worth pondering if the public disappointment towards Tsai&#39;s job performance will create any negative impact on [the DPP] in the presidential and legislative elections [in January],” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s other major political party and the DPP&#39;s main opponent, the Kuomintang, are seen as friendly towards Beijing, which considers the self-governed island to be breakaway Chinese territory awaiting reunification. The DPP rejects this eventuality.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan can suggest how to govern it after reunifying, PLA strategist says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tsai stepped down as chairwoman in December after the party suffered massive defeats to the KMT in mayoral and county elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, dozens of former DPP party workers have come forward with their stories since a whistle-blower colleague posted on social media about her ordeal. She accused a DPP executive of covering up her complaint of having been sexually harassed by a filmmaker when they were working on a promotional project for the party in September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least four senior DPP figures have resigned so far due to their poor handling of the cases or alleged involvement in them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The #MeToo wave has since spread beyond the political sphere, with high-profile figures including academics, TV pundits, doctors, mainland Chinese dissidents in exile, former Taiwanese diplomats and judicial officials as well as celebrities among the accused.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one of the latest cases, Chuang Suo-hang, Taiwan&#39;s de facto ambassador to Thailand, stepped down on Wednesday after he was alleged to have sexually harassed a fellow worker at the island&#39;s representative office in Bangkok.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s foreign ministry said on Saturday that, based on the government&#39;s “zero tolerance” standards, it had asked Chuang to resign following an initial investigation into his alleged wrongdoings. It said the complainant had reported the case to the ministry, but did not give details.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday, popular Taiwanese actor and singer Aaron Yan was accused by a celebrity YouTuber of filming the pair during a sex act without consent when the complainant was only 16 years old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After first apologising via a statement on Facebook, Yan abruptly appeared at a press conference held by his accuser on Wednesday, and apologised to him in person for making him “suffer what you did not deserve”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two days earlier, popular television host Mickey Huang apparently attempted to self-harm after confessing to sexual misconduct. This came after internet celebrity Zofia said she had been forcibly kissed in a car and tricked into posing topless for photos for a purported “art exhibition” when she was only 17. She did not name Huang, but left easy clues to help identify the accused.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At noon the same day, Huang uploaded three videos to his Facebook page expressing regret for not living up to public expectations and “violating their trust”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an emotional outburst, he also lamented that it was unfair that he was the only one to get caught while 13 other high-profile show business figures he knew well were able to escape being named for similar or other wrongdoings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang&#39;s wife later confirmed he had been admitted to a hospital for what local news media reports said were self-inflicted wounds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The local #MeToo movement, which has gained momentum since June 1, was sparked by the hit Taiwanese Netflix drama Wave Makers, about a fictional group of political workers working on an election campaign. One of the female aides finds herself in a dilemma over whether she should expose sexual harassment by a male colleague.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wave Makers: top Netflix election drama by The World Between Us director&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The first DPP whistle-blower admitted on social media that she was inspired by the show to come forward. Ironically, a male actor in the series was also the target of sexual assault allegations, which he has strongly denied.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, former disciplinary court chief Lee Po-tao, who retired a month early citing health reasons, denied in a statement on Wednesday that his resignation in May had anything to do with allegations of having sexually assaulted a female colleague.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He did, however, express regret for any action that might have been deemed inappropriate, saying: “For one who had worked with me relatively closely at the disciplinary court, I am deeply sorry and regretful if I had made her feel uncomfortable at any venue or occasion.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee, 70, also said he was willing to face a fair investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other high-profile figures involved in recent #MeToo allegations include Bartosz Rys, a former deputy representative of the de facto Polish embassy in Taipei, and exiled mainland Chinese poet Bei Ling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mainland Chinese dissident Wang Dan also faced allegations of sexual assault from two men, one of whom sued Wang for forcible kissing and attempted rape in New York in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rys, Bei and Wang have dismissed the allegations against them as groundless.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canadian authorities look into cause of Titan submersible implosion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225280/canadian-police-look-circumstances-deaths-titan-submersible-implosion?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 06:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/3fecfeb0-14be-495c-9797-72f22a3b599a_93f8e4c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Transportation Safety Board of Canada (TSB) said on Saturday it is conducting an investigation into the loss of the Titan submersible and has been speaking to those who travelled on Titan&#39;s mother ship, the Polar Prince.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The development comes as authorities from the United States and Canada began the process of investigating the cause of the underwater implosion and grappled with questions of who was responsible for determining how the tragedy unfolded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maritime agencies are searching the area in the North Atlantic where the vessel was destroyed, killing all five people aboard. Debris was located about 12,500ft (3,810 metres) underwater, several hundred feet away from the Titanic wreckage it was on its way to explore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are conducting a safety investigation in Canada given that this was a Canadian-flagged vessel that departed a Canadian port and was involved in this occurrence, albeit in international waters,” said Kathy Fox, chairwoman of the transport board. “Other agencies may choose to conduct investigations and that&#39;s up to them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Polar Prince left Newfoundland on June 16, towing the ill-fated Titan. There were 41 people on board – 17 crew members and 24 others – including the five who died when Titan imploded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fox said she understands the international interest and that the TSB will share information they collect with other agencies, such as the US National Transportation Safety Board and the US Coast Guard, within the limits of Canadian law. Voice recordings and witness statements are protected under Canadian law, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our investigation will go where the evidence leads us,” she said. “我们不想重复工作。 We want to collaborate.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Royal Canadian Mounted Police also on Saturday announced it has initiated an examination of the circumstances that led to the Titan deaths to decide whether a full investigation is warranted. That full investigation will only take place if it appears criminal, federal or provincial law may have been broken, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Titan sub firm faces backlash for posting pilot job ad during search mission&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The coastguard led the initial search and rescue mission, a massive international effort that likely cost millions of dollars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not entirely clear who would have the authority to lead what is sure to be a complex investigation involving several countries.拥有并运营泰坦号的 OceanGate Expeditions 公司总部位于美国，但该潜水器在巴哈马注册。 OceanGate 总部位于华盛顿州埃弗里特，但在泰坦被发现后关闭。 Meanwhile, the Titan&#39;s mother ship, the Polar Prince, was from Canada, and those killed were from the UK, Pakistan, France, and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Transportation Safety Board said on Friday that the US Coast Guard has declared the loss of the Titan submersible to be a “major marine casualty” and the coastguard will lead the investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The coastguard has not confirmed that it will take the lead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deep-sea investigations promise to be long and painstaking, given the murky depths of the ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is an incredibly unforgiving environment down there on the sea floor,” said Rear Admiral. John Mauger, of the coastguard First District.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How the overall investigation will proceed is complicated by the fact that the world of deep-sea exploration is not well regulated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A central part of any investigation is likely to be the Titan itself. Questions have been raised about whether the vessel was destined for disaster because of its unconventional design and its creator&#39;s refusal to submit to independent checks that are standard in the industry&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Titan was not registered as a US vessel or with international agencies that regulate safety. And it was not classified by a maritime industry group that sets standards on matters such as hull construction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate chief executive Stockton Rush, who was piloting the Titan when it imploded, complained that regulations can stifle progress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Bringing an outside entity up to speed on every innovation before it is put into real-world testing is anathema to rapid innovation,” Rush wrote in a blog post on his company&#39;s website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One question that seems at least partially resolved is when the implosion likely happened. After the Titan was reported missing, the Navy went back and analysed its acoustic data and found an “anomaly” on Sunday that was consistent with an implosion or explosion in the general vicinity of where the vessel was operating when communications were lost, said a senior US Navy official.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The navy passed on the information to the coastguard, which continued its search because the data was not considered definitive, according to the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity to discuss a sensitive acoustic detection system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Titan launched at 8am local time that day and was reported overdue that afternoon about 435 miles (700km) south of St John&#39;s, Newfoundland. Rescuers rushed ships, planes and other equipment to the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How the Titanic sub&#39;s unconventional design may have destined it for disaster&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Any sliver of hope that remained for finding the crew alive was lost early on Thursday, when the coastguard announced that debris had been found near the Titanic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Killed in the implosion were Rush, two members of a prominent Pakistani family, Shahzada Dawood and his son Suleman Dawood;英国冒险家哈米什·哈丁； and Titanic expert Paul-Henri Nargeolet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A flurry of lawsuits is expected, but filing them will be complex and it is unclear how successful they will be. Plaintiffs will run into the problem of establishing jurisdiction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least 46 people successfully travelled on OceanGate&#39;s submersible to the Titanic wreck site in 2021 and 2022, according to letters the company filed with a US District Court in Norfolk, Virginia, that oversees matters involving the Titanic shipwreck.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But questions about the submersible&#39;s safety were raised by both by a former company employee and former passengers.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrives in Egypt on a two-day visit to strengthen ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3225279/indian-prime-minister-narendra-modi-arrives-egypt-two-day-visit-strengthen-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 04:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/6ebadd0f-5ee5-414a-86bd-7fc732888119_09f5186b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪于周六开始对埃及进行为期两天的访问，这次访问突显了两国之间不断发展的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪的航班于周六下午降落在开罗国际机场，他结束了对美国为期四天的访问，并在美国与美国总统乔·拜登举行了会谈，在美国国会发表演讲，并会见了美国和印度高层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自1997年以来印度总理首次对埃及进行国事访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪受到接待埃及总理穆斯塔法·马德布利接见，两人检阅仪仗队并聆听国歌。莫迪在推特上感谢马德布利“在机场欢迎我的特殊姿态”，并补充道，“愿印度与埃及的关系蓬勃发展，造福我们两国人民。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪和马德布利随后据埃及国营中东和北非通讯社报道，双方就加强埃及与印度关系举行了会谈。据中东和北非地区报道，两国高级政府官员出席了会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度外交部发言人阿林达姆·巴格奇 (Arindam Bagchi) 表示，莫迪还与埃及伊斯兰法学家大穆夫提·肖基·阿拉姆 (Grand Mufti Shawki Allam) 讨论了“打击极端主义和激进化”的问题。事务部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪预计将于周日与总统阿卜杜勒·法塔赫·塞西举行会谈。两国还将签署一系列旨在巩固两国关系的备忘录。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“毫无疑问”：拜登与莫迪会谈中讨论了共同的中国挑战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;也在周日，莫迪将参观伊斯兰开罗一座历史悠久的清真寺 Al-Hakim，该清真寺最近在印度 Dawoodi Bohra 社区的帮助下进行了翻修。预计他还将参观赫利奥波利斯战争公墓，向参加第一次世界大战的印度士兵致敬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪的访问是在塞西作为正式客人参加印度共和国日阅兵六个月后进行的。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;1月份，塞西和莫迪同意采取措施，在五年内将双向贸易额从2021-22年的73亿美元增加到120亿美元。塞西访问期间，两国还签署了扩大网络安全、信息技术、文化和广播领域合作的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度是埃及产品（包括原油和液化天然气）的前五个进口国之一天然气、盐、棉花、无机化学品和油籽。 Major Indian exports to Egypt include cotton yarn, coffee, herbs, tobacco, lentils, vehicle parts, ships, boats and electrical machinery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 50 Indian companies have invested around US$3.15 billion in various parts of the Egyptian economy, including chemicals, energy, textiles, garments, agribusiness and retailing, according to India&#39;s External Affairs Ministry.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden vows to fight Republicans’ ‘extreme’ anti-abortion agenda]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225278/joe-biden-vows-fight-republicans-extreme-anti-abortion-agenda?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 03:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/222600f7-4c35-4413-abbf-e5b7068c80b6_148ccbe6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国最高法院废除美国宪法规定的堕胎权一年后美国总统乔·拜登周六发誓要与共和党人在全国范围内限制该程序的“极端而危险”的努力作斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高等法院推翻具有里程碑意义的罗伊诉韦德案裁决的决定通过了该规定堕胎权回到各个州——其中一些州已经采取行动大幅限制堕胎程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“州禁令只是一个开始，”拜登在裁决周年纪念日的一份声明中表示。 “他们的议程极端、危险，与绝大多数美国人格格不入。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持堕胎和反堕胎的团体周六在美国首都举行了相互竞争的活动，副-卡马拉·哈里斯总统在南部北卡罗来纳州的一次演讲中谈到了与生殖权利有关的医疗保健“危机”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 20 个州（主要位于南部和中西部）已彻底禁止堕胎或严格限制堕胎机会而其他人（主要是沿海地区）已采取行动保护堕胎诊所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约十几个州关闭堕胎诊所，迫使数万名妇女前往其他地方终止妊娠。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拜登还警告说，共和党人正在努力制定全国范围内的堕胎禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国会共和党人希望在全国范围内禁止堕胎，但除此之外，还可以通过服用 FDA 批准的终止妊娠药物来终止妊娠。总统说，他指的是食品和药物管理局。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国法官表示“我们每天都因推翻堕胎权而受到打击”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;在华盛顿的一次小型集会上，抗议者举着标语和 T 恤，上面写着“我是后罗伊一代”和“未出生的生命很重要”等短语，敦促在国家层面限制堕胎。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;反堕胎活动家史蒂夫·卡伦和他的妻子劳拉从中西部威斯康星州前往首都“庆祝”罗伊的逆转，这也是他们的结婚纪念日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“堕胎决定回到各州真是一件幸事，”五个孩子的家庭主妇劳拉说。 “但最终我们想要的是未出生的孩子在全国范围内得到保护——我们国家的每个人都有权生存。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于美国国会存在分歧，拜登几乎无能为力。尽管如此，他表示他将推动联邦层面的保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的政府将继续保护获得生殖保健的机会，并呼吁国会一劳永逸地恢复联邦法律中罗伊诉韦德案的保护一切，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;堕胎权被证明是民主党在 2022 年中期选举中的一个关键问题，并且在 2024 年总统竞选中可能同样重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们&#39;我们也成为共和党竞选活动中的一个亮点。初选候选人目前正试图包抄前总统唐纳德·特朗普，后者是目前该党提名的领跑者，他因立场反复无常而受到批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佛罗里达州州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯周五在华盛顿发表讲话。对他在该州签署成为法律的为期六周的堕胎禁令表示欢迎，而前副总统迈克·彭斯则向每一位候选人发起挑战，要求他们支持全国范围内的堕胎禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是正确的做法 - 不要这样做让任何人告诉你事实并非如此。”德桑蒂斯含蓄地抨击了特朗普，后者批评佛罗里达州的法律“过于严厉”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一天，拜登赢得了美国领导人的支持。堕胎权利团体，包括计划生育协会、NARAL 和 Emily&#39;s List。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>