<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Hope you can be happy every day’: Chinese boy, 6, bids fond farewell to bus driver on last day of kindergarten, warming hearts online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226938/hope-you-can-be-happy-every-day-chinese-boy-6-bids-fond-farewell-bus-driver-last-day-kindergarten?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/933467d3-a27c-4cc7-9cbd-75fdfd3e93e4_16806b07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个关于中国六岁男孩寄出告别信的故事一名公交车司机向他表示感谢，并表示幼儿园毕业后将走另一条路，这句话在大陆社交媒体上融化了人们的心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男孩名叫阳阳，来自中国东部的山东省，获得了第一名。据山电视频报道，每天都有公交车前往幼儿园，并与司机吕传伟建立了友谊&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在幼儿园的最后一天，阳阳决心与吕传伟告别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在两人的一段广为流传的视频中，阳阳问吕第二天什么时候上班，坐哪趟车。阳阳补充说，他会早起，乘坐吕驾驶的公交车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二天，阳阳和妈妈一起上了车，付了车费后，递给了一封父母帮他写的信。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;信中，洋洋表示很喜欢乘坐吕驾驶的公交车，也很喜欢司机的下一站提醒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“希望你能幸福阳阳写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阳阳补充说，因为他已经读完幼儿园，正在另一个地区上小学，所以他不能再乘坐吕驾驶的公交车了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我会想念你的。”阳阳写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男孩答应以后会查看吕的工作安排，以便他有时可以和他一起坐公交车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“再见，我就像坐公交车一样。”他写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吕没有立即打开信，而是送给阳阳一些书籍和一辆玩具车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体用户已经被迷住了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“哦，这孩子真可爱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“公交车司机也很可爱。他们充满了爱。”另一位网友说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于可爱孩子的故事经常在大陆社交媒体上引起共鸣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，中国北方一名六岁男孩被拦住在大陆社交媒体上热传的一段视频中，他用断梯子防止父亲摔倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，中国东部的一位父亲对八岁儿子在学校的慷慨行为进行了奖励，而不是批评他他的平均学业成绩激励了大陆社交媒体观察者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI-generated hits of Hong Kong stars surprise fans, bring dead singers back to life and raise questions about copyright]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227291/ai-generated-hits-hong-kong-stars-surprise-fans-bring-dead-singers-back-life-and-raise-questions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/0725a5bc-e228-4899-bdc0-82a17e978215_4f6c26a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当香港邪教偶像云光演唱的粤语流行歌曲大受欢迎时，他感到很惊讶由于人工智能的使用，最近与听众进行了交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;YouTube 内容创作者使用人工智能生成他的声音，然后将其与两首歌曲（词曲作者林家谦的《孤独》和《我亲爱的朋友》）整合在一起” 由香港男孩乐队 Mirror 的强涛演唱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在六月初的两周内，这两首歌曲的观看次数都超过了百万次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我什至不知道如何唱这些歌曲，”79 岁的万说，他通过用搞笑的暗示性歌词演唱歌曲来娱乐歌迷近 50 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是谢谢你关注我，因为我从来没有这样在我的职业生涯中很受欢迎。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能在音乐行业中占有一席之地已有几年，但最近，它已经开始创作出知名艺术家的新作品，其中包括一些早已去世的艺术家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;生成式人工智能可以分析歌手作品的数字编译，并创作出似乎由他们演唱或以他们的风格表演的新歌曲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;音乐传奇人物保罗·麦卡特尼透露，将会有一个决赛披头士乐队今年发行的歌曲，借助人工智能，它将由 1980 年去世的乐队成员约翰·列侬 (John Lennon) 配音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，内容创作者制作了人工智能克隆的歌曲翻唱由黄家驹创作，于 1993 年去世，享年 31 岁。他是 Beyond 乐队的主唱，Beyond 乐队是香港最具影响力的摇滚乐队之一，其中包括他的兄弟、贝斯手黄家强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;翻唱过四张专辑他的歌曲在 5 月份推出的 YouTube 频道“KakuiAI”上吸引了超过 100 万次观看。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;格莱美新规则称，随着人工智能音乐的崛起，只有人类创作者才能获胜&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Leslie 66 岁的陈建添 (Chan Kin-tim) 于 1986 年至 1993 年间管理 Beyond，并拥有黄之锋 20 首未发行歌曲的出版权。重现死去歌手的声音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我拒绝了这个想法，他的弟弟也是如此，”陈说。 “很多人认为人工智能很强大，不关心真实性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说他更喜欢听其他艺术家表演黄的歌曲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“讨论人工智能是可以的翻唱和玩乐纯粹是为了娱乐，但粉丝需要知道什么是真的，什么是假的。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡华语流行歌手孙燕姿，自 2017 年以来一直没有发行过专辑。 ”你与在几分钟内推出新专辑的人打架吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;艺术家能保护他们的作品吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最近人工智能的热潮引发了有关版权和版权的问题。艺术家如何阻止内容制作者制作假货。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学法学副教授 Ryan Whalen 的研究领域包括创新政策和法律技术，他表示在音乐中使用生成式人工智能的趋势可能会出现让音乐家变得脆弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他们独特且可识别的声音可以通过人工智能再现时，他们的市场力量可能会被稀释，这会引发侵权问题，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“风格这首歌的内容不属于受版权保护的内容。因此，这就提出了一个单独的问题，即你可以在多大程度上真正保护你的音乐呈现风格。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果使用人工智能的内容创作者的来源包含受版权保护的材料，例如很大一部分内容，那么他​​们将面临风险&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;人工智能正在挑战我们重新思考“真”与“假”之间的区别&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“也就是说，追究侵犯版权的人的成本相当高，所以很多公司他说：“我们不会提起诉讼，只会发出删除请求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港法律中，音乐作品的版权（旋律和歌词）归作曲家所有，而音乐作品的版权归作曲家所有。录音归唱片公司或制作人所有。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;迪士尼在漫威的《秘密入侵》系列中使用人工智能让好莱坞感到震惊&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Whalen 表示，与人工智能生成的内容相关的法律问题仍然模糊。他认为，通过检查用于生成虚假音乐内容的人工智能模型是如何“训练”的，版权侵权可能会变得更加清晰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要复制特定歌手的声音和风格，必须向人工智能训练模型提供反馈包含大量歌手的歌曲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，有一种观点认为，在训练模型的早期阶段，实际的版权侵权就会发生，”他说。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;香港调解仲裁中心主席苏文杰律师表示，使用人工智能创造声音并将其融入保留原始歌词、旋律和编曲的歌曲中可能会侵犯版权。&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;Flash 小说故事：你能分辨出它们是人工智能创造的还是人类创造的吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他解释说，该法律适用于表演受版权保护歌曲的街头艺人，但问题是这种行为是否损害了版权所有者的权利并导致版税损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“使用版权所有者的旋律和歌词在 YouTube 频道上发布人工智能生成的歌曲可能会吸引大量观众，从而为内容创作者带来广告收入。这带来了侵权风险，因为版权所有者可能认为这些收入可能是他们的。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，一些版权所有者可能决定不做出反应，认为新的人工智能演绎是一种推广他们的作品，而其他人可能会威胁那些上传内容的人，如果他们不向香港作曲家及作家协会支付版权使用费，就会采取法律行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但有时，唱片公司不知道是谁上传者是，所以他们直接要求在线服务提供商删除侵犯版权的内容。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，如果人工智能生成的封面被破坏，内容创作者也将面临民事和刑事责任&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“世界上第一家配备人工智能 DJ 的广播电台”：你能分辨出其中的区别吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“香港没有保护个人数据隐私和版权的法律。个人形象和声音的权利。但当内容创作者未经授权录制某人的声音并使用人工智能将其转化为不同的内容时，这可能会违反隐私法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果人工智能生成的作品包含侵权内容并以更高的价格出售出于商业目的，海关当局也可以作为刑事犯罪采取执法行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国网信办主任对生成式人工智能的力量表示担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在香港，更新的版权条例5 月生效，旨在加强对数字环境的保护，包括鼓励在线服务提供商与版权所有者合作打击在线盗版的安全港制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府还公布了业务守则，提供了切实可行的措施在线服务提供商在收到其平台上的在线盗版通知后可能采取的指导和程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所以说：“在安全港制度下，当版权所有者通知平台发现侵权内容时，他们需要通过提醒上传者或自行删除内容来采取行动。如果他们这样做，他们的责任将被免除。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;人工智能歌曲“令人毛骨悚然但令人安慰”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;目前，香港歌迷对新的人工智能生成的音乐内容做出了反应带着敬畏和恐惧的心情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家庭主妇、三个孩子的母亲曾子瑜，49 岁，自 1989 年以来一直是 Beyond 的粉丝，她说她很震惊地在社交媒体上看到偶像黄家驹的人工智能封面&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“语气、发音甚至颤音听起来都像他。奇怪的是，这让我回想起十几岁时购买他的磁带时是多么兴奋。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她认识到，人工智能生成的歌曲仅基于可用内容，直到他 1993 年去世为止.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果黄今天还活着，他的风格就会改变。这是人工智能无法预测的。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;46 岁的执行教练 Marcas Wan Kam-yeung 表示，当黄的人工智能生成的新歌曲在 6 月份出现时，他感到很震惊，也就是这位明星去世 30 周年的那个月&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这感觉令人毛骨悚然但又令人安慰，因为这听起来像他，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他自己也是一名键盘手，他担心人工智能趋势可能会对音乐家产生影响，尤其是那些为电视广告制作歌曲的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;47岁的保险公司高管张贤明也是听Beyond长大的，他说这些差异对他来说是显而易见的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参与《Beyond》致敬专辑的本地独立乐队 AirTub 的贝斯手表示：“对我来说，人类的不完美有时会让歌曲变得更好。人工智能无法模仿真人的情绪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浸会大学音乐学院实践副教授、容祖儿、刘德华和张敬轩等粤语流行歌星的音乐制作人曾奕民博士张先生怀疑人工智能真人翻唱的趋势能否持续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“公众可能会觉得听到一个已故歌手演唱新歌会很耳目一新，但我们需要看看每年是否还有需求。”从现在开始，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕竟，艺术或流行音乐需要人的元素。歌迷实际上爱上了歌手、他们的歌曲以及他们的表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“即使人工智能翻唱完美无瑕，人们也可能不会喜欢人工智能创造的冷漠和客观的感觉。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;新人工智能材料背后的内容创作者在很大程度上仍处于人们的视线之外，人们对香港有多少人、他们是谁或他们如何运作知之甚少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》联系了我们据信参与其中的几位人士，但只有一名自称为“VT”的人通过电子邮件匿名回复。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;类似 ChatGPT 的技术正在与智能家居设备集成，以增强服务&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;退伍军人云光 (Wan Kwong) 最近推出的人工智能歌曲的创作者表示，这位歌手深受几代香港人的欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;承认这一趋势给音乐产业、歌手、版权带来了挑战。他说：“最终，我们的目标是促进人工智能和人类创造力之间的共生关系，其中人工智能作为工具来放大和增强艺术家、内容创作者和行业专业人士的创造力。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他拒绝提供任何个人信息，只透露自己在一家人工智能战略咨询公司工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;万则想知道人工智能趋势是否开启了新的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt; “我期待与年轻歌手合作，”他说。 “我不知道如何唱人工智能歌曲，但我会学习并希望在我的音乐会上正确地表演它们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他确信一件事。 “只有有血有肉的表演者才能在舞台上与观众、乐队、舞者互动，传递情感。人工智能只是技术，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China jobs: graduates face ‘sluggish prospects’ and US$3,000 a year or a helping hand to US$40,000 plus bonuses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3227312/china-jobs-graduates-face-sluggish-prospects-and-us3000-year-or-helping-hand-us40000-plus-bonuses?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/d9ce6fc1-a4d4-45f3-b799-7075e00044c2_ecfaeaf3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是关于中国就业环境的第三个故事，来自农民工和新鲜人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年底，当北京宣布结束疫情管控措施时，22岁的大学生何宇和她医学检验专业的同学们突然面临着“ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当核酸检测被取消时，我们的工作机会也随之被取消，”上个月从中国中部河南省一所非精英医学院毕业的何说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于过去三年中国严格的零新冠政策，大量的检测使得何的专业需求量很大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但现在她所在的46名学生中只有三人班级找到了每月工资约为 2,000 元（279 美元）的工作，这还不到中国应届毕业生平均月薪的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一开始我们感到绝望，但现在我们现在基本上已经接受了就业前景低迷的事实。”正在申请硕士学位的何说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是今年中国创纪录的 1158 万名大学生中的一员。就业市场竞争激烈，机会不断减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界第二大经济体报告称，5 月份 16 至 24 岁的年轻人中有 20.8% 没有工作，这是自 2017 年以来青年失业率最高的一次。这些数字是首次编制的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使精英院校的毕业生拥有高需求的资格，他们的薪酬也可能会较低，尽管他们大学的良好声誉和资源被认为会降低他们的薪酬。提供更好的前景和失业保障。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵鼎新，24岁，将从上海一所顶尖精英大学毕业，将前往北京从事私募股权工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就读于在学校全国知名的金融课程中，她选择了一份起薪为每年 30 万元（41,500 美元）的有保障的工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果市场状况好转，再加上奖金，我预计的年薪可能会达到50万元。”赵说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“疫情确实降低了薪资预期，过去绝大多数人预计年底工资为30万元，现在降至20万元。” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“一时无解”：中国青年失业问题只会愈演愈烈&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，她的预期收入仍然减少了三分之一，仍然超过全国平均年收入国家统计部门 1 月份的报告显示，这一数字为 36,883 元人民币（5,098 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵获得了即时市场信息，她的学校设计了定量模型来评估就业市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们可以利用这些指标来实时改变我们的求职策略，同时老师们总是给我们一对一的就业辅导。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受益于扎实的内容名牌大学的声誉和及时的就业市场信息，再加上一线城市更好的实习机会，赵和她的同学都找到了收入相对较好的工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但对于毕业于不太热门大学的学生来说，较小的城市和不受欢迎的资格，他们可能会越来越难找到工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们的最后一年，学校只给我们举办了一次职业鼓舞人心的集会，事实上我们没有” 23 岁的谷宇说，他将从河南省郑州的一所私立大学毕业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与美国不同的是，美国的精英大学往往是私立的—— &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的重点大学基本上都是政府资助的，而民办院校在用人单位中的声誉相对较低。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们看来，这次动员大会更像是一次敦促我们赶快提交就业证明的会议，而不是为我们找到工作提供实际帮助，”电子商务补充道顾专业，指的是学生、大学和新雇主之间签订的一份合同，保证了他们的第一份工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顾正计划前往一线城市寻找更多的机会，甚至&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“招聘网站上的公司声称他们每月支付约7000至13000元，但面试后我发现这只是3000元左右的底薪”顾说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就是我们在全国一线城市之一广州所提供的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年中国研究生的平均月收入为5,990元根据 Mycos 上个月发布的《就业蓝皮书》，该数字为 828 美元，较 2021 年增长了 3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大学数字咨询平台提供的数据显示，应届毕业生的就业前景自疫情爆发以来，收入增长大幅下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据数据显示，疫情爆发前四年，毕业生起薪平均增幅为 8%，这一数字自 2020 年以来缩减了一半&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告补充道，“新冠病毒可能是影响薪资增长的主要超额因素之一。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蓝皮书数据显示，从精英学校毕业的年轻人2019年院校就业三年平均月薪是非名校学生月薪的1.2倍。报告显示，受疫情影响，精英大学毕业生三年后薪资增长率仅增长了68%，不到2017年毕业生增长率的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非精英大学的毕业生也有同样的增长。报告称，三年后薪资增幅从121%下降至同期的66%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“名牌大学在资源整合方面具有一定的优势，特别是在利用校友资源、提供就业机会等方面。” “指导服务、整合就业信息”，中国就业研究院副研究员毛宇飞说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最明显的结果是名校毕业生多份工作选择的结构性悖论， ”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;毕业生寻找农村就业机会，但与毛泽东时代不同&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;经济不景气时，企业往往会更加严格毛补充说，通过人才选拔来降低招聘成本，这使得非精英大学毕业生更难找到工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毛认为，非精英大学应该利用在线平台整合就业信息，为他们提供就业机会。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管北京放弃了严格的病毒政策，但中小型私营企业仍面临着长期的不确定性和低迷的市场前景&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蓝皮书显示，去年300人以下中小企业招收的应届本科生比例比五年前下降了10%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告补充说，在中国房地产低迷的情况下，建筑行业中小企业就业的应届毕业生数量比五年前下降了30%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s home prices to decline further amid high mortgage rates, glut of new units, lack of mainland buyers: JLL]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3227343/hong-kongs-home-prices-decline-further-amid-high-mortgage-rates-glut-new-units-lack-mainland-buyers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/d8602081-3c95-4aea-b777-8219ac321f0c_efdf5b6e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港住宅楼市低迷尚未见底，复苏之路仲量联行表示，考虑到高利率、未售出的新房过剩以及中国大陆购买力缺乏等不利因素，这一过程将是漫长而艰难的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;股市波动、外部经济充满挑战等因素该房地产公司在周二发布的年中房地产市场报告中表示，环境因素以及新生儿和结婚人数的减少也正在影响住房需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港房地产市场目前正在经历最长的价格调整“自 2008 年以来，市场尚未见底。”香港仲量联行董事长曾舜晞表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年第二季度房价环比下跌 1.2%， JLL 表示，第一季度反弹 4% 后，较 20 个月前的峰值暴跌 15.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司目前预计下半年价格将下跌 5% 至 10% ，导致 2023 年总体下降 5% 至 8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告补充说，已竣工项目中未售出的单位数量是 2007 年以来的最高水平。香港现有83,000个住房单位，其中18,000个已竣工，其余正在建设中。此外，据仲量联行称，预计 2023 年将有约 25,000 套公寓上市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据之前周期的观察，目前的情况并不能保证房价可持续回升，”曾表示，补充说，鉴于该行业面临的阻力，当前的下行周期将比之前的低谷更长。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港抵押贷款变化对房地产市场的影响有限&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;世界经济并不曾荫权表示，预计未来一到两年将显着复苏，中国与欧洲和美国的关系也不会在不久的将来显着改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港经济第一季度增长2.7%与去年同期相比，结束了连续四个季度的收缩。政府对全年经济增长的预测为3.5%至5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾表示，房地产市场的复苏只会从利率下降趋势开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美联储在连续 10 次加息后采取错开进一步加息的举措后，香港金融管理局 (HKMA) 自 2022 年 3 月以来首次暂停加息，将香港基本利率维持在 5.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但抵押贷款利率已从加息周期前的 1.5% 上涨了一倍多，达到 3.5%。根据美联物业的数据，这意味着一套贷款价值比为 90%、贷款价值比为 90% 的公寓在 30 年内的每月按揭付款已飙升 30.1% 至 25,461 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;香港房价 5 月份下跌 0.7%，结束了 4 个月的上涨势头&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港金管局周五晚间自 2009 年以来首次放宽抵押贷款规则，以使首次购房者和其他购房者更容易借贷想要升级到更大的公寓的人。经纪人和银行家表示，此举激起了潜在购房者和现有业主的兴趣，但不会对整体房地产市场前景产生重大影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仲量联行的房价预测与其他公司的房价预测相呼应。分析师。莱坊 (Knight Frank) 预测全年住宅价格将下降最多 5%，而花旗 (Citi) 预计年底价格将与 2022 年持平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与待售房价相比仲量联行的曾先生表示，住宅租赁市场将获得来自中国大陆的人口流入以及顶尖人才通行证计划下招聘人员的到来的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些[人]可能不会立即买房，但他们肯定会租一间，这将有利于租赁市场。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年到目前为止，香港已收到超过 10 万份各类人才计划的申请，批准率超过 60%据 JLL 称，下半年豪华租金价格将上涨 5%。这与戴德梁行 (Cushman &amp; Wakefield) 的预测一致，即 2023 年租金价格指数将上涨约 5% 至 8%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing now home to half of China-developed AI models as more tech talent and investments head to the nation’s capital]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3227308/beijing-now-home-half-china-developed-ai-models-more-tech-talent-and-investments-head-nations?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/a863d680-89e0-4b9a-b0f3-876a05ef62a9_5b9ba1bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京现在拥有中国一半的大型语言模型 (LLM) –据地方当局称，继上海之后，越来越多的公司在中国第二大城市向市场推出了一系列生成式人工智能 (AI) 服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京市经济和信息化局局长姜光智表示，中国资本拥有全国三分之一以上的“核心人工智能公司”，在已开办的约 80 个法学硕士项目中，有 40 个来自中国资本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;姜表示，北京将为用于训练人工智能模型和应用程序的计算资源提供约4000万元人民币（550万美元）的补贴，同时还承诺通过每季度在一系列工业场景中实施法学硕士应用程序来推广人工智能模型据当地新闻媒体《科创板日报》周二报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京（在法学硕士发展方面）领先中国城市，因为该城市在计算能力、数据集、用例场景、投资方面具有显着优势。科创板日报援引蒋的话说。 “我们希望进一步将资源集中在人工智能创新上，并使其与经济和社会的需求保持一致。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法学硕士是深度学习人工智能算法，可以识别、总结、翻译、预测和生成内容使用非常大的数据集。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生成式人工智能是指算法，例如为 ChatGPT 和类似服务提供支持的算法，可用于创建新内容，包括音频、代码、图像、文本、模拟和视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京对人工智能创新的承诺反映了中国对这项技术的巨大押注，该技术将成为改造和提高传统产业效率的主要催化剂，同时在后新冠疫情时期提振经济。 -19复苏正在失去动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人工智能是当今技术发展的重要趋势，也是下一轮工业革命的驱动力，”江说，并补充说法学硕士有望进一步发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;中国拥有上半年获得融资最多的人工智能初创企业：报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他表示，北京还将推动采购“安全可靠”的人工智能模型，以帮助政府机构市政府、国有企业和各种公共机构提高了生产力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在微软公司支持的初创公司 OpenAI 于 11 月发布 ChatGPT 后，中国大型科技公司纷纷开发具有竞争力的本地服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;参与LLM开发的主要科技公司包括互联网搜索提供商百度、视频游戏和社交媒体巨头腾讯控股、人工智能专家商汤科技、电信设备制造商华为技术有限公司以及电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团控股和京东.com。阿里巴巴拥有《南华早报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，尽管百度、阿里巴巴和科大讯飞等大型科技公司在中国，互联网监管机构中国国家互联网信息办公室尚未为任何生成式人工智能产品颁发许可证。已试行推出类似 ChatGPT 的服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国将制定并实施人工智能模型国家标准&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在上周于上海举行的世界人工智能大会 (WAIC) 上，中国将制定并实施人工智能模型国家标准&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;宣布中国成立了一个新的政府机构，负责实施法学硕士国家标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;隶属于工业和信息化部 (MIIT) 的中国电子技术标准化研究院，表示已联合百度、华为、网络安全公司360安全技术和阿里巴巴牵头成立一个特别工作组，负责制定新的LLM标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在WAIC活动上，工信部副部长徐晓兰强调了中国政府承诺加大对国内人工智能产业的支持力度，目前国内人工智能产业预计超过4,300家企业。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why ‘ironclad friend’ Cambodia might just be China’s model ally]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227180/why-ironclad-friend-cambodia-might-just-be-chinas-model-ally?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/f2820c0e-86be-4dc2-84aa-1a7f93ceb6d2_45b81407.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;If Beijing stops and looks around, its friends aren&#39;t doing too well. Its “no limits” comrade in Moscow just survived a mercenary mutiny with a column of a few thousand irregulars and ex-criminals almost strolling into the capital. And Iran is still reeling from protests after Mahsa Amini died in “morality police” custody last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “anti-hegemonic” coalition of China, Russia and Iran, as former US national security adviser Zbigniew Brzezinski forecast in 1997 (what historian Niall Ferguson now calls the “axis of ill will”), looks increasingly fragile.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearer home, Laos is so badly in debt to China that Beijing is likely to have to write off billions of dollars at some point – not a great look for the export of its infrastructure-led development model. Myanmar&#39;s junta wants Beijing to offer international cover as it perpetuates civil war, but also wants to weaken its dependency on China through engagement with India and Russia. Pakistan is, as the Economist put it, in “perma-crisis”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whatever inroads China made in Thailand and the Philippines have hit a dead end. Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos Jnr has returned the country to its pro-Western agenda, while a coalition set to take power in Bangkok next month is expected to be more pro-US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That makes Cambodia, an “ironclad friend”, something of an outlier. It often looks like the least troubled of China&#39;s closest Asian partners and usually delivers only good news. To be the ambassador in Phnom Penh must be one of the easiest jobs for a Chinese diplomat. Cambodia isn&#39;t badly in hock; national debt was just 33.7 per cent of gross domestic product last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has close trading relations with Western nations, its main export partners, allowing Chinese companies in the country to make handsome profits. In the first quarter of this year, China had a US$2.2 billion trade surplus with Cambodia. Its housing market often resembles a bubble waiting to burst, but it&#39;s proven sturdy enough for the Chinese who want to invest there for their retirement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s government may be increasingly dictatorial but it&#39;s stable. The ruling Cambodian People&#39;s Party (CPP) is assured total victory at the general election on July 23, and Prime Minister Hun Sen is likely to orchestrate a peaceful power transfer to his eldest son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cambodia&#39;s government may or may not have secretly agreed to let the People&#39;s Liberation Army station troops at its Ream naval base, but the fact that Washington, which takes this seriously, continues to increase its aid to, and trade with, Phnom Penh indicates that Cambodia is able to profit from the West and China without fully aligning with one side.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Put differently, wouldn&#39;t Beijing prefer that Laos and Myanmar are more like Cambodia? Last November, the Global Times dubbed the China-Cambodia relationship “a model of regional cooperation at a time when the world is full of challenges”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there&#39;s something of a contradiction. In many ways, the China-Cambodia friendship is more transactional than Beijing&#39;s relations with other countries. There is no ideological bond between the two countries, unlike for Laos or Cuba, for instance. Phnom Penh isn&#39;t forced to make nice with Beijing to avoid conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hun Sen, Cambodia&#39;s prime minister since 1985, once called China “the root of everything that is evil” in Cambodia. His government came to power in 1979 by ousting the Beijing-backed Khmer Rouge regime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet it isn&#39;t the only authoritarian regime to forge closer relations with Beijing to offset criticism and rancour from Western democracies. And Hun Sen appears content with the Chinese partnership, especially after he was assured of new investment during his visit to Beijing to meet Xi Jinping in February. It also seems Xi gave the nod of approval for Hun Sen to hand over power to his eldest son, Hun Manet, in a dynastic succession.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what happens when Chinese investment streams into Cambodia start to dry up?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Phnom Penh could well turn around, thank Beijing for all the infrastructure it has built (such as US$2 billion Phnom Penh–Sihanoukville expressway), and then focus on re-engaging Western democracies, shipping its exports through the same roads and ports that China has funded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s far easier to imagine Cambodia becoming more evenly aligned with the United States, Japan and Europe (as it was during the 2000s and early 2010s) than it is to imagine the same for Laos or the Myanmar junta, or even other Chinese partners like Iran and Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite Washington&#39;s opprobrium at Phnom Penh&#39;s “ironclad friendship” with Beijing, Cambodia&#39;s trade in goods with the US grew from US$4.2 billion in 2018 to over US$12.6 billion last year. Indeed, Washington doesn&#39;t act as though it has “lost” Cambodia to China, even if that&#39;s what some in the US capital might think.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing ought also to be concerned about Cambodia&#39;s “hedging” with Vietnam, the ruling CPP&#39;s traditional patron. The Cambodia-China-Vietnam triangle of relations is little understood, but Hanoi has significantly increased investment in its western neighbour in recent years, and bilateral trade rose from US$3.8 billion in 2017 to over US$10.5 billion last year (compared to China-Cambodia trade of US$14.5 billion last year).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Phnom Penh&#39;s skylines are dominated by Chinese-built office buildings and condominiums, while coastal Sihanoukville is politely referred to as “new Shenzhen”, or less positively as a “Chinese colony”. Military relations are close. Before the Covid-19 pandemic, it seemed as though a contingent of Cambodian officials or ruling party-aligned associations was jetting off to Beijing for training each week. But China&#39;s influence in Cambodia is by no means monopolistic nor permanent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden picks China specialist for ambassador to Marshall Islands]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227372/biden-nominates-china-specialist-be-ambassador-strategic-marshall-islands?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/12/3a95ad07-4031-49e7-a3ef-57b2bd9c323c_259516dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden on Tuesday nominated a senior career diplomat to be US ambassador to the Marshall Islands, a strategic Pacific territory that has become a focus for competition with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nominee, Laura Stone, is currently deputy coordinator at the State Department&#39;s office of Covid-19 response and previously served as deputy assistant secretary for India, Nepal, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, Bhutan and Maldives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Chinese speaker, Stone also worked previously as coordinator of efforts to counter Chinese malign economic influence and as acting deputy assistant secretary for mainland China, Taiwan, Hong Kong and Mongolia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Marshall Islands is one of three Pacific island nations covered by so-called Compacts of Free Association (COFA) with Washington, under which the US retains responsibility for their defence and provides economic help, while gaining exclusive access to huge strategic swathes of the Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Renewing the pacts become a key part of US efforts to push back against China&#39;s bid to expand its influence in the Pacific, but according to regional news reports, a final deal with the Marshall Islands has been held up by disagreement over how to address the legacy of massive US nuclear testing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Chinese diplomats have been courting the region and China&#39;s construction and mining companies have expanded their business in Pacific island nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, the US said it had renewed COFA terms with Micronesia and Palau and its chief negotiator told Reuters then he hoped to finalise a deal with the Marshall Islands, whose COFA is due to expire this year, in coming weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Pacific region lags in LGBTQ rights despite Cook Islands ending gay sex ban&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under memorandums of understanding agreed this year, the US will commit a total of US$7.1 billion over 20 years to the three nations, subject to US Congressional approval.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marshall Islanders are still plagued by health and environmental effects of 67 US nuclear bomb tests from 1946 to 1958, which included “Castle Bravo” at Bikini Atoll in 1954 – the largest US bomb ever detonated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, more than 100 arms-control, environmental and other activist groups urged the Biden administration to formally apologise to the Marshall Islands and provide fair compensation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore man jailed for stealing police jacket had ‘fetishistic interest’ in uniforms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227348/singapore-man-jailed-stealing-police-jacket-had-fetishistic-interest-uniforms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/4123347e-edc3-4106-83e9-dc04f6b6d8a8_85d444cc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Upon noticing a police jacket on an unattended traffic officer&#39;s motorcycle parked along the road, a man in Singapore with a fetish for uniforms decided to grab the jacket and take off with it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam Seng Yip, 52, was sentenced to two weeks&#39; jail on Tuesday after pleading guilty to two charges of theft in December last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report from the Institute of Mental Health stated that Lam had been diagnosed with having “sadomasochistic and fetishistic interests amounting to a paraphilic disorder”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His “fetishistic interest” was mainly in the uniforms of various uniformed services such as the military or police, court documents stated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam had already been convicted in 2019 of stealing operational items from police and Aetos traffic marshalls and given a mandatory treatment order. Details of the order were not disclosed in court documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He stole the police jacket in a separate incident in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then in June 2022, Lam stole a police officer&#39;s operational bag from her unattended car as the officer attended a police matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 20, 2019, at around 9pm, a traffic police officer was attending to an accident at the junction of Buangkok Green Road and Yio Chu Kang Road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parking his motorcycle along the road in front of a block at Hougang Avenue 9, he then placed his traffic police jacket on top of his bike.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I come here to be myself&#39;: fetish parties never a drag at Tokyo&#39;s Department H&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lam was driving by and saw the motorcycle and unattended jacket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He returned to the scene about half an hour later and stopped his car along the road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam grabbed the jacket, which had a name tag and a sergeant rank epaulette. It was worth about S$140 (US$104), court documents stated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Noticing Lam behaving suspiciously, the traffic police officer chased him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Lam ran to his vehicle and drove off with the jacket. He later removed the name tag, rank and insignia from the jacket and threw them away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam was arrested the same day at around 11:30pm and the jacket was seized from him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly three years later, Lam stole a police bag from another police officer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 24, 2022, sometime around 11pm, he came across a police car parked in front of Block 171 at Woodlands Street 11.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The police officer had parked the car there and left to attend to a case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam noticed that the car&#39;s windows were wound down and that there was a bag on the back seat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He then grabbed the bag and “ran as far as he could from the incident location” before booking a private hire car to return home, court documents stated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bag contained items including a police vest and cap, as well as credit cards. The total value of the items was around S$383.20.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indonesian police probe bondage mummification claims against student&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lam was arrested the day after and the stolen items were recovered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy Public Prosecutor Ronnie Ang sought a sentence of six to eight weeks&#39; jail, noting that Lam was not a first-time offender and had committed similar offences before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, District Judge Kessler Soh imposed a lower sentence of two weeks&#39; jail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The judge said that he hoped that Lam would seek psychiatric treatment so that he does not repeat his offences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For each count of theft, Lam could have been jailed for up to three years, fined, or both.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published on .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Theranos co-founder Elizabeth Holmes on track for early release from 11-year jail sentence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227370/theranos-co-founder-elizabeth-holmes-track-early-release-11-year-jail-sentence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 06:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/12/0b699ee4-e3fe-4428-a997-4fdc19b6e541_87065aa7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Disgraced Theranos CEO Elizabeth Holmes has apparently behaved well enough during the first six weeks of her more than 11-year prison sentence for duping investors in her blood-testing hoax to be eligible for release nearly two years ahead of schedule, federal officials confirmed on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US Bureau of Prisons currently projects that Holmes, 39, will be released from a Bryan, Texas prison on December 29, 2032.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That would be 115 months, or slightly more than nine-and-a-half years, after she began her prison sentence of 11 years and three months imposed by US District Judge Edward Davila last November after her conviction on four counts of fraud and conspiracy following a high-profile trial in San Jose, California, that riveted Silicon Valley for months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Holmes&#39; prison sentence has not changed, but like all prisoners who follow the rules can qualify for an early release under the federal government&#39;s “good time” guidelines. Her projected release date – a few weeks before her 49th birthday – is in line with a prisoner serving her length of sentence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Davila sentenced Holmes, legal experts predicted she might be able to get out of federal prison in about nine years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bureau of Prisons declined to explain the specific reasons for Holmes&#39; projected release date, citing “privacy, safety, and security reasons” in a statement provided on Tuesday to Associated Press. “Every inmate earns good conduct time and is projected in their projected release date,” the statement pointed out.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Elizabeth Holmes enters prison to begin 11-year sentence for Theranos hoax&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Holmes&#39; former lover and top lieutenant at Theranos – Ramesh “Sunny” Balwani – is also on track for an early release from his nearly 13-year prison sentence after being convicted of 12 counts of fraud and conspiracy last year following a separate trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Balwani&#39;s projected release date is April 1, 2034, according to the Bureau of Prisons. That would be nearly 11 years after he began his sentence at a Southern California prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both Holmes and Balwani, 57, are hoping to get out even earlier as their lawyers pursue appeals seeking to overturn their respective convictions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although they had separate trials, Holmes and Balwani were accused of essentially the same crimes centred on a ruse touting Theranos&#39; blood-testing system as a breakthrough in healthcare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The claims helped the company become a Silicon Valley sensation that raised nearly US$1 billion from investors and at one point anointed Holmes with a US$4.5 billion fortune, based on her 50 per cent stake in Theranos.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ex-NBA player Enes Kanter Freedom, wife of jailed Chinese rights activist Cheng Yuan speak on US ‘corporate complicity’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3227371/ex-nba-player-enes-kanter-freedom-wife-jailed-chinese-rights-activist-cheng-yuan-speak-us-corporate?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 06:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/12/e5b1c918-5ba4-44b6-87fa-737c4f37a735_b2788f14.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The National Basketball Association will be invited to testify in front of members of the US Congress for playing a role in enabling China&#39;s human rights violations, Representative Chris Smith said at a hearing he chaired on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smith, a Republican of New Jersey, spoke at a hearing titled “Corporate Complicity: Subsidizing the PRC&#39;s Human Rights Violations” hosted by the Congressional-Executive Commission on China, a bipartisan panel that advises lawmakers and the executive branch on human rights and the rule of law in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the five witnesses on Tuesday was Enes Kanter Freedom, a former NBA player who claims he has been blacklisted after 11 years because of his outspokenness about the Chinese government&#39;s treatment of Tibetans and Uygurs. The NBA has rejected this characterisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Freedom, an American citizen born in Switzerland to Turkish parents, said he was criticised by Boston Celtics representatives and the NBA players union in 2021 for wearing shoes that read “Free Tibet” and “Free Uygur” during games.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, Tencent, which has exclusive streaming rights for NBA games in China, stopped streaming Celtics games online after Freedom, who was on the team, posted a video calling Chinese President Xi Jinping a “brutal dictator”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident followed a series of troubles for the NBA and its teams in China, starting in 2019 when then Houston Rockets general manager Daryl Morey tweeted his support for Hong Kong&#39;s protest movement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Freedom said on Tuesday that the league&#39;s response to his criticism of China was quite different from its “very supportive” stance when he criticised Turkey&#39;s human rights record.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi Minglei, the wife of jailed Chinese activist Cheng Yuan, spoke about another US-based company she said was complicit in Beijing&#39;s violations of human rights: Milwaukee Tool.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She described how inmates at Hunan province&#39;s Chishan prison, where her husband is held, were forced to make gloves for the brand under poor conditions, including long hours and being subject to punishment if they failed to meet quotas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Milwaukee Tool, which is owned by Hong Kong-based Techtronic Industries, has denied the allegations. Responding to charges in December 2022, the company said that “Milwaukee Tool does not tolerate the use of forced labor” and that “a thorough investigation of these claims was conducted, and we have found no evidence to support the claims being made.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese firms are concealing exports&#39; Xinjiang ties, say US customs officials&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Shi said that she hasn&#39;t seen Cheng since he was detained in 2019, but that he told family members in China during their visits that he had been subject to solitary confinement and forced to drink out of a toilet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although he has not specifically said that he has been working on gloves bearing the Milwaukee Tool logo, the mere chance that he might be should be intolerable to Americans,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smith said he had written to Milwaukee Tool raising his concerns about their alleged practices and to the NBA Players Association requesting that it help its members terminate contracts with Chinese sportswear companies. He added that both would be invited to testify before the commission, along with the NBA and apparel and equipment maker Nike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can&#39;t believe … the cowardice of the NBA in kowtowing to Xi Jinping and Company, the Chinese Communist Party. It just silenced every single player,” Smith said on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Robert Silvers, under secretary for policy at the Department of Homeland Security, said on Tuesday that the US government had “zero tolerance” for forced labour and that it was taking seriously concerns about “loopholes” in implementing the Uygur Forced Labour Prevention Act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Activists have frequently said that the “de minimis” customs provision enabling duty-free shipments for imports under $US800 may allow some companies to escape scrutiny, but the US government has maintained that de minimis shipments are scrutinised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The issue is that the government receives less information about those shipments, Silvers said, while requesting additional congressional funding to address such enforcement challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The act, which became law in 2021, created a “rebuttable presumption” that all goods partially or wholly produced in Xinjiang are tainted by forced labour and therefore ineligible for import.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Companies have the option to appeal if they can produce “clear and convincing evidence” that their supply chains are free of forced labour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Witnesses on Tuesday also pushed for greater disclosure requirements for American companies doing business in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isaac Stone Fish, founder of Strategy Risks, a consultancy on corporate exposure to China, said insurance premiums on deals in China need to be increased.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re not properly pricing the risk and the government has a role that it can play in that,” he said. “If you make it more expensive, through insurance for companies to make certain kinds of investments in China, it&#39;s going to change the math for them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fish said asking companies to testify would compel them to address concerns regarding their supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Companies are very afraid of being hauled in front of Congress to testify,” he said, adding that it “forces them to answer difficult questions”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese military tests evacuation skills to prepare for possible Taiwan conflict, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3227350/chinese-military-tests-evacuation-skills-prepare-possible-taiwan-conflict-analysts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/fa12cfdf-aab5-4cb9-962b-13e422a18a97_7c0ffc89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s military tested helicopters and drones in the rescue of wounded soldiers from islands in a first-of-its-kind drill carried out by the command responsible for overseeing the Taiwan Strait, according to state broadcaster CCTV.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exercise was conducted by the People&#39;s Liberation Army Eastern Theatre Command on an unidentified island off the east coast of Zhejiang province, CCTV&#39;s military channel reported on Monday. It is unclear when the exercises took place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The test, which used helicopters coordinated by land and air forces, focused on speeding up the evacuation of wounded soldiers from “medium- to long-distance islands” in both peace and wartime, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Military analysts said the exercise addressed a PLA vulnerability – evacuation skills – and was to prepare for possible military conflicts near coastal islands and in the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan&#39;s annual air-raid drills to simulate evacuations in event of PLA attack&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the report, a brigade of the Coastal Defence Force under the command took part in the drills. The brigade is stationed on coastal islands to the east of Zhejiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Due to geographical restrictions, medical evacuation of officers and soldiers is carried out over long distances and difficult,” said a video caption shown in the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Drones were used for reconnaissance and pinpointing the locations of the mock wounded soldiers in the exercise, according to the video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video showed the wounded were transported by a helicopter and transferred to a command hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In this medical and logistics exercise, we introduced air mobility forces for the first time, which greatly shortened the evacuation and treatment time for the wounded,” the report quoted Su Xingliang, director of the brigade&#39;s support department, as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Su said the exercise improved the medical treatment abilities of the coastal forces and future drills would involve working with local medical forces to ensure that every wounded person could be treated within the “golden rescue time”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yue Gang, a retired PLA colonel, said he believed the brigade involved in the exercise was responsible for overseeing the Zhoushan islands, an archipelago of many small islands off the northern coast of Zhejiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Rescue by helicopters is about exploring new medical treatments and overcoming obstacles such as sea transport that can be very time-consuming,” Yue said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted that a Z-8 helicopter with a range of 800km (497 miles) was used in the exercise, which could be deployed in military conflicts in the Taiwan Strait or over the disputed Diaoyu Islands, known as the Senkakus in Japan, which also claims them.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Xi&#39;s military visit &#39;highlights concern over US intervention over Taiwan&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Eastern Theatre Command oversees the Taiwan Strait and in a recent inspection tour to the command, Chinese President Xi Jinping ordered troops to stay vigilant about potential risks amid rising tensions in the waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Evacuation of wounded soldiers in the event of a possible military action against the island has been seen as a weak link in the PLA&#39;s logistics support, according to a report released last year by the China Maritime Studies Institute of the US Naval War College.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“PLA experts believe that [Chinese navy] medical evacuation assets are inadequate,” the report stated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Song Zhongping, a former PLA instructor, said the exercise was meant to improve military logistics, including rescue missions in island battles, “which of course include rescue missions for [our] military struggles over Taiwan”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>