<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Hope our love will not change’: Chinese woman, 23, surprises Taiwan singer Richie Ren at concert by thanking him for saving her life 22 years ago]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3222296/hope-our-love-will-not-change-chinese-woman-23-surprises-taiwan-singer-richie-ren-concert-thanking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/c18c0fb4-6e52-4662-b758-1002ccaf2ad9_2a503762.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个年轻女子感谢台湾歌手任贤齐捐款的感人故事22年前她的生活牵动着中国无数人的心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深受1980年代和90年代成长起来的人们喜爱的任正非在中国大陆仍然很受欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“悲伤的太平洋”、“太温柔”和“嘿，女孩这样看”等歌曲为许多人留下了回忆，他慷慨和积极的社会形象也确保了庞大的粉丝群。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他22 年前，他在前往中国东北辽宁省沉阳市参加一场音乐会的途中进行了捐赠，而在他 2023 年全国巡回演唱会期间，这一历史在同一座城市重演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在特别会议期间演唱会现场，歌迷可以点歌，一位年轻女子站起来说：“我今年23岁，但认识你22年了。小时候，您还把我抱在怀里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2001年，我刚一岁多的时候，患上了先天性心脏病。由于我的家庭经济状况不佳，我的生活岌岌可危。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你们在去沈阳演唱会的路上看到了我的新闻，慷慨地捐助了 3 万元人民币（4,200 美元），使我能够手术挽救了我的生命。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女孩随后点歌《不要改变》表达她最美好的祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望我们之间的爱永远改变，人与人之间的博爱和同情心也将保持不变，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被这个故事所吸引，任正非的粉丝们翻出了关于二十多年前捐赠的新闻报道，上面有照片和歌手的心声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要勇敢，记住我在等你，”任正非在女孩的救命手术前说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国，大约据MedSci报道，中国医学科学院阜外医院李守军教授称，每年有16万新生儿被诊断为先天性心脏病，这一数字一直在稳步上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;临床数据显示，大约如果不及时治疗，50% 的患者在三岁前死亡，60-70% 的患者活不过五岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事在大陆社交媒体上引发了大量感人的评论：“我很感动。这是善良和感恩的人之间的共同旅程，”一位说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位同意：“一方面，这是他不求回报的无私付出，另一方面，是女孩的生命得救，双双怀揣感恩之心。这是真爱。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人称赞任正非是一个真正的榜样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Richie真的是一个善良的人。我以前看过几篇关于他的类似新闻，其中一篇是他帮助父母找到了走失的孩子。帮助别人对他来说似乎是一件很自然的事情，”一位人士说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How much should Hong Kong pay for IVF treatments? Couples must weigh cost of test-tube babies as city reluctant to raise subsidies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222767/how-much-should-hong-kong-pay-ivf-treatments-couples-must-weigh-cost-test-tube-babies-city-reluctant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/b12b431e-c4b9-4e74-95ab-a277ddf927a1_ffb21543.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;42 岁的香港保险代理人 Flora Chan 已经数不清流产的次数自 2009 年结婚以来，她一直在怀孕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她多次自然受孕，但每次都在短至 5 周和长至 11 周内不幸结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年后2016 年，Chan 和她同样 42 岁的个体经营者丈夫在失望和沮丧中前往沙田威尔斯亲王医院寻求体外受精 (IVF) 治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了避免排长队，可能几个月后，她们选择接受私人服务的治疗，这意味着总共要支付大约 200,000 港元（25,528 美元），但流产仍在继续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后她求助于一位私人专家，该专家进行了测试结果发现基因异常，并在试管婴儿治疗的同时给她开了药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇花了 300,000 港元，但 Chan 终于怀孕并一路分娩。他们的儿子现在是一个健康的三岁孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 说，虽然她和她的丈夫可以负担得起试管婴儿治疗，但许多其他夫妇可能无法支付 50 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“资助这些治疗可能不会在一夜之间解决出生率问题，但肯定会在一定程度上有所帮助，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;浪费了 130,000 美元，她的身体被“毁坏”以避免将卵子冷冻香港&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;体外受精是治疗不孕症最常见的辅助生殖技术 (ART) 类型之一，是指从女性卵巢中取出卵子，与精子一起受精的一系列医疗程序&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港每年出生的婴儿数量在去年下滑至 32,500 的历史最低点，许多年轻女性和已婚夫妇推迟生育&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在联合国人口基金最近的一份报告中，这座城市的总生育率或 TFR（一名妇女预计生育的孩子数量）在世界上表现最差&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其得分为 0.8，紧随其后的是韩国 0.9、新加坡 1.0 和日本 1.3。 TFR 应该是 2.1 才能让人口自我更新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对不断下降的出生率，一些立法者呼吁政府扩大对不孕症治疗和卵子冷冻服务的补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;日本、新加坡、以色列和中国大陆已经增加了此类补贴，但尚未看到显着回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国研究发现，筛查技术可以提高试管婴儿活产率&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然香港当局和专家基本上认为提高补贴不会削弱出生率下降的趋势，许多人同意可以做更多工作来帮助寻求不孕症帮助的夫妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;理事会的数据《人类生殖科技》显示，2020年有超过4,600名香港妇女接受ART手术，其中约有1,630名婴儿出生，占当年活产的3.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年有超过6,000名婴儿出生大约有 2300 名婴儿出生，占当年活产的 4.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种治疗在 30 多岁的女性中更为常见，其次是 40 多岁及以上的女性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;全市只有三间公立医院为40岁以下需要转诊的已婚妇女提供资助试管受精服务，但资助的促排卵周期只有三个，每个周期约港币10,000元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么在香港，许多女性被剥夺了成为母亲的机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;患者在转诊后必须等待长达 12 个月才能进行生育力低下评估，然后再等 4 到 7 个月才能开始治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;不愿轮候或不合资格接受公营试管婴儿服务的人士，可求助私营机构，每次治疗至少需支付港币 80,000 元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;需要更多资源以缩短排队时间&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;30 岁出头的香港人 Carol Chan 于 2021 年在伊利沙伯医院终止了妊娠，因为她三个月的胎儿被发现患有重型地中海贫血，这是一种严重的遗传性血液病，危及母亲的生命。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 和她的丈夫都是这种疾病的携带者，IVF 是他们唯一的解决方案，因为可以在将胚胎转移到子宫之前对胚胎进行疾病筛查——这种疾病发生的几率为 25% .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她被转介到玛丽医院接受体外受精治疗。她在公立医院等了六个月，并支付了约40,000港元，但唯一通过筛查的胚胎并没有成功怀孕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们想立即开始另一个周期，但我们不得不多排几个月的队，会进一步耽误时间紧迫的治疗。”去年他们搬到加拿大后，健康的女婴在多伦多出生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对我们来说非常昂贵，”她说。 “以同样的价格，我本可以在公立医院多做几个周期，但我们不能再等了，因为我们即将移民。我们感谢玛丽医院的服务和照顾，但当然，需要更多资源来缩短排队时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前玛丽医院生殖医学科主任吴鸿宇教授Mary Hospital 表示，需要更多的工作人员和空间来进行咨询、胚胎孵化和咨询，以提高服务能力并缩短排队时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在公立医院增加一名医务人员可能意味着提供额外的 200 个周期的试管婴儿治疗一年，他说。但他认为，在私营部门补贴治疗的成本效益较低，因为那里的治疗费用更高，而且不能保证成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与其他程序不同，IVF 治疗可能需要多次尝试才能怀孕，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大学妇产科名誉临床副主任张丽萍医生同意公共部门需要更多资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这是一个private pain&#39;：准妈妈流产和&#39;失去的禁忌&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“但如果政府要补贴私营部门的 IVF 服务，患者应该接受适当的评估，最好在公立医院，以确保治疗是必要的并防止滥用，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她解释说，许多夫妇直接在私营部门进行试管受精，而一些不孕症病例可以通过药物治疗和...即使有足够数量的卵子，它们的质量也很可能较低，”她说。 “这意味着在实验室中成功受精和着床的几率较低，母亲流产的几率更高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不能生孩子吗？先检查男人——50% 的生育问题归咎于他们&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她补充说，40 岁以上的女性有 40% 到 50% 的流产几率，她们的孩子也有更高的风险患上唐氏综合症等疾病.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年，超过 430 名 40 岁以上的女性接受了冻融胚胎移植，这是一种常见的体外受精过程，其中卵子受精，胚胎被冷冻和储存，直到它们解冻并植入女性的子宫.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些女性中只有 106 人怀孕，而在这组女性中，有 79 人继续分娩，几乎五分之二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 40 岁以上的女性中，在没有冷冻的情况下进行新鲜周期 IVF胚胎解冻后，只有不到 3% 的人继续怀孕，不到 2% 的人分娩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学 (HKU) 公共卫生学院院长 David Bishai 教授)，也是一名试管婴儿的父亲，表示监管保险政策是政府可以解决的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前香港的大部分保险产品并不涵盖ART程序的费用。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“不涵盖 ART 的健康保险单是有缺陷的产品，”Bishai 说。 “保险中基本福利包的规定必须来自政府，并且应包括经批准的技术，以帮助家庭应对意外的医疗困难。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;如果你想要孩子，请提前计划&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;为响应立法者关于建立集中式卵子银行和补贴更多试管受精治疗的呼吁，卫生局局长罗仲茂本月早些时候表示，大多数计划生育夫妇并不关心此类服务。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“生不生是个人的选择，政府不应该干预，但政府会努力提供家庭友好型政策，为生育营造支持性的环境，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;我的孩子还活着吗？”：夫妇在胚胎混合抚养陌生人的儿子得到 93,000 美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在公共医疗系统中分配资源时，重要的是要在提供辅助生殖服务和其他服务之间找到平衡点挽救生命的医疗服务，尤其是私营部门无法获得或可能更昂贵的服务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;港大人口专家叶兆辉同意，ART 无法扭转局面出生趋势下降，表明新加坡和以色列的失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“附带收益很小，与成本不成比例，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，政府&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生殖医学专家梁家康医生表示，准备结婚的夫妇和新婚夫妇应及早定期进行生育测试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;那些发现生育能力下降迹象的人可以决定是早点生孩子还是冷冻卵子和精子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说政府可以为此类检查发放代金券，并扩大计划生育协会婚前和孕前检查的服务能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这很伤脑筋但很值得”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;立法会议员 Nixie Lam Lam，41 岁，8 岁怀有试管婴儿几个月的她说，应该做更多的工作来让女性了解自己的生殖健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在成长过程中经历过严重的痛经，但直到 2019 年，她才准备怀孕后，她发现自己的子宫受到了影响，后来导致 4 年内发生了 3 次流产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam 和她的丈夫，一位 34 岁的私人投资者，随后求助于 IVF .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很多香港女性直到30岁才关心自己的生殖健康，”她说。 “政府应该补贴 20 多岁女性的相关检查，例如子宫颈抹片检查和盆腔超声检查，以便尽早发现问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频创作者 Sona Ng So-na，33 岁，是一个两岁孩子的母亲老试管婴儿女孩，回忆起自己的怀孕是一次“伤脑筋”的经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;嫁给了一个32岁的商人，在经历了三次流产后，她于2020年寻求试管婴儿治疗。尽管第一次尝试就怀孕了，但在最初的几个月里，她的阴道出现了很多斑点，医生开了黄体酮激素注射剂、药丸和栓剂来维持婴儿的健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我每天醒来都希望有时间会过得更快，”她说，“每天打针，我的肚子上布满瘀伤，有时拔出针头时满是血，非常可怕。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不知道谁打过在接受试管婴儿治疗后，她努力获取信息来回答她的许多问题。她希望卫生当局可以做更多的工作来教育和提高认识，例如建立一个问答网页。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她所经历的孤独感也促使她建立了一个社交媒体社区，聚集了数百名母亲准备接受试管婴儿治疗，希望提供一个相互支持和信息交流的平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但与生育相比，整个试管婴儿过程的挑战不值一提，”她说。 “如果一个人只是受到父母的压力，或者对孩子没有感情，就不应该尝试试管受精。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，最后，有了孩子，Ng 和她的丈夫觉得这一切都是值得的，他们正在为今年晚些时候的第二个 IVF 婴儿制定计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们非常爱孩子，而且我们从未如此快乐，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UN agency warns there is no let-up in drugs trade from Asia’s Golden Triangle]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222821/un-agency-warns-there-no-let-drugs-trade-asias-golden-triangle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/799ca103-e747-4c87-8bc1-2d62210da400_88fcb5ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;来自东南一个小角落的巨额冰毒等非法毒品交易联合国毒品和犯罪问题办公室周五警告说，亚洲没有放缓的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该地区继续生产和贩运大量甲基苯丙胺，同时生产氯胺酮和其他合成药物该机构的 2023 年报告《东亚和东南亚的合成毒品——自 Covid-19 大流行后边界重新开放以来的第一份报告》说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告显示了犯罪集团重新建立的模式自己处于大流行前阶段，并显着改变了贩运路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以片剂和冰毒形式存在的甲基苯丙胺的大部分来自被称为金三角的地区，该地区与缅甸、老挝和泰国相遇。鸦片和海洛因的生产曾经在那里蓬勃发展，主要是因为缅甸偏远的东部掸邦周围无法无天。该地区大部分是丛林，仍然是各种少数民族民兵的领地，其中一些是毒品交易的合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“甲基苯丙胺仍然是东亚和东南亚最常用的药物，并且使用在过去十年中有所增加，”报告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国寺庙在所有僧侣都未通过药检后空无一人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;工业规模生产也比劳动力更容易-鸦片的密集种植，从中提取海洛因。然后，毒品通过陆路、海上和空中在亚洲和太平洋各地分发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，主要有组织犯罪集团对领土的控制“使他们能够大规模增加和多样化供应市场扩张和支配的目的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最强大的区域贩运网络能够高度确定地运作，他们可以而且不会被阻止，并且他们能够规定条款和条件”它说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的十年里，东亚和东南亚几乎每年都有创纪录的甲基苯丙胺缉获量，但最新数据表明，缉获的毒品总量在 2022 年有所下降根据报告，减少到 151 吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;缉获量下降通常与生产减弱有关，但报告称“其他指标——逮捕、街头供应、纯度、创纪录的低批发和街头价格，以及接受治疗的人数——表明供应量仍然很高或没有变化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毒品和犯罪问题办公室东南亚和太平洋区域代表杰里米·道格拉斯周五在曼谷举行的新闻发布会上特别指出，缅甸掸邦的局势尽管这里是“亚太地区的生产中心”，但过去一年毒品缉获量空前下降，这让他“非常担忧”，他说这与该地区的冲突和不稳定直接相关。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;该报告表明，缉获量总体下降是由于贩运者将走私路线从陆路改为海路以逃避当局，并解释说货物是从缅甸沿海地区通过海路运输的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国最近取得了两项重大进展预计将通过海运运往第三国的冰毒半身像。周二，在泰国湾沿岸查获了近一吨毒品，泰国当局怀疑这些毒品正准备在国际水域装载到一艘更大的船上。泰国当局表示，在最近的几次突击行动中查获的毒品据称运往澳大利亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“走私者去年比前一年更成功，他们主要能够连接到市场Douglas 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国办事处还对柬埔寨已经成为“一个重要的过境点，在某种程度上是该地区的生产点”表示担忧毒品贸易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这表明，尽管金三角的合成毒品生产得到了整合，但这种发展可能反映出“生产的某种多样化和有组织犯罪的‘对冲’。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;它说，在柬埔寨各地发现了工业规模的氯胺酮实验室以及加工和储存该物质的设施，引起了整个地区的严重关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有组织的犯罪集团采用了供应驱动的市场扩张方式类似于 2015 年开始在该地区扩大甲基苯丙胺市场的方法，”该报告警告说，氯胺酮作为麻醉剂具有合法用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内陆老挝，靠近报告称，掸邦和泰国北部的毒品交易是打击毒品交易的另一个薄弱环节，“情报官员得出的结论是，毒品正在通过该国时几乎没有阻力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，除了成为毒品走私出境日趋重要的途径外，近年来缅甸也发现了冰毒片生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报道称，掸邦实验室生产的冰毒和其他毒品通常从“主要非国家武装团体控制或影响”的港口穿过湄公河进入老挝，“以及他们与跨国有组织犯罪集团合作的盟友。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老挝的案例也说明了阻止生产药物所需的成分进入非法实验室的困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据报道，老挝正成为缅甸毒品生产中使用的化学品的一条越来越重要的路线，这些化学品通过越南、泰国和中国进入该国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“阻断化学品流入缅甸的努力毒品产区也继续受到机构间协调缓慢和官僚作风、资源和人员不足以及跨境合作有限的阻碍，”报告说，贩毒者正在寻找获得供应的替代方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;制造甲基苯丙胺所需的主要化学品通常受到严格的国际控制，因此近年来非法实验室已开始使用不受严格监管的化学品。该报告称，在线订购也加快了获取此类化学品的物流，尤其是来自愿意掩饰交易性质的供应商。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shangri-La Dialogue: US defence chief Lloyd Austin doubles down on security alliance push]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3222826/shangri-la-dialogue-us-defence-chief-lloyd-austin-doubles-down-security-alliance-push?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/4099efc9-c881-48e0-b066-1e9e2cb6d500_ef316a92.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国防部长劳埃德奥斯汀强调美国决心加强在亚洲的联盟和伙伴关系- 太平洋周六上午在新加坡举行的重要安全峰会上发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强调没有恐吓、欺凌或胁迫的余地，他说美国正在加倍努力加强其安全联盟和伙伴关系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的共同目标很明确：阻止侵略并深化促进繁荣和防止冲突的规则和规范，”他在香格里拉对话会上说，香格里拉对话是由美国举办的为期三天的防务峰会国际战略研究所智库。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他向数百名官员和分析人士发表的演讲重点是美国对亚太地区热点问题的看法，特别是台湾和南海问题，华盛顿指责北京使用武力——有时违反国际法——将其地缘政治利益强加给该地区的其他国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着北京和华盛顿在台湾问题上发生冲突，在先进武器开发和为了在南海和其他地方进行近距离接触，美国已将资金转移到其亚洲盟友和合作伙伴以增强其防御能力，并与该地区的武装部队举行联合演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以我们正在加强与我们的朋友的规划、协调和训练，从东海到南海再到印度洋，”奥斯汀说。 “这包括澳大利亚、日本、大韩民国、菲律宾和泰国等坚定的盟友。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国加强了威慑以防止冲突，并支持“保护我们所有人”的规则和规范，他&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多内容……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 10 月份发布的国家安全战略中，美国将中国描述为唯一有意和有能力重塑国际秩序的竞争对手，使其变得更加强大。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样从 10 月开始的五角大楼国防战略表示，美国军方将重点努力阻止中国对美国利益的“侵略”，并“在威慑失败时在冲突中获胜” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京经常批评将美中关系定性为竞争，并指责美国对其在亚太地区的盟友体系进行遏制。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI, post-Covid work from home culture will reverse slump in world PC sales, Acer CEO says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3222770/ai-post-covid-work-home-culture-will-reverse-slump-world-pc-sales-acer-ceo-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/b87f40ac-f85b-4272-83b3-8186f924cafd_076f668a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;居家文化和单价上涨的冠状病毒后工作将阻止长期低迷这家全球第六大供应商的负责人本周在台北电脑展期间表示，消费者信心疲软导致 PC 销量下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;笔记本电脑和台式机的销量在过去 12 个月下降，原因是通货膨胀和台湾硬件和电子公司宏碁董事长兼首席执行官 Jason Chen 周三对邮报表示，利率综合影响了消费者信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在大流行期间远程工作和个人电脑购买量激增Chen 说，在家学习意味着在下一个所谓的更新周期中需要更换比以前更多的机器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更新周期通常是指企业每三到五年更换一次硬件和软件。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“从宏观层面来看，通货膨胀引发了利率，利率引发了消费者信心[减弱]，正因为如此，终端用户需求在大约四个季度前发生了剧烈变化，” 2014 年被任命为首席执行官的 61 岁的陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中央银行收紧货币政策以对抗通货膨胀，利率上升，去年由于能源价格上涨，全球大部分地区的通货膨胀率都在上升&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen 补充说，尽管 Covid-19 控制已经结束，但在家工作并没有消失的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说在家远程工作和学习期间大流行意味着每个家庭成员都拥有一台 PC，而不是共享一台。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;哇，多好的景色！皮尤研究中心 (Pew Research Center) 在 3 月份发布的一项调查中表示，中国的“数字游牧民”在加班的同时寻求天堂&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;大约三分之一的工作可以远程进行的工人在家工作。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“当我们谈论更新周期时，由于安装基础更大，所需的数量会更高，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会计和人力资源等领域，“人们已经习惯了这一点工作模式，很难让他们回来，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，消费者已经开始购买 PC 配件，例如扩展坞和不同种类的连接器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PC根据市场研究公司 Gartner 的数据，去年供应商的出货量达到 2.862 亿台，比 2021 年下降 16.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年前三个月的出货量仅为 5520 万台，相当于 30%与 2022 年第一季度相比下降了 %，Gartner 将其描述为“由于经济不确定性导致供过于求和 PC 需求持续低迷的不利组合”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宏基在第一季度售出了 352.3 万台，根据Gartner。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen 说，PC 平均销售价格的上涨势必会增加整体销售收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消费者通常愿意为具有强大计算能力的 PC 和由回收材料制成的零件支付更多费用材料，他补充说，PC 游戏市场已经“下降较少”，他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在未来几年，对 ChatGPT 等生成聊天机器人的需求将推动对最新型号 PC 的购买，Chen说，因为手机由于没有键盘和小屏幕而不适合使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生成式 AI 将变得更加流行，人们将把它用于生产目的，”曾工作 14 年的 Chen 说在英特尔工作，在台积电工作八年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen 表示，印度和印度尼西亚的个人电脑数量也越来越多，因为新兴制造业雇用了相对较多的年轻人口。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;下一个巴厘岛？台湾市试图在人才短缺的情况下吸引远程工作者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;市场研究公司 IDC 将计划在这两个国家扩大销售和营销的宏碁评为印度第四大供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Chen 表示，Chromebook 的订单也在增加，这是对全球 PC 销售的另一个推动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acer 等品牌与 Google 一起生产轻型笔记本电脑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的学区陈说，美国和欧洲正在下订单，宏基正在与印度和日本讨论销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ticking time bomb: just how widespread are Hong Kong’s undetected illegal property renovations?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222506/ticking-time-bomb-just-how-widespread-are-hong-kongs-undetected-illegal-property-renovations?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/bd639b10-6bc1-44f2-96fc-3642dbd0b6a7_19d5aa49.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;纸牌屋。一些将军澳日出康城的居民，发现有单位业主非法改装承重墙时，可能会有这种感觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发现结构墙已被部分拆除的是敏锐的观众在翻新公寓的视频中制作的。如果它没有被上传到一个拥有超过 30,000 名订阅者的与财产相关的频道（视频已被撤下），非法修改很可能一直隐藏起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这提出了一个观点——究竟有多少在仍然是世界上最昂贵的房地产市场之一的房地产市场中，还有其他类似的折衷公寓吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的公寓不仅昂贵，而且 59% 的私人住宅楼龄超过 30 年。 A Legislative Council report found that, at the end of 2019, many of the roughly 35,700 residential buildings were approaching the end of their 50-year working life. A fifth had been built in 1969 or earlier, and another 39 per cent were 30-49 years old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ageing flats are a concern as any permanent structural damage affects safety. Other factors such as property valuation and the determination of mortgages and insurance premiums are also affected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compromised load-bearing walls will shift the burden to other walls. Overloaded walls can fail, causing building damage. It is only a matter of time before structural failure happens – making it a ticking time bomb. The 2010 To Kwa Wan building collapse at Ma Tau Wai Road is a stern reminder that illegal modifications have serious ramifications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With such devastating consequences, the elephant in the room is the absence of a mechanism to detect such modifications. Owners are unlikely to report their own illegal work and the problem may never surface until it becomes too late to rectify. Some offenders may wrongly believe that, since the building has not collapsed, it probably never will.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most Hongkongers spend their life savings just to be able to afford a home. Often, this will be in multistorey building where owners and tenants have to depend on one other to comply with the law and deploy common sense. Like the Chinese saying, when everyone is on the same boat, we don&#39;t start drilling holes in it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But common sense is not always common. On a recent flight, while the seat belt sign was on, I counted no less than six passengers getting up to go to the toilet despite in-flight announcements to remain seated. Staying in place when the seat-belt sign is on is for the safety of all passengers. Only half were stopped while the others simply ignored the attendants and rushed into the toilets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While only a very small minority did this, the point is that it only takes one person to compromise the structural integrity of an entire building. Take the example of a recent flight in South Korea, when one person opened an emergency exit door mid-air and endangered all other passengers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If people cannot even be trusted to respect straightforward safety rules that are enforced in plain view, trusting everyone in the privacy of their own homes to respect all the building rules may be a little optimistic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Lohas Park incident, the different parties involved – at the very least, the homeowner, interior designer and renovation workers – had all failed to point out the significance of a load-bearing wall before commencing demolition work. Even after alterations, staff involved in filming the modifications did not realise the detrimental effect, despite including the original and amended floor plans in the video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not all is lost, however. There is a legal framework to deal with the high-density nature of homes, such as providing for the formation of an incorporated owners&#39; committee for building management and a deed of mutual covenant to set out the rights and obligations of a building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Owners planning alteration works on their flats are required to ensure they comply with the Buildings Ordinance and its subsidiary legislation. But this provides little comfort next to the question I posed at the beginning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If no one is able to detect these illegal modifications, could we all be living in a ticking time bomb? If using such strong words can raise awareness to prevent these illegal alterations from recurring, it will be worth it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden says ‘crisis averted’ as he celebrates debt ceiling deal in first Oval Office address]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222825/joe-biden-says-crisis-averted-he-celebrates-debt-ceiling-deal-first-oval-office-address?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 07:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/7b8a96b4-a1f1-47ef-999a-a0f35732bd7e_7c488b37.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;President Joe Biden celebrated a “crisis averted” in his inaugural speech to the nation from the Oval Office Friday evening, ready to sign a budget agreement that eliminates the potential for a first-ever government default that would have sent shock waves through the US and global economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bipartisan measure was approved by the Senate late Thursday night after passing the House in yet another late session the night before. Biden is set to sign it at the White House on Saturday with just two days to spare until the Treasury Department has warned the US would not be able to meet its obligations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement was hashed out by Biden and House Speaker Kevin McCarthy, giving Republicans some of their demanded federal spending cuts but holding the line on major Democratic priorities. It raises the debt limit until 2025 – after the 2024 presidential election – and gives legislators budget targets for the next two years, in hopes of assuring fiscal stability as the political season heats up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No one got everything they wanted but the American people got what they needed,” Biden said, highlighting the “compromise and consensus” in the deal. “We averted an economic crisis and an economic collapse.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re cutting spending and bringing deficits down at the same time,” Biden said. “We&#39;re protecting important priorities from Social Security to Medicare to Medicaid to veterans to our transformational investments in infrastructure and clean energy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s remarks were the most detailed comments from the Democratic president on the compromise he and his staff negotiated. He largely remained quiet publicly during the high-stakes talks, a decision that frustrated some members of his party but was intended to give space for both sides to reach a deal and for lawmakers to vote it to his desk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Passing this budget agreement was critical,” Biden was to say. “The stakes could not have been higher.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said on Friday that Biden was using the occasion to deliver his first address to the nation from behind the Resolute Desk in the Oval Office because “he just wanted to make sure that the American people understood how important it was to get this done, how important it was to do this in a bipartisan way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;McCarthy&#39;s moment: US debt win secures House speaker&#39;s standing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Biden praised McCarthy and his negotiators for operating in good faith, and all congressional leaders for ensuring swift passage of the legislation. “They acted responsibly, and put the good of the country ahead of politics,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, the 99-page bill restricts spending for the next two years and changes some policies, including imposing new work requirements for older Americans receiving food aid and greenlighting an Appalachian natural gas pipeline that many Democrats oppose. Some environmental rules were modified to help streamline approvals for infrastructure and energy projects – a move long sought by moderates in Congress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Congressional Budget Office estimates it could actually expand total eligibility for federal food assistance, with the elimination of work requirements for veterans, homeless people and young people leaving foster care.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The legislation also bolsters funds for defence and veterans, cuts back some new money for Internal Revenue Service and rejects Biden&#39;s call to roll back Trump-era tax breaks on corporations and the wealthy to help cover the nation&#39;s deficits. But the White House said the IRS&#39; plans to step up enforcement of tax laws for high-income earners and corporations would continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement also imposes an automatic overall 1 per cent cut to spending programmes if Congress fails approve its annual spending bills – a measure designed to pressure lawmakers of both parties to reach consensus before the end of the financial year in September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In both chambers, more Democrats backed the legislation than Republicans, but both parties were critical to its passage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Senate the tally was 63-36 including 46 Democrats and independents and 17 Republicans in favour, 31 Republicans along with four Democrats and one independent who caucuses with the Democrats opposed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vote in the House was 314-117.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI sector a bright spot in tough jobs market for China’s graduates, as ChatGPT frenzy spurs new employer demand]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3222811/ai-sector-bright-spot-tough-jobs-market-chinas-graduates-chatgpt-frenzy-spurs-new-employer-demand?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/7fecab30-8d11-4dac-8cd4-6d694131a28a_8827b31d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A surge in the number of job offers in China&#39;s artificial intelligence (AI) sector for college graduates has become one of the few bright spots in an otherwise bleak jobs market, according to a report by a local recruitment platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China&#39;s youth jobless rate has hit a new high and with conditions mostly tough for the country&#39;s 11.6 million fresh graduates, those with degrees related to large language models (LLMs), the AI technology behind the rise of Microsoft-backed OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT, are in short supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this space, the number of related job openings has surged 172.5 per cent from a year earlier, according to Liepin&#39;s 2023 employment report for Chinese university graduates.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Province rolls out 100-day plan to help China&#39;s anxious graduates &#39;land a job&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;San Francisco-based OpenAI launched its conversational bot ChatGPT last autumn, setting off a global AI arms race, with Chinese Big Tech firms rushing to launch similar services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A local headhunter said earlier that the explosion in demand for AI jobs started a while ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since late last year, we have been getting increased inquiries from local tech firms looking for talent working in LLMs and AI-generated content, and some are willing to offer fat pay cheques,” Max Xiao Mafeng, co-founder and CEO at recruitment agency TTC Consultancy, told the Post in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roles involving algorithms, deep learning, and natural language processing (NLP) – all critical to developing ChatGPT-like services – are among the most popular jobs in the LLM area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A student who majored in NLP at the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China – located in Chengdu, capital city of Sichuan province – said in a Thursday post to career-focused social networking site Maimai that he has already landed five offers from companies including Meituan, Shein, Xiaomi, battery marker CATL and logistics giant SF Express.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apart from AI, employment opportunities in the new energy and new materials sectors saw 93.9 per cent and 30 per cent year-on-year increases respectively, making them the second- and third-fastest growing sectors for job increases among the 18 emerging areas Liepin analysed in the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s expected 11.6 million college graduates this year – a record – comes at a time when the country&#39;s youth unemployment rate for those aged between 16 and 24 has also hit a record high, reaching more than 20 per cent in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 60 per cent of students surveyed in the Liepin report have not secured a job offer yet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, despite a much tougher regulatory environment in recent years that has seen thousands of lay-offs, the country&#39;s Big Tech firms are still the top choice among elite school graduates in China. Overseas returnees had a preference for multinationals, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, Chinese graduates expressed an increasing preference for job security over other factors, with employment in state-owned enterprises (SOEs) and governmental agencies top choices. Nearly half, or 45 per cent of students, wanted to work at SOEs, versus almost 27 per cent for governmental agencies, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Police attack on reporter sparks rare public debate, outrage in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3222716/police-attack-reporter-sparks-rare-public-debate-outrage-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/73514918-8d42-4787-b139-9210eaac3cba_20db83c8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The assault of a Chinese reporter by three police officers over his investigation into the deaths of two teachers has sparked a heated and rare public debate about the hostility and heavy restrictions faced by journalists in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The officers were suspended and detained for allegedly beating the reporter, surnamed Li, from the online outlet Jimu News, according to a statement issued on Thursday by the Bijie municipal government in the southern province of Guizhou.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement failed to quell the concerns of China&#39;s online community, with more than 5 million views of the attack by Friday. A number of state media outlets have also condemned brutality against journalists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li was assaulted on May 23 in Guizhou after arriving from Hubei province to follow up his earlier reporting on the teachers, who drowned in a local river after a sudden discharge by a power station upstream. Authorities are still investigating the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a widely circulated social media posting Xu Jiangqiao, an editor for Jimu News – which is affiliated to Hubei Daily – said “we stand firm to defend the rights of reporters and demand justice [for Li]”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For the Bijie [municipal government] in Guizhou, it&#39;s important to give us reporters and the public an account [of the incident], make public the identity of the attackers and any persons who instigated the attack,” Xu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese authorities sack, detain 3 police officers after reporter beating&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;State news agency China News Service also condemned the assault, saying in a commentary that it was “a blatant violation to journalists&#39; normal duties of supervision [of officials] through public opinion”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;one Weibo user wrote: “Why did the police officers follow the reporter? Who gave the order? This is the key!” Another said: “We should support the reporter and not let reporters covering social news feel frightened and disappointed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhan Jiang, a retired professor with Beijing Foreign Studies University who closely tracks China&#39;s media issues, said the industry had faced growing hostility in recent years, with an increase in censorship and violence against reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The media environment] is at a stage of suffocation. It&#39;s not that the supervision role of media has vanished but it is true that it has been greatly reduced,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Most investigative reporters have left the industry, especially those who specialise in &#39;hard core&#39; topics, and those who have stayed face huge difficulties in their reporting.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s already the epilogue&#39;: censorship, cost-cutting hit China&#39;s media industry&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One challenge – highlighted by Li&#39;s case – is a ban on local media from reporting on “negative issues”, which has prompted investigative journalists to cover stories in other provinces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Reporters are basically not allowed to report on local negative news … the governments cannot control media from other places – especially from other provinces – so this kind of incident happens if local officials feel offended,” Zhan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, several journalists were beaten and barred from reporting in Henan province, central China, after travelling there from Chengdu, Beijing and Chongqing to report on the deaths of several children who were found buried in an illegal construction site.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lethal illegal building works in China can&#39;t be torn down fast enough&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chu Chaoxin, a former reporter for Southern Weekly, was surprised that the latest incident had drawn such attention and public support for the reporter. “The media environment is not good, but it has received so much attention and that is unexpected to me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu said there were reporters who still strove for media freedom, despite the hostility and challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Media control has tightened since 2016, when Chinese President Xi Jinping ordered Communist Party outlets to toe the party&#39;s line on all major issues. In a high-profile visit to newsrooms, Xi said all reporting and commentaries should follow “the right direction”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s top party mouthpieces pledge &#39;absolute loyalty&#39; as president makes rare visits to newsrooms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to Zhan, the harassment of journalists also reflected the pressure on local governments to maintain social stability above all else. Under such a mentality, the space for media could further diminish, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi warned on Tuesday that China was facing more complex and difficult national security concerns. Chairing a meeting of the National Security Commission, he urged officials to be ready to face the challenges of “high winds and waves and even perilous storms”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China sits in 179th place on the Reporters Without Borders index – one spot above North Korea. The press freedom NGO describes China as “the world&#39;s largest prison” for journalists, with regular campaigns of repression against journalism and the right to information worldwide.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-Australia trade: what’s the state of relations after 3 years of ups and downs?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3222743/china-australia-trade-whats-state-relations-after-3-years-ups-and-downs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 04:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/d79e27d0-733c-4312-bb6a-db3f8eae6d8f_7448c6ce.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After no in-person talks since 2019, the trade ministers from China and Australia met twice in May, highlighting how relations between Beijing and Canberra continue to thaw after years of frosty diplomatic wrangling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australian Minister for Trade and Tourism Don Farrell first travelled to Beijing for a meeting with Chinese counterpart Wang Wentao on May 12 before the pair reunited in the US city of Detroit during an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (Apec) meeting later in the month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations between China and Australia turned sour in 2020 after the then-Morrison administration asked for a probe into the origin of the coronavirus with other world leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing responded with unofficial bans on Australian products, including lobsters, coal, cotton and logs, while it also imposed official import tariffs on wine and barley.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations have since improved, starting with a meeting between President Xi Jinping and new Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in November on the sidelines of the G20 meeting in Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what is the state of play in relations between Australia and its largest trading partner?&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China officially imposed duties of between 116.2 per cent and 218.4 per cent on Australian wines in containers of up to two litres in March 2021 after concluding anti-dumping investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The duties – higher than the preliminary tariffs – were due to be applied for five years, after the Chinese commerce ministry reiterated a decision made in November 2020 that the domestic wine industry had been hurt by the dumping of cheap Australian wine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canberra lodged a formal complaint with the World Trade Organization (WTO) over China&#39;s imposition of anti-dumping duties on Australian wine exports in June 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is believed that Australia has asked for the tariffs on wine to be removed in full, or returned to the previous pre-sanction levels, before Australia will drop its WTO investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In October, Wine Australia said Australian wine exports to China plunged by 92 per cent to A$21 million (US$13 million) in the year ended September 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s commerce ministry said in mid-April that it would review the necessity of continuing to impose anti-dumping and anti-subsidy tariffs on imported Australian barley, with the survey to be completed within a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Days before, Australian foreign minister Penny Wong said Australia would suspend its WTO case after China&#39;s tariffs of 80.5 per cent on Australian barley all but wiped out imports of the grain by the world&#39;s biggest beer market. Australia submitted its formal complaint to the WTO in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the start of June, Farrell said that China&#39;s review into the tariffs was heading in the “right direction” and that the process was “close to completed”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the tariffs, trade had ranged between A$1.5 billion (US$1 billion) and A$2 billion a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Australian lobsters were caught up in the unofficial bans after Canberra called for an international inquiry into the origin of Covid-19 in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since November 2020, legal imports of live Australian rock lobsters into China have fallen to virtually zero.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, before the ban was put in place, more than 90 per cent of Australian rock lobsters were exported to China, and figures from the Australian agriculture department showed that the market was worth about A$750 million (US$517 million) a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia has diversified lobster exports to Hong Kong and Vietnam, though some have entered the Chinese market via grey channels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was reported in early 2023 that China was discussing customs clearance for Australian lobsters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Coal was another commodity caught up in the unofficial bans after Canberra called for an international inquiry into the origin of Covid-19 in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March 2020 – before China&#39;s unofficial ban on Australian coal – imports of coking coal had reached 4.36 million tonnes, while 5.65 million tonnes of thermal coal entered the Chinese market, according to official data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s state planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, was reported to have held talks with four state-owned importers in January this year over a partial lifting of the verbal ban on Australian thermal and coking coal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, China&#39;s coking coal purchase from Australia quadrupled from the previous month, while thermal coal imports rose fourteenfold.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Once the biggest market for Australian cotton, the A$900 million (US$621 million) trade ground to a halt in late 2020 after China imposed a series of official and unofficial restrictions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China imported 20,000 tonnes of Australian cotton in 2022, compared with 400,000 in 2019, according to Chinese customs data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was reported in February this year that Chinese buyers were buying up Australian cotton, and that it was being shipped to a bonded warehouse in Qingdao and possibly one other location.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s foreign minister to visit Australia in July for &#39;reciprocal visit&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chinese ambassador Xiao Qian said in May – days after Australian trade minister Farrell returned from a trip to Beijing – that China would resume imports of Australian timber.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The once A$600 million (US$399 million) annual timber trade with China had been largely suspended since late 2020 after Beijing said it had found pests in shipments coming from several Australian ports.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Post reported in May that China&#39;s foreign minister, Qin Gang, may visit Australia in July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The expected trip to Canberra would follow a meeting between Australian foreign minister Wong and Qin&#39;s predecessor, Wang Yi, in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang also accepted an invitation from Farrell to visit Australia, during their meeting in Beijing in May.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russian forces tried to blow up my men, Wagner boss Yevgeny Prigozhin says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222824/russian-forces-tried-blow-my-men-wagner-boss-yevgeny-prigozhin-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 03:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/e0ddda5a-cc88-4381-b277-971c08d12917_d54724d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russian mercenary boss Yevgeny Prigozhin, who has been arguing with top military brass for months, on Friday escalated the feud by accusing pro-Moscow forces of trying to blow up his men.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin&#39;s Wagner Group troops have largely pulled back from the eastern Ukrainian town of Bakhmut, most of which they captured last month after taking heavy casualties, and handed over their positions to regular Russian forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin, writing on Telegram, said his men had discovered a dozen locations in rear areas where defence ministry officials had planted various explosive devices, including hundreds of anti-tank mines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When asked why the charges had been set, the officials indicated it was an order from their superiors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was not necessary to plant these charges in order to deter the enemy, as it [the area in question] is in the rear area. Therefore, we can assume that these charges were intended to meet the advancing units of Wagner,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;None of the charges went off and no one was hurt, he said, adding: “We assume this was an attempt at a public flogging.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russia&#39;s Wagner boss says 20,000 of his troops died in Bakhmut&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s defence ministry was not immediately available for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin, who regularly complained his men were not given enough ammunition for the assault on Bakhmut, said on Wednesday that he had asked prosecutors to investigate whether senior Russian defence officials had committed any “crime” before or during the war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>