<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s missing hikers spotlight lacklustre efforts at locating foreigners]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3229497/japans-missing-hikers-spotlight-lacklustre-efforts-locating-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/293075f5-a453-4a00-a28b-3c094faa9caf_1ee73bcb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名法国妇女在日本徒步旅行中失踪五年后，她的家人回来了法国的家再次寻求有关她失踪的信息，并敦促日本当局加大力度寻找她的下落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在当局对寻找失踪妇女采取看似漫不经心的态度之后，家人再次呼吁提供信息，突显了外国游客在日本零星失踪的问题，并让人质疑官员解决此类失踪问题的严肃性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒂菲因·贝隆 (Tiphaine Veron) 于 2018 年 7 月 29 日在热门山城日光失踪，当时她已 36 岁。东京以北。她入住了镇上的酒店，将行李和护照留在房间里，然后就消失了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本在冲绳寻找失踪部队时发现的直升机残骸&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;贝隆号家人确信她的失踪并非意外。在去年出版的一本名为《Tiphaine》的书中，你在哪里？ ，家人详细介绍了他们在与日本警方和该国司法系统打交道时遇到的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了回应家人的呼吁，联合国强迫失踪问题委员会于 4 月正式要求日本当局改善2018 年 9 月，法国对该案展开绑架调查后，法国与法国同行展开合作。一名政府官员在 7 月中旬表示，日本对联合国专家组的要求做出了“适当回应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国委员会表示，法国当局曾于 2018 年多次要求日本警方收集和保存手机数据2021 年，但“没有收到任何回应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本警方在日光车站分发传单寻求信息，以纪念贝隆失踪五周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在社交媒体上，有关于她的命运有很多猜测，从事故到绑架或谋杀。社交媒体用户质疑为什么安全摄像头在她离开酒店后无法捕捉到她的行踪，以及为什么调查人员无法从她的手机获取数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人指出，一名美国公民也被列为两名英国妇女（2000 年的露西·布莱克曼 (Lucie Blackman) 和 2007 年的林赛·霍克 (Lindsay Hawker)）惨遭杀害，动摇了人们普遍认为日本是世界上最安全的旅游国家之一的信念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝隆号在日本失踪。该案与今年早些时候帕特里夏·穆拉德（Patricia Murad）悬而未决的失踪案有一些相似之处。 Murad 是一位来自美国康涅狄格州的 61 岁男子，当时他正在日本独自徒步旅行，并于 4 月 10 日在日本中部和歌山县失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 6 月份接受《每日邮报》采访时，她的丈夫柯克说，他的“直觉”告诉他，他经验丰富且游历广泛的妻子“信任了错误的人”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为她与某人进行了交谈，并且信任他们足以接受从他们那里乘车，”他说。 “她的脚趾出现了问题，所以她有可能接受了搭车，然后被绑架了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆拉德失踪后，她的家人和朋友曾多次前往日本，与警方和当地山区救援队合作沿着她所走的路线，甚至包租直升机和无人机去搜索路径周围更大的森林区域，但无济于事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本警方在没有发现有关穆拉德的线索后，于五月中旬暂停了搜索尽管家人恳求继续寻找，但命运仍然如此。六月初，在又一次无果而终的日本之行后，一家人停止了自己的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但贝隆家族并没有放弃，并继续敦促日本当局采取更多行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “自从她失踪以来，我们一直在努力寻找蒂菲因，在一个失踪人员案件没有得到调查的国家，”家人在专门寻找她的网站上发布的一条消息中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不会放弃。我们需要答案，”蒂芬的弟弟达米恩周六告诉共同社。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why China’s students now face a longer long march to join the Communist Party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227665/why-chinas-students-now-face-longer-long-march-join-communist-party?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/4fabf880-52d7-41fd-86a6-fd5625574bc5_b840db86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;吴睿的申请已在系统中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20 7月1日，中国共产党成立102周年纪念日，正在江苏省一所大学读书的3岁男孩申请加入中国共产党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了表达自己的“诚意”，他煞费苦心地手写了“提交。他说：“我把这看作是对我……是否愿意加倍努力入党的考验。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一周后，该大学负责党务的学生导师正式接受了他的入党申请，但即使对于像吴这样热心的人来说，这也只是这个过程的开始——他现在必须经过党委平均持续两年的严格政治筛选。在此期间，委员会将检查他是否真正认同党的理想并忠于党的领导。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴是数以千万计希望加入垄断决策的政党的中国公民之一-打造世界第二大经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，吴和他未来的同志们的长征正变得更加艰难。根据中国各大学网站上的党委指示文件，他们在过去几年中面临着更严格的政治审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月，中组部公布了最新的党员人数。结果显示，只有一半的申请者被认定为“积极分子”，这种身份使他们能够参加党支部的学习和活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在 10 月份发布的党员招募新规定中，享有盛誉的党员组织中国社会科学院大学表示，对候选人的政治审查将包括他们对党的理论和政策的态度，以及他们过去“重大政治斗争中的表现”——这里指的是像6月4日这样的敏感时期。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;学校表示，还将与学生家乡的警察和社区管理人员交谈，收集有关他们过去的行为及其家庭成员的任何背景或犯罪记录的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政治审查必须认真、实事求是、注重自身一贯表现。审查应形成结论性材料。未通过政治审查的人不能入党。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的外交法标志着新的红线，而不是跨越红线&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果一切顺利，吴经常组织学校合唱团、舞蹈团比赛的学生会积极分子，将于明年7月在党旗前举起右拳，宣誓成为预备党员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;如果党组对他在试用期内的表现感到满意，一年后才能成为正式党员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的导师告诉我，从去年开始，选拔过程变得更加严格。只有那些在上大学之前曾在军队服役的人，或者像我一样积极在学生会服役的人，或者在Covid-19控制期间从事大量志愿工作的人才会入围。”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该党的官方统计数据还表明，该党加强了对新申请者的筛选程序，并加强了对年轻党员的监督。中共最高人事办公室中组部表示，去年30岁以下党员总数下降至1243万人，比2021年7月1日减少18.9万人，下降1.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数其中的下降来自大学校园。根据官方数据，学生党员人数从 2021 年的 305 万人下降到去年的 290 万人，减少了 15.2 万人，降幅约为 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党收紧了对学生的政治筛选程序。观察员和负责招聘的党内官员表示，新的申请和对年轻干部的纪律监督，加上 Covid-19 的干扰，是招聘人数减少的主要原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加强对年轻干部的筛选教授表示，对于同时也是党的最高领导人的习近平主席来说，年轻干部变得非常重要，因为他把希望寄托在在新时代接受教育的年轻一代身上，以接管中国的社会主义政权。清华大学国家战略研究院高级研究员谢茂松。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在 1 月份对党纪机关的主旨演讲中，要求反腐败监督机构“加强教育、管理和监督”。谢说，共产党“不急于”突破一亿党员大关，因为它已经已经达到了覆盖中国各个方面的临界规模。相反，在面临内部和外部压力的斗争时，共产党“更加明确地关注质量”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着美国及其盟友决心破坏中国的崛起，我们将继续看到前所未有的挑战。党需要在压力下站稳脚跟、保持忠诚、表现出色的新鲜血液。”谢说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那些为了攀登权力阶梯而入党的人，从长远来看将成为党的负担，因为他们会受到诱惑并成为最薄弱的环节。除了纪委大力度反腐抓捕系统内已有的腐败分子外，组织部近年来还加强了前端筛选，过滤掉那些表现软弱的人。”&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;一位负责大学招生的党员表示，除了追求质量的方向外，Covid-19也是最年轻党员招生人数下降的部分原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有政党为了控制疫情的蔓延，包括组织部在内的各个部门都被调来了。消息人士称，由于一些党委因社交距离措施而无法开会，导致申请批准出现一些延迟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此外，许多申请人在 Covid-19 控制工作中接受了测试。虽然他们中的大多数表现都很好，但我们确实看到了一些人没有做好充分准备，在关键时期与党同甘共苦。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京的一位政治研究人员表示，筛选11 月份，许多中国大学看到学生抗议国家严格的 Covid-19 控制措施，之后，准党员的资格将进一步收紧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这被视为一场政治斗争，因为北京方面表示， “颜色革命”的元素。那些被发现参加抗议活动的人将很难通过政治审查。”由于此事敏感性而拒绝透露姓名的研究人员表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，政党申请人 Ray吴说，尽管过程漫长，但他的学校里不乏希望入党的人，尽管党员身份可能会导致那些计划去海外（尤其是美国）继续深造的人。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;事实上，申请入党的人数一直居高不下。官方数据显示，2022年有近2100万人提交了入党申请，比上年增加了约30万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认识几个朋友，在决定去深造后，就撤回了入党申请。”美国，因为申请签证的时候会被问到是否是党员。但他们并不是大多数。党员身份对于留在中国的人来说非常重要。这是大多数政府工作的先决条件。”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党员身份几乎被列为参加选拔生考试的要求——选拔生指的是由共产党人事部门选拔的学生&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月份16-24岁人群失业率再创新高，达到21.3%，高于上月的20.8%。所以这样的“铁饭碗”工作对于应届毕业生来说就变得非常有吸引力。它们也被视为在中国公共管理系统开始职业生涯的最佳途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管校园招聘有所下降，但共产党仍然净增党员130万，增长1.4%，去年会员总数突破 9800 万。这约占全国人口的 7%，使其成为世界上人数第二多的政党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;距离共产党 1921 年成立之初还有很长的路要走，当时共产党只有据政党历史学家称，该党成立时有 58 名党员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界上最大的政党是印度人民党 (BJP)，由总理纳伦德拉·莫迪 (Narendra Modi) 领导，拥有 1.8 亿党员。自 2014 年以来，它一直是印度的执政党，并在民主选举中击败了主要竞争对手印度国大党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但规模约为印度人民党一半的执政党共产党一直是印度的执政党。 1949年，在一场血腥的内战后，将民族主义者国民党赶出了大陆，成为中华人民共和国自1949年以来唯一的政权。自成立以来，共产党的入党过程一直是出了名的困难和竞争，严格的招募、纪律和组织被视为其成功的关键因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就连习近平主席在申请入党时也被拒绝了九次。据官方媒体报道，他最终于 1974 年入党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央党校官方报纸《学习时报》前副主编邓聿文表示，共产党或许“ “世界上最难加入的政党”，因为它是按照列宁创立的布尔什维克派建立的，强调严格的权力等级制度。这是习近平自 2012 年上台以来一直致力于复兴和加强的传统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们显然在寻找党员的质量而不是数量，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;习近平担心，前任党内的自由主义氛围会腐蚀党的理想信念，使其在面对西方煽动的颜色革命时不堪一击。加强和加强高校党支部成为防御的第一步。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Barbenheimer’ memes are big on social media, and Japan doesn’t like it]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3229568/barbenheimer-big-social-media-and-japan-doesnt-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 11:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/f5e41967-d91c-4b63-b1c9-735bbca2a3a8_03820140.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;双倍剂量的美国热门电影《巴本海默》正在推动社会——日本是唯一经历过核武器袭击的国家，媒体对此表示强烈反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;结合原子弹发明者奥本海默传记和有关时尚娃娃的喜剧《芭比娃娃》的模因已被广泛传播。 X（以前称为 Twitter）上的趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本用户已经接受了“#NoBarbenheimer”标签，当芭比电影的美国帐户插话说：“这将是一个值得纪念的夏天。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8 月 6 日和 8 月 9 日将纪念广岛和长崎原子弹投下 78 周年。这个岛国以庄严的仪式纪念这一周年，并呼吁消除核武器。尽管克里斯托弗·诺兰的《奥本海默》尚未在日本被禁，但它上个月在美国影院首映，但尚未确定上映日期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日语帖子将“巴本海默”模因描述为“可怕” ”，并批评了将芭比电影中的蘑菇云和演员结合起来的图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;引起的轩然大波迫使芭比娃娃发行商华纳兄弟的日本办事处做出回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是“非常令人遗憾的”华纳兄弟日本有限责任公司在芭比娃娃的日本官方账户上发布的一份声明中表示，该电影的美国账户以不恰当的方式参与了“巴本海默”运动。该公司表示，它与该模因或该运动无关，并且正在寻求其美国母公司的“适当回应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在日本 Twitter 用户注意到美国官方 Twitter神田国际研究大学历史讲师 Jeffrey J. Hall 表示，“芭比电影的账户正在以积极的方式回应蘑菇云‘巴本海默’模因。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果华纳兄弟的美国办事处认真对待这个问题并道歉，这可能会导致大部分强烈反对平息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为爆炸性时刻打扮得漂漂亮亮：《巴本海默》双片炒作中的香港粉丝&lt;/h3>;&lt; 《芭比与奥本海默》于美国同一个周末上映，引发了观众一次电影院观看两部电影的现象。好莱坞电影在美国首映后稍后在日本上映是很常见的。芭比娃娃将于 8 月 11 日在日本首次亮相。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通常发行环球影业电影的东邦东和公司 (Toho-Towa Co.) 的一位官员表示，奥本海默在日本的上映时间尚未确定。该官员补充说，这一决定将由环球影业做出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“奥本海默可能会获奖，届时我们可以期待在日本影院广泛上映，”霍尔说。 “日本电影发行商将电影上映推迟六个月或一年的情况很常见，而且很少是出于政治动机。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk removes giant, flashing ‘X’ sign after furore in San Francisco]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229569/elon-musk-removes-giant-flashing-x-sign-after-furore-san-francisco?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 11:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/0e1ec800-5981-4aaa-8efb-69498896b738_eba5ca7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这家前身为 Twitter 的公司从旧金山的顶部移除了一个高耸、闪烁的 X周一，这家更名后的科技公司与市政府官员就这个有争议的标志发生了争执。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，X 被安装在该公司市中心办公室的屋顶上，这是所有者埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 为这家陷入困境的社交媒体重塑品牌计划的一部分。媒体巨头的字母表中的第 24 个字母。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当地居民抱怨该标志在夜间发出的明亮闪烁的灯光。一些人还抱怨安全问题，认为这个隐约出现在建筑物边缘的标志似乎没有牢固地固定在屋顶上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旧金山建筑检查和城市规划部收到了 24 份关于该标志的投诉，该机构通讯主管帕特里克·汉南 (Patrick Hannan) 表示，其中包括对其“结构安全和照明”的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天早上，建筑检查员观察到该结构正在被拆除，”汉南说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;业主汉南表示，X 租用办公室的房产必须支付安装和拆除该标志的许可证费用，以及该市调查的费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;旧金山对违规行为进行了调查Twitter 大楼顶部放置了“X”标志&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一名跟进投诉的建筑检查员于周五首先前往这家科技公司的总部，但根据发布的投诉，他们不被允许到屋顶检查该标志投诉显示，X 代表告诉检查员，该结构是“活动的临时灯光标志”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二次尝试据该市称，周六检查该标志的检查员也遭到拒绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市向 X 发送了一份违规通知，警告其需要获得该标志的适当许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当联系时针对媒体的投诉，X 回复了一条自动消息，表示将“很快”做出回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克总体上消除了对该标志和品牌重塑的强烈反对，并用一个大笑的表情符号回应了一个人X 用户发帖称，该市在新标志问题上与他意见不合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位亿万富翁上周初取消了 Twitter 全球知名的鸟类标志，并重新命名了该公司，他希望将其打造成一款受超级应用启发的公司自从去年 10 月马斯克以 440 亿美元收购 Twitter 以来，随着营销人员对马斯克的管理风格感到不满，该平台的广告业务已经崩溃。以及对公司的大规模解雇，破坏了内容审核。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的 X 向 Gene X Hwang 提供了珍贵的 @x Twitter 账号&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为回应，他已着手建立订阅者基础上周，由于缺乏适当的许可，工人们在拆除总部的 Twitter 标志和蓝鸟标志时被拦下。周一也消失了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一群在马斯克接任后失业的前 Twitter 员工在 5 月份针对该公司提起的联邦民事诉讼中表示，这位亿万富翁明确表示他无意支付租金或遣散费等费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人无意中听到马斯克的一名律师曾粗鲁地侮辱旧金山，称鉴于居住条件，房东期望 Twitter 支付租金是不合理的，诉讼称.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Country Garden cancels US$300 million share placement, bankers tell investors: IFR says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3229563/country-garden-cancels-us300-million-share-placement-bankers-tell-investors-ifr-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 10:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/5575b5d1-ee59-44ab-925e-379728f8986c_4345f9e7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;碧桂园控股取消了 23.4 亿港元（3 亿美元）的配股，IFR据报道，援引向投资者发送的消息，这是中国最大的私营开发商之一的最新挫折。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，独家账簿管理人摩根大通告诉投资者，午夜后不久，主要配股被取消。此前，IFR 表示，碧桂园将以每股 1.3 港元的固定价格发行 18 亿股股票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;碧桂园警告称，由于利润率下降和减值准备，碧桂园上半年将出现净亏损。该公司一度被开发商认为是更安全的投资，但现在已成为该行业金融传染的代表，该行业约占该国国内生产总值的四分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;碧桂园面临着 29 亿美元的债务偿还。今年剩下的时间里，其流动性困境将考验其按时完成并避免首次违约的能力。对开发商可能拖欠付款的担忧导致其债券近几周暴跌。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国顶级开发商预计上半年亏损，寻求政府支持&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;碧桂园的代表没有立即发表评论彭博新闻社报道称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;摩根大通最近下调了碧桂园的股票评级，因为围绕中国私人建筑商的流动性担忧不太可能很快缓解。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: drone hits same Moscow high-rise tower that was struck on Sunday]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229564/ukraine-war-drone-hits-same-moscow-high-rise-tower-was-struck-sunday?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 10:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/0d9e4e01-3f3c-49fb-90ac-0d808817b2ae_4180cf17.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，一架无人机袭击了莫斯科的一座办公大楼，该大楼是在周末被击中的，该市市长表示，至少还有一架无人机被击落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“多架无人机在试图飞往莫斯科时被防空系统击落。一架（无人机）与上次一样飞入（莫斯科）市的同一座塔楼。莫斯科市长谢尔盖·索比亚宁（Sergei Sobyanin）在 Telegram 上发帖称，“21 楼的外立面遭到损坏。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前还没有有关伤亡的信息，”他补充说，紧急服务人员已赶赴现场。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;周日，俄罗斯表示，在一次袭击中击落了针对首都的乌克兰无人机，该袭击损坏了商业区莫斯科市的两座办公楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无人机袭击后不久，莫斯科伏努科沃国际机场被毁。据塔斯社报道，紧急服务部门称，“伏努科沃机场暂时关闭，无法进出机场，飞机将改道至其他机场”，塔斯社后来报道称，该机场已恢复运营正常运作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科及其周边地区距乌克兰边境约 500 公里（310 英里），在乌克兰冲突期间很少成为目标，直到今年发生几起无人机袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日的袭击是最近发生的一系列无人机袭击事件中的最新一起，莫斯科将袭击事件归咎于基辅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫表示，这次袭击是“一次&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰在六月开始了期待已久的反攻，但面对前线俄罗斯军队的顽强抵抗，取得了一定的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple supplier Foxconn plans 2 new component plants in India, spending US$500 million to build out footprint]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3229560/apple-supplier-foxconn-plans-two-new-component-plants-india-spending-us500-million-build-out?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 10:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/2cc8​​5784-6514-45cd-8b29-e5b9da6c6a34_b1f9976e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;苹果公司主要供应商富士康科技集团计划投资近500美元作为从中国稳定多元化的一部分，台湾公司计划在印度南部卡纳塔克邦建造的工厂中至少有一家将生产苹果零部件，包括 iPhone 零部件”，知情人士表示。由于此事尚未公开而不愿透露姓名的知情人士表示，预计最早将于本周发布正式公告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些新工厂的具体位置尚未确定。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;富士康退出价值 200 亿美元的印度合资企业，对莫迪的芯片梦想造成打击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;苹果没有立即回复置评请求。富士康没有回复置评电子邮件。卡纳塔克邦政府没有在非工作时间回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，富士康还与南部泰米尔纳德邦政府签署了初步协议，将建立一家零部件工厂，投资额为该邦工业部周一表示，投资额为 160 亿卢比（1.95 亿美元）。计划在 Kancheepuram 区实施的项目可能会创造约 6,000 个就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;得益于印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪 (Narendra Modi) 推动当地制造业发展的激励措施，富士康等苹果供应商在过去几年中扩大了在印度的业务。卡纳塔克邦等邦也吸引了能够快速决策、减少繁文缛节并提供补贴的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富士康在印度的举措突显了这个南亚国家如何迅速成为制造商寻找新产品的热门目的地。在华盛顿和北京之间日益紧张的局势下，中国成为中国的替代品。这也是 Covid-19 大流行和乌克兰战争期间全球供应链加速转变的结果，并可能重塑电子产品的制造方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的零部件工厂计划还包括据彭博社此前报道，富士康正在投资 7 亿美元，在卡纳塔克邦首府班加罗尔机场附近的一块 300 英亩的土地上建设一座工厂。该工厂可能组装 iPhone，预计将创造约 10 万个就业岗位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富士康位于中国郑州的庞大 iPhone 组装厂 — 目前是全球最大的苹果大牌产品生产地 — 雇用了约 20 万名员工，但生产旺季期间数量激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于新冠疫情相关的供应中断，郑州工厂的产量在 2022 年年底假期前大幅下降，这是促使苹果重新审视其依赖中国的供应的几个因素之一富士康的决定表明，供应商可能会比预期更快地将产能迁出中国，这对莫迪政府来说是一个妙招，随着西方投资者和企业对北京的不满，莫迪政府看到了缩小印度与中国技术差距的机会。监管不稳定、经济放缓和美国贸易限制。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France loves its frogs’ legs. But for Indonesia and Vietnam, that’s becoming a problem]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3229561/france-loves-its-frogs-legs-indonesia-and-vietnam-thats-becoming-problem?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 10:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/5dcf2af5-4af1-4f56-8c8e-4262c39c2fdf_4663359f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一提到法国菜，我们首先想到的，除了蜗牛和鹅肝，可能是青蛙腿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;您可以在法国的大多数餐馆点青蛙腿，通常将其炸至酥脆，并用大蒜调味。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;法国人每年吃掉约 4,000 吨这种传统菜肴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管法国农业部将青蛙腿视为 Bourgone-Franche-Comté 东部地区的烹饪遗产，但其中大部分来自&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在法国本土，食用青蛙物种已经受到保护数十年。在法国和欧盟大部分地区，对于捕获的数量都有严格的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在勃艮第-弗朗什-孔泰地区，在比赛结束之前的特定条件下，允许捕获并杀死草蛙。 2 月和 4 月，它们来到池塘繁殖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，法国每年从国外进口超过 2,500 吨青蛙腿以满足需求。这道菜在比利时也很受欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但欧洲饥饿的青蛙食者正在给供应国带来麻烦。印度尼西亚是最大的青蛙腿出口国，欧洲对这种美味的需求不仅威胁着稀有青蛙物种的数量，而且还威胁着生态系统的平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着明代美食需求的爆发，中国的青蛙餐厅蓬勃发展&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“蛙腿贸易几乎不受政府监管或监控，”爪哇岛万隆市动物博物馆馆长、两栖动物专家 Ganjar Cahyadi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，没有关于这个群岛国家野生青蛙数量的官方数据。 “我们不知道有多少青蛙被出口，还有多少在野外。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个两栖动物主要出口国越南的情况也类似。动物福利组织国际人道协会的 Mai Nguyen 表示，近几十年来，该国的青蛙数量大幅减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我还是个生活在农村的孩子时，很容易看到并发现青蛙。”捉青蛙。但今天——几乎 40 年后——甚至很难找到野生青蛙，”她说。然而，政府没有计划限制这些动物的销售或出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚，尤其是印度尼西亚的雨林，以其丰富的生物多样性而闻名。 New species continue to be discovered there frequently.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the widespread hunting of frogs may wipe out entire species before scientists even find them, said Cahyadi, adding that more urgently needs to be done for research and, above all, for the protection of the animals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frogs are both prey and hunters, making them a critical part of the food chain. When it comes to reducing the population of insects such as grasshoppers and mosquitoes, the amphibians are indispensable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Frogs are natural insecticides.它们吃的昆虫可能会给农业和公共卫生带来问题，”卡亚迪说。 “Without frogs, we would have to use more chemicals to control these insects.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This would not only be detrimental to the environment, but also to people&#39;s health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One solution could be to focus on breeding frogs for export instead of hunting them, Cahyadi said. This would also benefit the local economy and create jobs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French fishmonger Patrick Francois came up with a similar idea 13 years ago. He established what was probably the first frog farm in France, in the southern village of Pierrelatte near the Provence region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I saw that people were trying to produce more and more locally. That&#39;s why I threw myself into it,” said Francois, who now breeds frogs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His project was made possible with a special frog species that scientists developed. While frogs only eat moving animals, these frogs also eat things that do not move.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From when they are born to when they are killed, the frogs spend their time in some of the hundred or so tanks in Francois&#39; breeding hall, which is filled with the sound of water and the loud croaking of the male frogs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Francois also has environmental goals in mind, when he considers the frozen imported frogs&#39; legs from Southeast Asia or frogs imported alive from Turkey. “The very fact that no frogs are taken from the wild,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He now supplies frog legs to about a dozen upmarket customers. “No more, because our production is not enormous either.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Scientists are now able to regrow frog legs. Are humans next?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, a handful of other breeders in France have followed suit and set up frog farms. The Agriculture Ministry wrote in 2019 that the breeders produced about 10 tonnes of frog legs a year, and estimated that it could be significantly more in the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even so, France is still only likely to supply a fraction of the nation&#39;s total annual consumption for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong homeowners slash prices as they race to sell before property values fall further]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3229532/hong-kong-homeowners-slash-prices-they-race-sell-property-values-fall-further?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/64178a69-af4c-430f-bd41-b2215ffbf187_8f6bae55.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Homeowners in Hong Kong are offering steep discounts as they race to offload their properties quickly before the market falls further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a recent case that underscores the trend, a seller in Tai Po was forced to take a 28 per cent loss when he offloaded his property for HK$4.3 million (US$550,000) less than he had paid for it in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Owners are only managing to attract buyers when they cut prices by at least 10 per cent from what they were two months ago, said Louis Chan Wing-kit, CEO of the residential division at Centaline Property Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If [owners] want to offload their properties now, they have to cut asking prices substantially as home prices will fall further in the coming quarters,” said Louis Chan Wing-kit, CEO of the residential division at Centaline Property Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) said the delinquency rate on residential mortgage loans in negative equity between April and June more than doubled to 0.09 per cent from 0.04 per cent at the end of March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were 3,341 cases of negative equity – where the value of a home falls below that of the mortgage on it – at the end of June, the results of a quarterly survey by the HKMA showed. This was a 47.6 drop from 6,379 instances in the previous quarter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But analysts said a further fall in pre-owned home prices could fire up the number of negative equity cases in the coming months as owners rushed to cash out before the market slumps too far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s house prices have come under pressure from rising interest rates that make mortgages more unaffordable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The HKMA last week raised the city&#39;s base rate for the 11th time in 17 months in lockstep with the Federal Reserve, as the US central bank resumed its fight against inflation after a breather six weeks ago. Hong Kong&#39;s monetary policy follows the United States as the city&#39;s currency is pegged to the US dollar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s commercial banks including Bank of China (Hong Kong), HSBC and Hang Seng Bank raised the lending rate for their best customers by 12.5 basis points to 5.875 per cent starting Friday after the 25 basis points increase in the base rate to 5.75 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were only two transactions recorded at the 10 largest housing estates in the city over the weekend, according to data compiled by Centaline Property Agency, the lowest volume in the last 12 weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In some cases, owners have been accepting significant losses as they desperately try to drum up interest in their properties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 789 square-foot, three-bedroom unit with parking space in phase one of The Horizon development, located at Pak Shek Kok in Tai Po, was recently sold at a 28 per cent discount, for HK$10.95 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The owner offered the unit at a price of HK$12 million two months ago but did not get any interest,” said Dick Lam, a property agent at Midland Realty. The sale represented a booked loss of HK$4.31 million when compared with the HK$15.26 million the owner paid in January 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, a 672 sq ft, three-bedroom unit in the fifth phase of Mei Foo Sun Chuen in Lai Chi Kok changed hands for HK$7.38 million, a 24 per cent discount, and a 601 sq ft three-bedroom flat in Serenity Place in Tseung Kwan O went for HK$6.2 million, a 14 per cent loss.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New supply of houses is another concern for sellers in the secondary market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are 83,000 new homes available, according to Joseph Tsang, chairman of JLL&#39;s Hong Kong office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Developers have a lot of stock to be offloaded,” said Tsang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Derek Chan, head of research at Ricacorp Properties, said the transaction volume would continue to drop plagued because of the latest rate hike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But home seekers will gradually come back to the market as the economy in the city improves,” he added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Belt and Road expansion in Pakistan at risk as terrorist attacks surge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3229543/chinas-belt-and-road-expansion-pakistan-risk-terrorist-attacks-surge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/cf4b303c-9a35-45ca-9b56-e925f1e99a53_5da77882.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An upsurge in terrorist attacks in western Pakistan highlights the risks involved in expanding China&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative in the country even as Chinese firms are “learning the ropes” on how to cope with the rise in violence, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid ongoing celebrations to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC), attacks by insurgents of the Pakistani Taliban movement, or TTP, in July spread to areas of Balochistan province considered vital to the expansion of connectivity between Xinjiang and the Chinese-operated port of Gwadar on the Arabian Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese companies have built some US$25 billion worth of mostly power generation and logistical infrastructure since work on CPEC began in earnest in 2016. The overall value of projects scheduled for completion by 2030 is estimated at US$62 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nine Pakistani soldiers were killed while repulsing a July 12 attempt by a TTP suicide squad to storm a garrison in the remote town of Zhob, a vital link in roads being built to provide a shorter new route along the country&#39;s western axis to Gwadar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another three Pakistani troops were killed on the same day in a battle with TTP militants in the Sui area of Balochistan, leading security officials to conclude that the Pakistani Taliban had been provided logistical support by ethnic Baloch separatists who have been fighting security forces since 2004.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Zhob attack was connected to CPEC. That&#39;s why the [Pakistani] army chief of staff reacted by rushing to Quetta”, the administrative capital of Balochistan, and issued a statement saying “foreign” nationals were involved, said Afrasiab Khattak, a former member of Pakistan&#39;s senate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The high command of Pakistan&#39;s army, which dominates national politics, subsequently issued several statements blaming the attacks on TTP insurgents who enjoy “safe havens and liberty of action” in Afghanistan, and demanded that the Taliban regime live up to its commitment to prevent the export of terrorism from the war-torn country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Syrian among 40 suspects held over Sri Lanka suicide bombings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The situation in western Pakistan has deteriorated since the Taliban took over in Afghanistan” two years ago amid the withdrawal of United States-led international forces after two bloody decades of occupation, Khattak said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While CPEC projects have not directly been hit as they are protected by multiple layers of security, terrorists have targeted non-CPEC projects involving Chinese firms, such as the Dasu hydropower dam. Chinese nationals have also been targeted – three language teachers were killed at Karachi University in April 2022, while a dentist was shot dead in Karachi last September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This prompted the Pakistani authorities to extend CPEC-level security to all Chinese companies, and to restrict the movements of Chinese nationals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite repeated denials by the Taliban regime, “the TTP is part of the Taliban and it has now been equipped with weapons left behind in Afghanistan by US forces”, Khattak said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This has enabled the TTP to revive the insurgency that Pakistani security forces defeated in 2015 after eight years of fighting which claimed more than 70,000 lives and crippled the national economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is now a full-blown insurgency with a shadow government which is targeting the symbols and personnel of the Pakistani state,” Khattak said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But if Pakistan were to carry out its repeated threats of retaliatory cross-border attacks against TTP bases in Afghanistan, it would “further aggravate the situation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Taliban [regime] wouldn&#39;t be able to restrain anti-Pakistan sentiment within its ranks, and it would be forced to reconsider its alliance with Pakistan” under which the Islamist movement enjoyed safe havens in border areas of western Pakistan during their 20-year war with the US and its allies, Khattak said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The security situation has been further complicated by the spillover of fighting between Afghanistan&#39;s Taliban regime and the rival Islamic State Khorasan (Isis-K) across the border into tribal districts of Pakistan&#39;s northwestern Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pakistani officials said they suspected Isis-K was responsible for a suicide bombing at a rally of a pro-Afghan Taliban Islamist party in the Bajaur tribal district on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Afghan Taliban and TTP both condemned the incident, while Isis-K on Monday claimed responsibility for the attack that killed at least 54 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bajaur attack coincided with the arrival of Chinese Vice-Premier He Lifeng in Islamabad for talks on the second phase of CPEC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has repeatedly told “all-weather strategic partner” Pakistan to take greater action to protect its nationals and projects, following lethal attacks by the TTP and Baloch rebels over the last two years in particular.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But CPEC development “will continue alongside terrorism”, said Abdul Basit, a senior associate fellow of the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies at Nanyang Technological University in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese know what they have gotten themselves into, and are learning the ropes on how to muddle through.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Singapore-based analyst suggested that Chinese security agencies could take a more direct approach in dealing with the militants responsible for killing Chinese nationals, instead of relying solely on Pakistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also hinted that the assassination of the Afghanistan-based TTP militant behind the July 2021 vehicular suicide attack, which killed nine Chinese nationals working on a hydropower dam in northern Pakistan, could have involved some level of Chinese assistance. There have been no official indications of China&#39;s active involvement in Pakistan&#39;s anti-terrorism operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a meeting with He on Monday, Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif said “obstacles” to the friendship between Pakistan and China would not be “tolerated”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Second funeral in Hong Kong for singer Coco Lee held before cremation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229559/second-funeral-hong-kong-singer-coco-lee-held-cremation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 09:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/01/6c72564e-3da8-499c-8606-f8e58f463706_fd0a4ff1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A second private service for late pop diva Coco Lee was held on Tuesday morning, with family and friends in Hong Kong paying their final respects before cremation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The funeral at a parlour in North Point followed an emotional vigil the day before as those close to Lee gathered to remember the trail-blazing singer, before the venue was opened for more than 1,000 fans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Tuesday&#39;s service, Lee&#39;s body will be taken from the Hong Kong Funeral Home in North Point to be cremated at the Cape Collinson Crematorium in Chai Wan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her family had previously announced that eight people would serve as pallbearers, including her brother-in-law Billy Ho, singer Jenny Tseng, two close friends, co-president of Warner Music Asia Jonathan Serbin and one of Lee&#39;s fans, Yang Yang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee died in early July after a suicide attempt, according to her family. They said she had been diagnosed with depression a few years ago, but her condition deteriorated.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Gone too soon&#39;: family, friends and fans gather to remember pop diva Coco Lee&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Here are the live updates for Tuesday&#39;s procession:&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Private service starting&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Amid the sombre atmosphere, friends and family of Lee bowed three times before the star&#39;s coffin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The seats inside the grand hall of the funeral home are almost full, save for a few frontrow spots.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Friends and family arriving&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Friends and family of the late pop star arrived at 9.30am for the ceremony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There has been no sign of Lee&#39;s estranged husband or high-profile guests, who could have entered via the underground car park.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also appears that the 200 fans who were allowed in earlier will stay inside for the service.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Numbers considerably smaller&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 200 fans at the private viewing formed most of Lee&#39;s supporters at the funeral home on Tuesday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fewer than 100 other fans not permitted inside gathered across the road from the entrance of the home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, about 1,400 fans went inside to pay their respects to Lee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A fan from Taiwan, who did not provide his name, told the Post it was his first time in Hong Kong and he did not think it was fair that only members of the group could go in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I did not want to come as part of a group and I don&#39;t think I should be treated differently for doing so.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Some super fans allowed private viewing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;About 200 members of the super fan group Coconuts were given a private opportunity to say goodbye to Lee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the organisers told the Post they allowed members to register for the private viewing beforehand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fans will go inside, bow three times to the coffin and pay their respects before leaving.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post learned the fan group had been in touch with Lee&#39;s family for the special arrangement before the funeral.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong pop diva Coco Lee&#39;s family announces pallbearers, husband is not one&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;Fans gather early&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lee&#39;s fans have been gathering outside the funeral home since about 8am.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite not being allowed inside, they came early to send off the hearse, which is expected to set off for Cape Collinson Crematorium at 10.30am.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Teacher Li Liming, 47, from Maoming, Guangdong province attended the service on Monday and was back for another round.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will just wait at the entrance and say our last farewell,” Li, who travelled with a group of mainland fans called Coconuts, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts or know someone who is experiencing them, help is available.在香港，请拨打 +852 2896 0000 联系撒玛利亚人，或拨打 +852 2382 0000 联系预防自杀服务。 In the US, call the 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline at 988 or +1 800 273 8255. For a list of other nations&#39; helplines, .&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>