<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Just earn a little less’: Hong Kong cabbie impresses mainland Chinese tourist short on cash by waiving part of fare]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227629/just-earn-little-less-hong-kong-cabbie-impresses-mainland-chinese-tourist-short-cash-waiving-part?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/f7e4519e-2c0c-4c48-b49d-4a332d5e6921_ad251506.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个关于香港出租车司机带一名内地女子去的温馨故事尽管她没有足够的现金支付全额票价，但她还是选择了自己想要的目的地，这引起了其他前往这座城市的旅行者的共鸣，促使他们分享他们愉快的经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近有报道称，积极情绪的爆发是在当地人与在新冠大流行期间关闭边境三年后回国的大陆游客之间的紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地人抱怨大陆游客行为粗鲁，抬高价格并造成交通拥堵，而一些大陆人则表示，他们一直在担心大陆游客的行为。因说普通话而受到歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月，香港国泰航空公司解雇了三名机组人员，他们被指控歧视一名不会说英语的内地乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乘坐出租车的女子她在内地社交媒体平台小红书上发帖称，她于7月1日到香港参加韩国流行歌手郑容和的演唱会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在以下时间打了一辆出租车前往西九龙站：当天乘高铁返回中国大陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在与丈夫乘坐出租车时，她意识到自己几乎花光了所有现金，只剩下 17 港元（2.2 美元）。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她问出租车司机：“我可以只付现金吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司机确认只收现金后，她立即道歉并建议他要么让他们出去几百米后，或者，如果他带他们到自动取款机，这样她就可以取款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令她惊讶的是，她以为司机会感到沮丧或生气，却让她放心了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“没关系。距离不算太远，如果你不登机的话我就一分钱也赚不到。所以我就少赚一点，”他告诉那位女士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“司机真的很好。看到我着急，他还安慰我，询问行程怎么样。”她在帖子中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了表达谢意，她和丈夫送给了司机两个在网上买的菠萝包。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当出租车到达西九龙站时，车费已达到港币 49 元，“比港币 17 元贵很多”，她在帖子中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;她还准备要司机的银行账号给他转钱，幸好西九龙有ATM机，她就提取现金支付了车费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港这次遇到的香港人都很友善。在整个旅程中我说普通话没有任何问题。我会再来。”该女士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的故事在社交媒体上引起了许多人的共鸣，他们分享了在香港的积极旅行经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“我上周与一位友善的出租车司机有过类似的美好经历。我只有一堆硬币和一张500港元的纸币。当我们接近目的地时，我开始一边查计价器一边数零钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“司机告诉我用我有的零钱付款。还好我零钱够多，他还免了我的行李费。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有人说：“有一次我因为着急，乘飞机时误拿了一张屈臣氏会员卡，而不是我的八达通卡。”一辆公交车。我身上只有100港元现金，但巴士司机并没有向我收费。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三个人也表示同意：“我前几天在香港，遇到的每个人都很好。晚上九点多阿姨还带我们去了金紫荆广场。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s foreign policy chief Wang Yi tells India border dispute should not define relationship]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227899/chinas-foreign-policy-chief-wang-yi-tells-india-border-dispute-should-not-define-relationship?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/16/b138bfb7-4643-42ea-9463-df7e388008e8_0599ed02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最高外交官王毅敦促印度放宽对中国投资的限制，并补充说诸如持续的边境对峙等问题“不应定义两国之间的整体关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅在一次区域会议期间与印度外交部长苏杰生会面时发出上述呼吁外交部长在印度尼西亚首都雅加达举行会议，并补充说，新德里应聚焦“共同利益”，与中国“相向而行”，以化解边境紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管人们期望纳伦德拉·莫迪总理和中国国家主席习近平下个月将在约翰内斯堡和 9 月在新德里面对面会晤，自 2020 年 6 月在有争议的喜马拉雅边境发生致命冲突以来，两国一直陷入军事对峙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管过去三年举行了数十次军事会谈，今年也进行了多次高层交往，但几乎没有迹象表明双方准备在这个高度紧张的问题上做出让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪上个月访问白宫期间承诺加强与华盛顿的军事关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 6 月 25 日以来一直淡出公众视野的外交部长秦刚缺席了东南亚国家联盟 (ASEAN) 会议。据中国外交部称，印度尼西亚出于“健康原因”。秦的前任、现任习近平的最高外交政策助手王先生接替了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度是否会放弃南海立场，支持马尼拉海牙裁决？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周五的最新会议外交部声明称，这次会议是应印方要求举行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中印作为世界前两个发展中国家和永远的邻居，共同利益明显大于分歧，实现共同利益王说，发展和繁荣具有全球示范意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，两国应该“相互支持、相互成就”，而不是“相互猜疑”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道：“我们应该把精力和资源集中在各自的发展、改善民生和加快振兴上，而不是让具体问题决定整体关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而印度则坚持必须完成边境部队的脱离接触在关系恢复正常之前，北京表示双方应该超越当前的争端。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，印度应该“与中国相向而行，找到双方都能接受的边界问题解决方案”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称，双方同意尽快就边界问题举行下一轮军长级会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王还表示，北京方面“高度关注”印度对中国企业的限制，“希望印方为中国企业提供公平、透明、非歧视的营商环境”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2020年发生致命边境冲突以来，印度加大了对中国企业的审查力度。据路透社报道，中国投资并对包括 TikTok 在内的 300 多个中国应用程序发布了全面禁令。最近，政府要求中国移动电话公司引入印度股权合作伙伴，并任命印度高管担任关键职务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏杰生在会后的一条推文中表示，他和王讨论了“与和平与发展相关的悬而未决的问题”。边境地区的安宁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的谈话还涉及东亚峰会或东盟地区论坛的议程，“金砖国家（巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非）和印度-太平洋地区”，推文称&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国外交部称，他对王毅表示，“印中关系正常化符合双方共同利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印方愿意以开放的心态妥善处理双方分歧，推动印中关系尽快重回正轨，为下一阶段高层交往创造有利条件。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;印太18国部长级会议在雅加达举行，主要议题是美中竞争加剧、乌克兰战争和朝鲜多次导弹挑衅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和印度关系密切印度与俄罗斯的关系并拒绝批评莫斯科的侵略，但这对他们自己的紧张关系影响不大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度将于 9 月主办今年的 20 国集团峰会，这次活动可能会提供一个机会改善与中国的关系。然而，最近几周，印度对北京的批评越来越直言不讳。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;向华盛顿倾斜，印度战胜中国的时代到来了吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年在美国国会发表的演讲本月，莫迪提到了“强制的乌云”和“不可能的债务负担”，几乎不加掩饰地抨击了中国备受批评的经济强制措施和所谓的“债务陷阱”外交。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏杰生，在本月初访问非洲期间，他还表示印度不是“采掘经济体”，在非洲追求“非常狭隘的经济目标” — — 这显然是指中国扩大其军事和经济存在的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[MTR Corp to go big in Greater Bay Area, review international business but Hong Kong remains its ‘filet mignon’, chairman Rex Auyeung says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227920/mtr-corp-go-big-greater-bay-area-review-international-business-hong-kong-remains-its-filet-mignon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/41f8ea9d-331e-4ce0-ad5b-553356914faf_ef98264c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港铁路巨头港铁公司将向中国大陆扩张，特别是在其非执行主席表示，大湾区是其未来的一个重点关注点，尽管该公司致力于通过更多的长期战略规划来改善该城市的运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧阳伯权表示，该公司正在对其国际业务进行持续审查，并准备在必要时重新审视不可行的部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这是自接掌港铁以来罕见的独家采访2019 年担任该公司非执行董事长的欧阳表示，与批评者的说法相反，该公司的国际业务并未拖累其利润。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自接任以来，他表示自己觉得有必要寻求公司治理的改进，并补充道：“我注意到的一件事是，由于我们业务的[海量日常]性质，我们的执行团队往往会关注眼前的事情……并且可能不会花钱”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港地铁公司将在 5 年内投资 650 亿港元用于铁路资产管理&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;未来 5 年将花费 20欧阳表示，该计划将增加 ​​650 亿港元（83 亿美元），以更好地修复和维护已有 44 年历史的铁路网络，并准备在需要时提高这一数字。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果管理团队来找我们，比如说，经过进一步审查，我们认为我们需要更多，我不会关上门，因为我们的目标是表现，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Auyeung 表示，及早发现和快速解决问题至关重要，他解释了公司如何越来越多地依靠技术来解决这些问题，虽然他不能保证不会出现中断，但目标是将其提高到超出目前的水平占整体无缝运营的 99.96%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧阳表示，这家半私有化公司还通过向初创企业提供 3 亿港元的投资基金，走上了技术进步的快车道，以补充其铁路运营。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司近年来因几起备受瞩目的事件而受到批评，其中包括两起火车脱轨事件和两起涉及车门脱落的事件。在其中两次情况下，通勤者不得不在轨道上行走。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;使用紧急出口造成出行混乱，香港工会猛烈抨击港铁公司&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在上周的采访中，欧阳表示该公司和他之前曾道歉，他们努力做得更好，但也敦促公众记住该公司运营的 300,000 公里（186,411 英里）隧道和 271 公里铁路网络，每晚只有两个小时的窗口期进行维护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个很好的警钟，我们不能继续认为所有这些事情都会继续顺利进行，因为系统正处于需要更多维护的阶段， “ 他说。 “必须有办法在某些事件发生之前甚至之后发现问题。你能多快恢复？有两个问题：早期发现和恢复速度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为他进行的治理审查的一部分，他表示该公司确定了以香港业务为核心的三大业务支柱，或者，正如他所说，这是公司的“菲力牛排”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，上个月，政府专家在最近一份关于该公司铁路资产管理制度的报告中，敦促其管理层灌输一种意识：员工对操作风险的所有权和责任，并实施一种报告和记录一线员工有关风险管理的有用信息的文化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我代表董事会，我们承认政府的担忧。我们将非常努力地实现我们在资产管理方面所承诺的目标。”欧阳表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是在 2019 年反政府抗议活动最激烈的时候以及在面对香港最昂贵的铁路项目——沙田至中环铁路线的建设丑闻，欧阳表示，该公司一直在寻求改进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“港铁完美吗？”他说。 “不。它还有改进的空间。因此，我们需要继续寻找方法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧阳看到了来自大陆的更多机会，他说大陆很快就会有关于交通主导的发展计划的“一些好消息”，并且正在寻找至少两个在已有的 22 个铁路项目的基础上，又新增了一些城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我相信您已经听说过这种 TOD（以交通为导向的开发），这是世界各地每个人都在谈论的概念。如果你问我的话，这就是港铁正在寻找的东西，尤其是大湾区。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港港铁公司耗资 650 亿港元的维护计划可能会脱轨。原因如下&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;至于跨境高铁服务，他表示，广深港高铁香港段每天的旅客吞吐量为5万至6万人次，而2019年的这一数字仍远低于10万人次。在大流行之前，他称之为相当美好的一天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及该铁路是否仍未得到充分利用且财务状况不佳时，他说：“我建议不要仅从财务角度来看待它，相反，我从整体经济发展的角度来看，它确实打通了香港与中国许多地方的桥梁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，目标是让港铁公司在香港的发展中发挥更大的作用。湾区是一个新兴经济增长引擎，人口至少为 8600 万，旨在将九个内地城市与香港和澳门连接起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港将于周日重新开通通往中国内地的高铁服务&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在谈到其国际业务时，他表示：“我们目前拥有国际市场，这些市场具有悠久的历史。对于我们现在面临的所有地缘政治问题，我严格从商业角度来看待它。我们从那个市场得到什么？这是我们想要跟随的市场还是我们想要留下来的市场？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他没有具体说明哪些海外单位正在受到审查，但指出，尽管有些个别单位受到了影响，但整体投资组合表现良好。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司由香港政府持有 75% 的股份，还在内地和澳门以及英国、瑞典和澳大利亚等海外地区经营铁路服务。这些业务去年的收入整体增长 3.9%，达到 260.1 亿港元，占公司去年总收入 478.1 亿港元的 54%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扣除利息、财务费用、税项及税后利润去年，可变年度付款（即息税前利润）较 2021 年跃升 54.7%，达到 9.62 亿港元，占该公司去年深圳铁路项目非经常性亏损之前 28.5 亿港元总额的三分之一。 /p>;&lt;p>;“我在街上听到一些评论，国际企业转移或分散了资源。不，这不是事实，因为我们并没有拿走任何香港资源并将其投入国际市场，从而损害了本地业务，一点也没有，”他说。 “香港是我们的菲力牛排，我不能忽视香港业务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的国际业务是有利可图的，但当你把它切成小块时，有些业务需要更多我称之为踢球，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政会议召集人、资深立法会议员叶刘淑仪自 2019 年以来一直敦促该公司放弃海外业务，专注于香港本土，告诉《华盛顿邮报》，该公司的一些海外业务是多余的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着大量与北部都会区和交椅洲人工岛有关的大型铁路项目正在酝酿中，[港铁公司]资源将全面紧张。它应该避免员工超载，并避免通过无利可图和多余的海外投资来分散他们对这些时间紧迫的项目的注意力，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;港铁公司将让牡蛎湾项目“对开发商尽可能有吸引力”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;欧阳还透露了沙田至中环铁路线的争议，一周前，当政府表示警方的刑事调查仍在继续，律政司已寻求裁判法院复核判决时，争议出现了转折。部分伪劣工程涉及罪魁祸首礼顿承包商（亚洲）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“档案尚未结案，”他说。 “我们的工作是继续向他们提供他们需要的信息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起丑闻于 2018 年曝光，导致额外成本 100 亿港元，使其成为香港最昂贵的铁路项目耗资 907 亿港元，延误了两年多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们作为一家企业从这次情况中学到了很多东西，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Heavy rains and floods swamp northeast US as record-breaking temperatures hit the south]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227930/heavy-rains-and-floods-swamp-northeast-us-record-breaking-temperatures-hit-south?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 07:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/9f2c0355-e3fe-4acd-8fc8-d97ed9d9fa2a_db5db137.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周日，大雨再次袭击了已经饱和的美国东北部地区。一周，引发了另一轮山洪爆发、航班取消和停电。在宾夕法尼亚州，周六下午晚些时候突然发生的山洪夺去了至少四人的生命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宾夕法尼亚州巴克斯县上梅克菲尔德镇的官员表示，周六华盛顿十字路口地区的暴雨冲走了几辆汽车。当局称，至少四人死亡，另外三人失踪，其中包括一名 9 个月大的男孩和一名 2 岁的女孩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东海岸的其他地区正在经历大雨，包括佛蒙特州。那里的当局表示，周日山体滑坡可能会成为一个问题，因为该州在连续几天的洪水之后将面临更多的降雨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着佛蒙特州降雨量的增加，我和我的团队将继续监测局势。今天全州都有山洪警报。佛蒙特州州长 Phil Scott 表示，保持警惕并做好准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据跟踪服务 FlightAware 称，周日的强风暴导致纽约地区机场数百个航班取消。仅新泽西州纽瓦克自由国际机场就有超过350个航班被取消，纽约肯尼迪国际机场也有超过280个航班被取消。数百架航班也被延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家气象局向康涅狄格州、马萨诸塞州西部、佛蒙特州和新罕布什尔州的部分地区发布了山洪警报和龙卷风警报。马萨诸塞州和新罕布什尔州边境地区发布了龙卷风警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区还报告了数千起停电事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约州州长凯西·霍赫尔（Kathy Hochul）敦促人们留下来周日不要开车，直到暴风雨过去。目前还没有该州暴风雨和洪水造成人员伤亡的立即报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在新泽西州北部，一些道路于周日关闭，工作人员正在修复在压力下弯曲的混凝土碎片。大雨和洪水。当地的小溪冲垮了通道，岩石滑坡堵塞了 46 号公路沿线的通道。道路上一片狼藉，岩石上覆盖着棕色污泥。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“炎热而危险的周末”：全球热浪将美国烧焦至亚洲和欧洲&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在宾夕法尼亚州，一场突如其来的倾盆大雨在上梅克菲尔德镇造成了致命的后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消防队长蒂姆·布鲁尔 (Tim Brewer) 告诉记者，该地区的气温约为 6 点半到 7 点。 45 分钟内降雨量达 1 英寸（约 18 厘米）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时路上约有 11 辆汽车，其中 3 辆被冲走。布鲁尔说，路面上有大约 4 到 5 英尺的积水。布鲁尔说，截至周日中午，四人的尸体已被找到，三人（一名妇女和两个孩子）仍然失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;八人从汽车中获救，两人从小溪中获救。他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;远至北卡罗来纳州南部，一名 49 岁妇女的死亡被归咎于洪水，周六深夜，她的汽车被冲出亚历山大县的道路。与她同车的一名男子获救。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，佛蒙特州正在开展最近几天大雨后的恢复工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佛蒙特州交通局表示，12 州道路仍然关闭，12 条道路部分开放，其中一条车道部分开放，87 条之前关闭的道路已重新开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强降水并不是困扰美国的唯一极端天气。席卷美国西南部的灼热热浪已使大约三分之一的美国人处于某种类型的高温监视或警告之下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括地球上最热的地方——死亡谷的严酷气温，该地区沿美国部分地区延伸加利福尼亚州中部与内华达州的边界。周日，拉斯维加斯也面临着达到历史最高气温纪录的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，美国环境保护局向从蒙大拿州到俄亥俄州的几个州发布了空气质量警报，因为从加拿大山火。纽约州州长霍楚尔表示，由于野火，她预计纽约州北部和西部地区将于周一发布空气质量警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“空气质量警报已在纽约州大部分地区发布。五大湖、中西部和北部高原，”国家气象局（NWS）表示。 “这是由于加拿大野火烟雾在这些地区持续浓浓。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;厄尔尼诺现象和气候变化相结合，使世界陷入热浪：科学家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;南加州人，他们看到NWS 表示，周六气温最高可达 41-43 摄氏度（105-110 华氏度），接下来第二天也会出现类似的严酷气温，加利福尼亚州、内华达州和亚利桑那州部分地区的气温预计将达到 46 度。 p>;&lt;p>;到周六下午，地球上最热的地方之一加利福尼亚州著名的死亡谷已经达到了危及生命的 51 度。第二天，午后气温徘徊在 47.7 度左右，预计最高温度可能达到 53 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;游客们参观了国家公园，以一睹国家气象局警告的“威胁生命的气候” “白天的高温”将持续到周二晚上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家气象局表示，高温是美国与天气相关的头号杀手，并敦促美国人认真对待这一风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“截至今天凌晨，从南佛罗里达州、墨西哥湾沿岸到西南部，总共有超过 8000 万人处于高温警告或高温警告之下，”国家气象局在周日早上的公告中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;当局连日来一直拉响警报，建议人们避免白天户外活动，避免脱水，在这样的温度下，脱水很快就会致命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在主要城市，热浪发生的频率越来越高，强度也越来越大。根据联邦环境保护局的数据，美国城市在 2010 年代和 2020 年代每年发生六次，而 1960 年代每年两次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种热浪不是典型的沙漠高温，” NWS 拉斯维加斯办事处周四在推特上指出，“其持续时间长、白天极端温度和温暖的夜晚”是不寻常的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加拿大，气候温暖，加上几个月的降雨量低于平均水平，周六，2023 年迄今为止，毁灭性野火烧毁的土地面积已攀升至 2,470 万英亩（1,000 万公顷），创历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们发现今年的数字比加拿大自然资源部研究员 Yan Boulanger 告诉法新社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然很难将特定的天气事件归因于气候变化，但科学家坚持认为与人类有关全球变暖是热浪倍增和加剧的原因。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand PM Chris Hipkins says Pacific region less secure due to China’s assertiveness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3227931/new-zealand-pm-chris-hipkins-says-pacific-region-less-secure-due-chinas-assertiveness?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 08:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/a2a49e50-1806-45f9-a803-9aab679bd756_94563801.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着中国变得更加自信，太平洋地区变得更具争议性和不安全性，新新西兰总理克里斯·希普金斯 (Chris Hipkins) 周一表示，他概述了该国需要与志同道合的伙伴合作，同时仍与北京保持接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的崛起及其寻求施加影响力的方式是日益增长的影响力的主要推动力。希普金斯在奥克兰中国商业峰会上发表讲话时表示，战略竞争，尤其是在印太地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的地区正变得更具竞争性、更难以预测、更不安全，”他说。 “这给像新西兰这样的小国带来了挑战，因为我们的繁荣和安全依赖国际规则的稳定性和可预测性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种关系需要谨慎管理，但中国仍然是重要的贸易伙伴，他说。补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;希普金斯在年度活动上发表讲话不到一个月，他率领贸易代表团成功访问了新西兰最大的贸易伙伴中国，他在中国面临一些国内批评，因为他在人类问题上没有那么直言不讳。正如一些人所预料的那样，权利和其他问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这个日益复杂的全球环境中，我们与中国的关系将继续需要谨慎管理，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰总理不同意习近平称习近平不是“独裁者”，与拜登合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;惠灵顿历史上对中国采取的态度比澳大利亚或其其他五眼安全伙伴、加拿大、美国和英国更为和解。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“共同的利益和关切并不意味着我们将始终采取相同的做法。有时采取不同的方法可以达到相同的结果，从而发挥战术优势。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平告诉希普金斯，中国和新西兰应该是“伙伴，而不是对手”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国驻新西兰大使王小龙在致辞中表示，中新关系健康、稳定、蓬勃发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于中新关系的不同，两国之间存在分歧并不奇怪。我们各自的情况。但我们不同社会制度和发展水平的国家不能和平共处并非必然，”他在希普金斯峰会后发表的讲话中说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Protectionism not the answer for an Indian manufacturing sector in need of support and investment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227704/protectionism-not-answer-indian-manufacturing-sector-need-support-and-investment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/16/f89f2a1d-5e4f-4fa2-9d24-3f192d56593f_b9ab5209.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;塔塔日立 (Tata Hitachi) 董事总经理桑迪普·辛格 (Sandeep Singh) 在 6 月份呼吁进行公平竞争印度建筑设备市场领域。塔塔日立 (Tata Hitachi) 是印度最大的跨国集团之一塔塔 (Tata) 与日本日立 (Hitachi) 的合资企业，生产和销售挖掘机、装载机和其他建筑设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辛格谈到中国企业“闻所未闻”的低价竞争，他说，中国品牌已经垄断了印度建筑设备市场近20%的份额。他的言论是在一个微妙的时刻发表的，正如印度外交部长苏杰生所说，印度对中国智能手机制造商进行打压之后，印中关系“不正常”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;顶级行业机构印度建筑设备制造商协会（ICEMA）表示，印度建筑设备行业在土方、材料装卸和其他产品领域面临着来自廉价进口产品的竞争。据ICEMA称，印度建筑设备行业位居世界第三，仅次于中国和美国。但它在全球出口中所占的份额远远落后于第三位&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度建筑设备市场的激烈竞争是该行业令人印象深刻的增长的结果。由于政府持续关注基础设施开发和采矿业，上一财年建筑设备销售额同比增长 26%，所有细分市场的年销售额突破 10 万台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singh 表示，建筑设备制造业业界已要求中央政府调查此事，并帮助缓解中国企业涌入的影响。他表示，希望能有“一个能够保护塔塔日立、JCB、现代、沃尔沃和 Larsen &amp; Toubro 等制造商利益的解决方案”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府的回应将充分说明其长期目标尤其是建筑设备行业的愿景，更广泛地说，是印度发展成为下一个全球制造中心的愿景。保护主义可能是一个快速解决办法，但这不一定是印度前进的最佳出路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府不应诉诸保护主义，而应解决建筑设备行业的制造问题，”巴尔德夫·赖辛哈尼 (Baldev Raisinghani) 表示, an industry veteran, adviser to Kram Infracon and former president of the Jaypee Group, one of India&#39;s leading contracting companies. “Only the fittest will survive in a tough market, and to be fit, domestic companies need inexpensive core enablers of manufacturing. That&#39;s where the government should step in.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;India&#39;s crackdown on Xiaomi just the first step in its economic strategy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Logistics costs are 14 to 16 per cent of India&#39;s gross domestic product, roughly double the 8 per cent global average. India has expanded its road network by about 30km per day during the past year while also focusing on creating waterways, a cheaper form of transport. Going forward, a national logistics policy and the PM Gati Shakti initiative are expected to cut logistics costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other challenges facing the Indian construction equipment industry are rising interest rates, high steel and other commodity prices, and power shortages. Last year, high steel prices were implicated in elevated product costs and the lower-than-expected demand for construction equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another gap to be bridged is the localised content in construction equipment, which is only 50 per cent, according to the ICEMA. This suggests the industry is still dependent on imports for critical components.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While localisation is a gradual process for any company, full localisation covers both product and people. For instance, Zoomlion India, a subsidiary of a Chinese firm that produces mobile cranes, tower cranes, earth-moving, foundation and concrete construction equipment, started to localise in 2018 “after sensing a uptick in the business opportunities in India”, said the firm&#39;s business director Danish Kamal Lari.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zoomlion&#39;s localisation started with training and appointing Indian staff to key technological positions in keeping with its vision of establishing “a local entity with local operations with the support of the Chinese principal”, Lari said. Now the focus is on localising products, with the firm moving to establish a manufacturing plant near Pune.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raisinghani said localisation should be a government focus. To this end, “a dedicated production-linked incentive scheme for the construction equipment industry would encourage investment from domestic as well as global manufacturers, thereby helping the industry reduce import content and enhance capacity to meet the growing demand effectively and realise its full potential,” said Dimitrov Krishnan, ICEMA president and managing director at Volvo CE India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In particular, encouraging investment in the development of more environmentally friendly products could help India achieve its commitment to cut its emissions to net zero by 2070. In May, Minister for Road Transport and Highways Nitin Gadkari called for the development of construction equipment running on alternative fuels or electricity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Widening the portfolio of construction equipment made in India would plug gaps in the existing array as well as boost manufacturing, a highly desirable goal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manufacturing, which accounts for merely 17 per cent of India&#39;s gross domestic product, has been floundering of late. It grew a paltry 1.3 per cent in the last financial year and 3.4 per cent in the last five years. Meanwhile, China accounted for 30 per cent of global manufacturing output in 2021, 10 per cent higher than a decade previously.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scale is frequently cited as China&#39;s strength. For India to achieve a similar scale – or for that matter, for it to evolve as an Asian alternative to Chinese low-cost manufacturing – it cannot afford to go slow in creating a more enabling business environment. Neither should it turn away brands with a vision to grow, in every sense of the word, in India, no matter where they come from.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Chinese entities are turning to People’s Daily censorship AI to avoid political mines]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227876/why-chinese-entities-are-turning-peoples-daily-censorship-ai-avoid-political-mines?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/16/6afe43b9-b7fb-40d0-9226-226cd18c320e_7778988e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;There are many ways Chinese companies, public institutes and celebrities can find themselves in hot water when posting content online for public consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A map that misrepresents Beijing&#39;s South China Sea claims, the unintended inclusion of a disgraced official in a picture, or any hint of an obscure political taboo can lead to consequences, as a number of cases in recent years has shown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s internet regulator can impose penalties, including hefty fines, and a business can be partially suspended without warning. For singers, film stars and television personalities, careers can be ended by an online slip.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To make matters worse, perceived offenders can be boycotted by angry internet users. The online community is also policed by nationalistic voices and even business competitors looking for the chance to torpedo a rival.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation has led to the emergence of content moderation with Chinese characteristics, with numerous data companies available to screen material before it reaches the public sphere.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People&#39;s Daily – mouthpiece of the ruling Communist Party and arguably best placed to identify Beijing&#39;s shifting and often vague red lines – is also offering to sell its expertise to companies wishing to eliminate potential political risks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s internet watchdog to boost tip-offs to stamp out &#39;illegal&#39; content&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Its product Renmin Shenjiao was launched in July last year, just months before the 20th party congress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s growing market for outsourced content censorship and the heavy focus on political sensitivities come amid the party&#39;s push in recent years for ideological dominance and conformity, according to observers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like other countries, violence, pornography and hate speech are unacceptable on Chinese social media. But, while the power to control content is more diverse in the West, in China it is concentrated in the hands of the ruling party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The increasing reliance on external pre-screening by Chinese government agencies, state-owned enterprises and private companies offers a glimpse into their struggle to avoid political red lines that are not always explicit until they are crossed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the different approaches to content moderation, observers said all countries had one thing in common – the growing volume and complexity of material meant artificial intelligence would inevitably replace human eyes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to some estimates, the amount of data generated each day by social media globally could reach 463 billion gigabytes by 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Entertainment, media in China set to drive US$479.9 billion in revenue: PwC&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Already, the social media management platform Hootsuite puts Twitter&#39;s daily active users at 238 million, with at least 500 million tweets per day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2013, state-owned Beijing News reported that an estimated two million people in China were employed to manually monitor and analyse online content.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the United States, Facebook had about 15,000 content moderators in 2020, while Chinese tech firm ByteDance reportedly employs more than 20,000 in that role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Artificial Intelligence is already used in China and other countries to help with the task, though Renmin Shenjiao – which means People&#39;s Proofreading – assures potential customers that it also uses human censors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Advertisements for the product which appeared in People&#39;s Daily in June said Renmin Shenjiao&#39;s services include screening of written materials, photos, videos, and posts on social media platforms, including WeChat and Weibo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A sales handout for potential clients seen by the South China Morning Post lists an annual fee of between 46,000 yuan and 99,000 yuan (US$6,400-$13,700), depending on how much material needs to be screened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clients upload material to the platform for review by AI and a team of censors. Content that could be flagged as risky includes material related to ideology, religion, purged government officials, Chinese dissidents, and maps related to disputed border areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the sales document, animations of government leaders, content related to their relatives, and references to disgraced celebrities would also be picked up as potential risks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Renmin Shenjiao sales representative said clients included public institutions and state-owned enterprises, as well as a smaller number of private companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not rare for businesses in China to find themselves under fire when their content is deemed to overstep a political red line.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the show of China&#39;s most popular e-commerce influencer Li Jiaqi came to an abrupt end on June 3.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While he later said the suspension was due to a “technical error” there was speculation that authorities forced Li to end the show after he displayed an ice-cream shaped like a tank – an image associated with the Tiananmen Square crackdown on June 4, 1989.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Lipstick King&#39; Li Jiaqi a no-show at scheduled live stream on Sunday&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A Beijing-based entrepreneur in the chat AI industry said any content or communication-related business in China ha to go through content moderation to survive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Any ads that you see have been checked or otherwise they will just not survive. The market has always been there, and AI has been used in content moderation software for a long time,” said the entrepreneur, who asked not to be identified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stepping on Beijing&#39;s political red lines, even unintentionally, could prove very costly to any company and could add to the already difficult and competitive business environment, the entrepreneur said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s cyberspace watchdog to &#39;clean up&#39; internet, fight &#39;hostile forces&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Most content moderation software is provided by China&#39;s major tech companies, which feed in regular updates on new rules or sensitive topics and events, according to the entrepreneur.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tech companies Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post, and Tencent provide content moderation under their cloud services units.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent Cloud&#39;s AI algorithm models can be applied to platforms, including live-streaming sites, to identify videos, photos, audio and texts. Alibaba&#39;s counterpart service covers photos and texts, and identifies spam as well as political and other sensitive content.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Renmin Shenjiao&#39;s algorithm generally might not be as strong as its tech company rivals, the idea is that it will be better at filtering political content, according to a person with knowledge of the product.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was because Renmin Shenjiao staff were part of the People&#39;s Daily group, and may have knowledge of new taboos that were otherwise not known to the public, the person said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts caution that the rising demand for political content screening services is a worrying sign of China&#39;s tightening information environment. The boundary is also evolving, with more ambiguity regarding new taboos, they say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fact that the services were so openly marketed suggested “the internal politics of party operations are becoming increasingly controlled as the Xi Jinping era progresses”, said Neil Thomas, a fellow in Chinese politics at the Asia Society Policy Institute&#39;s Centre for China Analysis.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Meta&#39;s Threads tops China&#39;s App Store despite Great Firewall ban&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Thomas&#39; view, the aim is to ensure “greater ideological conformity within the party state”. He noted that content moderation in China had a focus on political sensitivity, while Xi “places great value on political correctness”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thomas said the increasing demand for absolute ideological uniformity was also affecting private firms, as scrutiny and the risk of something going wrong extended beyond government agencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everyone is expected to toe the party line in their public statements and the political risk for private firms of being even accidentally unaligned with Xi Jinping Thought is steadily increasing,” he said, referring to Xi&#39;s political doctrine that was enshrined in the country&#39;s constitution in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Companies that want to maximise profit will rationally acquire content moderation services that minimise the risk of overstepping political boundaries or being out of sync with Xi Jinping Thought.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think this shows that China is the global centre of censorship and China is at the forefront of innovation when it comes to new ways to strengthen the censorship process.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Thomas, the repercussions of political comment on social media in the West come mostly from citizens with different ideologies, resulting in a populist backlash rather than official or legal sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Political risks are issues that companies face everywhere. It&#39;s just that in China, the level, the intensity and the explicit legal consequences of straying from political correctness are much greater than in the West,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s net watchdog pledges fast lane for businesses to report online slander&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rana Mitter, a professor of the history and politics of modern China with the University of Oxford, said many countries automated the process of moderating social media as much as possible “and put the responsibility in the hands of the user, not the state”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The difference is that in China, the motivation and the impetus is coming from the party itself, top-down. In the liberal world, it&#39;s coming from companies like Meta, Alphabet and so forth,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mitter said one of the primary goal&#39;s of Beijing&#39;s content moderation regime “is to make sure that the ideological dominance of the CCP – which is now very strong in China – continues to operate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nationalistic blogger Sima Nan banned from Chinese social media&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He noted that the demand for content moderation also came amid concerns about controlling nationalist ideas in China, with some netizens appearing to be more nationalist than the government, which right now might “look to be a bit more subtle, more nuanced” in its relations with other countries like the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mitter said China&#39;s information environment had tightened over the past decade, and that “there is a very strong top-down demand from the party in the government that the language, particularly around politics but also [the more broadly defined] cultural issues must be very heavily censored”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mitter predicted that outsourced content moderation service would become more widely used, even by individuals, when ambiguity arose. “[What] the party state considers sensitive is sensitive,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Right now, the definition of what is &#39;security sensitive&#39; in China is being expanded very significantly. But also the lines are not being drawn clearly. The problem is that&#39;s going to be very chilling to atmospheres of entrepreneurship and innovation,” Mitter said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lynette Ong, a political-science professor at the University of Toronto, said the tight environment was reinforced by “a certain degree of mass mobilisation”, with the rise of online nationalism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This could be seen when people online adopted jubao – the act of accusing and reporting what they consider wrongdoings to authorities, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ong, who has researched content moderation in China, noted that People&#39;s Daily and other state media, such as state news agency Xinhua, had commercial entities that provided screening services to clients, ranging from different levels of party committees to universities, government agencies, as well as police and courts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;For China, ChatGPT is an advance but also an &#39;ethical problem&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Thomas, from the Asia Society, said the human content moderators offered by Renmin Shenjiao “adds a layer of political safety to companies … that they might not be able to get from other providers”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Human speech is complex and humorous and subversive, and content can be hard to detect. So the proliferation of content moderation technologies is never going to eliminate the need for human censors to help implement the parties policies in this regard,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But the advent of new technologies is part of the reason why Beijing is investing in the official content moderation technologies – to try to reduce the burden of censorship work which currently requires huge amounts of human resources that could be better deployed elsewhere.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Beijing-based executive from a leading technology consulting firm said it would always be easy for AI to discern “factual mistakes” – such as an inexact quotation of the leader&#39;s doctrine, or an unwitting mention of an official under investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was more difficult for technology to screen and judge if someone was expressing dissent in a subtle way, the executive said, adding that AI may not be able to identify sensitivities in advance.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why a joke about the PLA has got China&#39;s stand-up comics worried&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A recent example cited by the executive was entertainment group Shanghai Xiaoguo Culture Media, which was punished after its stand-up comedian Li Haoshi joked about a popular PLA slogan in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The entertainment group was banned from performing in Beijing and fined 13 million yuan (US$1.9 million), while the PLA slogan has already become a sensitive topic that is screened by many censorship software products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only those with a sensitivity to news might be able to identify whether something might hit the “red lines” in scenarios like this, the executive said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Jun Mai&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s I&T strategy must keep quality of life at its heart]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227820/hong-kongs-it-strategy-must-keep-quality-life-its-heart?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/15/6371b2f9-556b-48da-8d6c-a04e819b2920_10e4691b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The wheels seem to finally be turning for Hong Kong, at least on the innovation and technology front. In what Secretary for Innovation, Technology and Industry Sun Dong described as “a big gift from the country to celebrate the 26th anniversary of Hong Kong&#39;s return to Chinese rule”, it will soon be easier for data to flow from mainland locations in the Greater Bay Area to Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This came about after the signing of a memorandum of understanding between the Hong Kong government and the Cyberspace Administration of China. Exactly how the data flow will happen is being developed by the Hong Kong and mainland authorities and will be unveiled within a few months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are details such as privacy protection to iron out, but as Sun noted, it took years of negotiations to loosen restrictions on data flow, at least for the Greater Bay Area. Cross-border data transfer involving banking and personal care information is essential to realising the central government&#39;s plans to develop Hong Kong into an international innovation and technology (I&amp;T) centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “big gift” of data is just one of several pieces that must fall into place for Hong Kong to realise its I&amp;T potential. The city is playing catch-up after watching Shenzhen transform into a tech powerhouse in just two decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The San Tin Technopole is already in the works and is just a stone&#39;s throw away from Shenzhen. The Hong Kong-Shenzhen Innovation and Technology Park and the Shenzhen Innovation and Technology Zone are only separated by the Shenzhen River. The potential for synergy is enormous.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The San Tin Technopole project in the northern New Territories is expected to take 10 to 15 years to come to fruition with the potential for 215,000 jobs to be created in the area. The San Tin Town Centre is billed as “a self-sufficient, integrated neighbourhood with comprehensive public and community facilities including an iconic recreational and cultural complex”. The area is expected to “also provide daily support to those working and residing in the I&amp;T park”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Are the government&#39;s plans truly ready to make San Tin the city&#39;s first self-contained new town that serves as a model community for healthy, green living, offering better work-life balance and bigger homes in addition to being the engine of I&amp;T development?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on the brief the government has given lawmakers, 50,000 housing units, of which 70 per cent are earmarked as public housing units not meant for these new workers, seems woefully inadequate for this new community. One of the biggest hurdles in Hong Kong&#39;s quest to attract talent is housing, and not just home prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Size, proximity to work, access to facilities and community all play a role. To truly create a vibrant I&amp;T community that attracts talent, investors and businesses, the government must learn from past mistakes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It must look long and hard at what went wrong with Tin Shui Wai, once known as “the city of sadness”. Its size, isolated location, high concentration of public housing, and lack of job opportunities all forced residents to sacrifice time and money to commute, contributing to a town planning failure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For everything riding on the San Tin Technopole, the government cannot afford to get it wrong. The jobs, homes and community have to be in place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po has been busy, too, recently hinting at more good news for the city&#39;s I&amp;T development after his trip to Shanghai to woo leading technology companies and start-ups to set up shop in Hong Kong. He wrote on his blog: “In terms of attracting enterprises and investment, we have received a lot of positive responses.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All this encouraging news will help keep the momentum going for the government, which must make it a priority to continue to restore the buzz around Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Targeted work, such as that of the Office for Attracting Strategic Enterprises, tasked with luring investment and business in strategic industries, will pay off only if we are also ready to incubate the talent and families who will be the core of the I&amp;T strategy that will drive the economic growth our government is expecting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pod of more than 50 pilot whales dies after mass stranding on Scottish beach]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227928/pod-more-50-pilot-whales-dies-after-mass-stranding-scottish-beach?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 05:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/db404bac-cb61-408f-9e65-98383c14cd06_b124c93e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A pod of more than 50 pilot whales has died following a mass stranding on a Scottish beach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marine rescuers were called to the scene at Traigh Mhor in North Tolsta, on the Isle of Lewis, to reports that dozens of the mammals were in difficulty there at around 7am local time on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Initial reports suggested there were around 55 animals consisting of both adults and calves, however it was soon discovered that only 15 were still alive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Charity British Divers Marine Life Rescue (BDMLR) tried to refloat two of the more active whales that were still low down in the water on the outgoing tide and one got away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However the other subsequently restranded and died later on, as did three others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At around 3:30pm it was decided that the remaining whales should be euthanised on welfare grounds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cause of the stranding is not known but it is thought the pod may have followed one of the females.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A statement from BDMLR said: “One of the dead whales appeared to have had a vaginal prolapse – so it&#39;s currently suspected that the whole pod stranded due to one female giving birth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Pilot whales are notorious for their strong social bonds, so often when one whale gets into difficulty and strands, the rest follow.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The coastguard, Scottish Fire and Rescue Service, police and Scottish Marine Animal Stranding Scheme (SMASS) were also at the scene on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Western Isles Council said it had officers at the scene.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s second whale sighting in 2 days as experts say give animals peace&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;BDMLR added: “At about 3:30pm, the local vet along with the coastguard, fire and rescue, and a forensics vet came to the conclusion that the shallow beach and rough wave conditions made it too unsafe to refloat the remaining animals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Considering how long the pilot whales had been out of the water in addition to the poor conditions, it was decided that they should be euthanised on welfare grounds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;d like to extend our thanks to the Lewis community, Stornoway Coastguard, police, Stornoway and Shawbost Fire and Rescue, SMASS, SSPCA, Civil Air Support, CalMac and of course our dedicated team of medics who all came together in their efforts to rescue these whales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A sad outcome for this pod and obviously not the outcome we were all hoping for.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SMASS will now carry out postmortem examinations on the whales to investigate why they stranded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pilot whales are small whales characterised as part of the dolphin family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A coastguard spokesman said: “HM Coastguard assisted British Divers Marine Life Rescue this morning following reports of around 50 stranded mammals on Traigh Mhor, Isle of Lewis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Alerted at around 7:40am, Stornoway, Bragar and Ness Coastguard rescue teams were sent to the scene to provide safety cover. Police Scotland and the Scottish Fire and Rescue Service were also in attendance.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘First’ Captagon lab found in Iraq, says country’s interior ministry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3227926/first-captagon-lab-found-iraq-says-countrys-interior-ministry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 04:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/ecd57c94-c588-442d-a4ef-2f53e0d9d0f2_6d0874bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Iraq said on Sunday it has found a site in a province bordering Saudi Arabia where Captagon is produced, a rare discovery in a country that has become a transit route for the illicit drug.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, and maybe for the first time, a laboratory where Captagon is produced was found,” interior ministry spokesman General Saad Maan said in a video posted online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iraq has long been a transit country for Captagon, the amphetamine-like stimulant plaguing the Middle East, but officials say it has also become a consumer market for the drug.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Iraq seizes three million Captagon pills on Syria border&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The laboratory was discovered in the southern province of Muthana, a statement from the ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oil-rich Saudi Arabia is believed to be the largest market for the drug.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry did not announce any arrests but said the site contained machines capable of producing Captagon pills as well as 27.5kg of raw materials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vast majority of the region&#39;s Captagon, which derives its name from a once-legal drug used to combat narcolepsy, is produced in Syria – another Iraqi neighbour – and Lebanon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iraqi authorities have stepped up raids that have netted large amounts of Captagon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Sunday&#39;s announcement appears to be a game changer, according to Maan, who said finding the laboratory shows that there is a “bid by some to launch (Captagon) production in the country”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Iraqi security forces said they had dismantled an “international drug trafficking ring” and arrested three of its members in Muthana province. Two million Captagon pills were also seized.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Syria said at an Arab foreign ministers meeting in May that it was ready to “strengthen cooperation” with Jordan and Iraq, “affected by drug-trafficking and smuggling across the Syrian border”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Areas in central and southern Iraq bordering Iran have become major narcotic trafficking routes for drugs, including crystal methamphetamine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2022, Iraqi security forces announced the arrest of a man producing “large quantities of crystal meth” in Iraq with fabrication skills acquired abroad.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tunisia and EU sign pact to stem migration and combat human trafficking]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3227925/tunisia-and-eu-sign-pact-stem-migration-and-combat-human-trafficking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 04:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/e5ec6e19-60ed-4667-b59c-2f8ca3660e55_36b0c49c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Tunisia and the European Union on Sunday signed a “strategic partnership” deal that includes combating human traffickers and tightening borders during a sharp increase in boats leaving the North African nation for Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deal follows weeks of talks and Europe&#39;s pledge of major aid to Tunisia amounting to 1 billion (US$1.12 billion) to help its battered economy, rescue state finances and deal with a migration crisis. Most funds are contingent on economic reforms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It contains agreements on disrupting the business model of people smugglers and human traffickers, strengthening border control and improving registration and return. All essential measures for bolstering efforts to stop irregular migration,” Netherlands&#39; Prime Minister Mark Rutte said on Twitter. Rutte resigned on July 7 after Netherlands&#39; ruling coalition failed to agree on migration policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European Commission chief Ursula von der Leyen said the bloc will allocate 100 million (US$112 million) to Tunisia to help it combat illegal migration. The deal promotes macroeconomic stability, trade and investment, green energy transition and legal immigration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of undocumented African migrants have flocked to the city of Sfax in recent months seeking to head for Europe in traffickers&#39; boats, amounting to an unprecedented migration crisis for Tunisia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are very pleased, it is a further important step towards creation of a true partnership between Tunisia and the EU, which can address in an integrated fashion the migration crisis,” Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dutch prime minister resigns amid dispute over migration policy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meloni, whose country has suffered a sharp increase in immigration boats, said there would be an international conference on migration in Rome next Sunday with a number of heads of state, including Tunisian President Kais Saied.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 75,065 boat migrants had reached Italy by July 14 against 31,920 in the same period last year, official data showed. More than half left from Tunisia, overtaking Libya, which has traditionally been the main launch pad.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Saied said this month his country would not become a border guard for Europe.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>