<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Nodding head, blinking and opening mouth cost Chinese boy and grandfather US$2,800 in online ‘free gaming skins’ scam]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3223958/nodding-head-blinking-and-opening-mouth-cost-chinese-boy-and-grandfather-us2800-online-free-gaming?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/6e218019-f460-4198-9683-0105aadf220f_cf9370ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个试图从直播中收集“免费游戏皮肤”的中国男孩结束了20,000 元（2,800 美元）被网络诈骗者损失，再次引发了对中国游戏欺诈和儿童手机成瘾的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 10 岁的孩子住在中国中部河南省的农村，据河南电视台 6 月 8 日报道，5 月 23 日，小宇被骗从他祖父的银行账户转账。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小宇说他正在看快手直播-一名玩家在网易游戏开发的游戏蛋蛋派对上直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男孩被告知，通过使用微信应用程序扫描二维码，他可以免费获得游戏皮肤或角色外观，花费100多元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扫码后，小鱼收到错误提示，微信账号连同微信钱包里的钱全部冻结，除非他在期限内采取措施一个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他被要求在消息平台QQ上添加一个人以获取有关“措施”的说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小宇说那个人让他下载腾讯会议，中国版的 VooV 会议应用程序，以便他可以与该人分享他的手机屏幕以获得“更好的指示”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骗子随后指示小宇下载银联应用程序，这是中国统一的移动支付应用程序银行业，让他爷爷登录，查看他名下哪张卡有钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他们让小鱼扫描一系列二维码“解冻微信账号”，通过扫描&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的两万块钱，点点头、眨眼、张嘴就没了。”小宇的爷爷刘某在描述人脸识别流程时说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他用了10年的时间才攒够了这笔钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体上，此案再次引发了对儿童沉迷手机和游戏诈骗的担忧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国互联网络信息中心和互联网信息中心联合发布的一份报告，2021 年中国 6 至 18 岁的互联网用户估计有 1.91 亿，占该年龄段全国人口的 96.8%中国共青团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约有19.5%的受访未成年手机用户表示，他们在心理上对互联网有高度或适度依赖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京市青少年协会调查法律援助研究中心2021年调查显示，未成年人游戏成瘾倾向主要是由于游戏精心设计的激励机制、易受诱惑、来自同学的同伴压力和家长的疏忽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蛋蛋派对游戏2023年第一季度左右，在多个手机应用商店的游戏类应用排行榜上名列前茅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《每日电讯报》报道，该游戏以简单的玩法和可爱的设计深受中国未成年人欢迎中国财经媒体《深燃》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然从游戏皮肤中获利在游戏开发商中很普遍，但免费和廉价的皮肤也成为诈骗者最常用的骗取玩家钱财的工具之一。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;处理账户问题经验较少的未成年人很容易被诈骗者错误信息的严厉措辞吓到，成为他们敲诈勒索的受害者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Antony Blinken’s trip to China shows desire to re-engage, ‘avoid worst-case scenario’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224189/antony-blinkens-trip-china-shows-desire-re-engage-avoid-worst-case-scenario?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/ec8b45f6-f3b3-4d80-a549-b85e02baba95_0b08533a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯(Antony Blinken) 将就他的高风险会见高级官员本周末访问中国，但观察人士对两国关系取得重大突破的期望不大，尽管期待已久的访问表明两个大国希望重新接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿和北京周三均证实布林肯将于周日抵达中国进行为期两天的访问，这是五年来第一位进行此类访问的美国高级外交官。此行也是在布林肯因中国间谍气球进入美国领空发生争执而在最后一刻推迟计划访问四个月后进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据美国国务院称，布林肯将讨论维护的重要性开放沟通渠道以“负责任地管理”关系，同时提出双边关切的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“激烈的竞争需要激烈而强硬的外交，以确保竞争不会演变成对抗或冲突，这就是我们的目标发言人马修·米勒 (Matthew Miller) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;‘微妙的时机’：为什么布林肯的沙特阿拉伯之行是‘给中国的信息’&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;阿尔弗雷德·吴 (Alfred Wu)，副教授新加坡国立大学李光耀公共政策学院表示，周三早些时候布林肯与中国外长秦刚的通话将为美国官员的访问定下基调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国外交部的一份声明，秦就其核心关切告诉布林肯，美国应该“表现出尊重”，停止损害中国的主权、安全和发展利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，这次通话可能旨在让秦传达了北京在台湾问题上的立场：“秦需要确保布林肯了解此次访问的重要性，并了解中国的底线，即台湾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国关系陷入新的困境8 月份时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 访问了自治的台湾，尽管北京一再警告不要进行此类访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月份，两国关系进一步受到考验，当时美国击落了一个据称是中国间谍的气球，越境进入其领土，促使布林肯推迟了他的中国之行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国社会科学院美中关系专家卢翔表示，周三的交流很重要，并指出双方的语气双方似乎“相对克制”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别是，他说美国的宣读没有提到任何具体问题——例如台湾——只是笼统地说讨论了双边和全球问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我个人的感觉是，美国现在已经充分认识到，美中关系不仅处于最低点，而且处于高度敏感阶段——因此美国在此期间更加谨慎，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;卢说，人们还认识到，如果“紧张趋势”继续下去，美国总统乔·拜登可能成为自四十多年前关系正常化以来第一位不访问中国的美国领导人。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;本周末的出访也将使布林肯成为拜登政府首位访华的内阁级官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果拜登足够清醒，就会有一些鼓励校准美中关系。美中关系不仅仅是一个双边问题，而是一个全球问题，”卢补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着美中关系跌至新低，外交渠道是否仍然有效？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于庞四川大学国际事务教授钟颖表示，布林肯与秦的交流对美中关系来说是一个好消息，但仍存在不确定性和挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方都有强烈的愿望重新接触，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，华盛顿已经试图淡化取得突破的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们去北京的目的不是负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔·克里滕布林克 (Daniel Kritenbrink) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现实、自信的方法和真诚的愿望，以尽可能最负责任的方式管理我们的竞争。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kritenbrink 还期望布林肯“重申美国对维护台湾海峡和平与稳定的持久利益”， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢表示，布林肯的访问将使华盛顿更好地了解北京在台湾问题上的立场和“明确战略”，而新加坡的吴表示，主要目的是尽量减少冲突风险和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说：“这是为了避免最坏的情况发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清华大学国际安全与战略研究中心高级研究员周波经常说两个主要全球大国之间的接触通常看起来很正常，但考虑到最近美中关系的低谷，这种接触变得更加重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他警告说，虽然布林肯与中国高级官员的计划会晤等双边交流将周警告说，虽然有利，但两国关系的解冻效果不太可能显着。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几乎没有妥协的余地。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Class dismissed: worse to come for Hong Kong schools as closures loom amid falling births, migration]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3224217/class-dismissed-worse-come-hong-kong-schools-closures-loom-amid-falling-births-migration?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/f8be4f95-cfe1-47d7-9393-2d72c8b6c527_693c5f0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;家庭主妇郑思丽带着孩子与其他十几位父母和他们的孩子一起上个月就一所面临关闭威胁的学校向香港教育部长请愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这群人举着白色的大床单，上面写着“我爱宝欣”和“宝欣是我的家”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;新学年入读小一的学生不足 16 名，黄大仙宝仁献主小学的命运岌岌可危。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;低于最低人数意味着学校不再有资格获得政府补贴，这是一个信号，表明它必须关闭、与另一所学校合并或筹集大量资金以继续自己经营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现年 36 岁的 Cheng 是 Po Yan 的前学生，她自己有三个孩子，是侄子和侄女的法定监护人。其中三个孩子已经在学校上学，她希望她六岁的老二也能去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说学校也欢迎有特殊教育需要的孩子和少数民族孩子。对她患有轻度自闭症的 11 岁侄子照顾得很好，男孩的成绩在小一和小四之间稳步提高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我唯一喜欢的学校，”她说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 20 日当天，教育局局长蔡玉莲拒绝与在场的媒体见面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宝欣是五所被告知不会见面的小学之一在只有 15 名儿童入学，比政府的最低要求还差一个之后，从下一学年开始获得政府拨款开办小一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在 2017 年出生的 56,500 名儿童中只有 42,000 名报名参加小学之后今年在公立学校。近年来，随着移民潮的涌入，一些人已经不在这座城市了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着 2018 年以来出生的婴儿数量去年降至创纪录的 32,500 人，教育工作者预计情况会更糟。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上一次入学率下降袭击香港学校是在 2004 年至 2010 年间，当时有 90 多所小学关闭。公立学校数量从2000年初的600多所减少到今年的456所。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;学校选择“死胡同”？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港小一报名结果公布分两轮 - 在学年开始前一年的 9 月，然后在 6 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每年 9 月左右，想要将孩子送到公立学校的家长会在他们选择的学校注册。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一所学校必须有至少 16 名学生才有资格获得政府补贴以支付所有费用，包括教师的工资，并可以继续开办小一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些少于超过16名学生仍可获得小二及以上的资助，但必须在三年后关闭，届时所有剩余学生将转往其他学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校也可以选择自筹资金，即指集资开设小一班、与另一所学校合并或申请对学校进行检讨。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;学生人数下降的香港学校被促考虑合并以求生存&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 9 月轮次中没有找到名额的孩子会在 6 月通过中央分配及时分配到新学年的学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些家长对孩子的分配学校不满意，然后转向他们更喜欢的其他学校，希望能在那里找到一席之地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种最后一刻抢椅子的过程，通常被称为“敲门”，是可能的，因为所有学校都可以自行决定录取两个或小学一年级每班三个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着今年入学人数的急剧下降，政府于 5 月 30 日宣布将每班削减一个可自由支配名额，削减 1000 多个自由名额.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果家长把孩子搬出去，这将帮助不太受欢迎的学校面临失去学生和资源的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但代表教育界的立法会小学校长朱国强，说面临停课威胁的学校真的别无选择，因为所有的选择都是“死胡同”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，它一直在严厉打击学校，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港当局否决了 2 所入学人数不足的中学的生存计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;那些申请自办学校的人他说，获得资助的小一班必须证明他们在银行有至少 300 万港元（383,100 美元），以证明他们有能力支付教师工资和其他费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;选择他说，审查成功的希望很小。这个过程意味着要接受一组教育局官员在几天内的检查，并在各项绩效指标上获得“良好”评级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱说官员告诉他，很少有学校有过去在此类审查中幸存下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位代表学校理事会的校长在不愿透露姓名的情况下表示，教育当局推动合并的选择，作为应对入学率下降的一种方式，只是另一种选择&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“合并就是裁员，这只是让学校有序关闭的一种方式，”校长说。 “最终只有一个校园被使用，另一个必须关闭。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Po Yan 考虑关闭&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本月，Po Yan 向该局申请批准其申请失败了一项审查，这意味着它是面临裁员的五所学校中唯一一所考虑到 2026 年关闭的学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长洲基督教会长洲堂金刚小学和黄孔儒大盛小学大新在证明资金充足后，成功申请开办自费小一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救世军中原慈善基金学校正与救世军安伟利纪念学校商讨合并事宜。两者都在柴湾，属于同一个教会团体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后一所位于坚尼地城的圣查理斯学校，由于位于一个集水区，仍然有&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港中学表示，随着学生人数下降，班级规模应该缩减&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;宝欣是一所由宗教团体经营的拥有 58 年历史的天主教学校, 香港无玷圣母会, 位于黄大仙公共屋村的老年区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有44名教师, 多年来入学人数不断下降, 小一的人数班级从三班减少到一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这所学校以招收特殊教育需要 (SEN) 儿童而闻名，但这给一些家长留下了这不是一所好学校的印象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;校长余思伟在电台节目中感叹，学校在 3 月 31 日被告知无法开设小一班后，只有 20 天的时间来选择生存选项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校申请接受审查，但被拒绝了。其校友会随后联合起来筹款自费办小一班，但局方表示学校没有第二个选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说，薄颜早料到，由于其入学人数下降了一段时间，而同一地区的其他学校每年都成功地吸引了学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港教师移民，让有特殊需要的孩子为新员工而苦苦挣扎&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3 >;对特殊需要儿童的担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;接受《邮报》采访的校长普遍认为，鉴于人口数量不断减少，未来还有更多坏消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;名誉主席Langton Cheung Yung-pong香港资助小学校长会表示，学生人数下降严重，令教育界忧心忡忡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他促请政府在所有学校实施小班制，因为近五分之一的学校每个班级仍然有 30 名学生，而不是 25 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;招收非华裔学生和 SEN 儿童的学校的师生比例也可以提高，因为他们需要更多资源和人手照顾他补充说，这些学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung 说，如果主要招收 SEN 学生的学校被取消，这些孩子将流向其他可能没有照顾他们经验的学校。这意味着如果像宝欣这样的学校消失了，其他学校将承担后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果学校没有足够的受过SEN教学培训的教师，一旦孩子出现情绪问题或扰乱课堂秩序，课堂秩序将难以维持。 ，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特殊教育需要和家长协会（一个拥有近 700 名成员的家长支持组织）总干事戴银容说，只有像宝仁这样入学率低的学校， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有特殊教育需要的学生真的需要少一些学生的课堂环境”，她呼吁教育局在招生时将一名有特殊教育需要的孩子算作两名学生，让学校&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她担心如果像宝欣这样的学校关闭，其他没有照顾SEN孩子经验的学校可能不会收留他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，最终受害的是孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“全是中文”：香港少数族裔学生碰壁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于家庭主妇郑思丽来说， Po Yan 即将关闭是一个打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局官员打电话询问她是否愿意将她的三个大孩子搬出 Po Yan 时，她很生气，因为她最小的孩子无法上小学那里有一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府想要让我的四个孩子四处转学，只是因为这所学校只缺一个学生入学，”她说，并补充说她还没有为她的孩子选择另一所学校。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;她说，一些将有特殊需要的孩子送到所谓的精英学校的家长，很沮丧地发现他们的孩子被同学排斥，在那里不快乐。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的自信心在破岩增长了很多，因为老师们更多地关注弱势学生，用心去教书，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Uncertainty clouds Chinese millionaires who chased Australia’s golden visas: ‘Our life is a mess’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3224260/uncertainty-clouds-chinese-millionaires-who-chased-australias-golden-visas-our-life-mess?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/79a947ef-466b-434e-a028-b86f2d2e07a0_a01bea4c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;2018年Paul Wang离开北京老家去澳洲开始新的生活，投资 100 万澳元（680,000 美元）在一家食品加工企业，希望根据该国的投资签证计划获得永久居留权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五年过去了，他一家三口的希望仍然搁置，因为政府已将有争议的“黄金签证”计划搁置一旁，导致处理时间过长，使王这样的富裕移民陷入困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没想到会花这么长时间，” 44 岁的王说。“我们的生活因此变得一团糟。我们根本无法提前计划所有的不确定性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当澳大利亚在 2012 年推出商业创新和投资计划 (BIIP) 时，希望富有的企业主、投资者和企业家能够通过引入资本并推动创新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，结果并不令人满意。 3 月份发布的一项政府审查发现，BIIP 移民对经济的贡献低于澳大利亚平均水平，因为尽管这群人富有，但他们往往年龄较大，而且通过被动投资的资本回报获得的收入较低。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚为留住顶尖人才，减少移民改革中的“工人剥削”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;审查估计 BIIP 持有人一生的经济贡献为 60 万澳元，不到澳大利亚人 160 万澳元的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在 13 个月前上台后，澳大利亚工党政府将优先事项转移到缓解关键技术工人短缺问题上。部分原因是，大多数 BIIP 永久签证需要近三年的时间来处理，高于之前的平均 12 个月左右，此外还有四到五年的投资周期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang 一直在等待21 个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;类似的投资签证计划已在加拿大、英国和新加坡被取消，因为政府认为它们不会创造就业机会，并且可能成为存放投机资金的一种手段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每个类别的澳大利亚签证在 Covid-19 期间出现积压。随着疫情的缓解，政府总体上缩短了处理时间，但等待 3,000 多名 BIIP 持有人及其家人（其中许多是中国人）的等待时间却只增不减。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些 BIIP 申请人计划于 2019 年在悉尼抗议周五反对政府的政策转变，这是罕见的，因为中国移民在很大程度上避免了公众异议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在被问及签证延误时，内政部在一份电子邮件声明中表示，政府将优先处理所有签证和规划水平，拒绝对 BIIP 持有者的投诉发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它表示将在今年晚些时候发布新的移民战略，其中包括“彻底重塑”BIIP 计划。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;居住和公民身份规划公司 Henley &amp; Partners Australia 的董事总经理 Tony Le Nevez 表示，延误引起了人们对政府可能会取消 BIIP 计划的担忧，该公司的客户在该国每人至少投资了 500 万澳元。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我只是认为投资者计划目前不在他们的关注范围之内——他们可能会在未来对其进行彻底改革。与此同时，我认为他们可能只是打开一个小窗口。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府计划将其 BIIP 分配从上个财政年度的 5,000 个签证减少到今年的 1,900 个——不到水平的 20% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BIIP 持有者表示，鉴于不确定性，他们正在缩减商业投资，推迟人生决定，并在某些情况下出售澳大利亚的房产。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;亚裔澳大利亚人担心“红色警报”战争贩子将加剧种族主义仇恨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一些人表示，他们必须坚持亏损的企业，以保持他们的签证前景，从而错失回报更高的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“永远的等等意味着，即使我的生意亏本经营，我也不能关门大吉，”在墨尔本拥有一家家具店的中国投资者 Tan 说，出于隐私原因，他要求只透露姓氏担忧。他已经等了 33 个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于签证身份的不确定性，王先生去年放弃了为他的工厂购买更多土地的计划，他说他准备出售他在澳大利亚的资产明年为了女儿的教育搬到美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我知道很多人不会同情我们——我们只是一小群人，”王说。 “但我们没有受到公平对待。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[With Hong Kong’s property market reeling from falling deals and prices, an uptick in rates will dampen mood further, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3224215/hong-kongs-property-market-reeling-falling-deals-and-prices-uptick-rates-will-dampen-mood-further?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/7efa46a3-e532-45ae-86b2-01cda1a82835_2d1dcdb6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;高利率环境可能会给香港的二手房市场带来压力，直到分析师表示，考虑到美联储可能进一步加息及其对香港抵押贷款利率的影响，明年，利率上升对生活的交易量造成了影响-据香港两家主要房地产机构的高管称，房屋价格较今年每周平均水平下降了 40% 至 50%。他们预计高利率将在短期内进一步压低价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中原地产亚太区副主席兼住宅部门首席执行官 Louis Chan 说：“市场将继续下去。”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不排除抵押贷款利率进一步上升的可能性。美联储自 2022 年 3 月以来连续 10 次加息以控制通胀后首次维持利率不变，现在又加息一两次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就连香港金融管理局 (HKMA) 行政总裁余伟伟-man，周四警告说，在降息之前，香港的利率可能会继续维持在目前的高水平一段时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么香港房主在市场上涨时降价?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“公众不应将今天暂停加息视为加息周期结束或近期降息，”岳说。 “他们在做出投资决定或进行抵押贷款之前应仔细评估利率风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从美联储于去年 3 月开始加息周期以来，中原城市领先指数 – 中原地产的衡量住宅价格的指标 – 下跌了 6.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在元朗，6 月上半月的二手交易量环比下降超过 40% 至 27 宗，原因是业主削减据中原地产称，价格略有下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该数字与美联物业整理的数据相比较，美联物业追踪了该市 35 个大型住宅区的交易。根据该机构编制的数据，该机构表示，自 3 月以来，交易量持续下降，连续 14 周低于 100 笔，自 5 月初以来已降至不足 50 笔。它表示，过去六周的每周平均交易量为 34 笔，而今年的总体平均交易量为 73 笔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;短期内，为了吸引价格具有竞争力的新住宅项目的买家，二手房业主急于Midland 表示，要出售可能需要进一步降价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汇丰银行、中国银行（香港）和恒生银行表示，他们将维持最优惠贷款利率在 5.75% 不变，而渣打银行和东亚银行周四表示将维持利率在 6% 不变，但香港金管局的 Yue 警告称，“今年利率有可能再上升一两次”，呼应美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔 (Jerome Powell) 在今年有必要“进一步”加息以降低通胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着利率上升削弱信心，香港房价增长急剧放缓&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于抵押贷款利率更高从加息周期前的 1.5% 翻了一番，达到 3.5%，一套 600 万港元（766,640 美元）、贷款价值比为 90%、30 年的公寓的每月按揭还款额飙升了 30.1%根据美联物业的数据，升至 25,461 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莱坊大中华区研究及咨询主管 Martin Wong 表示，高利率的逆风只会在 2024 年开始缓和。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“一些中小型单位的买家可能无法通过银行的压力测试，这将在短期内压低房价，”Wong 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国加息周期尚未结束结束，”他说，并补充说，香港银行仍有可能提高最优惠利率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，岳表示，金管局并未考虑对其抵押贷款政策进行任何调整，指出&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“去年房地产价格下跌了 15%，但今年已经反弹，”他说。 “金管局需要更多时间监察供求、交易、物价等经济数据，以决定是否放宽按揭政策。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blinken’s visit may not deliver a breakthrough in US-China relations, but watch for positive ripple effects]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224148/blinkens-visit-may-not-deliver-breakthrough-us-china-relations-watch-positive-ripple-effects?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/6974a3cf-9458-445a-a46b-733479c0946e_c2b76b7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;很少有人期待美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯今年的中国之行取得任何有意义的突破星期。此次访问不会改变美国在知识产权、芯片安全、南中国海或台湾问题上的立场，但这不是重点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方在如此高级别会面这一事实本身就是一个表明关系中危险的消极趋势至少有机会得到修复。自美国总统乔·拜登去年在印度尼西亚巴厘岛与中国国家主席习近平会面以来，双方几乎没有找到共同点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家安全担忧加剧导致两国关系螺旋式下降，中国的气球和海上部队之间的险情。布林肯的会谈虽然未能达成重大协议，但仍可能大大有助于将双边关系从悬崖上拉下来。 Any tangible results will be subtle, but they can have ripple effects through governments and in corporate boardrooms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few months, the Biden administration has expressed its openness to re-engage, only to be met with a cold shoulder from China. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen recently stated in congressional testimony that “decoupling would be a big mistake” and Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin said at the recent Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore that “conflict is neither imminent nor inevitable”. The Biden administration is running a political risk of being seen as soft on China by agreeing to meet without a clear sign that something positive will come out of the talks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On China&#39;s part, the acceptance of this meeting is partly out of necessity. China desperately needs sentiment to improve among Western business executives. These talks will occur against the backdrop of significant economic stress. Foreign investment in China is falling and Chinese stocks are struggling.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;The good days aren&#39;t coming back&#39;: China&#39;s economic downturn takes a toll&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On top of these are the rising difficulties for major international financial institutions, some of which have supported China for decades. These firms are now pulling out of initial public offerings and finding China a much tougher environment in which to operate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relationship has nearly reached a breaking point. Even former high-flying billionaire investors like Ray Dalio, a long-time China bull, said at the Forbes Iconoclast Summit in New York this week that he thinks the US and China are headed for conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unnecessary difficulties for foreign businesses are also putting a damper on relations. New application rules for visits make trips to the mainland unnecessarily difficult by requiring reams of often invasive personal information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of US students studying in China has also dropped precipitously to around 350 for the most recent academic year. The Covid-19 pandemic might have been the initial cause, but these students aren&#39;t returning in droves, either. This compares to the nearly 300,000 Chinese students who were studying in the US in 2021-22 despite bilateral tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A heavy-handed approach to visits only accelerates corporate plans to minimise their China exposure. What was once a contrarian view of Beijing&#39;s overreach is now becoming consensus. If Beijing shows some positive momentum in relations, then the better it is for its broader economy, investment and people-to-people contact. The alternative is a more isolated China, which benefits no one.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With regard to Blinken&#39;s visit, meetings scheduled over two days is one sign both sides are taking this more seriously. While a hosted dinner might be off the table, the longer the visit, the greater the opportunities for pull-asides, or informal talks away from the main meetings. It&#39;s in those informal moments where much of the diplomatic work gets done.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To further set expectations, a certain amount of talking past each other is to be expected in any US-China dialogue. Both sides are often posturing for their home audience to prove how tough they can be on the other side. Even though Foreign Minister Qin Gang has demanded Washington “stop interfering in China&#39;s internal affairs”, Blinken is likely to bring up human rights and Taiwan. These haven&#39;t ended talks in the past, and they shouldn&#39;t be sticking points this time, either.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington also has much on the line. As sober analyses of supply chains have made clear, there is no easy cutting off of commercial ties in industries that rely on Chinese processing and manufacturing. Lazard&#39;s recently released critical materials research brief highlights China&#39;s crucial role in mining and refining materials for clean energy, healthcare and advanced electronics. While it&#39;s de rigueur in domestic politics to call for cutting ties completely, in some areas that isn&#39;t a practical reality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other areas, such as combating climate change, are also enhanced through cooperation. As the orange-tinged smoky skies over Washington last week made clear, the effects of rising temperatures and changing weather patterns do not pay heed to political borders. Any outcome that puts a visit by John Kerry, the US special presidential envoy for climate, back on the calendar makes the Blinken trip worthwhile. He has been waiting months to officially restart conversations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington also gains by continuing to show its openness to dialogue, which signals to allies and unaligned countries that nuanced foreign policy trumps any hardline policies that threaten conflict. Putting aside Dalio&#39;s concern on the inevitability of great power conflict, there is nothing inevitable about the US and China heading to war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are no guarantees that these meetings will lead to anything except more than empty talk, of course. However, dialogue is the best chance for more to happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the meeting is simply an airing of grievances akin to the Seinfeld “Festivus” episode, minus the humour, then it will be clear further dialogue is unlikely. That will be a choice made by officials, not historic inevitability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 15 dead after truck hits bus carrying elderly passengers in Manitoba, Canada]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224258/least-15-die-after-truck-hits-bus-carrying-elderly-passengers-manitoba-canada?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 07:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/1dd0e138-e36d-4e31-91f5-72d044bf71a0_561ddea3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;At least 15 people were killed in the Canadian prairie province of Manitoba on Thursday after an articulated truck hit a small bus that was carrying a group of mainly elderly people, local police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crash is one of the most lethal road accidents in recent Canadian history. Separately, the Winnipeg Free Press newspaper said the victims had been on their way to a local casino.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crash occurred at the junction of two major roads near the town of Carberry in southwestern Manitoba, 170km (105 miles) west of Winnipeg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve been able to establish that at least 15 people have been confirmed deceased as a result of this collision,” said Assistant Commissioner Rob Hill, who commands the Manitoba Royal Canadian Mounted Police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hill told a televised news conference that “sadly, this is a day in Manitoba and across Canada that will be remembered as one of tragedy and incredible sadness”. The bus had been carrying about 25 people, most of them elderly, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said the drivers of both vehicles were alive. They declined to say who might have been responsible for the crash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Media reports initially identified the vehicle as a van rather than a bus. They said it was operated by Handi-Transit, which transports the elderly and those with disabilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Canadian Broadcasting Corporation showed a still photo of a white minivan-sized vehicle that had been burned out. It also showed a picture of a blue truck with a smashed-in front.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Watch this&#39;: Australia wedding crash bus was going far too fast, police say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wheelchairs and crumpled walking frames remained near tarpaulins covering bodies at the site, the Winnipeg Free Press said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a tweet, Prime Minister Justin Trudeau lamented what he called “incredibly tragic” news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m sending my deepest condolences to those who lost loved ones today, and I&#39;m keeping the injured in my thoughts. I cannot imagine the pain those affected are feeling,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My heart breaks hearing the news of the tragic accident near Carberry,” Manitoba Premier Heather Stefanson said on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In neighbouring Saskatchewan, 16 people died in April 2018 after a truck hit a bus transporting a junior hockey team on a rural road. The truck driver was sentenced to eight years in prison in 2019.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s ‘blank paper’ graduates fear years of remote learning and no experience make them unemployable]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224211/chinas-blank-paper-graduates-fear-years-remote-learning-and-no-experience-make-them-unemployable?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/526a190a-05b2-4f12-9bb7-5b2b4e8ddef4_939659e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After fishing for more than 50 positions across various job portals, Connie Xu finally got a nibble – the chance to interview for an internship with a company in a major Chinese city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 22-year-old, who graduated this month with a degree in Chinese language and literature, considered herself a good candidate for the position, with the necessary skill set and classroom experience from projects at university. So, the Guangdong native travelled 90 minutes for the interview, anticipating that this could be her shot at gainful employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It did not go as she had hoped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They said I&#39;m a greenhorn. In the words of my interviewer, I am a piece of blank paper without any actual work experience,” she recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, she continues to search. And she is hardly alone in struggling to find a job, especially among her fellow fresh graduates – all 11.58 million of them – entering China&#39;s workforce this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unemployment rate among Chinese aged 16 to 24 continued its rise in May to an all-time high of 20.8 per cent, up from the previous record-breaking 20.4 per cent in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s highly restrictive zero-Covid policy, which endured for nearly three years of the pandemic and featured citywide lockdowns, was abruptly abandoned in December, but the effects continue to be felt among the world&#39;s largest workforce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Much of the class of 2023 spent nearly all of their formative college years cut off from in-person learning and internships, and now many are struggling to convince employers that they can handle a real job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Four years of university, and we were stuck on campus for three years,” Xu lamented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Miriam Wickertsheim, a Shanghai-based recruiter for foreign companies, said that fresh graduates she spoke to recently – those who studied for their undergraduate degree from 2019 to 2023 – feel more unattractive to recruiters after basically earning their degrees online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Their interviewers said they only learned remotely, so there were fewer social activities and fewer opportunities to work face-to-face, to develop teamwork and social skills,” she said. “Employers said they would just wait for the next batch of graduates.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that many small, private Chinese companies, which traditionally provide the first jobs for a lot of fresh graduates, suffered during the pandemic and are still trying to recover.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even if companies are putting up job openings, they are replacement positions instead of expansions. These are not positions that could be junior or graduate level,” Wickertsheim said. “It takes quite a lot of time and resources for a company to take a fresh graduate and teach them to a point where they are adding economic value to the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the moment, when the business climate is challenging, a lot of companies are reluctant to make those kinds of investments, especially when young graduates often have a certain turnover [rate] and higher volatility.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is China&#39;s youth unemployment rate and why does it cover ages 16 to 24?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;At the same time, a lot of young people now are holding degrees that are simply not in demand, said Wickertsheim, who has worked in China for more than 13 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Graduates a decade ago studied engineering or finance or accounting, because this is what their parents or teachers recommended to them, so they could for sure find a job. Now, a lot of people have been brought up in a growing economy, and they are more at liberty to study something they find interesting, so that might make it a little bit more challenging to find work.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, China&#39;s youth unemployment rate keeps breaking records and continues to spark heated discourse across the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With one out of every five members of the 16-24 demographic unable to find a job, the central government has vowed to address the worsening trend that comes at a time when a bumpy post-pandemic recovery has led to weak consumer demand and mixed investor sentiments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 1, China&#39;s Ministry of Education announced a nationwide 100-day campaign “to guide graduates to take the initiative to seek jobs, and help more college graduates find employment as soon as possible, before and after leaving school”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For China&#39;s undergraduates, their job hunt typically begins in the fall semester of their final year, when major companies and public institutions hold campus-recruitment drives and aim to fill most of the headcount for their junior roles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following spring-recruitment period, usually between March and May, fills any leftover quota and usually features fewer positions for pending graduates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But even those who do manage to land a job – often with their university&#39;s help – might not find themselves in the most advantageous position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mo Haonan, a construction engineering major in Hangzhou, landed himself an internship through a recruitment drive organised by his university. He said the school invites companies that are actively hiring to job fairs, in a bid to expedite the hiring process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, his employment was short-lived, as the 21-year-old was laid off by his company weeks after helping out on a project.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;More freedom&#39;: China&#39;s youth embrace &#39;flexible&#39; work in bleak job market&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“They just treat us as cheap, dispensable labour. After finishing one project, they couldn&#39;t get any more clients, so they just fired us without much compensation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And now, he fears, it could appear to future interviewers and corporate recruiters that he was laid off because of poor performance, which he said is not true, but nonetheless makes him feel a degree of shame.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, there is somewhat of a silver lining for fresh graduates, according to Eddie Cheng, an executive recruiter for Chinese companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Underperforming or non-essential middle-management positions are usually the first to go during lay-offs, while companies might open up more management-trainee positions, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some companies actually fire middle or senior positions and hire fresh graduates because they are cheaper. They are more willing to pay less money to hire a fresh graduate and train them up [for a few years]. The cost of hiring a general manager could be used to hire more than 30 fresh graduates,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can China&#39;s economy handle an unemployment crisis?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Xu, with her degree in hand, says she is exhausted from the endless job hunt. Asked whether she would still have majored in the same degree if she could do it all over again, she said she was of two minds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the one hand, choosing Chinese language and literature seems more conservative for me, because this major is versatile, and there are many job options related to this major available for the civil service exam. I am also interested in Chinese language and literature,” she said. “However, when it comes to finding a job, other majors can accomplish the same.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the foreseeable future, Xu said she believes that those without internship experience will continue to be the first to have their resumes eliminated early in the application process. And she noted that even her friends who have earned outstanding grades have yet to land a job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Companies are all rushing to cut jobs, how will they hire? Even if they do, they will employ those who can take on multiple roles. This batch of graduates was locked down in school for three years, where do we get our industry experience from?”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Anxiety’ over new US trade policy focused on American workers, cutting China reliance: Katherine Tai]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3224257/anxiety-over-new-us-trade-policy-focused-american-workers-cutting-china-reliance-katherine-tai?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 06:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/1f4d3f26-af67-4ce2-83cb-37ef0b789f50_a0f67cda.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Washington&#39;s top trade official acknowledged encountering resistance and “anxiety” in promoting the Biden administration&#39;s new vision of a trade policy focused on American workers while it slashes reliance on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Trade Representative Katherine Tai on Thursday said “fragile supply chains” and “an unsustainable version of globalisation” were negative outcomes from decades of championing market liberalisation and low prices for consumers as domestic manufacturing suffered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When efficiency and low cost are the only motivators, production moves outside our borders,” Tai said in a speech at the National Press Club in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such an approach, she continued, meant production was “increasingly consolidated in one economy, such as the PRC, which manipulates cost structures, controls key industries, and became a dominant supplier for many important goods and technologies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pursuing de-risking and resilience in supply chains was about “improving national security and reducing opportunities for economic coercion”, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a direct message to Beijing, Tai singled out “consuming” rather than “exporting and supplying” as an American “superpower” that the US needed to employ in deciding how to “leverage the power of access into our markets”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Tai acknowledged encountering some resistance domestically to the new US tack yet cautioned that “complacency really isn&#39;t an option”. Some allies have also balked, like India, which last month opted not to take part in trade negotiations at the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework ministerial meeting in Detroit, Michigan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turning away from past practices was difficult, she said, noting that “there&#39;s a certain comfort to hanging on to the old structures and the old ways because they&#39;re comfortable”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China fights US &#39;de-risking&#39; with first-ever supply chain expo&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s one vein of anxiety and negativity that I encountered [that says] … you are just trying to take apart the system, you&#39;re trying to take us back to a state of nature. And that is absolutely not what we are trying to do”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tai&#39;s comments followed an observation shared by Republican congressman Tom Cole of Oklahoma lamenting America&#39;s formal withdrawal from the Trans-Pacific Partnership, a US initiative to expand trade across the Asia-Pacific region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Abandoning the TPP “was a missed opportunity”, Cole said during a House Rules Committee hearing last month on China&#39;s economic tactics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2016, US President Joe Biden&#39;s predecessor, Donald Trump, withdrew the US from the 12-member TPP, now called the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership, in the name of protecting domestic manufacturing and American workers. The initial deal was signed during the Barack Obama administration to counter China&#39;s rise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Tai stressed that the Biden administration was doing “non-traditional things” that “promote resilience, sustainability and inclusiveness in terms of economic outcomes” because it saw “significant limitations” in “liberalisation qualification for the sake of liberalisation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her remarks came just hours before US Secretary of State Antony Blinken was expected in Beijing for a five-day visit. Blinken&#39;s trip would be the first by an American secretary of state since 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken is slated to meet Chinese President Xi Jinping. Previously scheduled for February, the visit was abruptly cancelled after an alleged Chinese spy balloon was spotted and downed over American territory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While many analysts hailed the trip as a breakthrough in US-China relations after deep communication fissures emerged between the two global powers, Tai at a separate appearance on Thursday described it as “ordinary”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Detroit, recent Apec host city, embodies Biden&#39;s trade policy goal of renewal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“For those of us in the administration, it is just the usual course of business in ordinary conduct, that we have communication channels,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, US Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink voiced Washington&#39;s aim of managing its competition with Beijing “in the most responsible way possible”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Intense competition requires intense diplomacy, if we&#39;re going to manage tensions,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US grand jury indicts Pentagon leak suspect Jack Teixeira, Justice Department says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224256/us-grand-jury-indicts-pentagon-leak-suspect-jack-teixeira-justice-department-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 05:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/b6c51a90-d4b9-4903-9e5c-87c8e074bd5f_376e6348.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A federal grand jury has indicted a US Air National guardsman accused of leaking top-secret military intelligence records online, the Justice Department said in a statement on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jack Douglas Teixeira, 21, of North Dighton, Massachusetts, was indicted on six counts of wilful retention and transmission of classified information relating to national defence, the statement said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Each charge of unauthorised retention and transmission of national defence information provides for a sentence of up to 10 years in prison, up to three years of supervised release, and a fine of up to US$250,000, the department added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Teixeira is accused of committing one of the most serious US security breaches since more than 700,000 documents, videos and diplomatic cables appeared on the WikiLeaks website in 2010.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was arrested in April after allegedly posting highly classified material on the messaging app Discord, prompting concerns about how a low-level airman could have such broad access to military secrets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two commanders in his unit were later suspended.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federal law requires the government to secure an indictment within 30 days of a person&#39;s arrest, and Thursday marked the 30-day deadline.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is the Espionage Act and what might it mean for Trump?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A member of the Massachusetts Air National Guard&#39;s 102nd Intelligence Wing, Teixeira had earlier waived his right to a preliminary hearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He had been charged in a criminal complaint with one count of violating the Espionage Act for unlawful copying and transmitting sensitive defence material, and a second charge related to unlawful removal of defence material to an unauthorised location.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US tourist, 21, dies after she and friend pushed into ravine at Germany’s Neuschwanstein castle]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224255/us-tourist-21-dies-after-she-and-friend-21-pushed-ravine-germanys-neuschwanstein-castle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 03:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/fcdb943c-7151-42d0-933e-c1c3419b976e_7a9827b1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An American man has been arrested in the death of a US tourist and an assault on another near Neuschwanstein castle in southern Germany after he allegedly pushed the two women down a steep slope, authorities said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident near the popular tourist attraction happened on Wednesday afternoon near the Marienbruecke, a bridge over a gorge close to the castle that offers a famous view of Neuschwanstein.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 30-year-old man met the two women tourists, ages 21 and 22, on a hiking path and lured them onto a trail that leads to a viewpoint, police said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He then “physically attacked” the younger woman, police said. When her companion tried to intervene, he choked her and pushed her down a steep slope.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The assailant then appears to have attempted to sexually assault the 21-year-old before pushing her down the slope as well. She fell nearly 50 metres (165 feet), ending up close to her friend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A mountain rescue team reached both women. The 22-year-old was “responsive” and taken to a hospital, police said; a helicopter carried the 21-year-old to a different hospital with serious injuries, and she died there overnight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The suspect left the scene but was arrested quickly nearby. Bystander video posted online showed police leading away a handcuffed man in a T-shirt, jeans and a baseball cap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Witness Eric Abneri, a recent business graduate from the University of Pittsburgh who shot the video, said the man appeared to have scratches across his face.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New Zealand man killed UK tourist after Tinder date, jury finds&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“He did not say a single word. He didn&#39;t open his mouth; he didn&#39;t mumble,” Abneri said. “He just walked with the police and that was it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Abneri said he and friends arrived at the scenic overlook as a helicopter arrived and they saw rescuers lower themselves down to the victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m honestly absolutely stunned someone is still alive from this. It is like falling from the top of an absolute cliff,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Abneri described it as “a very, very difficult rescue because of those cliffs and because the helicopter came mere feet above the tree line at the top of the hill”. “They did an unbelievable job,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said the man they arrested was American and described him as also a tourist; prosecutors said the women were fellow US citizens. The 22-year-old remained hospitalised on Thursday, according to prosecutors. Authorities did not identify either the suspect or the victims or give any further details.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said a judge in nearby Kempten on Thursday ordered the suspect held pending a potential indictment – a process that can take months – and he was taken to jail. He is under investigation on suspicion of murder, attempted murder and a sexual offence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said they and prosecutors were focusing on trying to reconstruct exactly what happened and called for any witnesses to come forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neuschwanstein, located in southern Bavaria close to Austria&#39;s border, is one of Germany&#39;s most popular tourist attractions. It is the most famous of the castles built by King Ludwig II of Bavaria in the 19th century. Construction started in 1869 but was never completed. Ludwig died in 1886.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>