<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[World’s first mass-produced humanoid robot? China start-up Fourier Intelligence eyes two-legged robots with AI brains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3230850/worlds-first-mass-produced-humanoid-robot-china-start-fourier-intelligence-eyes-two-legged-robots-ai?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/8945fe8e-9967-46d4-881b-bf54fdddf29d_b80c6778.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当 Fourier Intelligence 在 2020 年展会上推出其瘦长、漆黑的人形机器人 GR-1 时7 月在上海举行的世界人工智能大会 (WAIC) 立即抢尽风头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然自 11 月 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT 推出以来，全球科技界一直关注人工智能 (AI) 软件，但中国制造的GR-1——据说能够以每小时5公里的速度用两条腿行走，同时承载50公斤的负载——让人们想起了从特斯拉到小米等跨国公司正在追求的双足机器人的潜力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于上海的初创公司 Fourier 来说，GR-1 是一次不太可能的胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我们一次前所未有的尝试 - 当它出现时我们几乎没有任何参考资料Fourier 创始人兼首席执行官 Alex Gu 最近在中国金融之都接受《南华早报》采访时表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fourier 的关注点并不总是在人形机器人上。该公司以 19 世纪法国数学家和物理学家约瑟夫·傅里叶 (Joseph Fourier) 的名字命名，最初于 2015 年在上海科技中心张江成立，旨在开发康复机器人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司目前的产品包括智能健身车、无线机器人手套和一系列计算机引导的装置，帮助用户恢复手臂和腿部的运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但就像他的许多同龄人一样，42 岁的顾是机械工程专业的毕业生来自上海交通大学的他一直梦想着创造自己的人形机器人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于是在2019年，Fourier将其智能康复设备带入了10多个国家的数百家医院和医疗中心，并在全球站稳脚跟。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，由于技术壁垒和开发成本较高，世界上很少有公司能够成功推出人形机器人。在美国，有一些项目，包括波士顿动力公司的Atlas（该公司以机器狗Spot而闻名）和Agility Robotics的Digit。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国，大多数公司选择将精力集中在轻量化上。四足机器人等产品。顾认为他可以做得更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“康复机器人中使用的许多技术本质上也适用于人形机器人，”顾说。 “人形机器人需要非常好的电机，既强大又轻便，我们能够自己开发它们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;GR-1诞生于傅里叶总部一楼的一个小实验室，那里上个月记者走访时，一群工程师正在忙着改进和测试机器人。该团队在 2022 年（项目启动三年后）取得了重大突破，成功使这个 1.65 米高的机器人能够用双腿站立并行走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们看到它站立时第一次不受束缚地自行行走，这对我们所有的工程师来说都是一个很大的鼓励。”顾说。 “感觉就像抚养一个刚出生的婴儿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fourier 后来在网上发布了一段 GR-1 行走的视频，得到了很多观众的称赞，但也有很多人持怀疑态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些海外观众表示该视频是计算机生成的，”顾说。 “我知道这个领域还处于早期阶段，人们会有不同的看法，就像20年前有人争论电动汽车是否能够在道路上行驶一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了尽管存在技术挑战，研究人员和机器人专家警告说，企业在更广泛的消费市场中将人形机器人商业化仍面临巨大困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[人形机器人]现在大多生活在实验室中，而且非常昂贵，”说张晓荣，中国神都科技研究院院长。 “一台质量相对较高的机器可能要花费数百万元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些问题并没有阻止企业尝试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国智能手机巨头小米创始人雷军，2022 年 8 月在舞台上展示了​​该公司的第一个人形机器人 Cyber​​One，它被认为能够行走，但除此之外没有什么其他功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不到两个月后，特斯拉亿万富翁创始人埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 推出了原型机在公司的人工智能日期间展示其备受期待的 Optimus 机器人。它在舞台上现场行走和跳舞。观众还观看了一段机器人执行搬运盒子和移动金属棒等任务的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克在上个月的 WAIC 会议上表示，Optimus 的目的并不是“拥有极高的智能”，而是为了帮助人类完成“无聊、重复或危险的任务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顾说他与马斯克有着相似的愿景，但补充说机器人“也可以通过提供情感价值成为人类非常好的朋友”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;虽然当前的人形机器人“在运动和认知能力方面与人类仍有很大差距”，但大型语言模型 (LLM)（支持 ChatGPT 等人工智能聊天机器人的软件类型）的开发可能会“改变时代” ”，顾说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“法学硕士将赋予机器人逻辑推理的能力，使它们变得更像人类，”顾说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然顾强调傅立叶将专注于Fourier 联合创始人兼首席战略官 Zen Koh 表示，一些人工智能公司已经在法学硕士领域寻求潜在合作，开发构成机器人“身体”的硬件，并让人工智能开发人员专注于“大脑”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望与所有主要企业合作，并且……作为一个系统，保持开放，”Koh 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;GR-1 机器人已经以小型形式交付。顾说，数量给一些大学和人工智能公司进行研发。他计划在年底前开始量产，并在 2024 年交付数千台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克去年还声称可以在 2023 年开始生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顾预计傅里叶的人形机器人，他表示，在养老、教育、宾客接待等多种场景中，该机器人具有巨大的潜力，未来三到五年将比康复机器人产生更多的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，还有很长的路要走。在人形机器人成为我们日常生活的一部分之前，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不要指望一年左右就会出现奇迹 - 即使对于特斯拉来说，我们也必须给他们时间[以实现大规模生产人形机器人]，”顾说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，不要低估这个东西可能在五年或十年内成为人们家庭生活一部分的可能性。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘The first Chinese chief in Africa’, but does he – and others like him – wield any real influence?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3230814/first-chinese-chief-africa-does-he-and-others-him-wield-any-real-influence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 07:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/f14e5c78-08bd-4385-89da-72f8e5560c4a_6b076722.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;50岁时，前英语教师胡杰国移居尼日利亚并建立了一家价值数百万美元的中式酒店，当时东亚面孔在那里并不常见。现年 70 多岁的胡生活在拉各斯，周围都是政府资助的、手持冲锋枪的警卫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡在 2001 年被授予酋长头衔时得到了这种保护，这对于非非洲人来说是一项罕见的荣誉。胡锦涛当时表示，这个头衔并没有什么特别之处，只是他现在可以“随时见到州长和总统”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十七年后，他身穿金色长袍，戴着圆顶小帽。尼日利亚西南部约鲁巴部落的胡锦涛做客中央电视台，讲述他作为“非洲第一位华人酋长”的一生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛以此身份为当地政府提供涉华建议并帮助中国公民在尼日利亚遇到问题。就连中国驻尼日利亚大使也会向胡锦涛咨询。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么硅谷的中国风险投资家的聚会结束了&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中华全国侨联出版的《国内外》杂志一位海外华人大使表示，“胡杰国像熊猫一样稀有，我们需要好好保护他。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡杰国出生于 1948 年，与母亲和兄弟姐妹在上海长大。 。他的父亲前往香港创办纺织生意。然而，二战后国际局势动荡，加上共产党在中国取得胜利，香港经济变得低迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，跟随一位将生意迁往英国殖民地尼日利亚的朋友，胡的父亲也搬到了那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，胡老在拉各斯建造了纺织厂，与包括奥卢塞贡·奥巴桑乔（1999年至2007年担任尼日利亚总统）在内的政治家成为朋友，并成为当地海外领导人中国人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着年龄的增长，他梦想着将家族生意传给儿子，但小胡更感兴趣的是把他来之不易的教师生涯留在家乡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;胡锦涛是文革后期（1966-1976）第一批进入大学的“工农兵”学生之一。政治运动叫停了全国高考，抢走了那些被送到农村向农民学习、当农场工人的年轻人的教育机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1970年至1976年间，少数幸运的工人、农民和士兵被选入大学，不是根据学业成绩，而是根据他们的工作经验。其中就有胡，他选择了英语专业，并于1972年毕业成为一名英语教师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上课时，他在黑板上写下：“为了革命，我们必须努力学习英语。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化大革命期间，中国基本上对外界关闭，胡担心如果他表现出移居国外的意图，就会受到政治迫害，但这种情况在 1977 年左右发生了变化，时任中国驻尼日利亚大使冯玉九和胡父亲的一个朋友到上海看望胡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“胡老师，”冯告诉他，“华侨领袖也需要一个接班人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，在1978年，中国改革开放之年，胡锦涛抵达拉各斯，由于担心国内政局不明朗以及未知的非洲大陆，胡锦涛最初的不情愿在冯的坚持下被克服了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;然而，胡认为，曾让他父亲受益匪浅的纺织业已经饱和。他想做自己的事情，所以他开始在一家酒店餐厅工作，很快就晋升为经理。随后前往加拿大学习酒店管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回到拉各斯后，他于1997年投资800万美元建造了金门餐厅及酒店。该建筑采用中国风格设计，有两个房间。入口处有白色的守护狮子。政客和商人纷纷涌入，进一步扩大了胡氏家族的网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他的父亲与奥巴桑乔总统​​交往时，胡锦涛与时任拉各斯州长、尼日利亚现任总统博拉·蒂努布成为了朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;甚至在胡成为部落酋长之前，他就在尼日利亚和中国政府之间轻松调动，而酋长头衔只会增加他的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 1998 年以来，胡一直帮助中国公司在尼日利亚投资。中国土木工程建设公司 (CCECC) 就是一个例子，该公司获得了一个价值 5.6 亿美元的项目，用于改造和维护一条 3,000 公里（1,860 英里）长的铁路。胡锦涛还接见了中国石油天然气集团公司代表团，并向尼日利亚石油资源部长介绍了他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛与中国各省合作，在尼日利亚举办商品交易会、开设工业园，吸引中国私营企业前来投资。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2004年，奥巴桑乔任命胡锦涛为总统顾问，负责中小企业发展。一年后，他陪同奥巴桑乔来到中国。访问期间，尼日利亚总统参观了三峡大坝等大型项目，并签署了多项经贸协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1999年，奥巴桑乔就任总统，蒂努布就任拉各斯州长时，胡锦涛想做点什么为了代表华侨华人表示支持，他决定兴建学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛历来重视教育事业，帮助兴建了四所学校，每所可容纳3000名学生，设备齐全– 与该国许多其他学校不同 – 有灯光和风扇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒂努布在另一位前中国驻尼日利亚大使梁引柱的陪同下奠基。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2001 年，承认由于胡锦涛的贡献，拉各斯约鲁巴族首领授予他酋长头衔，并经总督批准。胡锦涛穿着约鲁巴人的传统服装出席仪式，酋长向他提供了几个头衔供他选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛选择了巴巴·阿塞（Baba Ase），意思是“服务酋长”，并表示他想“服务” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自20世纪80年代以来，中国在非洲的影响力一直引人注目，国有企业大量投资，雇用了大量中国工人。据估计，截至2012年底，生活在非洲国家的中国人已超过100万，根据中国商务部2019年的数据，私营部门目前占中国对非洲直接投资的一半以上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大英博物馆令人难以置信的中国历史展览是一个启示&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京大学非洲研究助理教授徐亮表示，继胡锦涛之后，至少有 22 名中国人获得了这一称号，大约是其中一半是国营公司员工，其余来自私营企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“将酋长授予中国人可能是一种趋势，但这不仅仅是因为越来越多的中国人（在非洲）做生意，而且他们的影响力已经越来越大。”长大了，”徐说。 “我们需要明白，西非国家正处于转型之中，他们更有动力吸引那些能够帮助他们发展的人——无论是当地人还是外国人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐，最近出版了《 《中国酋长在非洲：中非人文交流视角分析》一文估计，仅尼日利亚就有数百名外国酋长，其中华人只占一小部分。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;徐通过中国官方媒体和社交媒体对中国领导人的报道认识了胡锦涛。他将胡归类为“社区领袖”，指的是从事贸易、服务和制造业的私营商人，他们获得这些头衔主要是因为他们在中国人中的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐将他们与“基础设施建设者”区分开来。 ”，其中大多数在中国国有企业工作。中土尼日利亚公司至少有四名总经理被授予酋长头衔，中地海外的两名员工也被授予酋长头衔，这两家公司都是中国国有建筑公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一些国有企业，接受酋长头衔需要经过批准由公司。通常情况下，管理者都会获得头衔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2007年，在奥贡州帕帕兰托，Sepco III的经理方一波被授予“Baamole”的头衔，意思是“黑暗中的光明使者”。中国电力建设公司承建电站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年，中土集团尼日利亚经理李庆勇在拉各斯荣获“皇家道路建设者”称号，孔涛经理荣获“瓦基林·阿尤卡”称号。 2019 年在阿布贾举行的“工程总监”）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与胡锦涛不同的是，大多数中国领导人，尤其是国有企业的领导人，并没有特别积极——有些人甚至因没有履行职责而受到批评。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;有一次，当地的村长给孔打电话，询问他是否知道有一个中国公民打算在附近购买土地。当孔给出否定的回答时，总长说：“你是工程总长。你必须注意你周围的一切。土地要卖了，你不知道！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孔后来查了一下，但一般来说，中国酋长参与地方事务并不容易。许多人表示，语言障碍、对当地文化缺乏了解，再加上自己的工作已经太忙了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从某种意义上说，这些中国领导人的冷漠态度与中国的“不干涉政策”很相似。 ，从宏观层面来看，这意味着北京的投资几乎不附加任何政治条件。据中国商务部统计，截至2020年底，中国对非洲直接投资已超过474亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，西方传统上将贷款条件设定为促进民主和发展等举措。减少腐败。双方都没有取得令人满意的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国被指责为“流氓捐助者”，从长远来看会损害非洲，而西方的做法导致了发展失败，因为如果受援国不能合作，西方就会停止合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛总体上支持不干预，但他对所谓的无偿援助表示怀疑，并希望中国政府也能帮助打击腐败。&lt;/p>;&lt; “对于尼日利亚政府来说，完成任何事情都需要钱，”他说。 “无论是国有企业还是私营企业都无法改变这一点。只有政府才能有所作为 [...] 在我看来，我们不能仅仅提供援助。我们需要提出要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐还指出，中国和西方对非洲的做法并不一定是对立的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它们可以相辅相成”。他说。 “不同的是，我们认为很多问题是在发展中慢慢解决的，我们不会因为他们有问题就断绝关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“同时，我们也希望非洲在非洲设定的指标上变得更强。西方国家。西方在这方面做得很好。他们在要求透明度、效率或更好的法律体系方面拥有经验[…]我们希望通过发展，非洲国家能够找到解决方案并满足这些指标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科技巨头如何破解食品配送2018年底，27岁的中地海外员工李曼虎获得称号时，他感到很困惑。媒体将这一荣誉归功于中地海外，因为中地海外正在建设连接尼日利亚和喀麦隆的跨境桥梁，但也有人指出，李先生由于负责公共关系，与当地人关系密切，或许更重要的是，他分散了工资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最近的一次电话中，李告诉我，他仍然不确定为什么被授予这个称号。 “也许是因为我与总酋长保持着良好的关系，”他说，并提到他经常去看望这位80岁的老人，并给他送礼物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在东南部克罗斯河加冕后李在中国的抖音上开设了一个名为“中国酋长李曼虎”的帐户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他发布了他的加冕视频，其中一位穿着红白条纹灰色长袍的主持人宣布：“根据根据传统统治者会议法令的规定，埃通地方政府区最高统治者和尼日利亚克罗斯河埃通传统统治者委员会成员，特此正式承认亚当[李曼虎]先生为恩图伊·奥法（Ntui Ofa）酋长头衔我是鄂东国的。”当地人爆发出热烈的掌声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频已获得超过 20,000 个点赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管李说他对这个奖项感到困惑，但他相信酋长可能是一个重要的社交工具。与胡的父亲在国内有着广泛的人脉关系的胡不同，其他中国人常常难以融入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李记得，当他 2017 年第一次来到克罗斯河时，当地人经常找到借口骗钱。离开公司。当中国员工开车上街时，警察可能会伏击他们，直到他们提供baksheesh（小费或贿赂）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一次，当他们计划建造一座桥梁时，当地人声称他们需要付费才能崇拜河流神。请求遭到拒绝，他们拔掉了公司发电机的插头，停止了工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在李获得称号后，情况发生了变化。没有河神可以安抚。警察看到他的金色车牌（只为酋长专用），挥舞着他的车通过检查站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李甚至鼓励在尼日利亚的中国游客下载加冕视频，并说他们是他的朋友，以避免遇到困难。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但李的个人开支却增加了。他被邀请参加当地的节日，并穿着传统服装。他的抖音记录了这些欢乐的活动：部落舞蹈；有节奏的歌曲。有时他跳舞。有时当地人会要求他向他们的手上吹空气，这是一种祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的水坝如何摧毁柬埔寨下游的生计&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当然，他需要给他们钱，就像所有其他酋长一样。很快，李就被邀请参加毕业典礼、婚礼和葬礼。 “我是否真的去并不重要，”他开玩笑说，“只要钱到了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年初，李被授予“Ekok Chiefdom Ntufam Ofa I”边境另一边的喀麦隆当地酋长，李也与他保持着良好的关系。在他的第二次加冕典礼上，李克强身穿白色上衣、红色长袍，戴着一顶松软的尖顶红色帽子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他与 80 岁的尼日利亚酋长（他的喀麦隆人的密友）一起骑马穿越边境。同一民族的同行——抵达法语国家的英语区曼育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东道主是曼育省长，他身穿白色西装，头戴鸭舌帽。李说，在喀麦隆，加冕礼需要政府许可，这就显得更加珍贵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣布后，一位戴着彩虹色网遮住脸的传统舞者开始跳起来，伸出双手，问道两位传统统治者、总督和新登基者的空中祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然李作为一个年轻人在不同国家获得两个酋长头衔而引起了中国的广泛报道，但他的喀麦隆加冕视频却获得了 30 万个赞抖音上——喀麦隆法语网站上没有他的踪迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在喀麦隆，授予外国人酋长头衔似乎一直存在争议。在西非被授予酋长头衔的24名中国人中，有21人获得了尼日利亚头衔，但只有两人获得了喀麦隆头衔，而喀麦隆头衔不被当地人认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年，来自一家中国私营公司的龙先生被授予了酋长头衔。喀麦隆法语网站报道称，这是该国有史以来第一位三级酋长。他身穿金边白袍，头戴头巾——就像该地区的统治者——的照片在Facebook上疯传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位当地互联网用户被引述说：“中国人有一天会成为世界上最伟大的人。”喀麦隆总统。我们等待这种骗局迅速取消。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学者们经常谈论非洲殖民地的“间接统治”。英国非洲学家特伦斯·兰杰 (Terence Ranger) 在其 1983 年的文章《传统的发明》中解释说，由于英国和非洲的制度如此不同，英国管理者开始根据他们认为的传统来发明非洲传统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们着手编纂和传播这些传统，”兰杰写道，“从而将灵活的习俗转变为硬性规定。”这些发明的传统还被用来重新定义欧洲人发号施令、非洲人默许的分层社会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 20 世纪 60 年代的非洲独立运动中，领导人和知识分子常常认为酋长制是殖民政府对传统亲属关系的扭曲。以及殖民统治的残余。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括几内亚和坦桑尼亚在内的许多国家都禁止了这种传统制度。那些保留它的人并没有赋予它很多功能。这可能是一些喀麦隆人对外国酋长感到愤怒的部分原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当外国人获得酋长头衔时，历史记忆使他们非常敏感，”徐在有关中国酋长的论文中写道。 “很容易引起对‘新殖民主义’的担忧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但徐认为中国酋长不属于殖民叙事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一方面，”他写道，“授予决定是由非洲酋长而不是中国人做出的，这与欧洲殖民者任命酋长有本质的不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“另一方面，非洲人民的监督可以影响外国酋长的任免” ，追究他们的责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;一位中国艺术家让丁丁不再那么种族主义，并成为埃尔热最好的朋友之一&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管对外国酋长保持警惕，但自 20 世纪 90 年代以来，大多数西非国家见证了土司制度的卷土重来。耶鲁大学教授凯特·鲍德温 (Kate Baldwin) 撰写了《民主非洲的传统酋长悖论》(2015)，她表示，大约 15% 的非洲国家在获得独立时在宪法中保护酋长权。 2010 年这一数字上升至 24%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日利亚是一个突出的例子。该国可能是英国发明最重要的试验场：利用豪萨-富拉尼族埃米尔统治北部各州的穆斯林，并为东南部各州的伊博族建立“授权酋长”，因为伊博族没有酋长传统.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐认为，殖民创造常常被认为是尼日利亚政治动荡的根源，但酋长制却蓬勃发展，在 1970 年代和 80 年代的经济危机期间对当地发展发挥了至关重要的作用.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独立几十年后，虽然尼日利亚在1999年修订的宪法中没有赋予酋长任何实权，但也没有彻底禁止该制度。如今，酋长在伊博文化中很常见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外国酋长受到欢迎，尽管他们的头衔往往意味着荣誉而不是权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在奥卡镇，有两级酋长， ”一位在阿南布拉州东南部的奥卡社区被授予功绩的伊博族酋长说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一个顾问委员会。这些酋长分别代表 Awka 社区 33 个村庄。名誉酋长，授予奥卡镇为该镇发展做出贡献的人[…]外国酋长通常属于名誉酋长阶层。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;老挝农民的生计岌岌可危。中国开发商排干沼泽&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;因此，尼日利亚人并没有太在意这项授予。 “这就像获得荣誉学位一样，”来自阿南布拉、在拉各斯 CCECC 工作的维维安·奇索姆 (Vivian Chisom) 说。 “我真的不在乎中国人是否获得头衔。这是仪式性的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chisom 本人并不认识任何中国领导人，但她在社交媒体上读到过有关李曼虎的报道。 “他绝对没有任何权力决定社区中的任何事情，”她说，并补充说，李甚至可能买下了这个头衔，这并非闻所未闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng Cheng，一家中国工厂尼日利亚老板表示，荣誉称号很容易买到，但能否解决问题取决于持有者的能力，与称号无关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李澄清自己没有买荣誉称号，胡耸耸肩对建议不予理睬，称中国领导人“献出贡献，接受感谢”。感谢越多，越好”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊博族酋长不知道有任何中国人购买图书，并声称这些图书不出售给公民或外国人，至少在奥卡不出售。另一方面，常驻中国的尼日利亚人 Samson Fashola 表示：“这是一款现有游戏，并非中国独有。我们的公民也会购买头衔。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早在 2007 年，BBC 就曾报道过“尼日利亚人为头衔而疯狂”，而当地人则担心这一荣誉会被贬低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“给予外国投资者酋长头衔可能会引发不同民族之间争夺国家权力和外部发展资源的竞争。”徐在他的论文中写道。当首长决定授予李首长职位时，当地议会的一位首长拒绝了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他总是找借口从我们公司拿走好项目，”李说。 “他担心如果我当了酋长，他就做不下去了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着房地产市场放缓，非洲对中国的出口大幅下降&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最终，随着酋长态度坚决，当地酋长也就放弃了争论。李开始获得好的项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李于 2020 年底在 Covid-19 大流行期间返回中国。那时他已经离开家人三年了，并多次感染疟疾。他还觉得自己在国有公司的潜力有限。他于 2021 年离开中地海外，开始在中国寻找商机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但非洲一直在他的脑海中挥之不去。 2022年7月，他前往喀麦隆开展贸易业务。然后在三月下旬，他回到尼日利亚。虽然他不住在克罗斯河州，但他的酋长地位仍然得到承认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他向潜在的商业伙伴和政府官员介绍自己时，他会提供自己的身份证——酋长李曼虎说。 – 他说当地人会表达他们的尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他从北京首都国际机场向近 49 万抖音粉丝发布了“再见”。 “虽然这里有很多东西放不下，但我觉得我的部落更需要我。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s increase in military exercises helps aid diplomacy efforts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3230733/chinas-increase-military-exercises-helps-aid-diplomacy-efforts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/b95db2ae-be83-442a-ad2b-91e7831ddb90_c19fd31d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;过去十年，中国人民解放军 (PLA) 扩大了外交范围在习近平主席推动国家军队现代化并赢得全球尊重的推动下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《南华早报》通过分析官方通讯社新华社发表的文章发现，自2013年以来，中国举行的军事演习次数外国军队数量增加了一倍多。中国海军也增加了港口访问，特别是对南半球国家的访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最高军事指挥机构中央军委的军事官员也访问了更多的外国同行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但是，尽管上周刚满96岁的解放军已经做出了这些努力来树立和平力量的形象，但它也变得更有能力将军队部署在远离海岸的地方。这引起了美国和其他一些西方国家的怀疑，他们指责中国想要重塑国际秩序，违背自由民主价值观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解放军远望五号探测船的对接2022年在斯里兰卡的军事行动引起了印度的强烈抗议，其在非洲之角吉布提的第一个外国基地引起了人们的关注，最近，中国帮助建造的柬埔寨云朗海军基地引发了人们对中国海军可能在那里建立存在的担忧尽管北京一再否认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一月份关于中国军事外交的听证会上，美中经济与安全审查委员会委员兰德尔·施赖弗 (Randall Schriver) 表示：“在[共产党]的指导下中国人民解放军正在开展形式多样的军事外交，更加频繁地举行双边和多边演习，建立对外基地和进入机会，同外国伙伴开展军事行动，积极推动对外开放。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个对外议程非常有力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回顾2012年习近平上台以来党的十八大以来的新华社报道，可以看出，解放军扩大了外交范围，俄罗斯和巴基斯坦仍然是其最大的军事伙伴。尽管受到 Covid-19 的干扰，但与这两个国家的关系继续变得更加密切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但就北京与解放军寻求争取的其他国家的关系而言，中国在实质和内容上仍然远远落后。 depth of joint military drills, experts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is also interacting less regularly with its top geopolitical rival, the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As tensions have risen with the West, military exercises between China and Russia have had the greatest range of areas being trained, with live fire drills and joint rescue missions most common, according to the Post analysis. China has taken part in at least 45 exercises that also involved Russia, with 20 of them bilateral exercises, since the 18th party congress in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two countries also continued their exercises during the Covid-19 pandemic, including the Zapad/Interaction-2021 and Joint Sea 2021 drills. That was despite a sharp drop of diplomatic outreach from China during its three years of closed borders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) that includes China and Russia has been also holding larger combined exercises on counterterrorism.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As the US and China woo with military drills, who will Southeast Asia choose?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The bloc of Central Asian nations plus India, Pakistan and Iran identifies combating terrorism, extremism and separatism as a core tenet of its security policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 4,000 troops took part in the SCO Peace Mission 2021 drills, held in Russia – the most in the series of exercises. The focus was on combined command and “mixed formations” of personnel of different militaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The drills with the SCO are much more substantive in scale and in the weapons and equipment sent than those that China holds with Asean [Association of Southeast Asian Nations] countries,” said Jackie Wong Siu-hei, a predoctoral fellow at George Washington University who has compiled data on China&#39;s military diplomatic outreach from 2000 to 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The only Asean member that China has held military exercises with which involved more sophisticated arms – including armoured vehicles and live-fire drills – is Laos, a country that relies heavily on Chinese infrastructural investment, Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But those drills still pale in comparison to SCO exercises. Wong said the size of the drills and the weaponry China sends reveal its varying military diplomatic goals with other nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared with the US, China&#39;s drills with its Asean neighbours are smaller and less in-depth. In the 2023 Cobra Gold multilateral exercises in Thailand, China only took part in its search and rescue portion with 25 troops. The US sent its biggest contingent in a decade of more than 6,000 troops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A reason behind the limited engagement between Asean countries and China could lie in America&#39;s long history of working with nations in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US military outreach has included giving Asian military leaders executive education, as well as the American arms that have made their way to many Asian countries&#39; arsenals. Many aspects of US training have been embedded into the military training of Asean countries – a result of using American arms such as F-16 fighter jets and complying with the confidentiality conditions that come with using these weapons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By contrast, SCO countries use few US arms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said that meant Asian countries are less inclined to hold in-depth combined training with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China might be thinking that it has consolidated its identity that contrasts with the US,” he said. “美国正在发射导弹并举行更多的实弹演习。 China is perhaps saying that its military cooperation is oriented around peace, unlike the US.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zenobia Chan, a PhD candidate at Princeton University&#39;s politics department and one of Wong&#39;s co-authors in the research, said the vast difference in the level of participation meant military exercises of Asean countries that China takes part in are largely symbolic, with a low level of participation by PLA personnel and the main activity being search and rescue exercises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asean countries still participate in them because they wish to maintain good ties with both the US and China, she said, citing interviews with officials from Singapore, Indonesia and the Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For them, China&#39;s a very important economic partner, whereas the US is more the military partner or guarantor.他们不想让任何一方不高兴。 So it means that they are constrained by US factors in that they can&#39;t work too closely with China, but they also don&#39;t want to offend China, if you will.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said in countries that receive a lot of arms deliveries from the US, the number of Chinese infrastructure projects correlated with the number of combined military exercises. That correlation does not exist with countries that do not use many American arms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our theory is that because a lot of countries rely a lot on trade with China and also these infrastructure projects, they want to preserve that economic relationship with China. On the other hand, those countries that actually receive lots of American arms deliveries, they also rely on the US for security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And to please both sides, they do these more symbolic exercises with China in order to placate China while still getting US arms deliveries or security guarantees in some cases,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of those symbolic acts of diplomatic outreach also include port visits and senior level meetings, such as those between defence ministers and more senior officials including the vice-chairmen of China&#39;s Central Military Commission (CMC), the country&#39;s highest military command.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior-level meetings are part of the key performance indicators of military diplomacy, Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The upper level, they want you to do military diplomacy.那么，如何表明你已经完成了军事外交呢？你访问。 That&#39;s just how the incentive structure is set up within [China],” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of the port visits were performed in Africa by fleets on missions in the Gulf of Aden to protect ships from pirates. In 2023, the fleet visited Nigeria, Congo-Brazzaville, Gabon and Ghana, and held combined exercises with their militaries, the review of Xinhua articles shows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Peace Ark missions that provide free medical care to local residents also perform a bulk of the diplomatic outreach.今年，医院船访问了基里巴斯和所罗门群岛； the Pacific nations that switched diplomatic allegiance from Taiwan to Beijing in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pacific is emerging as one of the most active theatres of the China-US geopolitical rivalry. The US with its regional allies have met with multiple countries in the Western Pacific to counter Chinese initiatives there, such as a policing pact signed with the Solomons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though the US and China once held bilateral military exercises, these stopped in 2019. The last one was a humanitarian assistance and disaster management drill in Hawaii involving more than 200 Chinese troops and as many American troops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, the only time Chinese and American troops would take part in drills together would be in exercises involving several countries, such as this year&#39;s Cobra Gold and those under the banner of Asean Defence Ministers&#39; Meeting Plus (ADMM-Plus) which includes the 10 Asean members as well as Australia, China, India, Japan, New Zealand, South Korea, Russia and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s military diplomacy is becoming a more prominent component of its overall foreign policy,” said Anna Ashton, director of China corporate affairs and US-China relations at risk consultancy Eurasia Group. “With regard to security issues, China is asserting an alternative vision for maintaining international peace and security.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi&#39;s vision for world safety is encapsulated in his Global Security Initiative (GSI), which confronts some foreign policy principles of the West. It criticises sanctions that have not been authorised by the UN Security Council and supports regional groupings in the Global South, which aligns with Beijing&#39;s long-time opposition against non-Asian countries weighing in on contentious issues such as the territorial disputes in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The GSI is China&#39;s concept for maintaining global peace and security in the 21st century,” Ashton said. “It is still fairly abstract, but it clearly supports China&#39;s vision of the ideal global architecture in contrast to the existing, US-dominated architecture.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelensky thanks Germany’s Olaf Scholz for additional Patriot launchers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3230913/zelensky-thanks-germanys-olaf-scholz-additional-patriot-launchers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 06:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/b8489b37-c527-4b45-a762-53e6f0ad45b9_b219e16a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky has thanked Germany and its Chancellor Olaf Scholz for two additional Patriot air defence system launchers his embattled country has received.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is very important,” Zelensky said in his evening address on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thank you.谢谢你，德国。 Thank you to the people,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thank you, Olaf!”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Zelensky cites &#39;treason&#39; as he fires military enlistment chiefs in all Ukraine regions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;News of the Patriot delivery was made public a few days ago and Zelensky thanked Scholz immediately after that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US-built Patriot systems are particularly valuable for Ukraine because, according to Kyiv, they have already intercepted Russian hypersonic missiles several times. Every strengthening of Ukraine&#39;s air defence means saving thousands of lives, Zelensky emphasised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new German deliveries also include 10 more Bandvagn 206 multipurpose tracked vehicles, six heavy-duty articulated trucks and about 6,000 rounds of smoke ammunition for 155-millimetre calibre artillery pieces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Germany also provided machine guns, shooting glasses, binoculars and mine-clearing equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to air defence help, mine clearance support is particularly important at the moment, Zelensky said. Due to mines and unexploded ammunition, around 174,000 square kilometres of Ukrainian territory are currently dangerous for citizens.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rape victims, imperfect or not, are not to blame]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230657/rape-victims-imperfect-or-not-are-not-blame?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/02bca356-e0de-4e74-9799-b96f6d29e6e5_1d934a6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A star-studded Chinese TV drama delving into workplace sexual harassment titled Imperfect Victim recently ended but the debate it triggered rages on.该剧共 29 集，每集 45 分钟，以一起强奸案为中心：美丽年轻的私人助理赵迅指控她强大而英俊的​​老板、公司总裁程功强奸了她。 But the case is complex, and so are the characters involved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Within three months, Cheng, a married man, promotes Zhao from a trainee to the position of senior assistant, multiplies her salary and showers her with gifts worth 880,000 yuan (US$122,170).她几乎没有试图阻止他。然后在一个雨夜，警察在收到有关强奸的匿名举报后出现在该公司的公寓套房。受到创伤和困惑的赵否认自己受到了侵犯。 Five days later, she files a lawsuit against him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The popular and high-quality drama led to a heated discussion among the audience about the nature of sexual harassment, gender inequality, the unbalanced power play in the office and, interestingly, who is really the victim.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many viewers disliked Zhao, accusing her of being weak, vain and greedy.有人说，这个角色是一个“既想当情妇又想有贞操牌坊”的人——这是封建时代用来纪念女性非凡贞操的纪念碑。有人说，赵在整部剧中几乎没有说过“不”。 “一个女孩，无论多么天真和愚蠢，都知道如何说不。所以，赵勋只是一个狡猾的女人，想得到东西而不付出努力。”一位人士说道。 Some – mostly male, I imagine – even claimed the president was the real victim.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the show&#39;s opening scene, Zhao, wrapped in a white towel, is curled up in a bathtub, crying while it rains outside and her boss sleeps in the bedroom. Her pained expression tells me clearly that she felt violated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if she did not fight back when he forced himself upon her, her silence did not mean she was willing.只要一个人不同意发生性行为，就构成强奸。对我来说很明显她没有。在进入卧室之前，很明显她想离开，但他把她抱起来并带她上床。 It&#39;s clear to me that he committed sexual violence, a crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many in the audience have scrutinised areas where Zhao could have done better;例如，她可以拒绝他的礼物。 But the reality is that in many Chinese companies, the boss has such power over his employees that refusing his gift may mean the end of employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am not too surprised by the criticism aimed at Zhao.对强奸受害者进行人格诽谤并不罕见，而且不仅仅在中国。 Some 35 years ago, Hollywood produced a rather unusual film called The Accused, which focused on the victim&#39;s experience.一名年轻女子在酒吧被三名男子轮奸。她成功起诉了他们和旁观者。当袭击者受到起诉时，她的性格受到质疑。她有饮酒史吗？ Was her skirt too short?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Imperfect Victim, the president countersues Zhao for defamation.她的个人信息被泄露，她在网上遭到无情攻击，她的名誉被毁。 Unable to bear it all, she tries to commit suicide but survives with serious injuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In real life, her death would have been a probable outcome.但导演决定积极正面地诠释这一点。在她出色的律师的帮助下，赵赢得了官司，程被责令向她道歉。她得到了她要求的1元赔偿——这与钱无关，而是为了洗清自己的罪名。 For me, that was an unrealistic touch in an otherwise very realistic drama.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Xiaoxuan, a prominent face in China&#39;s #MeToo movement, was also sued for defamation after she accused Zhu Jun, a high-profile TV presenter, of sexual assault.她提出反诉，要求道歉和赔偿，但未果。去年，北京一家法院裁定她缺乏足够证据，上诉被驳回。这并不令人意外。 High legal barriers and social stigma have silenced many victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am delighted to see a TV drama like Imperfect Victim dealing with such serious social issues head on.几个世纪以来，女性低人一等的儒家思想主导了中国社会。 It is partly due to the deeply rooted patriarchal culture that sexual harassment is prevalent in the workplace, so much so that on International Women&#39;s Day this year, the government issued a guidance specifically to combat the problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I do find the title Imperfect Victim problematic in that it might further encourage a victim-blaming culture.让我们不要关注受害者的弱点，而是以批判的眼光审视肇事者。 A victim is a victim, whether she is perfect or not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump swoops into Iowa Fair to scramble DeSantis’ effort to reboot campaign]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230912/trump-swoops-iowa-fair-scramble-desantis-effort-reboot-campaign?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 05:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/6430402b-ac0b-48fa-ba4f-f47d43b4f962_87fcf05e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Republican presidential rivals Donald Trump and Ron DeSantis were holding competing events in the early nominating state of Iowa on Saturday, at a time when the former president overwhelmingly dominates opinion polls and the Florida governor is scrambling to reset his troubled campaign.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis, who has had two staff shake-ups in the past three weeks and is sinking in the polls, had long planned to attend the Iowa State Fair, a political must for aspiring presidential candidates in the state that kicks off the Republican nominating contest in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s late announcement on Tuesday that he was also going to attend the event on the same day as DeSantis amounted to a political gatecrashing of an appearance the Florida governor hopes will kick-start his stalled campaign.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis is making a high-risk bet that he can halt Trump&#39;s march to the Republican presidential nomination by winning Iowa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked about his governing style on Saturday, DeSantis said he cared more about protecting voters than his own fortunes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So we&#39;ll do what&#39;s right. We&#39;ll take the consequences and let the chips fall where they may,” he said in an interview with Iowa&#39;s Republican Governor Kim Reynolds at the fair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the start of the interview, Reynolds reproached a group of protesters who were blowing whistles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later on, a large crowd cheered Trump as he arrived at the fair.后来他在露天酒吧发表演讲，吹嘘自己目前的领先地位。 “We&#39;re way up in the polls,” Trump said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;DeSantis replaces campaign manager as 2024 US presidential bid flounders&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While DeSantis steered clear of attacking Trump, DeSantis barbs were fair game for the former president. He told reporters he did not think he had written off the Florida governor too early.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked whether he saw DeSantis as his main rival, Trump responded: “I don&#39;t see him.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump, the Republican frontrunner by a large margin, brought along a delegation of Florida Republicans who endorsed him over DeSantis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the other candidates came here they had like six people,” Trump told supporters in a speech at a restaurant bar at the fairgrounds. “We stopped at three different places and we&#39;ve never been treated so well.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Judge warns Trump not to threaten witnesses in 2020 election subversion case&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Iowa holds the first of the state-by-state Republican nominating contests on January 15. DeSantis hopes that a win in the Midwestern state will give him valuable momentum against Trump before primaries in New Hampshire and South Carolina.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s appearance at the fair could steal the limelight from the governor and dominate the headlines. It is held in the state capital Des Moines and runs from August 10 to August 20. Last year, it attracted more than 1 million visitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s appearance will also complicate efforts for the rest of the Republican field. Apart from Trump and DeSantis, nine other candidates will be attending the fair between August 11 and August 18, but all are languishing in single digits, more than 40 points behind Trump according to the latest Reuters/Ipsos poll of likely Republican voters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to that August 3 poll, Trump also leads DeSantis by 34 points, 47 per cent to 13 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of Trump&#39;s rivals had agreed to be interviewed individually by Reynolds between August 11 and August 18. Trump turned down her invitation, angered by her public neutrality in the primary race and her appearance with DeSantis at several of his Iowa events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On stage with Reynolds, DeSantis avoided speaking about Trump, instead homing in on Biden&#39;s economic policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On day one, we take all Biden regulations and executive orders and throw them in the trash can,” DeSantis said. “Bidenomics is basically Americans have a lower standard of living so that he can pursue his political, ideological agenda, and that is not acceptable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Bloomberg&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Meta confirms Lil Tay’s Instagram account was hacked in death hoax amid publicity stunt claims]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230911/meta-confirms-lil-tays-instagram-account-was-hacked-death-hoax-amid-publicity-stunt-claims?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 04:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/b0bb8c01-766f-4597-b226-45a367141c67_386bc7ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Lil Tay&#39;s Instagram account was indeed hacked, leading to a post that falsely reported the Asian rapper&#39;s death earlier this week, according to Meta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite swirling allegations the hoax was just a ploy for publicity, the social media giant – which owns Instagram – confirmed the hacking to TMZ on Saturday, noting it helped the controversial 14-year-old regain control of her account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A statement claiming to be from the family of Tay was posted to her feed on Wednesday, alleging she and brother Jason Tian, 21, had both suddenly died.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have no words to express the unbearable loss and indescribable pain,” read the since-deleted post. “她哥哥的去世给我们的悲痛增添了难以想象的深度。 During this time of immense sorrow, we kindly ask for privacy as we grieve this overwhelming loss, as the circumstances surrounding [Tay] and her brother&#39;s passing are still under investigation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;News of their deaths rocked social media, however suspicions grew throughout the day as some close to Tay, whose mother is Chinese, said they could not (or would not) confirm the allegations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Business Insider, Tay&#39;s father, Christopher Hope, “declined to answer whether his daughter was still alive,” while her former manager Harry Tsang said the situation called for “cautious consideration.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What&#39;s more, police departments in both Los Angeles (where Tay reportedly lived) and Vancouver (where she grew up) said they had no reports of her death and no investigations into the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following day, Tay confirmed to TMZ that not only are she and her brother alive, but her account had been “compromised by a 3rd party and used to spread jarring misinformation and rumours.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But questions about the legitimacy of the hacking claims soon arose, with many on social media wondering if the death hoax was instead a publicity stunt or “shameless cry for attention.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lil Tay not dead, says her social media accounts were hacked: new report&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a statement to Fox News Digital on Thursday, Tsang said he believes “the reported hacking incident may not have occurred” – and suggested Tay&#39;s older brother may be to blame.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My rationale for this perspective is twofold,” he explained, while noting that he has not spoken to Tay&#39;s family in two years. “首先，在 Meta/Instagram 等平台上恢复受损帐户通常不需要 24 小时的时间范围。 Secondly, the actions of Lil Tay&#39;s brother, renowned for his propensity for extreme measures, led me to hypothesise an alternative motive behind this occurrence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsang went on to suggest that money and renewed fame could have been motivations behind both the hoax and hacking claims – “an endeavour to illicitly extract funds from devoted supporters and unwitting bystanders,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before this week, Tay&#39;s brother was believed to be the source of 2021 posts accusing their father of abuse.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Six dead after migrant boat capsizes in Channel, search continues for the missing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230910/six-dead-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-channel-search-continues-missing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 03:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/a65f38ae-eb81-40e6-bacf-7a5c1c5c4d09_7f1aa430.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Six Afghans died when a migrant boat heading to Britain sank in the Channel on Saturday, French officials said, as a search continued to find those still missing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This shipwreck is a terrible human tragedy,” French State Secretary for the Sea Herve Berville told reporters at the port of Calais, the hub for rescue operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He denounced “criminal traffickers” who send migrants “to their death” and pledged to fight their smuggling networks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deputy public prosecutor for the coastal city of Boulogne, Philippe Sabatier, told Agence France-Presse all six fatalities were Afghan men believed to be in their 30s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rest of the passengers were “almost all Afghans with some Sudanese, mostly adults with some minors”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The French and British coastguard services rescued 61 survivors, said Berville.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French coastal authority Premar said up to two people could still be missing and that search efforts would continue until nightfall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My thoughts and prayers are with those affected by the tragic loss of life in the Channel today,” British interior minister Suella Braverman said on social media site X, formerly known as Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French Prime Minister Elisabeth Borne posted that her “thoughts go out to the victims” as she praised the efforts of the rescue teams.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;41 migrants, including 3 kids, missing after Mediterranean shipwreck&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s pretty tough, they&#39;re humans. You will never get used to bringing back dead bodies,” said Regis Holy, the captain of a boat that retrieved five of the victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There will be even more tragedies … they (migrants) risk everything, it will never stop,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesperson for the Utopia56 humanitarian group blamed border “repression” for the tragedy, telling Agence France-Presse the difficulty of securing legal passage only “increases the dangerousness of crossings and pushes people to take more and more risks to reach England”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calais mayor Natacha Bouchart of the right-wing Republicans party denounced a “failure” by the French government to stop such crossings and demanded migrants be moved inland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In England, the MP for the Channel port of Dover, Natalie Elphicke, a member of the ruling Conservative Party, also called for more effective French government action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today&#39;s tragedy underlines why we must stop the small boats to keep people safe and prevent loss of life in the Channel,” she wrote on X.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These overcrowded and unseaworthy deathtraps should obviously be stopped by the French authorities from leaving the French coast in the first place,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The boat capsized at around 2am local time off the northern coast of France, according to the prosecutor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Agence France-Presse reporter in Calais saw some of those rescued disembarking from a patrol boat with emergency services on site.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Channel between France and Britain is one of the world&#39;s busiest shipping lanes and strong currents are common.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Stranded migrants saved, but dozens missing off Italy in rough seas&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Around 1,000 migrants are on the northern French coast waiting for an opportunity to cross the Channel, according to the authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 100,000 migrants have crossed the Channel on small boats from France to southeast England since Britain began publicly recording the arrivals in 2018, official figures revealed on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French authorities have stepped up patrols and other deterrent measures after London agreed in March to send Paris hundreds of millions of euros annually towards the effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent days there have been several attempts to cross the Channel in boats after an improvement in the weather.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overnight on Thursday, Premar reported that 116 migrants had been rescued, including children, on three separate boats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 755 migrants were detected on Thursday on 14 small boats headed for England&#39;s southern coast, UK interior ministry statistics showed, the highest tally on a single day this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those boats brought the number of arrivals so far this year to nearly 16,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The figures have piled pressure on British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak&#39;s government, which has made “stopping the boats” a key priority ahead of general elections due next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Five migrants died at sea and four went missing while trying to cross to Britain from France last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2021, 27 migrants died when a boat capsized in the Channel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following year saw a record 45,000 migrants make the crossing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Afghan universities ready to readmit women but not until Taliban leader says it’s OK, official says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3230909/afghan-universities-ready-readmit-women-not-until-taliban-leader-says-its-ok-official-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 03:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/71720c73-fc24-4bcc-aa4a-80b37422aad2_fa090d9f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Afghanistan&#39;s universities are ready to readmit female students, but the ruling Taliban&#39;s leader has the ultimate say on when that might happen – if it happens at all, an education official said Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Taliban barred women from campuses last December, triggering global outrage. Girls had been banned from school beyond sixth grade soon after the Taliban returned to power in August 2021. Afghanistan is the only country in the world with bans on female education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Afghanistan&#39;s higher education minister, Nida Mohammed Nadim, said at the time the university ban was necessary to prevent the mixing of genders and because he believed some subjects being taught violated the principles of Islam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the ban, issued from the southern city of Kandahar by the Taliban leader Hibatullah Akhundzada, was in place until further notice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An adviser at the Higher Education Ministry, Molvi Abdul Jabbar, said universities were ready to readmit female students as soon as Akhundzada gives the order for the ban to be lifted. He was unable to say when or if that would happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Akhundzada “ordered that the universities be closed, so they closed,” he told Associated Press. “当他说营业时，他们就会在同一天营业。 All our leaders are in favour of (restarting girls&#39; education), even our ministers are in favour of it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jabbar said he last met Akhundzada seven or eight years ago. He fought alongside him against the Russians during the 10-year Soviet war in Afghanistan and has been part of the Taliban for 27 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is only because of our obedience (to Akhundzada) that we are following his orders,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Who will be the midwives?&#39;: Shut out of jobs, Afghan women retrain as nurses&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;His comments are another sign of diverging opinions within the Taliban about the decision-making process and Akhundzada&#39;s edicts, with chief spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid moving quickly to reject reports of division. They also show the authority that Akhundzada wields over the Taliban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nadim had presented the ban as a temporary measure while solutions were found to fix issues around gender segregation, course material and dress codes. He said universities would reopen for women once they were resolved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Taliban made similar promises about secondary school access for girls, saying classes would resume for them once “technical issues” around uniforms and transport were sorted out, but girls are still shut out of classrooms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jabbar said the education sector was as it was before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everything is ready in advance, whether it&#39;s school or university studies.可能是（开始）时间不同，早上有男生，下午有女生。 Or there will be girls in the morning and boys in the afternoon.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His comments come days ahead of the second anniversary of the Taliban&#39;s return to power.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shippers warned to stay away from Iranian waters over seizure threat as US-Iran tensions high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3230908/shippers-warned-stay-away-iranian-waters-over-seizure-threat-us-iran-tensions-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 02:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/27ff0525-7619-4319-aa22-1bb3063b6752_5afb6b7a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Western-backed maritime forces in the Middle East on Saturday warned shippers travelling through the strategic Strait of Hormuz to stay as far away from Iranian territorial waters as possible to avoid being seized, a stark advisory amid heightened tensions between Iran and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A similar warning went out to shippers earlier this year ahead of Iran seizing two tankers travelling near the strait, the narrow mouth of the Persian Gulf through which 20 per cent of the world&#39;s oil passes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Iran and the US now near an apparent deal that would see billions of Iranian assets held in South Korea unfrozen in exchange for the release of five Iranian-Americans detained in Tehran, the warning shows that the tensions remain high at sea. Already, the US is exploring plans to put armed troops on commercial ships in the strait to deter Iran amid a build-up of troops, ships and aircraft in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US may put armed troops on commercial ships to stop Iran seizures&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US Navy Commander Timothy Hawkins, a spokesman for the Middle East-based 5th Fleet, acknowledged the warning had been given, but declined to discuss specifics about it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A US-backed maritime group called the International Maritime Security Construct “is notifying regional mariners of appropriate precautions to minimise the risk of seizure based on current regional tensions, which we seek to de-escalate,” Hawkins said. “Vessels are being advised to transit as far away from Iranian territorial waters as possible.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, a European Union-led maritime organisation watching shipping in the strait has “warned of a possibility of an attack on a merchant vessel of unknown flag in the Strait of Hormuz in the next 12 to 72 hours,” said private intelligence firm Ambrey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Previously, after a similar warning was issued, a merchant vessel was seized by Iranian authorities under a false pretext,” the firm warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU-led mission, called the European Maritime Awareness in the Strait of Hormuz, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Iran transfers jailed US citizens to house arrest in step towards swap deal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Iran&#39;s state-run IRNA news agency cited this Associated Press report without quoting any Iranian officials regarding it. Iran&#39;s mission to the United Nations did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Strait of Hormuz is in the territorial waters of Iran and Oman, which at its narrowest point is just 33km (21 miles) wide.航道双向宽度仅为 3 公里（2 英里）。任何影响它的因素都会波及全球能源市场，可能导致原油价格上涨。 That then trickles down to consumers through what they pay for petrol and other oil products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There has been a wave of attacks on ships attributed to Iran since 2019, following the Trump administration unilaterally withdrawing America from the 2015 Iran nuclear deal and reimposing crushing sanctions on Tehran.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those assaults resumed in late April, when Iran seized a ship carrying oil for Chevron Corporation and another tanker called the Niovi in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The taking of the two tankers in under a week comes as the Marshall Islands-flagged Suez Rajan sits off Houston, probably waiting to offload sanctioned Iranian oil apparently seized by the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those seizures led the US military to launch a major deployment in the region, including thousands of Marines and sailors on both the amphibious assault ship USS Bataan and the USS Carter Hall, a landing ship. Images released by the Navy showed the Bataan and Carter Hall in the Red Sea on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 02:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Anger as Hawaii wildfire death toll climbs to 80; residents confront devastation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230907/anger-hawaii-wildfire-death-toll-climbs-80-residents-confront-devastation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 02:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/e80f76d5-9a0d-4867-9d42-03f022602e74_ae5da74d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The death toll from a horrific wildfire in Hawaii climbed to 80 as residents confronted the devastation and criticisms grew on Saturday over the emergency response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 2,200 structures were damaged or destroyed in the fire, the Federal Emergency Management Agency said, estimating that it would cost some US$5.5 billion to rebuild affected communities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hawaiian authorities said they were opening an investigation into the handling of the fire as a congresswoman from the state&#39;s Big Island acknowledged that officials had underestimated the dangers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the historic resort city of Lahaina on the island of Maui, resident Anthony Garcia said the fire had gutted the flat he was renting and destroyed all his belongings and memories.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It took everything, everything! It&#39;s heartbreaking,” the 80-year-old California native, who has lived in Lahaina for three decades, said. “It&#39;s a lot to take in.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The town of 12,000, once the proud home of the Hawaiian royal family, has been reduced to ruins, its lively hotels and restaurants turned to ashes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A majestic banyan tree that has been the centre of the community for 150 years has been scarred by the flames, but still stands upright, its branches denuded of green and its sooty trunk transformed into an awkward skeleton.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;This is insane&#39;: probe launched as anger mounts over Hawaii wildfire response&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hawaii&#39;s Attorney General Anne Lopez said her office would examine “critical decision-making and standing policies leading up to, during and after the wildfires on Maui and Hawaii islands this week.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Late on Friday, Maui County officials revised the death toll to 80 and Governor Josh Green warned that the number of fatalities was sure to rise further. More than 1,400 people were in emergency evacuation shelters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We underestimated the lethality, the quickness of fire,” Hawaii Congresswoman Jill Tokuda told CNN on Saturday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maui suffered numerous power cuts during the crisis, preventing many residents from receiving emergency alerts on their mobile phones – something, Tokuda said, officials should have prepared for.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have got to make sure that we do better,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fires follow other extreme weather events in North America this summer, with record-breaking wildfires still burning across Canada and a major heatwave baking the US southwest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Europe and parts of Asia have also endured soaring temperatures, with major fires and floods wreaking havoc. Scientists have said global warming caused by carbon emissions is contributing to the extreme weather.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For some of those who made it back into Lahaina, there was a momentary sense of elation when they tearfully reconnected with neighbours they feared might not have escaped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You made it!”奇娜·乔 (Chyna Cho) 在废墟中拥抱安珀·兰登 (Amber Langdon) 时喊道。 “I was trying to find you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For some of the luckiest, there was joy – albeit tempered by the scale of the tragedy that counts among the worst natural disasters to hit the state of Hawaii.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I just couldn&#39;t believe it,” Keith Todd told Agence France-Presse after finding his home intact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m so grateful, but at the same time it&#39;s so devastating.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Todd, 64, discovered his home and his neighbour&#39;s house untouched, and his solar panels providing electricity to the fridge, which was still dispensing ice on demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fears of looting were also on residents&#39; minds, and county authorities said anyone accessing Lahaina would have to prove they lived or were staying at a hotel there, and that a curfew would be in place between 10pm and 6am.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of those who made it back to Lahaina wandered in stunned silence trying to take in the scale of the destruction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anthony La Puente, 44, said the shock of finding his home burned to nothing was profound.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It sucks not being able to find the things you grew up with, or the things you remember,” he told Agence France-Presse of the house he had lived in for 16 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The only thing I can say is that it hurts.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Maui wildfire death toll hits 53, resort town in smouldering ruins&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden said in a statement on Wednesday evening that he had ordered “all available federal assets” to help Hawaii.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, media mogul Oprah Winfrey has offered a helping hand to Maui residents who have been impacted by the fires. And she is not alone among celebrities expressing their concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The billionaire talk-show host, who is a part-time resident of the island, delivered a variety of supplies on Thursday at a shelter in Wailuku, two days after the fire hit the historic town of Lahaina.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a little overwhelming … but I&#39;m really so pleased to have so many people … supporting and, you know, people are just bringing what they can and doing what they can,” she told the BBC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Instagram video shared by non-profit organisation Kāko&#39;o Haleakalā showed Winfrey carrying pillows and giving one to a resident lying on a cot. The account thanked Winfrey “for following through” by also delivering cots and toiletries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She even spent some time with the people here. It was very much appreciated,” the caption said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winfrey also told the BBC she “went shopping” at Walmart and Costco to get her supplies, which also included shampoo, nappies, sheets and pillowcases. In recent years and months, the mogul&#39;s properties in Montecito also faced a variety of natural disasters, including floods and fires.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the fires broke out, Winfrey and her Hollywood peers spoke out to raise awareness and voice support for Maui residents. Fast X actor Jason Momoa, who was born in Hawaii, recently shared a set of informational photos from environmental non-profit Āina Momona.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are devastated and heartbroken for our friends and &#39;ohana on Maui who [have] been impacted by the recent wildfires,” Momoa wrote. He also shared a link to resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Instagram, Momoa urges tourists to avoid Maui for the time being.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Maui is not the place to have your vacation right now,” Momoa wrote. “DO NOT TRAVEL TO MAUI.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Do not convince yourself that your presence is needed on an island that is suffering this deeply,” his post continued. “Mahalo to everyone who has donated and shown aloha to the community in this time of need.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amazon founder Jeff Bezos and his fiancee Lauren Sanchez said they will give US$100 million towards restoration efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sanchez said in an Instagram post they are “heartbroken” by the recent events in Maui and are creating a fund to “help Maui get back on its feet now and over the coming years.” Bezos, who has a net worth of US$163 billion according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index, owns an estate on La Perouse Bay at the southern tip of the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The immediate needs are important, and so is the longer term rebuilding that will have to happen - even after much of the attention has subsided,” said Sanchez, a helicopter pilot and founder of Black Ops Aviation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musician Mick Fleetwood also mourned the destruction, writing on Thursday on Instagram, “MAUI and The Lahaina community have been my home for several decades.” The Fleetwood Mac star owned a waterfront restaurant and bar, Fleetwood&#39;s, that was lost to the flames.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On behalf of myself and my family I share my heartfelt thoughts and prayers for the people of MAUI,” he continued. “We are committed to supporting the community and those affected by this disaster in the days month[s] and years to come.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actor Pierce Brosnan and his wife Keely Shaye Smith – who have a home in Kauai – also brought awareness to the wildfires. Shaye Smith shared a video of a beach sunset on Thursday and encouraged followers to take action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My sincere and heartfelt prayers for Maui &amp; Hawai&#39;i Counties, the Hawaiian community, residents, families and animals affected by these unprecedented wildfires,” she wrote. “If you are able, please consider making a donation to the Hawaii / Maui Community Foundation to help those in need.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Tribune News Service, Bloomberg, Business Insider&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 02:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>