<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Is the acai berry craze boon or threat for the Amazon?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3232389/acai-berry-craze-boon-or-threat-amazon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/080b874c-c3e9-4812-8416-847ce324204c_95b36229.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;何塞·迪奥戈 (Jose Diogo) 在巴西亚马逊酷热的环境中攀爬树木并收获一簇黑浆果：巴西莓，一种时尚的“超级食品”，正在重塑世界上最大的热带雨林 - 无论是好是坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;41 岁的迪奥戈生活在一个由逃亡奴隶建立的贫困偏远社区，他是一名与纽约或东京的高档超市货架截然不同，那里的浆果以果汁冰糕、冰沙、果汁、粉末和药丸的形式出售，受到格温妮丝·帕特洛 (Gwyneth Paltrow) 和梅根·马克尔 (Meghan Markle) 等人的欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他亲眼目睹巴西莓热潮给巴西亚马逊地区带来的变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2000 年代巴西莓因其丰富的营养和抗氧化特性而享誉国际以来，它释放了巨大的经济潜力亚马逊地区传统农民的繁荣，并被誉为在不破坏雨林的情况下为雨林带来“绿色发展”的一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但专家表示，这也威胁着亚马逊地区的生物多样性，因为单一作物阿萨伊棕榈田变得越来越常见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迪奥戈住在帕拉州北部的伊加拉佩圣若昂村，他正在用阿萨伊树赚的钱为自己建造一座砖房。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每个收获季节，我们的情况都会好很多，”他边说边把小浆果刮进一个大篮子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天气好的时候，他可以装满 25 个这样的篮子，他说，带回家的价格在 300 到 625 雷亚尔（60 美元到 128 美元）之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浆果被乘船运到州首府贝伦，在那里，汗流浃背的工人将大量浆果运到市场上出售。在脆弱的水果变质之前尽快出售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西莓长期以来一直被土著群体食用，是巴西东北部的主要烹饪方式，与木薯粉一起食用，或用于搭配鱼和其他菜肴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;过去二十年里，其深紫色果肉在巴西广受欢迎，人们经常将其制成果汁饮用，或制成加糖的冰糕，搭配水果和格兰诺拉麦片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从那时起，巴西莓开始流行起来。赢得了世界各地的粉丝，从美国到欧洲、澳大利亚和日本，在这些国家，它的售价从每碗 5 美元左右到每包 100 克有机巴西莓粉高达 20 美元不等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西巴西莓及其衍生物的出口量从 1999 年的 60 公斤猛增到 2021 年的 15,000 多吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Para 是巴西 90% 的巴西莓的产地，2021 年生产了近 140 万吨巴西莓，价值为该州经济带来超过 10 亿美元的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但研究表明，亚马逊地区阿萨伊棕榈树的扩张正在取代其他物种，从而导致某些地区的生物多样性丧失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“让大自然自行其是，每公顷你会长出 50 到 100 株阿萨伊树，”贝伦 Goeldi 博物馆研究所的生物学家 Madson Freitas 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当超过 200 株时，你就会失去 60 株。其他本地物种多样性的百分比。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着世界的分散，亚马逊雨林继续燃烧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他发表了一项关于这一现象的研究，他称之为“acai- ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他植物物种的丧失反过来会对巴西莓产生负面影响，由于蜜蜂、蚂蚁和黄蜂等传粉媒介的丧失，巴西莓的生产力下降，他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚马逊地区较长的干旱期（气候变化可能会加剧这种情况）也会损害巴西莓，因为巴西莓往往生长在雨季洪水泛滥的土地上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗雷塔斯（Freitas）和迪奥戈（Diogo）一样，都来自巴西莓。 “quilombo”，是 17 世纪和 18 世纪巴西逃亡奴隶建立的社区。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;他说，需要更强有力的保护法和治安来打击单一作物种植，并激励农民保护作物热带雨林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Igarape Sao Joao 的当地领导人 Salomao Santos 承认巴西莓的主导地位可能会成为一个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们这些生活在亚马逊地区的人知道我们不能他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回忆起过去的商品繁荣和萧条，例如甘蔗和橡胶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他希望为 quilombo 居民和其他人提供补偿他们保护了亚马逊地区，亚马逊地区数千亿棵吸收碳的树木是应对气候变化的重要资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们为世界提供了巨大的环境服务，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany’s University of Erlangen-Nuremberg stops accepting state-funded Chinese students and researchers over spying fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3232339/german-university-stops-accepting-state-funded-chinese-students-and-researchers-over-spying-fears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/ff184410-62a5-4f81-94b2-2d56fdb773f0_1ef33dac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一所德国大学决定停止接受中国政府机构资助的研究人员，引发警告随着两国关系继续降温，可能会实施进一步的限制甚至禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴伐利亚州埃尔兰根-纽伦堡弗里德里希·亚历山大大学 (FAU) 在内部消息中告诉工作人员，决定自 6 月 1 日起无限期暂停与国家留学基金管理委员会 (CSC) 奖学金获得者的合作，“以减少工业间谍活动的风险”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该消息已被《华盛顿邮报》看到，指出学生与中国教育部控制的国家留学基金委签署的一份合同。签署合同的学生宣誓效忠国家，承诺与中国大使馆保持联系，并在完成学业后返回中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该大学表示，这些承诺违反了德国的基本法，因为研究人员无法充分行使他们的学术自由和言论自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还警告说：“近年来，政治格局发生了巨大变化，防止科学和工业间谍活动、数据安全和保护知识产权等话题也出现了变化。”这对我们的 FAU 来说是一个挑战。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司还表示，其之前与中国电信巨头华为的合作是造成这一问题的原因，华为已被美国列入黑名单，并因安全问题被排除在多个西方宽带网络之外。日益受到国际关注。该公司表示，今后不会再与该公司签署任何研究或合作协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃森大学医院的华人病毒学教授卢孟吉表示，这种类型的合同不算什么。新的和 CSC 资助的接受者并没有认真对待这些承诺，但德国突然因为更广泛的政治局势而感到担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说弗里德里希·亚历山大大学的声明是一次性的，但补充道：“其他德国大学对采取类似措施持谨慎态度，部分原因是CSC资助的学生可以帮助缓解他们的财务担忧，但在当前的政治气候下，德国研究机构将更加警惕，以避免任何相关的间谍风险。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;陆补充道：“在我的印象中，国家安全委员会办公室只是一个小部门，我不认为它有能力和意图组织所谓的‘间谍’活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;根据国家留学基金委网站的消息，今年，这所国立大学计划向海外派遣 25,000 名学生，包括本科生、博士后、访问学者和研究人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国长期以来一直是中国人的热门留学目的地但弗里德里希·亚历山大大学的决定是欧盟学术机构减少对中国开放的最新例子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据德国媒体 Correctiv 报道，该国约有 30 所大学已接受 CSC据信自 2009 年以来已有超过 1000 名奖学金获得者通过该计划来到德国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国寻求安抚德国对乌克兰和平的支持&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德国也正在经历它对中国的看法发生了转变，并且该国最近公布了一项新的对华战略，该战略优先考虑消除中美关系中的风险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，德国联邦宪法保护办公室称中国是德国“在经济和科学间谍活动方面的最大威胁”，并强调研究合作是中国获取德国技术和知识的一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位为马克斯·普朗克学会工作的科学家，德国首屈一指的非大学研究组织表示，甚至在 FAU 禁令之前，分支机构研究机构就已被警告要小心 CSC 合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，这有可能使中国学生处于不利地位，因为需要向中国大使馆报告可能会导致德国学术界对他们不利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这位不愿透露姓名的科学家补充道：“没有统一的政策表明马克斯·普朗克学会将停止接受CSC计划的中国学生； FAU 的案例并不典型。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国教育部长贝蒂娜·斯塔克-瓦辛格 (Bettina Stark-Watzinger) 在接受巴伐利亚媒体采访时支持 FAU 的决定，并将北京资助的学生视为一个特殊风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“德国的研究机构和大学有责任保护自己免受接受中国政府奖学金的学生进行的间谍活动的侵害，”她告诉Mediengruppe Bayern。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，该大学表示，研究人员资助了研究人员由 CSC 和德国学术交流中心 (DAAD) 联合运营的博士后奖学金项目将不受该禁令的约束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，DAAD 有一套接纳客座学者的结构化流程，该流程必须遵守联邦经济事务和出口管制办公室（也称为 BAFA）的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公共机构的研究项目，特别是涉及机密技术的项目，必须接受 BAFA 的定期审核，BAFA 负责监督遵守情况对敏感商品、软件和技术的出口限制，特别是那些可能具有军事用途的商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在回答问题时，弗里德里希·亚历山大大学表示，在一次此类审计中，“我们被告知 FAU 必须设立一个接受客座研究人员的结构化流程，以符合 BAFA 的要求和出口管制”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，其分散的结构意味着它存在“流程上的弱点，我们现在正在审查和解决这些弱点”。 ”，但没有进一步详细说明这些弱点是什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;德国大使馆在柏林开始撤退时表示，中国是德国的“伙伴，而不是竞争对手”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卢表示，该大学可能会利用CSC 以与学生签订的合同为借口对中国研究人员施加限制，并表示“我认为审计才是真正的原因”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该大学表示无法就这一问题进一步置评。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢在他的大学负责与中国的国际交流与合作问题，他表示，过去招收中国学生的教师必须与州政府签订合同，以防止敏感信息或技术泄露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但他表示，如果两国之间的紧张局势加剧，学校可能会考虑正式告知员工和学生其责任的程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京首都医科​​大学校长饶毅警告说，任何减少学术交流的努力在道德上都是错误的，而且是“荒谬的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“高等教育和科学研究方面的国际合作是过去七十年支持世界和平的支柱的一部分。摧毁它们从长远来看会导致严重后果。”Rao 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他欧洲国家的大学也开始排除 CSC 资助的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少三所瑞典大学已经停止招收 CSC 资助的学生和研究人员。隆德大学和乌普萨拉大学不再接受 CSC 学生，而卡罗林斯卡学院宣布已取消与该委员会下一学年的联合项目，并正在与 CSC 协商审查其现有项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在丹麦，奥胡斯大学表示将不再招收由该委员会资助的博士生，但这一决定不会影响在校学生或已经接受录取通知书的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，荷兰也在考虑限制措施对 CSC 资助的学生进行审查，并制定适用于欧盟以外任何国家的安全检查法。荷兰政府正在考虑法律应涵盖哪些敏感技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已要求 CSC 发表评论。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Divided US embraces Trump mugshot merchandise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3232388/divided-us-embraces-trump-mugshot-merchandise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 09:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/a33479a6-9edb-4b1b-b487-4a5d5ec091d3_dd5daced.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普的历史性照片，周四晚上由佐治亚州法院发布，正在被朋友和敌人变成 T 恤、小酒杯、马克杯、海报，甚至摇头娃娃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普打着红色领带、闪闪发亮的头发、冷酷皱眉的照片被拍摄为这位共和党总统竞选领跑者因十多项重罪指控被捕，这是他试图推翻 2020 年大选的刑事案件的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持者和竞选经理对他被捕的形象表示欢迎，因为他们聚集在特朗普的周围，声称对他的指控是出于政治动机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于批评者来说，这张照片象征着他的一长串法律困境终于追上了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普的拯救美国筹款委员会正在推销“永不投降！”面部照片 T 恤（34.00 美元）、饮料架（两个 15.00 美元）和咖啡杯（25.00 美元）。他的儿子小唐 (Don Jr.) 正在营销“免费特朗普”照片 T 恤（29.99 美元）和海报（19.99 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在政治分歧的另一边，林肯计划是一个著名的反特朗普计划。由共和党人创立的特朗普集团正在出售印有照片和“FAFO”的小酒杯（6个售价55美元），“FAFO”是“Fuck around and Find Out”的缩写，是特朗普批评者的口号。工艺品网站 Etsy 有数十种模仿产品，其中包括模仿泰勒·斯威夫特演唱会的 T 恤（26.00 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在洛杉矶，一家与任何活动无关的 T 恤店已经开业周五下午，销售印有该图案的上衣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这是这个国家非常经典的消费主义，”来自佐治亚州亚特兰大的购物者 CJ Butler 说道。 “嘿，这是特朗普。他什么都卖，为什么不买一件 T 恤呢？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些政治战略家预测，这张照片可能会为这位共和党候选人筹集巨额资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他的超级粉丝会爱荷华州资深共和党总统竞选特工戴维·科切尔 (David Kochel) 表示：“如果看到这一点，他们就会拿出 25 美元来买那件衬衫或那个杯子。” “最终，竞选团队将庆祝他对 13 项刑事指控的起诉，这有点令人难过——但这就是我们的政治立场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普几个月来一直试图利用刑事调查从他在纽约的第一次起诉开始，他们就开始反对他，以争取他的支持者的支持。据报道，自 2015 年以来，他的筹款团体（包括他过去和现在的总统竞选活动）已在商品运营上投资了超过 9800 万美元，购买保险杠贴纸、连帽衫和咖啡杯等商品进行销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普和所有合作伙伴-被告在佐治亚州监狱按时投案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周三共和党辩论后，联合竞选经理克里斯·拉奇维塔(Chris LaCivita)在接受路透社采访时表示，他的团队一直致力于将四项起诉书转化为积极的证据，“确保我们抓住一切机会制作柠檬水，我认为我们做到了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他政治活动的资深人士表示，竞选活动可以从他们的商品销售中获得 50% 或更多的利润，LaCivita 周四警告说不要这样做那些试图在未经竞选团队许可的情况下从照片中赚钱的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，特朗普的竞选团队对这张照片的复制可能拥有哪些合法权利（如果有的话）尚不清楚。这张照片由富尔顿县法院分发给媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国联邦法院拍摄的大头照通常属于公共领域，尽管佐治亚州的州政策可能有所不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多美国各州制定了“形象权”法律，禁止未经许可在商业中使用个人形象。联邦商标法还禁止虚假广告和代言，特朗普也有可能根据其他州法律提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但根据美国宪法，政治模仿商品可能会受到知识产权索赔的一些保护，律师表示，特朗普是否真的会提起诉讼，更多的是一个战略问题，而不是一个法律问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“考虑到特朗普的两极分化程度，以及围绕他的市场上已经存在的一切，很有可能。”商标律师乔什·格本 (Josh Gerben) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普低着脸怒视镜头的姿势与他在电视真人秀节目《学徒》中的标志性姿势相呼应。他出演了几年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前总统在周四晚上的一次采访中告诉福克斯新闻数字公司，他只是因为佐治亚州官员坚持才拍摄了这张照片。他说：“这不是一种舒服的感觉，尤其是当你没有做错任何事的时候。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林肯计划联合创始人里克·威尔逊(Rick Wilson)在网上鞭打面部照片，敢于让特朗普的竞选团队起诉他在周五的 X 帖子中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“特朗普的支持者肯定将其视为一个强大的形象，他的对手也将其视为一个强大的形象，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore presidential election: will ‘anti-PAP’ protest voters spoil front runner Tharman Shanmugaratnam’s party?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3232361/singapore-presidential-election-will-anti-pap-protest-voters-spoil-front-runner-tharman?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/618e0e40-61c1-446b-9b05-e72b280e50da_43ca4ecc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;过去一周，两位争夺新加坡下一任总统的候选人揭露他们私生活的细节，分享从如何认识伴侣到个人生育秘诀等故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前内阁部长尚达曼和基金经理黄国松在各自领域都是有成就的人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9 月 1 日选举中的第三位候选人、前保险业首席执行官陈健联 (Tan Kin Lian) 面临着不同的挑战。他在社交媒体上发帖表达了对他在街上看到的“漂亮女孩”的欣赏，但并不缺乏共同点——尽管正如一些评论者指出的那样，是以一种令人毛骨悚然的叔叔的方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样有争议的是他的帖子评论说，一辆满载印度人的公共汽车让他以为自己在孟买，尽管印度人自 19 世纪以来一直是该岛的第三大族群。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有这些失态，谭仍被描述为9月1日选举中的黑马。他的主要优点是，他被视为与政府联系最少的局外候选人。因此，他可能会吸引许多希望利用总统选举来表达对执政的人民行动党（PAP）不满的新加坡人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里有讽刺意味。陈没有反对党资格。相反，他是人民行动党的前忠实拥护者，担任党支部主席十多年。他曾经经营的公司NTUC Income是一家劳工运动合作社，与国家关系密切。他被视为“另类”候选人，只是因为另外两人似乎更接近建制派，并且得到了政府的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼显然是人民行动党的首选，而建制派似乎更喜欢他。说服吴参选以确保竞争激烈。李显龙总理的夫人何晶对吴恩达大加赞扬。吴曾任主权财富基金 GIC 的首席投资官，该基金与新加坡金融管理局和国家投资者淡马锡控股一起管理新加坡的金融储备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，新加坡总统不担任行政职务。该职位的主要自由裁量权是阻止城市国家巨额储备的超支。反对派选民往往认为人民行动党过于严厉，但总统只有权力减少人民行动党的支出，而不是增加支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管存在这些技术细节，许多新加坡人仍拒绝将职位交给被认为过于严厉的人。接近人民行动党。自 1959 年执政以来，该党一直主导该国政治。然而，在 2020 年上一次大选中，大约十分之四的选民投票给反对派候选人。政策研究所的一项选举后调查发现，大多数新加坡人认为议会中的制衡以及不同的声音很重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡选举：选民否认人民行动党轻松上路，说出残酷的事实&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;许多人希望总统“采取行动”新加坡国立大学 (NUS) 政治学讲师丽贝卡·格雷斯·陈 (Rebecca Grace Tan) 表示：他们也在寻找让自己的声音被听到的方法。由于共和国的简单多数票当选制度，反对派在 2020 年大选中获得了 40% 的选票，但在 93 个当选席位中仅获得了 10 个席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些无法获得选举权的情绪在大选等“适当”渠道中充分表达他们对政治制度的感受，会导致选民寻找替代的代表途径，例如总统选举。”谭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使他们知道这一点总统的自由裁量权有限，在生活成本不断上涨的情况下，选民可以利用这个机会表达他们对人民行动党的不满。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近发生了一系列丑闻——从一名部长在腐败调查中被捕到高级官员因一桩婚外情引发的辞职，以及公众对两名部长因租用殖民时代国有豪宅而受到调查并随后获得批准的强烈不安，这些都损害了人民行动党作为高度诚信政党的声誉。一位资深观察家将当前局势描述为“过去 50 年来人民行动党在政治上最糟糕的时期之一”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李总理承认政府的声誉受到了打击，但最后坚持认为周末的国庆集会（类似于其他地方的国情咨文演讲的平台）表示，它彻底、透明地处理了这些问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢里登高等教育学院政治与传播学教授特伦斯·李 (Terence Lee)在澳大利亚，观察者说：“我的感觉是，许多新加坡人对李总理在议会中就丑闻问题做出的回答并没有完全放心或满意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;选民可能将选举视为“发泄情绪的机会” ”，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;直到 1991 年，新加坡总统都是任命的国家元首，这是国家团结的礼仪象征，不行使任何行政权力。 20 世纪 80 年代末，建国总理李光耀提议设立一名直选总统，以制止流氓政府掠夺储备金。宪法修正案于1991年获得通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于总统仍担任礼仪性职务，政府试图通过保持总统选举的冷静来维护总统的尊严。今年，它首次阻止了选举集会，并且没有指定任何指定的集会地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还限制了谁可以竞选总统。 2016 年对私营部门候选人提出了更高的资格要求。与此同时，权力已转移到总统顾问委员会，其中大多数不是由总统任命的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该职位确实具有否决权，可以阻止新加坡储备以及关键公共部门的支出任命——但必须得到理事会的同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年，政府还颇具争议地修改了宪法，限制定期选举少数族裔候选人。据称，这是为了确保该国定期有非华人总统，就像总统选举成为民选职位之前的惯例一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，上届选举的亚军无法当选再试一次，这让他的支持者非常失望。陈清木在 2011 年仅以 0.35 个百分点的差距输给了政府候选人陈庆炎。人们热切期待 2017 年的民意调查将成为第二次大冷门的机会。相反，政府认可的马来候选人哈莉玛毫无争议地获胜。宪法修改引发了罕见的抗议活动，其口号是“选举被剥夺#NotMyPresident”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡政府对选举的严密管理并没有平息甚至可能加剧了其批评者夺取选举权的决心。昆士兰大学名誉教授、长期任职的加里·罗丹 (Garry Rodan) 表示：“[总统选举]的设计体现了人民行动党对政治控制的痴迷。”新加坡政治学者。 “因此，许多人认为这是邀请他们投票反对人民行动党支持的候选人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的所有候选人都清楚地认识到选民希望总统能够成为自己的人，而不是简单地做自己的事。人民行动党的投标。这三人一直试图说服选民，他们可以完全独立地填补这一职位——这是尚达曼最难完成的壮举，尽管这三人都来自建制派。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到去年一个月后，他成为内阁的高级部长，预计他作为总统将仔细审查内阁的决定。自2001年以来，他一直是前总理吴作栋和现任总理李明博内阁的重要成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此之前，他是一名公务员，后来晋升为中央银行董事总经理。他辩称，尽管如此，他仍然拥有所需的“思想独立”，正如他在接受《亚洲周刊》采访时所说的那样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一方面，尚达曼并没有感到有压力否认自己在这些年的工作经历。政府。他是人民行动党最受欢迎的部长之一，备受尊敬，始终以远高于该党全国选票的优势赢得选区支持。他在大选中的表现以及他已经家喻户晓的事实，使他成为总统竞选中明显的领先者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于没有进行民意调查，尚不清楚他是否会成为总统候选人。政府背景将成为即将到来的选举的净资产或负债。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至于吴恩达，他从未担任过政治职务，但他确实在政府工作了 45 年。和尚达曼一样，吴先生在该州的金融机构中名声大噪。 2007 年至 2013 年间，他继续担任 GIC 首席投资官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为来自同一行业的人，吴先生可能无法将自己与尚达曼区分开来，尚达曼的财务资历明显更胜一筹——曾任职担任财政部长长达九年，担任央行主席的时间甚至更长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果是这样，那么陈可能会成为吸引反人民行动党选民的主要磁石。这一论点是在中国最大的中文日报《联合早报》的一篇评论中提出的。其标题表明，三方竞争可能会主要在“人民行动党”人士尚达曼和“反对派”人士陈达曼之间展开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈先生的记录并不乐观。他参加了 2011 年总统选举，但获得了不到 5% 的选票，失去了押金。然而，在那场四路斗争中，反对派支持者有一个明确且令人信服的选择，那就是陈清木。这一次，尽管有“漂亮女孩”的争议，陈健联仍有望在吸引反人民行动党选票方面取得更大成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在陈健联获胜的“怪事”中，执政党可能会被迫罗丹说，恢复 1991 年之前的任命总统制度。但即使没有这样的结果，任何进一步的“进一步收紧资格的新修正案只会增加选民对民选总统机构和人民行动党的幻灭”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已经播出的选民的第四种选择公开就是弃权。在新加坡，投票是强制性的，但由于投票是秘密的，新加坡人可以将未标记的纸张投入投票箱而不会受到处罚。在上一次有争议的总统选举中，投票率约为 95%，废票占总数的不到 2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在她的每周时事通讯中，新加坡活动记者克尔斯滕·汉 (Kirsten Han) 告诉她的订阅者，她已经决定通过破坏她的选票来帮助增加这一数字，部分原因是替代候选人的质量较差，但也因为政府对系统的修改方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对投票给某个人不感兴趣抗议候选人。事实上，我也想抗议这位抗议候选人，”她写道。 “我还相信，大量无效选票也可以发出自己的信息……这标志着对现状的幻灭和不满。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个想法是否会在竞选活动的剩余日子里获得动力仍然存在情况尚不清楚，但尚达曼敦促选民将这次选举视为对新加坡的未来“极其重要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可能阻止选民采用韩的方法的一个因素是，在计算胜利差距时，废票被排除在外。按照惯例，投票份额是根据有效投票总数计算的。因此，如果“反对派”选民想拉低尚达曼的支持率，空白选票无济于事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于总统无法发起政策，新加坡总统选举并不以政策为中心辩论和候选人没有详细的纲领。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，总统选举的意义很大程度上取决于结果对人民行动党的影响。政府必须在2025年11月之前举行大选。9月1日的民意调查结果将为人民行动党在下次大选中的前景提供中期晴雨表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大选之前或之后，预计总理将就任将权力移交给财政部长黄循财。人民行动党将寻求强有力的授权，以表明公众对即将上任的第四代（或“4G”）领导人团队的信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，糟糕的总统选举结果不太可能影响这些领导层过渡计划。新加坡国立大学政治学家 Chong Ja Ian 认为不应该反思 4G 的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些人将 PE 视为对人民行动党表现的公投，”他说。 “然而，由于 4G 与重大政策举措的联系较少，无论如何，结果对它们的直接影响可能较小。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，Chong 和其他分析师表示，结果将反映在李总理领导的现任政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很少有人预计尚达曼会失败。他在执政党的民意调查中一直是重磅人物，得分远高于该党的全国平均得分。例如，2020 年，他在裕廊集团选区获得了 74.62% 的选票，而他的政党则获得了 61.24% 的总体选票份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢里登研究所的李表示，他预计尚达曼将“轻松获胜”以明显而强有力的多数”。不过，他可能不会复制他的大选表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南洋理工大学政治学家Walid Jumblatt表示：“对于很多人来说，这次选举不会关乎尚达曼的受欢迎程度，但会关乎他的人气。”对人民行动党进行全民公投。尚达曼很可能获胜，但非尚达曼的选票数量很重要，因为它可以告诉我们很多选民的情绪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说，最近的一系列丑闻“重新点燃”了选民的情绪。现任总统哈莉玛轻松赢得上届选举后也出现了同样的不满情绪，这表明许多人认为她“被任命不公平”。 The controversies have played into perceptions of a ruling party out of touch with the plight of the masses, with presidential candidate Tan trying to bank on such sentiments by raising bread-and-butter issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore kick-starts presidential campaigning amid &#39;pretty girls&#39; controversy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rebecca Grace Tan from the NUS said: “Voters do want the most competent government, which is why so many of them support the PAP in the general election, but still want to express their disapproval with some ways in which the PAP functions.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voters have “the sense that there is little at stake” in presidential elections compared with general elections, making them more willing to vote for a non-establishment candidate, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In theory, Singapore&#39;s elected president has significant powers to block the use of the country&#39;s huge reserves.但由于执政党在财务上一直非常谨慎，这次总统选举——就像之前两次有争议的民意调查一样——不会是为了平衡新加坡的收支。 Instead, it will mostly be about balancing power.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Globetrotting with ease: as Chinese tourists spread their wings, we list language tips you should never leave home without]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3232052/globetrotting-ease-chinese-tourists-spread-their-wings-we-list-language-tips-you-should-never-leave?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/0eae8a95-a875-49ea-b7dd-525285d26a50_e4f4c52f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As overseas destinations witness a post-Covid-19 boom in travellers from China, mainland holidaymakers are certainly making their mark on the global tourism industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s 2023 May Day holiday saw a seven-fold year-on-year increase in the number of orders related to overseas travel, according to Ctrip, China&#39;s largest online travel services provider.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Outbound Chinese tourists are expected to reach 115 million by the end of 2023, recovering 74 per cent of the same figure in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearby countries like Japan, South Korea, and other Southeast Asian countries such as Thailand, Singapore and Malaysia remained firm favourites among Chinese in the first half of 2023, according to a report by the mobile payment service provider Alipay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alipay is an online payment platform established by Alibaba Group which owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, European destinations are as popular as ever.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To help you globetrot with ease, the Post has prepared a guide to the handiest phrases you will need on your travels.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thailand&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Land of Smiles, saying hello is the easiest way to survive in a polite country like Thailand. “Ka” is used by women, and “khrup” is for men.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Use this before a person&#39;s given name to show politeness and respect.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malaysians greet each other by asking “Apa khabar”, meaning “What news”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blending the lingo of Malaysia and Singapore?在句末加“lah”以示强调。 Also, “No lah”, “Let&#39;s eat lah”, etc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That&#39;s how to hail a taxi in the land of speedy drivers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps the most confusing piece of Singlish, “can”, has varying meanings depending on the Singlish modifiers used with it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The phrase “Can or not?” means “Can you do this?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And “Can meh?” expresses doubt which means “Can you really do it?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a positive response, you can say “Can lah” which means “Of course, it can be done.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Use this if you can&#39;t understand what a Singaporean says. It is derived from the Hokkien dialect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singaporeans greet each other with food – the Malay word “makan” means food or eat.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When asking for anything – food, information, or help – use this as a preamble.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Politeness goes a long way in Japan, adding a “onegai shimasu” at the end of any request will help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korea&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An English “hello” is never polite enough when greeting people older or of higher rank than you in South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korean food is famously spicy. Point at the dish and ask “Maywoyo” to check before you decide to order it or not.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;France&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Bonjour” is always welcome, even to passing strangers in the street. “Bonsoir” is for greeting people in the evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you ask politely, even French people will speak English with you.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Italy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ciao” and a smiling face will pretty much guarantee a pleasant trip in Italy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Italians prefer to show rather than tell. The best-known Italian hand gesture is “pinched fingers” which is used when a person fails to grasp a meaning, sometimes in a provocative manner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Open your arms and show both palms while shrugging your shoulders to show people you have no idea.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Greet Aussies like a local with “G&#39;day” – the phrase “Good day” jammed together.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A more colloquial and shortened version of “thanks”, “ta” is an informal way to show appreciation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;United Kingdom&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cheers” to Brits works even without a glass of beer. Use it instead of “thanks” and you will sound like a local.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brits more often than not greet each other by talking about the country&#39;s unpredictable weather.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;United States&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Keep the change” sounds outdated in these digital days, but it will always be welcomed if you thank people for service instead after tipping them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No, you are not being asked to tell anyone about anything, Americans say this to let YOU know that THEY know exactly what YOU are talking about.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US accuses Russia, China of covering for North Korea over missile launches]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3232387/us-accuses-russia-china-covering-north-korea-over-missile-launches?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 07:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/26/563701d9-50f6-47d1-ad90-f04611388b99_141be6bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The United States on Friday accused China and Russia of blocking a unified UN Security Council response to North Korea&#39;s missile launches, including Thursday&#39;s attempt by Pyongyang to put a spy satellite in space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During an emergency Security Council meeting, 13 of the 15 members – all but Moscow and Beijing – condemned Pyongyang&#39;s second spy satellite test in three months, which used ballistic missile technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This should be an issue that unifies us. … But since the beginning of 2022, this Council has failed to live up to its commitments because of China and Russia&#39;s obstructionism,” said US ambassador to the UN Linda Thomas-Greenfield.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The DPRK&#39;s nuclear threat is growing, and Russia and China are not living up to their responsibility to maintain international peace and security,” she added, using the initials for the Democratic People&#39;s Republic of Korea, the North&#39;s official name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thomas-Greenfield also denounced the presence of Russian and Chinese officials at a North Korean military parade last month that showed off new drones and nuclear-capable intercontinental ballistic missiles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They are celebrating – celebrating – violations of Security Council resolutions and continuing to block Council action,” Thomas-Greenfield said of Moscow and Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May 2022, China and Russia vetoed a resolution imposing new sanctions on Pyongyang, and no resolution or declaration by the Security Council on North Korea has been adopted since.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last unified Security Council action on North Korea took place in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese and Russian representatives said Washington was to blame for North Korea&#39;s aggressive stance, pointing to continuing US military drills with South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Biden trying to meet North Korea&#39;s Kim &#39;without preconditions&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;North Korea has long maintained its nuclear programme is pursued in self-defence, and said the same applies to its satellite programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our launch of the reconnaissance satellite is an exercise of the legitimate right to self defence to deter ever-increasing hostile military acts of the United States,” said North Korean ambassador Kim Song, adding that his country has never recognised UN Security Council resolutions on North Korea anyway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thomas-Greenfield rejected that position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We all know the truth: The DPRK puts its paranoia and selfish interests over the dire needs of the North Korean people,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The DPRK&#39;s war machine is fuelled by repression and cruelty,” Thomas-Greenfield added. “It&#39;s shameful, and it&#39;s a grave threat to global peace.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Expanded Brics could be successor to the non-aligned movement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3232157/expanded-brics-could-be-successor-non-aligned-movement?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/56854361-1cf7-499e-a079-27ba47b53ba2_811a4469.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Sceptics used to joke that the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (Apec) forum was an adjective in search of a noun. Others turn to the Brics bloc and ask: “Brics is all very well, but where is the mortar?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As South Africa hosted the 15th Brics summit this week in Johannesburg, the mortar question has been in the air: what binds a grouping of five countries – Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa – that have so little in common? Or the six countries – Argentina, Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates – that will become members of the group next year?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Financial Times, associate editor Janan Ganesh has a mischievous but plausible explanation: “grievance: against western primacy, against past slights”. He is not wrong, but there are other adhesive forces hard at work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, Brics is a grouping that has outgrown its name. It has the potential to become the modern-day equivalent of the non-aligned movement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Born out of the 1955 Bandung Conference in Indonesia, that movement of newly independent nations, which grew to encompass 120 members, insisted on sidestepping the two Cold War power blocs and their military instruments – Nato and the Warsaw Pact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This week, in a nationally televised address, South African President Cyril Ramaphosa said Brics members sought “a world that is more equitable, balanced and governed by an inclusive system of global governance”. He added that “the value of Brics extends beyond the interests of its current members” and that “an expanded Brics will represent a diverse group of nations with different political systems that share a common desire to have a more balanced global order”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From its first formal meeting in 2009, the Brics bloc has grown substantially – from about 25 per cent of global gross domestic product in 2010 to around 32 per cent this year in purchasing power parity terms – though almost all of this growth came from China and India. The six new members will lift this share to 37 per cent, according to Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This increase in economic significance has been mirrored in developing economies worldwide. In 1992, advanced economies accounted for 57.8 per cent of global GDP and emerging markets 42.2 per cent but, by 2023, this balance had flipped: emerging economies account for 58.9 per cent and advanced economies 41.1 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With rising economic significance has come an expectation of a stronger voice in international organisations and more significant influence on the rules of international trade and investment. The five Brics members share this ambition, and recognise that they speak on behalf of a much larger grouping of countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So while grievances are a Brics binding force, these are not just the postcolonial resentments that drew non-aligned movement members together in the 1950s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More modern grievances include a sense of undeserved hardships suffered due to the US banking crisis in 2008;发达经济体在国际货币基金组织和世界银行的席位和投票权中占据主导地位； Covid-19 大流行期间对获得疫苗的自私； and, failure to honour promises to provide financial support for developing economies struggling to manage the impacts of global warming.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The Global South are falling out of love with the West&#39;s liberal order&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;They also include anxiety over the US&#39; increasing preference for unilateral “settlement” of disputes, the dismantling of the role of the World Trade Organization in settling trade disagreements, and the weaponisation of the US dollar in delivering financial sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These grievances were apparent when the UN General Assembly voted in March last year to condemn Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine. Over 50 governments, all from the Global South, voted against the resolution, abstained or were absent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond grievances are a list of common objectives and concerns. First is a shared determination to develop “true multilateralism”, or what Chinese President Xi Jinping calls “the democratisation of international relations”, by reforming or building on international institutions – the United Nations, IMF, World Bank and WTO – and reconfiguring the global financial architecture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brics nations object to the rich West overpowering decision-making. And they are adamant on non-interference and respect for other countries&#39; sovereignty – no matter how obviously Russia has flouted this rule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brics members have managed to subordinate their profound differences to this list. China may have become the group&#39;s most dominant economy by far, and is host to the New Development Bank, but Beijing tempers antagonism by casting its role as using Brics&#39; influence on behalf of the Global South as a whole.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So what has been achieved at this summit?关于发行一种新货币来与美元竞争的问题并不多。 Instead Brics leaders will encourage more settlement of bilateral trade in local currencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Expansion of formal membership to 11 has come as the biggest surprise.阿根廷将增强拉丁美洲的声音；埃及、沙特和阿联酋不仅代表中东，还为新开发银行提供资金火力支持。埃塞俄比亚将非洲带入谈判桌。 And Iran delivers a stick in the eye to the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ramaphosa said other countries would be admitted once the core countries agree on criteria. Around 40 nations were in the queue before the summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Africa chairing the G20 in 2025 suggests there will be efforts to align the Brics agenda with that of the G20, but Russia hosting the Brics summit in 2024 raises questions about short-term continuity.与此同时，金砖四国的缩写显然已经超过了它的使用寿命。 Expect a new name soon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[7 children among 13 killed in Madagascar stadium crush; more than 100 injured]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3232386/seven-children-among-13-killed-madagascar-stadium-crush-more-100-injured?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 07:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/26/8ffc2a66-6515-4d8a-b985-33e31db74d07_91d5b828.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;At least 13 people, including seven children, were killed on Friday in a crowd stampede at a stadium in Madagascar&#39;s capital Antananarivo, according to the Red Cross and a local member of parliament.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So far 13 people have been killed and 107 injured,” said opposition MP Hanitra Razafimanantsoa on a local radio station.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Red Cross, who were on the scene, added: “We don&#39;t yet have the final list. Seven minors died.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prime minister of the Indian Ocean nation Christian Ntsay had initially put the toll at “12 dead and some 80 injured”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stampede occurred at the entrance to the Barea stadium where a crowd of around 50,000 spectators had arrived to attend the opening ceremony of the Indian Ocean Island Games.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cause of the tragedy was not immediately known but the Red Cross said the death toll could climb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There were a lot of people at the entrance, which triggered a stampede,” Antsa Mirado, a communications manager with the Red Cross, told Agence France-Presse.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Fifa statement after football stadium stampede kills at least 12 in El Salvador&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Madagascar President Andry Rajoelina, who was present at the opening ceremony, called for a minute&#39;s silence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A tragic event occurred because there was pushing. There were injuries and deaths at the entrance,” he said in a televised speech.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Television images broadcast images of dazed and shocked people trying to locate their shoes piled among objects lost in the deadly crush.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other images from inside the stadium, shared on social media, showed the stands packed with spectators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Indian Ocean Island Games are a multidisciplinary competition being held in Madagascar until September 3.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They have been staged every four years in different islands in the southwest Indian Ocean for around 40 years. The previous edition took place in Mauritius.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s ‘heart’ closer to US than China on trade, says New Delhi’s commerce chief at G20 meeting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3232385/indias-heart-closer-us-china-trade-says-new-delhis-commerce-chief-g20-meeting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 06:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/26/291d65ea-e1de-4b5a-82c7-4b8acab59e02_41c07f76.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s commerce chief has described the country&#39;s “heart” as belonging to the US and not China as it relates to trade in remarks delivered before ministers from both countries in New Delhi on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at a business meeting of Group of 20 member nations, Piyush Goyal asked Wang Shouwen, China&#39;s vice-minister of commerce, how Beijing felt about New Delhi opting not to join the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The RCEP, a free-trade agreement focused on Asia-Pacific and led by Beijing, comprises Australia, Brunei, Cambodia, China, Indonesia, Japan, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, South Korea, Thailand and Vietnam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, Wang singled out the growing trade relationship between China and India. In 2022, their bilateral trade reached US$130 billion, he said, adding that New Delhi was welcome to join the RCEP in the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Had there been a free-trade agreement between China and India, either bilaterally or in the context of the RCEP, Wang continued, trade potential between the two countries would have been “much further tapped … to the benefit of our two peoples”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So, it is your decision to decide whether you will join RCEP,” he added. “The RCEP door will be always open for India.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That prompted Goyal to state that although bilateral trade between the Asian neighbours was on the rise it was “largely skewed in favour of China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Indian industry feels that if you had entered into this agreement with the RCEP this trade would have suddenly increased, but it would only have increased the trade deficit further,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Share in China&#39;s growth&#39;: top diplomat tells South Asia in belt and road push&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;From 2022 to 2023, India&#39;s trade deficit with China reached US$83 billion, according to data from the Indian commerce ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in questioning China&#39;s policy on export pricing, Goyal asked the Chinese minister how Beijing could supply goods at a rate that was lower than the cost of raw materials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang replied by noting that India had been “successful in maintaining a global trade balance overall for the country”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So it is natural that you will have trade deficits with countries like China, but you will also have a trade surplus with other countries,” Wang said. “It is very good that you are able to maintain your trade balance globally.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goyal then said with a grin: “My heart here is with Katherine Tai from the United States of America”, referring to the US trade representative, who chuckled as she sat beside the Indian minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India has a US$28 billion trade surplus with Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After regarding the US with suspicion for decades, India in recent years has aligned more closely with Washington and its allies as China&#39;s military stature and economic influence have grown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, ties between India and China have been strained since a clash along their disputed Himalayan border in 2020 led to the deaths of at least 20 Indian and four Chinese soldiers. It was the deadliest border encounter between the two in decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What new defence, tech deals could mean for India-US ties amid China tensions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Both sides have continued to deploy a significant number of troops and advanced weaponry along their border areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday on the sidelines of the Brics summit in Johannesburg, South Africa, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping agreed to find a speedy resolution to the border deadlock, according to the Indian foreign secretary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi told Modi that improving China-India relations served the interests of both countries and was conducive to peace, stability, and development, according to the Chinese ministry of foreign affairs, which said the discussion came about at Modi&#39;s request.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some Indian media outlets later challenged China&#39;s claim, citing sources in the Indian government saying there had been a pending request from the Chinese side for a bilateral meeting and that the leaders&#39; conversation had been informal.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Seoul urges North Korea to end ‘K-pop ban’, give its citizens freedom of information]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3232368/seoul-urges-north-korea-end-k-pop-ban-give-its-citizens-freedom-information?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/4314427f-3c76-4bed-95d1-5532578ea8b6_1737843d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Since its founding in 1948, the dictatorial regime in North Korea has strictly blocked the entry of any information from the outside that could threaten its stability and legitimacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who spread messages deemed to deviate from its totalitarian principles have always been at risk of punishment under its publication law and administrative guidelines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is why North Korea&#39;s decision in 2020 to adopt an “anti-reactionary thought law”, a move specifically targeting South Korea&#39;s cultural content, drew little attention here at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly three years after the law came into force in North Korea to crack down on K-pop and other types of South Korean cultural content, Seoul released its first official message calling on Pyongyang to revoke what is also known as the “K-pop ban”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We strongly urge North Korean authorities to abolish the anti-reactionary thought law that denies its citizens access to outside information,” Unification Minister Kim Yung-ho said at a seminar on the human rights of North Koreans in Seoul on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China calls UN Security Council talks on North Korea an &#39;abuse of power&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The demand comes days after his meeting with reporters, during which Kim said the ministry under him would be more vocal in rights issues involving the North by, for example, criticising “policies such as the K-pop ban” more directly and proactively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The law, adopted by the North in December 2020, prohibits the creation, distribution and consumption of any content “aimed at breaking down our system”. It says violators could face, in serious cases, more than 10 years of hard labour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to human rights experts, the reality is harsher than what the law indicates. Citing North Korean defectors, they say one could be sentenced to life imprisonment for watching a South Korean film for just several hours, while execution is among the possible consequences for distributors, with the regime stepping up crackdowns to unprecedented levels in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This suggests a growing influence of South Korea&#39;s culture in the North, one researcher told The Korea Times.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Despite all the administrative guidelines and other rules against such content, North Korea enacted the new law, which suggests that its ruling elite increasingly feels that South Korean pop culture threatens their control,” said the researcher, who declined to be named.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unlike content from other countries, North Korean people can relate easily with K-drama actors who speak in a language they can understand, which could influence how they see their own society – and possibly whether it needs to change,” the researcher added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said the minister&#39;s open demand for the abolition of the law could be helpful in terms of promoting human rights internationally and galvanising support from like-minded countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But to make the message more convincing, South Korea should lift its own ban on public access to North Korean media, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A policy pledge made by the Yoon Suk-yeol administration to lift the ban has made little progress over the last year as many remain concerned about security problems among other possible ramifications, which the researcher thinks are overblown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to such criticism, Koo Byoung-sam, a spokesman for the ministry, said officials will continue to step up efforts to make progress on both fronts.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US, China to cover ‘expansive’ range of topics during Gina Raimondo visit, but no immediate solutions expected]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3232327/us-china-cover-expansive-range-topics-during-gina-raimondo-visit-no-immediate-solutions-expected?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/26/f7c09542-647e-462d-83df-d49d990cc107_9059b80b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo is expected to raise issues including raids on American consultancy firms and market access during her four-day China visit, according to sources with knowledge of the discussions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing, meanwhile, will demand further relaxation of US export controls as part of its broad concerns over ongoing containment efforts, they added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s ban on the sale of products from US memory chip firm Micron Technology, data security and Beijing&#39;s anti-espionage law are also set to be discussed, according to one source, with the issues seen as top concerns for American businesses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Secretary Raimondo represents both her respective department and the US government as a senior official, hence the topics to be covered could be expansive,” the person said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raimondo will “be accompanied throughout” her trip, which will start on Sunday, by US ambassador Nicholas Burns, the person added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese authorities raided the Beijing office of American due diligence firm Mintz Group and the Shanghai office of US consulting giant Bain &amp; Company earlier this year on national security reasons, fanning widespread fears among the foreign business community.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such investigations also generated confusion, as the world&#39;s second-largest economy has pledged to create a good business environment and vowed to keep investors onshore amid supply chain upheaval.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A key concern for Beijing ahead of the meeting is whether the US government will make any policy changes and clarifications regarding its export controls and plans to restrict financing to Chinese companies covering semiconductors and microelectronics, quantum information technologies and certain artificial intelligence systems, another source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is scepticism that Secretary Raimondo&#39;s short trip will result in anything substantive for US-China commercial relations,” said Han Shen Lin, China country head at The Asia Group consulting firm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What&#39;s more important is that the steady drumbeat of senior meetings between the US and China increases comfort for collaboration at the working levels – where real progress is made.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China eases home-buying rules to prop up slumping property market, economy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Ministry of Commerce and the US embassy in China did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Commerce ministry spokeswoman Shu Jueting said on Thursday that China will “declare its position” towards Raimondo on certain “imminent” trade issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We simultaneously also hope that the trade disagreement between both countries can be resolved and we&#39;ll push through in-depth discussions on practical cooperation,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re aware of the recent difficulties and challenges for bilateral trade and investment, which is related to a series of unilateral measures and protectionism actions from the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China will continue to show our concerns and do our best to create a stable and fair business environment.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Chinese authorities said Micron had failed to pass a cybersecurity review, and prohibited the sale of its products to China&#39;s critical information infrastructure operators, which include a wide range of entities from telecoms operators to banks and water utilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, US tech giant Intel terminated its deal to buy Israeli foundry Tower Semiconductor for US$5.4 billion “due to the inability to obtain in a timely manner the regulatory approvals [from Chinese regulators] required under the merger agreement”, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mintz, meanwhile, was recently fined around US$1.5 million for conducting “unapproved statistical work”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Shanghai vows 2-hour project approvals to woo foreign investments&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Raimondo&#39;s scheduled meetings represent the fourth major meeting between officials from China and the US this summer following recent trips by US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and climate envoy John Kerry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Veteran US diplomat Henry Kissinger was also given a red-carpet welcome on his return to Beijing last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[They] are accurately seen as an attempt to dial down the tension,” said Frank Tsai, adjunct professor of international studies at Xian Jiaotong-Liverpool University in Suzhou, “but this should be seen in light of Chinese perceptions of American aggressiveness, and the possibility of American amends: the Americans are at fault, so they should come to China.” He downplayed market expectations ahead of Raimondo&#39;s visit.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>