<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Grounded pilots: behind Hong Kong flag carrier Cathay Pacific’s new plan for junior flight crew to serve at airport]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3224476/grounded-pilots-behind-hong-kong-flag-carrier-cathay-pacifics-new-plan-junior-flight-crew-serve?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/2fcd195d-386c-44bb-92ae-59cac49c2c2d_1ef44f25.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;飞行员 Desmond Chan* 上周出现在工作中，既紧张又困惑在他担任香港旗舰航空公司国泰航空公司地勤人员的新职位时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 回忆起他在带领一群乘客从晚点抵达的航班到转机航班时在香港庞大的机场迷路的经历一，因为他不熟悉建筑布局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就像在野外求生。一种全新的体验，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 是首批在机场工作的约 20 名国泰航空初级飞行员中的一员，该项目是本月为获得飞行资格的学员毕业生推出的一项新入职培训计划。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在《华盛顿邮报》上个月看到的一份备忘录中，国泰航空飞行培训主管 Jules Tidmarsh 告诉员工，飞行员将被分配到“机场面向客户的接触点”，包括帮助到达的乘客&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tidmarsh 在备忘录中表示，飞行员将接受三天的机场基本知识课堂培训，然后在登机口和到达大厅工作两天。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;被选中的飞行员将完成为期两个月的轮换，然后返回他们的常规名单。他们将获得约 32,000 港元（4,092 美元）的基本月薪，但没有额外的地面工作津贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空在上个月的一份声明中表示，该举措“是对学员飞行员的极好补充”毕业生更广泛的专业发展”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，这是改进入职培训工作的一部分，“考虑到他们开始飞行训练的时间表，我们正在寻求扩大我们的学员飞行员毕业生的入职培训经验...在教学积压和为经验丰富的飞行员优先安排课程的情况下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然分析师表示，初级飞行员通常被聘为“替补”，预计不会进行真正的飞行，但地面计划被视为一个机会在人手不足的机场利用这个人力资源库。然而，初级飞行员表示他们需要更多培训，将他们派往地面服务再次打击了士气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在为期三天的课堂培训中，Chan 说他被告知他需要执行简单的任务，例如扫描&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 说，他的职责包括扫描登机牌、追踪迟到或走失的乘客，以及处理因航班迟到而愤怒的乘客。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空为初级飞行员提供晋升香港快运航空的机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我没有接受过如何平息愤怒乘客的培训。我真的是靠自己工作，”Chan 说，他补充说，他的培训师告诉他，新来的人通常只接受两周的培训，而他只接受五天的培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然 Chan 说他已经深入了解了为什么航班可能会如此耽误了，这与他作为飞行员的工作无关，他渴望重返天空。他估计明年下半年会轮到他接受飞行训练。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;代表国泰机师的香港机勤人员协会会长表示，虽然该计划使用的机师不是飞行，这无疑影响了士气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为他们不会这样做，除非原因之一是他们缺少地勤人员。他们试图用一块石头杀死两只鸟。这些家伙已经有一段时间没有接受训练了。他们四处闲逛并领取报酬，”董事长保罗韦瑟尔特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他估计，航母上四分之一到一半的二副没有飞行，而是在等待重新激活或接受培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;此外，他指出，由于该级别的人员短缺，高级飞行员非常忙碌。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着航班数量的增加，香港国泰航空的新机组人员每月收入高达 20,000 港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据估计，国泰航空集团的运营能力约为其 Covid-19 之前客运航班运力的 50%，该公司的目标是到年底达到 70%，到年底达到 100%截至 2024 年结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会表示，2019 年第四季度，该航空公司在国泰航空及其已解散的子公司国泰港龙航空拥有 3,840 名各级飞行员，而截至 6 月，这一数字因大流行而降至 2,417 名。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;它表示机长人数几乎减半，从 1,410 人减至 717 人，而副驾驶人数从 1,740 人减少 39% 至 1,030 人。副驾驶人数从 690 人下降 3% 至 670 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空早些时候表示，其“包括飞行员在内的所有员工群体的流失率都已恢复正常”，并已重新聘请了 250 名国泰航空飞行员，包括机长&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司补充说，今年有望招聘 3,000 名员工，其中包括 700 名飞行员。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空将在年底前向政府支付 15 亿港元的股息月&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国大学航空政策与研究中心的袁志乐表示，这项新举措旨在加强学员对机场运营和客户的了解，这在大型企业的管理培训生项目中很常见。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;然而，执行力是关键，Yuen 警告说，员工士气“在当前形势下对国泰航空尤为重要”。他说，重要的是让受训者“认同”以了解安排的价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“应提供足够的培训和支持，”Yuen 说。 “另一方面，地面服务不应受到这一安排的影响，[并且]不应给已经不堪重负的现有员工增加额外的负担。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;航空咨询公司创始人 Shukor Yusof Endau Analytics 公司指出，在入职培训期间，副驾驶可以执行非飞行任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国泰航空在许多方面都在努力应对。培训只是它正在努力解决的众多问题之一。由于飞行员减少，喷气式飞机要到一年后才能完全恢复，因此提高运力面临严峻挑战。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国际航空运输协会表示，香港在重建航空枢纽角色方面面临“艰巨”任务&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在大流行期间，作为削减成本举措的一部分，机组人员和飞行员的工资有所降低，国泰最近推出了旨在提振士气的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这包括调整飞行员的薪酬机制根据他们飞行的小时数或他们的花名册飞行时间——从 10 月开始以较高者为准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空的初级飞行员有机会申请在该航空公司的低成本部门香港快运航空飞行，作为副驾驶两年，成功的候选人然后能够以该级别加入主要航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，他们必须至少有 1,000 小时的飞行经验，因此不包括一些初级飞行员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;*应受访者要求更改姓名&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-China relations: Antony Blinken and Qin Gang begin talks in Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224492/us-china-relations-antony-blinken-and-qin-gang-begin-talks-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 15:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/e907b432-f13a-4fde-841a-4a19fb596ba5_2de808ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;期待已久的会谈正在北京进行据官方媒体报道，美国外长安东尼·布林肯 (Antony Blinken)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿周日上午抵达中国首都，这是美国官员五年来最高级别的访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;美国驻华大使尼古拉斯伯恩斯和中国外交部北美和大洋洲事务司司长杨涛在机场迎接他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六启程前往北京之前，布林肯说了他的一位目标是与中国官员建立“开放和授权的沟通”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还将“直接和坦率地谈论[美国]对一系列问题的非常真实的担忧”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“激烈的竞争需要持续的外交，以确保竞争不会演变成对抗或冲突，”布林肯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯是拜登政府中访问北京的最高级别官员。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，此次访问表明双方希望重新接触，但取得突破的可能性很低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“预计他将与中国制定路线图和时间表上海新闻网站澎湃新闻援引复旦大学美国研究所所长吴心波的话说，此行期间双边高层交流的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们普遍预计美国财政部长珍妮特耶伦和商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多将在布林肯之后访问中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中关系：国务卿安东尼·布林肯的访问得到确认&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国近几个月加强了国家安全审查，对多家美国咨询公司，并禁止美国芯片公司美光公司向中国客户销售产品。与此同时，美国已将更多中国公司列入其出口管制名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯的访问在周三与秦通电话后数小时得到确认，秦强调了北京在核心问题上的“严厉立场” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与布林肯通电话时，秦始皇还敦促美方尊重中国的主权、安全和发展利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯此行是会晤的重要成果中国国家主席习近平和拜登于 11 月在巴厘岛举行的 G20 峰会期间举行了会谈，当时两国领导人同意努力改善关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候计划的访问因疑似中国间谍气球而中止- 北京否认的说法 - 于 2 月飞越美国领土。在时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾之后，这一事件加剧了紧张局势已经迅速升温。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京认为这个自治的岛屿是一个叛逆的省份，将在必要时通过武力将其置于大陆控制之下。与大多数国家一样，美国不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对对台湾进行任何攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界上最大的两个经济体之间的定期会谈基本上冻结了几个月，但最近的高层会谈接触表明美中关系正在解冻。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国和中国外交官进行“坦诚、建设性、富有成果的讨论”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;5 月，美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文和中国最高领导人外交官王毅在维也纳举行了为期两天的“坦诚、实质和建设性的讨论”，讨论了台湾和俄罗斯在乌克兰的战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样在上个月，中国商务部长王文涛与中方举行了会谈吉娜·雷蒙多 (Gina Raimondo)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月初，两名美国高级官员——负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔·克里滕布林克 (Daniel Kritenbrink) 和国家安全委员会负责中国和台湾事务的高级主任莎拉·贝兰 (Sarah Beran) – 访问北京进行“坦诚、建设性、富有成果的讨论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务院发言人马修·米勒周三表示，布林肯将寻求与中国建立沟通渠道，并将“站出来为我们的价值观大声疾呼” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一份简报中，克里滕布林克表示，布林肯的访问将建立在美国和中国官员最近的其他接触之上，包括“坦诚、直接和建设性的讨论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Kritenbrink 说：“我们去北京并不是为了在我们处理彼此的方式上取得某种突破或转变。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们带着现实的态度来到北京、自信的态度和真诚的愿望，以尽可能最负责任的方式管理我们的竞争。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟高级官员一再表示，他们希望与中国“降低风险，但不脱钩”。拜登政府最近使用了类似的语言，却遭到了北京方面的冷遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China pushes for Asia-Pacific trade agreement membership, promises to ‘actively attract’ foreign investment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224486/china-pushes-asia-pacific-trade-agreement-membership-promises-actively-attract-foreign-investment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 14:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/7c664a72-fe36-47e7-a6c9-db47f160de17_2f3ebc17.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一直在推动加入高级别的亚太贸易和投资中国最高贸易谈判代表表示，该协定并将加大力度吸引外资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京已对跨太平洋伙伴关系全面进步协定 (CPTPP) 的 2,300 多个条款和项目进行了研究和评估)，并梳理了该国为实现成员资格需要开展和修订的改革、法律法规，中国商务部副部长王受文说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在亚太经合组织会议上的讲话 (星期六在北京举行的 Apec）2023 年中国 CEO 论坛上，王说中国已经向成员提交了一份文件，并且“愿意并且有能力”加入该协定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国正在积极调整自己的贸易标准通过试点 [市场] 开放试点来降低 CPTPP 的高门槛，我们将为该地区提供新的自由贸易动力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的 CPTPP 申请“不可能”让澳大利亚在制裁期间获得批准保持&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;王的讲话是在北京试图巩固其在全球供应链中的地位并对抗美国的“去风险化”努力之际发表的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国申请加入高- 2021 年 9 月美国在特朗普政府领导下退出前称为跨太平洋伙伴关系协定 (TPP) 的贸易协定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CPTPP 成员资格需要所有成员国的批准，即加拿大、墨西哥、秘鲁、智利、新西兰、澳大利亚、文莱、新加坡、马来西亚、越南、日本和英国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辛里奇基金会高级研究员斯蒂芬奥尔森表示，中国申请加入该地区自由贸易协定引发了地缘政治方面的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论正确与否，最初的 TPP 协议都被视为美国领导的联盟，旨在反击中国在该地区日益增长的影响力，”他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果中国最终加入协议，而美国仍处于观望状态，那将是具有讽刺意味的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》上个月报道说，中国未能获得公众认可在澳大利亚贸易部长 Don Farrell 访问北京期间从澳大利亚加入贸易集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CPTPP 的成员资格标准包括所有权和劳工标准——北京被视为达不到要求的两个领域。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;周六，王毅还表示，中国“制造业基本对外资开放，服务业将逐步开放。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未来，他补充说，中国还将“合理”放宽外资市场准入限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国将积极吸引外资。投资中国意味着拥有14亿人口的巨大市场，意味着安全、稳定、高效的产业链和供应链，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开放的中国市场将有助于跨国公司提高他们在世界上的竞争力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外国商界近年来对未兑现的承诺表示疲倦，并呼吁北京采取具体行动开放市场准入并提供政策确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;随着外部压力加大，中国呼吁加入 CPTPP 贸易集团&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2023 年前五个月，流入中国的外国直接投资下降 5.6%，至 843.5 亿美元，此前 2023 年下降了 3.3%前四个月，商务部上周表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚大学国际事务专家丁志杰和加州大学伯克利分校研究助理赵万军在一篇文章中写道去年 8 月的东亚论坛上，对中国参与贸易框架的看法存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些人认为，北京已准备好满足 CPTPP 的高标准，并打算利用加入谈判加速国内市场化改革，”他们写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其他人仍然对中国在遵守 WTO 原则方面的记录持怀疑态度。他们认为北京不太可能履行其承诺，其申请只是为了扩大其影响力。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk says Biden’s call for more taxes on rich Americans ‘all words, no action’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224488/elon-musk-says-bidens-call-more-taxes-rich-americans-all-words-no-action?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 14:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/0a95279a-0cd7-43a7-9983-840badc93e31_c6133620.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Elon Musk 是世界首富，也是电动汽车制造商特斯拉公司的负责人，他说乔·拜登总统呼吁对超级富有的美国人征税只会伤害中低收入群体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我同意我们应该将精心设计的避税计划定为非法，但据此采取行动会令人不安很多捐助者，所以我们只会看到言论，但不会采取行动，”他在一条推文中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那些实际上将被迫承担政府超额支出负担的人是中低收入工资收入者，因为他们无法逃避工资税。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克的推文是对拜登的一条推文的回应，他说“现在是超级富豪开始支付票价份额的时候了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乔拜登说富人需要缴纳“公平份额”的税&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在周六费城的竞选集会上，拜登要求工会工人支持他的连任竞选，并呼吁对富人和企业征收新税。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然美国的亿万富翁人数已增至约 1,000 人，但他们缴纳了约 8% 的收入税，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们缴纳的税款较低率比学校老师，消防员，可能这个房间里的任何人都高。是时候缴纳最低税了。我不介意他们成为亿万富翁。伙计，只需支付你应得的份额，”拜登说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我能做到，但我非常需要你。那你陪我吗？”拜登在费城会议中心向欢呼的工会工人人群讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统吹捧他在国内取得的成就，并辩称这些成就推动了经济增长、热门就业市场和中产阶级的收益。他引用了他上任头两年通过的法律，包括气候、健康和税收方案以及基础设施和半导体制造的新资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“伙计们，这不是刚刚发生的。我们做到了，”拜登说，并补充说大多数共和党人“反对我所做的一切，并且最想摆脱这一切。所以我们有一场战斗在我们手中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济焦点旨在帮助拜登将选举定性为他和共和党之间的选择，同时回避针对唐纳德特朗普的机密文件案和其他争议占据了头条新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统一直小心翼翼地不对对其前任的刑事指控发表评论，担心这可能会影响共和党的指控，即起诉是出于政治动机。拜登还面临着他自己对拥有机密文件的联邦调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Nothing more precious than life’: hero Chinese food delivery man leaps off high bridge to save drowning woman, then resumes work despite injuries]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224204/nothing-more-precious-life-hero-chinese-food-delivery-man-leaps-high-bridge-save-drowning-woman-then?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/567d97bc-25c0-4360-9569-cf47a09cb42c_25f3c787.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;对于中国送货司机彭庆林来说，这是另一个例行工作日，当瞬间，他的生活发生了翻天覆地的变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月13日，彭在中国东南部浙江省省会杭州市的勇敢和敏捷思维，此后在内地社交媒体上赢得人心和赞誉.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位来自中国南方湖南省的 31 岁男子正在骑电动自行车送外卖，这时他注意到一名妇女在钱塘江中挣扎，就在他的路旁&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭决定他只能做一件事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他翻过 12 米高的桥的栏杆，试图营救该女子。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一段由旁观者拍摄并发布到网上的视频显示，彭某犹豫了几秒，最终还是跳入了水中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很高，我的腿在发抖。但是，如果我不跳下去，她可能就活不下来了。没有什么比生命更宝贵，”他在事后接受中国蓝讯采访时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潜入水中几秒钟后，彭重新浮出水面，但他呼吸困难。一个可怕的时刻，他形容为“非常漫长”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在回想起来，我感到有点害怕，因为我不知道当时发生了什么，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彭跳水后不久，民警和救生艇赶到现场，10分钟内完成救援。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事发后，彭又有新的烦恼，他点的菜还没送到，他因延误而面临罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，他坚持了下来，完成了他的交付，他工作的平台决定不让他为损失的时间负责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他的行为之后由于英雄气概，Peng 获得了送餐公司和地方当局的嘉奖和表彰，他们给了他 5 万元人民币（7,000 美元）的奖励，并有机会免费上大学学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他救下的29岁女子虽经受磨难，但情况良好，她对彭表示深深的感谢：“没想到他会把我从‘阎王’手中抢回来，”她告诉City链接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，彭为他的勇敢付出了身体上的代价，他在触及水面时因压缩性骨折需要住院治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭的视频在社交媒体上发布的救死扶伤功绩，赢得了网络观察者的广泛赞誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“天下没有天上掉下来的英雄。而是普通人，临危不乱挺身而出，”一位评论者说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位评论者补充道：“彭庆林的两秒钟，对于这个女人来说，就是一辈子。他是一个真正的男人，一个真正的英雄。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个勇敢无私的英雄值得的不仅仅是认可。他应该得到所有这些有形的奖励，”另一人写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国已经深深地依赖送餐工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到 2022 年，为中国最大的两个送餐员工作的送餐司机总数根据公司数据，送餐平台的数量达到了惊人的 738 万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些工人在困难的条件和苛刻的工作时间表下面临确保及时送货的挑战，往往会引起公众的极大同情和支持。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;去年 12 月，在东南部的福建省，一群消防员不得不帮助一名精疲力竭倒在路边的女送货司机。他们将她带到了消防站，并通知了她的家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但有些送货司机就没那么幸运了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 7 月，中国东部山东省的一名顾客阻止了一场据网上报道，送货司机禁止她乘坐电梯，辱骂她并向她扔热面条。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[More South Koreans snap up plunging yen, flock to Japan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3224481/more-south-koreans-snap-plunging-yen-flock-japan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 13:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/fc8c7fed-cb11-413d-b31a-2da0cf001027_0c50fd06.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;越来越多的韩国人购买日本货币并作为日元前往日本汇率贬值至八年来的最低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汇率接近每 100 日元兑 900 韩元（0.71 美元），周二跌至每 100 日元兑 904 韩元，这是自以来的最低水平2015 年 6 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到 4 月份汇率处于 1,000 韩元的水平，市场观察家对如此急剧的下跌感到惊讶。他们谨慎地预测，该汇率可能很快就会跌破 900 韩元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日元走弱的主要原因是日本和其他主要经济体的不同货币政策。日本一直保持货币宽松政策，而许多其他国家则效仿美联储收紧货币政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本“挤满”游客，而中国游客甚至还没有回来&lt;/p h3>;&lt;p>;最近外国投资涌入韩国金融市场导致韩元相对升值，也加速了这一趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这导致越来越多的韩国人开始购买日本的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周三，韩国主要商业银行的日元存款余额为 8082 亿日元，比 5 月底增长 15.8%。在短短 10 个工作日内，韩国人的账户增加了 1103 亿日元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候购买了大量日元的上班族 Kim Ju-yeon 说，她认为没有理由不这样做&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此时购买日元非常有吸引力。韩元兑日元的平均汇率约为每 100 日元兑换 1,000 韩元。一旦恢复到正常水平，我预计投资回报率将在 10% 左右，这是我预期的最低水平，”Kim 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管今年第二季度总体而言考虑到淡季，前往日本旅游的韩国人数量明显激增。甚至有人说去日本旅行比在东南亚旅行更划算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据航空统计，6月1日至10日期间，有89,847人乘坐仁川和东京之间的航线。这是与 1 月份前 10 天的 66,741 人次相比增加了 34.6。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;飞往日本的低成本航空公司平均预订率为 90%，促使航空业增加航班数量并为日本引入新的目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，有人担心日元长期贬值会削弱韩国的出口竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本削减私人飞机和超级游艇的繁文缛节以吸引超级富有的游客&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日元比韩元走弱使得日本产品在海外市场上比韩国产品更便宜。由于许多游客选择日本而不是韩国，国内服务业也可能受到负面影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，日元疲软预计将暂时持续。日本央行可能维持鸽派政策，导致日元进一步贬值。预计今年下半年韩元将温和升值，具体取决于经济复苏的程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首发于&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Drone and missile war in Ukraine lays bare gaps in Europe’s air defences after decades of complacency]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224482/drone-and-missile-war-ukraine-lays-bare-gaps-europes-air-defences-after-decades-complacency?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 13:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/6717c4ce-bc60-47e9-ab57-64d2574a36d0_f68a382d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌克兰无人机和导弹战争的强度已经在欧洲国家中留下了空白专家表示，防空系统的堵塞将很困难、耗时且成本高昂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;防空系统很可能在周一开始的巴黎航空展上扮演主角，管理人员理查德·阿布拉菲亚 (Richard Aboulafia) 预测AeroDynamic Advisory 总监。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“您会看到很多关于导弹生产能力的讨论。导弹市场无疑是该行业中增长最快的部分，但制造商根本跟不上，”阿布拉菲亚说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自冷战结束以来，西方国家一直享有对天空的完全掌控战争和曾经旨在保护北约部队免受苏联飞机攻击的强大防御系统在很大程度上被放弃了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国会议员在最近的一份报告中指出，法国摆脱了其九个高射炮团中的八个。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;普京说俄罗斯的核弹现在在白俄罗斯，向西方发出警告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但随着越来越多的国家获得巡航导弹、短程弹道导弹，北约国家近年来再次转向防空美国战略与国际研究中心 (CSIS) 的高级顾问、退休的美国海军陆战队上校 Mark Cancian 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们开始了，但基本上没有得到太远了，”Cancian 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“再过五年，我认为会有更多，但这对乌克兰现在没有帮助，”他补充说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于缺乏防空系统及其发射的导弹，西方正努力响应乌克兰的补给请求——无论是短程防御还是远程防御。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柏林计划斥资 50 亿美元从 1000 亿欧元（1100 亿美元）的基金中拨款用于防空，用于在未来几年重建其武装部队，巴黎为 2030 年期间制定了相同的预算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于工业方面，欧洲导弹制造商 MBDA 最近几个月与法国和意大利签署了价值 20 亿欧元的合同，供应 700 枚 Aster 导弹，特别用于 SAMP/T 系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;波兰将花费 22 亿欧元在 44 个发射器和数百枚 CAMM 导弹上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在德国的带领下，17 个欧洲国家去年通过“欧洲天盾”项目在防空方面联合起来——尽管法国、意大利和波兰都没有参加。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划将涉及短程、中程和远程系统的联合采购，包括德国制造的 Iris-T、美国爱国者和美以 Arrow-3。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aboulafia 说，在盟国之间进行协调“意义重大”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，“每当北约试图标准化时，显然必须在谁领导生产和设计”，他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们以前看过这部电影，但最大的问题始终是法国，”阿布拉菲亚说，法国不愿放弃工业领导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰： Russian missile kills 4 in Kharkiv, ambassador calls for more support&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Germany&#39;s proposal does not take European security interests sufficiently into account, has failed to convince partners, and leaves many questions unanswered on the strategic, military, industrial , and economic levels,” Berlin-based think-tank SWP wrote in a recent report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By choosing US and Israeli technology rather than European, the German-led plan is also “at odds with the goal of strengthening Europe&#39;s industrial and technological defence base”, SWP added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The recent French MPs&#39; report directly criticised the Sky Shield, lamenting “the total lack of European solutions … versus promotion of American and Israeli products”.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Yet another Israeli offering, a new hypersonic missile interceptor from Rafael defence Systems, could tempt European governments when displayed in Paris next week, after Russia fired its much-hyped Kinzhal nuclear-capable weapons into Ukraine.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Alongside the Paris Air Show, the French government has invited ministers to a conference on air defence to try and smooth over differences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Germans have proposed an industrial agreement, we offer a strategic initiative : having the capacity for European air defence that is sovereign, with European equipment,” a French diplomatic source said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong-listed Chow Tai Fook Jewellery targets mainland China’s smaller cities to tap young consumers’ growing appetite for gold]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3224403/hong-kong-listed-chow-tai-fook-jewellery-targets-mainland-chinas-smaller-cities-tap-young-consumers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/397d2ce3-d8cc-45a4-bc89-333e99dc13e7_df489291.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chow Tai Fook Jewellery Group, China&#39;s largest jewellery retailer, is moving into smaller, less affluent cities in the mainland to pursue growth as retail spending falters in the world&#39;s biggest consumer market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Young consumers in lower-tier cities have demonstrated an increasing penchant for gold and diamonds, and the time is right to set up stores there to tap the burgeoning demand, said managing director Kent Wong Siu-kee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We found that some of the customers would travel from their hometowns to top-tier cities to visit our stores,” he told reporters at a media briefing in Shanghai. “Consumers in the lower-tier cities are willing to spend [on jewellery] and we need to open outlets that are within their reach.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong expressed confidence in China&#39;s economy, predicting that the recent turbulence will turn out to be short-lived.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s mainland now accounts for nearly 90 per cent of Chow Tai Fook&#39;s total revenue. The Hong Kong-listed retailer runs 7,269 shops in the mainland, most of them based in the affluent top-tier and second-tier cities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After reaching their target to open 7,000 stores in the mainland in the past financial year, two years ahead of schedule, the company plans to add another 600 to 800 outlets in the mainland in the current financial year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That number represents a slower rate of expansion, amid a weak consumer market. Chow Tai Fook established new 1,600 stores in the last financial year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said the company would focus on helping the new stores to develop as businesses. It normally takes about two years for a new jewellery shop to earn a good reputation and attract strong foot traffic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Top jewellery retailers like Chow Tai Fook have a large customer base, and it is not unusual for them to also have higher risk appetite when making and enforcing expansion plans,” said Chen Xiao, chief executive of Shanghai Yacheng Culture, a marketing and branding company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As they move down to those rural regions, smaller gold and jewellery retailers will face difficulties in retaining their loyal customers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese people have a long-held tradition of investing in gold, believing that the precious metal is the best hedging tool against inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow Tai Fook expanded rapidly in China during the Covid-19 pandemic as consumers bought more gold as a safe-haven investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was originally established in Guangzhou in 1929 by Chow Chi-yuan. His son-in-law, Cheng Yu-tung, who rose from being an apprentice at the jewellery shop, helped Chow Tai Fook expand in Hong Kong before taking over the company in 1956.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mainland&#39;s economy remains sluggish even after its reopening following three years of tough anti-Covid measures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Retail sales last month rose 12.7 per cent on the year, 5.7 percentage points lower than the 18.4 per cent annual jump recorded in April, data from the National Bureau of Statistics showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The growth missed the expected year-on-year rise of 13.6 per cent, which was based on a survey of analysts by data provider Wind Information in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jobless rate for people aged 16 to 24 hit a new high of 20.8 per cent in May, up from 20.4 per cent in April, fuelling worries about a further slump in consumer spending.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s fetishists find a safe haven for their sexual preferences at Tokyo’s Department H: ‘I come here to be myself’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/lifestyle-culture/article/3224364/japans-fetishists-find-safe-haven-their-sexual-preferences-tokyos-department-h-i-come-here-be-myself?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/a0800a57-2a37-42c6-bb49-7c85f4367b13_8538a4b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Makeshiki cuts quite a figure as he strides through the revellers. Tall for a Japanese man – admittedly enhanced by his boots – he is clad from head to toe in sheer black latex, although the skin-tight hood that conceals his face has openings for his eyes and mouth that are ringed in red.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such an expression of counterculture sexuality would be impossible to carry off in everyday Japan, but here, within the safe space of Department H at the Tokyo Kinema Club, the nation&#39;s fetishists are able to wear their preferences on their sleeve. Assuming they have that much clothing on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have been coming here every month for the last seven years,” says Makeshiki, who is cagey about giving too much away. He is 37 years old and works for one of Japan&#39;s big telecommunications companies, but is reluctant to provide details that could potentially identify him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am a salaryman. Some years ago I discovered that I love latex,” he says. “But this is my secret. I have never told my family or my friends, even my closest friends. I don&#39;t think they would understand. I actually do not think they would try to understand if I tried to explain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I suppose I am often uncomfortable in Japanese society and I come here to be myself,” he adds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is my freedom.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is a sentiment I heard expressed time and again over the course of the evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Department H is this year celebrating 15 years as Tokyo&#39;s premier event for fetishists of every flavour, although it can trace its history back to the first Salon KittyFire 2099 soirée in Shibuya in 1994.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The event gets its name from a Canadian government department in the X-Men comic-book series, whose members include Northstar – one of the first openly gay characters to appear in a US comic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While evenings were quieter during the coronavirus pandemic, party-goers are now making up for lost time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Held on the first Saturday of every month, Department H&#39;s doors open at midnight and the final attendees are typically ushered out well after dawn has broken over the Uguisudani district of love hotels, bars and convenience stores.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan raises age of consent from 13 to 16 as former teen stars seek change&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Each event has a theme, such as April Fool&#39;s Day and an evening dedicated to female sumo wrestlers. The Japanese wedding industry is enthusiastic about “June brides”, so I am welcomed in the foyer by two strapping transvestites wearing lacy wedding dresses, veils, high heels and two pairs of huge, fluttering eyelashes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IDs are carefully checked and, at reception, I quickly discover I am dramatically underdressed in T-shirt and shorts. The entrance fee is 5,000 yen (US$36), although the attractive lady at the desk in a wig and a black thong under a fishnet body stocking lets me know that I will get a discount if I make more of an effort with my attire next time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A large glass box set into the wall contains the “catch of the day”, a bare-chested woman with a mermaid&#39;s tail who smiles demurely and waves at passers-by. Double doors open to a gracefully curving balcony congested with men and women in chains and leather, rubber or latex or gossamer-thin layers that are designed to leave nothing to the imagination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one corner, a man is overseeing a workshop on shibari, the Japanese art of rope bondage, giving tips on knots and the best ropes to use. Nearby, tattoo fetishists are comparing skin ink on every part of their anatomies while others admire piercings. A man walks past in a gas mask and a pair of briefs. A short woman in red leather tugs at a man on a leash as he crawls hurriedly to keep up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mayumi is dancing alongside the stage on the ground floor of the venue, hair pulled back and encased in leather straps across her entire body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I guess it&#39;s curiosity,” she says when asked why she is here tonight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is my second time. I enjoyed the first time and met some interesting people, so I thought I would try it again.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 40-year-old consultant says Department H offers “a great atmosphere and anyone can do whatever they want. I really like that freedom.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suddenly, the stage comes alive with the master of ceremonies standing in a spotlight, replete in wedding dress. The applause is deafening. The MC introduces his fellow “brides” before the evening&#39;s festivities really get under way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Galatia Suzaku and Norio Ichigozaki appear in more traditional Japanese wedding attire, with the addition of a fox mask for the bride, and perform an athletic part-dance part-striptease that concludes with them both in their underwear. Next on stage, shibari expert Takashi Murakami intricately binds his pliant victim, Jin, and hoists him off the stage. As a finale, Murakami suspends Jin horizontally and gives him a couple of electric shocks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Not allowing same-sex marriage is &#39;state of unconstitutionality&#39;: Japan court&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tosuke has worked his way to the front of the crowd and is applauding enthusiastically.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This place is special to me and people like me,” he says. “Here, I can be anything I want to be and do anything I want. Department H is barrier-free.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Short and powerfully built, Tosuke is a 54-year-old anime artist who describes himself as a “gay bear” who also enjoys performing burlesque.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He dismisses the notion some may have that Department H is a pick-up joint for Tokyo&#39;s sexual minorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s not what all this is about,” he says. “There are plenty of bars and clubs where gays or anyone else can meet other people. But this night is all about having fun and doing what we want to.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To Tosuke&#39;s approval, the next act on stage is an accomplished burlesque dancer who makes the most of a pair of bright-red feathered fans. A team of samba dancers, in dazzling regalia and skimpy costumes, starts to dance as the crowd begins to take things into their own hands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A woman with bright-red hair, leather bindings and a studded collar has lined three willing participants up against a wall and is soundly thrashing their bare buttocks with a cat o&#39; nine tails.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearby, a young woman in leather and high heels sits astride a middle-aged man on his knees and is enthusiastically slapping his buttocks, while just yards away, a girl wrapped in bandages splotched with what I assume is fake blood sings on the stage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All around us, no one bats an eyelid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As I look on, Yuko sidles up alongside me. She is wearing the sort of all-in-one swimsuits that high-school girls wear and looks about 15 years old – but tells me she is 35.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She leans in to make herself heard and repeats the oft-heard refrain that Japanese society is not open and that here, at Department H, she can be herself and really feel “free”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still holding my eyes, she reaches out and with an indelible marker draws a smiley face on my forearm. And with the grin of a teenager but the insight of a 30-something, she adds the characters chikan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It means pervert and it won&#39;t wash off. No one gets out of Department H unscathed.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong father steps up to become autistic daughter’s mediator, mentor, coach and hero]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3224420/hong-kong-father-steps-become-autistic-daughters-mediator-mentor-coach-and-hero?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/fc82ab87-0b21-4966-b891-e5728b8995c6_9e2f090a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hongkonger Yuki Chan Ka-man was 24 when she was diagnosed with autism, and that finally explained the obstacles she faced as a child and in school, and her clashes with her mother.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was her father, Steven Chan Yiu-man, 63, who made the difference, stepping in as mediator between mother and daughter, being the girl&#39;s mentor and even her running coach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ka-man, now 29 and working full-time as an activity assistant at a care centre for children with special education needs, said: “I know it has been difficult to bring up an autistic child like me. I am stubborn and get emotional easily, but my dad treats me with great patience and tolerance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her father recalled that when she was seven years old, there were frequent angry spats between the girl and her mother, and he had to step in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When Ka-man started school, she could not write or even hold a pen properly, and her mother often scolded her,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her brother, one year younger, learned much faster and it infuriated Ka-man when her mother appeared to favour the boy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Eventually, Ka-man hated listening to her mum and would scream whenever her mum spoke to her,” Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It took him three years to fix the relationship. He had to persuade his wife to scold the girl less, to avoid provoking her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The turning point came when his wife fell ill. “I told Ka-man that her mum loved her and if she kept herself away, mum would be sad,” Chan recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;From the ashes: Hong Kong charity&#39;s HK$1.5 million bid to rebuild after fire&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Although the girl had some behavioural issues – she would subconsciously shake her head, blink at a high frequency and her lips would tremble – her autism went undetected through school and into early adulthood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was only after she dropped out of her higher diploma programme that she underwent checks that revealed the condition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clinical psychologist Rhonda Poon Wing-tak said it was rare for a person with autism to be diagnosed so late.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A child as young as two years old can be diagnosed,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Poon said there could be various reasons for a late diagnosis.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Early signs of autism could be picked up in child&#39;s first month: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Some patients may not display very obvious symptoms, and some parents are simply not aware that their children might be autistic,” she said. “The earlier a person with autism is diagnosed, the better.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Without early care and training, a person with autism could face challenges in social interaction, self-care and solving problems, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After her diagnosis, Ka-man was advised to exercise more, and her father took her running in parks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said that at first, she would be panting after running for just 10 minutes. But he kept up their runs and with his training, she has completed two 10km races in the Standard Chartered Hong Kong Marathon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finding a job was hard after she dropped out of her higher diploma course.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;With autistic daughter stuck at home, she opened a cafe to give her work&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;At her first job as a receptionist in a toy store, she said her colleagues and bosses teased her and called her “autistic girl”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan helped to calm her down by reassuring her that they were not discriminating against her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She has done better at her current job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan was proud that she contributed HK$6,000 (US$766) a month towards the family expenses, and happy that she even gave her mother HK$500 to attend morning tea gatherings with her friends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They are in a good relationship now and talk to each other every night after Ka-man gets off from work,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 2018 survey by rehabilitation organisation Heep Hong Society found that nearly one in two autistic adults in Hong Kong were never employed, and more than two-thirds of employers knew little about autism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The situation has improved a lot since 2018, and many employers have called to ask if we have any clients open to work,” said Alan Tam Tsz-hong, manager of the organisation&#39;s Star Light Centre, which helps people with autism aged 15 or above.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Hong Kong workplace is more inclusive now, but the mindset of frontline workers should also change. They should understand it is not weird to work with an autistic colleague,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a government survey in 2020, Hong Kong had 22,400 people with autism or 0.3 per cent of the population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Tam felt that was an underestimation. “After referring to data in other countries, we estimate the autistic population in Hong Kong to be around 100,000,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why US defence deal with Papua New Guinea is likely to ‘set China further back’ in the Pacific]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224451/why-us-defence-deal-papua-new-guinea-likely-set-china-further-back-pacific?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/d4840832-60fa-409d-88e2-857f7762a9d5_af123ff4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Papua New Guinea&#39;s recent defence of a landmark US security pact included a message to China that it was business as usual, as the Pacific becomes a new theatre for great power rivalry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Defence Cooperation Agreement, signed last month, would give US troops unrestricted access to some of PNG&#39;s seaports and airports – a move that could potentially bolster the US military&#39;s defence of its Guam bases in the Pacific “second island chain”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deal signalled greater presence for the US and a further setback for China in the region, where Beijing has failed to make major inroads beyond trade despite high-level engagement in recent years, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the PNG government sought to allay lawmakers&#39; concerns over a clause giving legal immunity to US personnel posted in the island country, it also assured China that ties with the island nation&#39;s No 2 trade partner would not be damaged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our friends in China know us,” Prime Minister James Marape told parliament on Wednesday, when debate on the US deal began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China and Beijing also know that this government gave Beijing priority over Taipei … the Chinese government knows exactly where the heart of this government is. And that is to promote national interests, not geopolitical interests or their interests.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We relate to trade with them and we never compromise on trade with them,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia has for decades been the main security partner for island nations in the southwestern Pacific, but the region has emerged to be yet another theatre for US-China competition as both seek to expand their political, economic and security influence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese companies have long eyed PNG&#39;s wealth of natural resources – from oil to minerals, natural gas, timber and fish – and have invested in mines, hydropower stations and basic infrastructure such as highways, telecommunications and housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But China&#39;s inroads into PNG and other southwestern Pacific countries have largely remained restricted to trade. An eight-nation tour of the region by then Chinese foreign minister Wang Yi in May last year failed to produce a security or policing cooperation deal due to a lack of consensus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Where diplomacy has succeeded, such as striking a security deal with the Solomon Islands, it has prompted greater engagement by the US and its allies Japan and South Korea to counter China&#39;s influence in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korea&#39;s &#39;pro-US&#39; Pacific tilt triggers alarm, warnings in China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Marape said on Wednesday that the defence cooperation agreement would allow PNG to work with the US in reconnaissance, surveillance, exchange of classified information and arms procurement, but not offer a “basis for military operations to be staged” in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are increasingly becoming aware that the traditional security alliances are inadequate to cover the current global, regional and national security challenges,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stewart Firth, a research fellow at the Australian National University&#39;s Pacific affairs department, said that while Marape was conscious of his country&#39;s “extreme military weakness”, it would be an exaggeration to expect the PNG bases to be used to support US troops in a potential attack on Taiwan by Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That might be drawing a long bow, but the arrangement would certainly complement the new base plans for the Philippines, whose northern islands are only a few hundred kilometres from Taiwan,” Firth said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The arrangement would support Guam by creating an arc of US military power from Australia to Guam and beyond.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines in April said it would give the US access to four more of its bases, three close to Taiwan and another further south next to the South China Sea, the site of several territorial disputes involving Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Firth said Chinese investment in PNG was unlikely to fall because of the new pact, because infrastructure-building had been good for Chinese companies and firms often mattered more than the Chinese government in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is already on the back foot in the Pacific, following the foreign minister&#39;s unsuccessful tour of the region last year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Firth said China appeared to have misunderstood the long tradition of regionalism among Pacific islands to work in concert. This put its proposed “Common Development Vision” with 10 Pacific countries, which included security cooperation, out of reach despite Wang&#39;s multinational trip.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think this [PNG-US] agreement will set China further back in the region,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of the Pacific nations have acted as a bloc to address common security challenges, including illegal fishing and rising sea levels, which threaten their economy and even existence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of the illegal fishing has been carried out by Chinese fishers, who make up the world&#39;s biggest industrial distant-water fishing fleet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The presence of Chinese ships in the southwestern Pacific has also been unwelcome.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palau recently sought US help to deter “unwanted activities” around its coasts by mainland Chinese vessels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a visit to Japan on Thursday, President Surangel Whipps Jnr said three Chinese boats had entered “uninvited” into Palau&#39;s waters since he took office in 2021. The US was responsible for Palau&#39;s security and needed to help deter unwanted activities, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s foreign ministry said the Chinese vessels were in the area to seek shelter and did not conduct surveys or investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palau, one of the four Pacific nations that recognise Taipei, has no official ties with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bernard Yegiora, an international relations lecturer at Divine Word University in Madang, PNG, said the security pact was a “significant victory for the US”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They will now closely monitor what China is doing in the western Pacific and in PNG. More importantly, the agreements will help increase US capability and capacity to contain China&#39;s influence in the western Pacific,” Yegiora said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PNG and the US also signed the Shiprider Agreement in May that aims to bolster PNG&#39;s ability to track illegal fishing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But PNG lacked a strategic foreign policy framework to help it engage with other states in Southeast Asia and the Pacific, Yegiora added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I doubt PNG has any strategic objective in helping the US hedge [against] China or see the issue from this strategic perspective. I say this because no PNG politician or political commentator has said anything about US strategic hedging or the need to understand US strategic hedging efforts in the Indo-Pacific region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The main interest which influenced PNG to help the US is our domestic security and economic interest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We see the deal as an opportunity to improve our capability and capacity to defend our borders and to inject more money into our economy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US troops to access PNG ports, airports in new security pact to counter China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said the PNG government could increase tax holidays for Chinese businesses investing in its planned special economic zones to prevent a fallout with China as a result of the US deal, which it has yet to ratify.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Zhou Bo, a senior fellow at Tsinghua University&#39;s Centre for International Security and Strategy, said there was no need to view the deal as targeting China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Neither side has mentioned targeting China,” said Zhou, a retired PLA senior colonel. “We are yet to be sure about the size of their activities, the number of personnel and equipment involved.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has also given logistical support for PNG, including Covid-related medical supplies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Multiple bilateral agreements were signed in February 2022 when Marupe attended the opening ceremony of the Beijing Winter Olympics, including those related to fishery and loans for a PNG electric grid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talks on the US security deal, on the other hand, began in 2016 under former PNG prime minister Peter O&#39;Neill, whose party now sits in the opposition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The signed pact covers the Lombrum naval base, the airport and seaport in the capital Port Moresby, and smaller ports, according to a passage read out in parliament by O&#39;Neill.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>